<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctcovhs/ctcovhs_default_ead.xsl"?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead> 

<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 

audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b"> 

<eadid mainagencycode="ctcovhs" countrycode="us" url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctcovhs/whiteJacobson.xml">whiteJacobson</eadid> 

<filedesc> 

<titlestmt> 

<titleproper>White and Jacobson Family Collection</titleproper> 

<author>Collection guide written by Historical Society Staff. </author> 

<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from the Institute of Museum and Library Services to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor> 

</titlestmt> 

<publicationstmt><publisher>Coventry Historical Society</publisher> 

<address><addressline>2382 South St.</addressline> 

<addressline>P.O. Box 534</addressline> 

<addressline>Coventry</addressline> 

<addressline>CT</addressline> 

<addressline>06238</addressline> 

<addressline>email: info@ctcoventryhistoricalsociety.org</addressline> 

<addressline>URL: http://www.ctcoventryhistoricalsociety.org</addressline> 

<addressline>Phone: (860) 742-3054</addressline></address> 



<date>Jan 25, 2018</date> 

<p>http://www.ctcoventryhistoricalsociety.org</p></publicationstmt> 

</filedesc> 

<profiledesc> 

<creation><date>.</date> 

</creation> 

<langusage> 

Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language> 

</langusage> 

</profiledesc> 

</eadheader> 

<frontmatter> 

<titlepage> 

<num>Collection number: CHS 2026</num> 

<publisher>Coventry Historical Society 

<lb/>2382 South St. 

<lb/>P.O. Box 534 Coventry, CT 06238</publisher> 

<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from the Institute of Museum and Library Services to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p> 

<list type="deflist"> 

<defitem> 

<label>Collection guide written by:</label> 

<item>Historical Society Staff</item> 

</defitem> 

</list> 

<p>&#x00A9; 2018 Coventry Historical Society. All rights reserved.</p> 

</titlepage> 

</frontmatter> 

<archdesc level="collection"> 

<did> 

<head>Collection Summary</head> 

<origination label="Creator"> 

<persname source="DA:CS">White Family; Jacobson Family</persname> 

</origination> 

<unittitle>White and Jacobson Family Collection</unittitle> 

<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="ctcovhs" countrycode="us">CHS 2026</unitid> 

<physdesc label="Extent"> 

<extent>8 linear feet </extent> 

<extent> 11 Boxes </extent> 

</physdesc> 

<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Coventry Historical Society</corpname> 

<!-- <address><addressline> 2382 South St.</addressline></address> --> 

</repository> 

<abstract label="Abstract">Correspondence, diaries, financial records, property records and photographs of the White and Jacobson families of Coventry, Connecticut. </abstract> 

<langmaterial label="Languages Represented"> 

<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>. 

</langmaterial> 

<physloc label="Physical Location">West Archives Storage Room, Family Collections Shelves</physloc> 

</did> 

<accessrestrict> 

<head>Restrictions</head> 

<p>The collection is open and available for research use. Copyright restrictions apply.</p> 

</accessrestrict> 

<userestrict> 

<head>Publication Rights</head> 

<p>For copyright status, please contact the Coventry Historical Society.</p> 

</userestrict> 

<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head> 

<p>[Identification of item],  White and Jacobson Family Collection, [Box no]., Coventry Historical Society</p> 

</prefercite> 

<acqinfo> 

<head>Acquisition Information</head> 

<p>Gift of George G. Jacobson II through Lyndon Wilmot, 2005. Some items were purchased by Coventry Historical Society at a sale at the home of Margaret E. Jacobson, 1999.</p> 

</acqinfo> 

<bioghist> 

<head>Biography</head> 

<p>James White purchased land in Coventry, CT on Ripley Hill Road in 1732 from the father of Abigail Lyman, shortly after marrying her. James White moved to Coventry, CT from Stafford Springs, CT. His descendants have owned and lived on land in the area on or near Cooper Lane for seven generations. The White family ran a cooper shop, store, farm and lumber mill. The White family was connected through marriage to the Lyman, Thompson, Colman, Yeomans, Armstrong, Washburn and Jacobson families, and through business to the Edgerton, Porter, Manning and Rose families. The White family also held local government and church responsibilities including terms as Selectman and State Representative.</p> 

<p>The Jacobson family emigrated from Sweden. Charles Jacobson married Margaret Smith in 1877 in Glastonbury, CT. Margaret Smith emigrated from Scotland. The Jacobsons settled in Mansfield, CT where they farmed and ran a hauling and carting business. Their son George Goodwin Jacobson I married Mary Laura White, daughter of Nathan Coleman and Sarah (Yeomans) White, in 1906. The house at the corner of Cooper Lane and Root Road eventually became their home. Margaret E. Jacobson, the daughter of George Goodwin Jacobson I and Mary Laura White, lived much of her life in the house at the corner of Cooper Lane and Root Road. George Goodwin Jacobson II is the son of the brother of Margaret E. Jacobson.</p> 

</bioghist> 

<scopecontent> 

<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head> 

<p>The collection documents seven generations of family members related to James White (1708-1765) and George G. Jacobson I (1883-1859) including personal correspondence, diaries, autograph books, genealogies, Bible records, photographs and poetry. Business activities of the families are recorded in business correspondence, receipts and account books. Land and property owned by the families is documented in deeds, property drawings, tax records, probate records and other legal documents. Reports, school records, student compositions, First church and library records document the history of the town of Coventry. Included are the Building Inspector's record (1964), the First Selectman and Treasurer's Reports (1867-186?) Committee, Girl Scouts, League of Women Voters and Coventry Historical Society. Records of Margaret E. Jacobson's career with the State Police are also included.</p> 

</scopecontent> 

<arrangement> 

<head>Arrangement</head> 

<p>The collection is arranged by subject and within each subject, chronologically.</p> 

</arrangement> 

<controlaccess> 

<head>Indexing Terms</head> 

<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in 

the library's online public access catalog.</p> 

<genreform encodinganalog="655">Account Books</genreform> 

<genreform encodinganalog="655">Account Books</genreform> 

<genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform> 

<genreform encodinganalog="655">Deeds</genreform> 

<genreform encodinganalog="655">Militaria</genreform> 

<genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform> 

<genreform encodinganalog="655">Probate Records</genreform> 

<subject>Libraries-Connecticut-Records and correspondence</subject> 

<subject>Selectmen-Connecticut</subject> 

<subject>Lumbering-1850-1920</subject> 

<subject>Farming-1900-1920</subject> 

<subject>Dairying-1910-1940 </subject> 

<subject>Coopers and cooperage-1800-1820 </subject> 

<subject>Coventry, (Conn.)-History</subject> 

<subject>Surveying--1800-1820</subject> 

<persname>Jacobson, George G., 1883-1959</persname> 

<persname>Jacobson, Margaret E., 1907-2005</persname> 

<persname>Seymour, George Dudley, 1859-1945</persname> 

<persname>White, Abner, 1742-1795</persname> 

<persname>White, Nathan Coleman, 1832-1903</persname> 

<persname>White, Montgomery, 1779-1865</persname> 

<persname>Crane, John N.</persname> 



</controlaccess> 

<relatedmaterial> 

<head>Related Collections</head> 

<p>The Kingsbury Box Factory wagon, built at the Armstrong Wagon Works on Armstrong Road in Coventry, CT and related items were also donated by the ancestors of Mary Armstrong White. Also held by Coventry Historical Society is a miniature of the house at 230 Cooper Lane, made by Walter Jacobson as a dollhouse for his daughter Donna, and an interview with George G. Jacobson II recorded by Ginney Dilk.</p> 

</relatedmaterial> 





<!-- Insert DSC here --> 





</archdesc> 

</ead>



