<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002//EN" "ead.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="eadcbs9b.xsl"?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtHi"
            url="http://www.chs.org/finding_aides/finding_aids/adam_william.html"
            >adam_william</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Dr. William Adam account book
                    collection</titleproper>
                <subtitle encodinganalog="245$b">A Guide to the collection at the Connecticut
                    Historical Society </subtitle>
                <author>Compiled by CHS Staff</author>

            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Connecticut Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
<addressline>1 Elizabeth Street</addressline>
<addressline>Hartford, CT 06105</addressline>
</address>
                <p>Copyright 2012, Connecticut Historical Society</p>
                <date>2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Created by CHS Staff, <date>June 2012</date>.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">

        <did>
            <head>Collection Overview</head>
            <repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository:"><corpname>Connecticut Historical
                    Society,
                </corpname><address>
    <addressline>Hartford, Connecticut</addressline>
   </address>
            </repository>
            <origination encodinganalog="100" label="Creator :">Adam, William</origination>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title :">Dr. William Adam account book
                collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Dates : ">1748-1875</unitdate>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Extent :"><extent>12 linear feet (48 volumes,
                    1/2 box)</extent></physdesc>

            <physloc label="Location:" altrender="Location :">Ms 100044</physloc>
            <langmaterial encodinganalog="546">English</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
            <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
            <p>Samuel Forbes (1729-1827) was born in Simsbury, Connecticut, the son of John and Lucy
                Pierce Forbes. When he first moved to Canaan, Samuel went to work for his father’s
                partner, Richard Seymour, in an iron forge. John Forbes bought the forge in 1751;
                his son Samuel developed it into a major manufactory along the Blackberry River in
                Canaan. Along with a general store, Samuel Forbes directed production at the
                Salisbury furnace and iron works in East Canaan. As part of the firm Pettibone &amp;
                Forbes, Samuel also owned two ore beds in Salisbury. He owned several blast furnaces
                in Norfolk, Conn. and a nail mill in nearby Washington, Conn.</p>
            <p>John Adam (1714-1802) was born in Scotland and immigrated to Boston in 1737. He
                married Sarah Leonard of Easton, Massachusetts and later lived in Taunton,
                Massachusetts, where they had sons John (1755-1826) and Robert (1762-1796), among
                their other children. In 1794 John Sr. moved to Salisbury, Connecticut.</p>
            <p>John Adam Sr.’s son John had been a partner in a slitting mill in Taunton before
                moving to Canaan, Connecticut in 1780, where he married Abigail, the daughter of
                Samuel Forbes. The partnership of Forbes &amp; Adam was formed shortly thereafter.
                By 1785 they had a successful rolling and slitting mill in East Canaan. John and
                Abigail’s children included Samuel F. (1783-1854) and Leonard (1788-1835) who
                followed their father into the iron trade. Samuel F. Adam is credited as the builder
                of the first blast furnace in East Canaan.</p>
            <p>Additional biographical information can be found in the collection file in the
                archivist’s office. Collections at the CHS related to the iron industry in
                Connecticut include Cornwall Iron Co. furnace records, labor accounts and a daybook,
                1836-1901; papers of Forbes &amp; Adam, 1766-1844; Ebenezer Jenks account book,
                1788-1823; Holley &amp; Coffing families of Salisbury family and business
                correspondence, 1786-1837; the papers of Wilson Clark; and an account book of Ore
                Hill Mine in Kent, 1789-1803. </p>


        </bioghist>
        <arrangement>
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>An attempt was made to separate the accounts of Samuel Forbes, John Adam Sr. and John
                Adam from those of the firm Forbes &amp; Adam. At times the distinction was
                difficult to determine. Further research into the individuals and the firm may
                reveal additional information that will improve identification of the volumes.</p>
            <p>Account books attributed to Samuel Forbes are arranged chronologically in Series I,
                those of John Adam Sr. in Series II, John Adam in Series III and those of Forbes
                &amp; Adam and the various re-organizations of the firm in Series IV. An additional
                Series was created for two account books that were kept by Samuel F. Adam, and one
                account book that does not appear to be related to the Adam or Forbes family and two
                bound volumes of a newspaper were assigned to Series V.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="520$a">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p> The value in this collection is the depth of information on rural northeastern
                Connecticut that can be gleaned from the volumes. Not only is the iron industry
                documented, but the literacy rate, women’s economic role in the community, skilled
                labor, accounting practices and the lives of free blacks are also part of this
                record.</p>
            <p>The earliest ledger in the collection belonged to John Forbes and his son Samuel,
                1748-1760. These entries indicate the men were blacksmiths, shoeing horses, mending
                tools, making a new chain. Turning the book over and starting from the opposite end,
                one can find records of the firm Pettibone &amp; Forbes, 1786-1793 which traded in
                iron ore. Entries in this portion of the volume include a note about the new ore
                bead "owned by Giles Pettibone and myself," and iron ore from the "bead dug by men
                that we employed to dig by the day."</p>
            <p>A real estate volume, dated 1755-1803, documents the transfer of the forge, mill and
                ore mine owned by John Forbes to his son Samuel. In 1760, there is an entry about
                building a forge in the town of Norfolk, and another entry noting the purchase of
                John Forbes’s 999 year lease of 1/32 of Salisbury Ore Hill. In 1784 Samuel Forbes
                purchases half interest in a forge and a quarter-interest in a saw mill on the
                Blackberry River. The volume also reveals that John Adam bought the Ore Hill Lot in
                Kent in 1796.</p>
            <p>The real estate transactions are recorded on the left hand page of the volume. The
                right hand page was used by Charles S. Adam to record daily and national events such
                as deaths, births, and marriages, and his financial transactions from 1854-1865. He
                notes that on Monday, March 9, 1863 he sold all of his rights in the furnace and
                gristmill.</p>
            <p>Charles appears to have scavenged paper wherever he could find it and filled more
                than one of his ancestor’s volumes with these types of entries. He also used pages
                from 18th century account books and some correspondence and other documents for his
                figuring, and these were found interleaved throughout the volumes he filled. The
                loose items have been removed and placed in folders, with the page at which the
                document(s) was found noted. Charles used straight pins to affix slips of paper
                where he did his figuring onto pages of his entries. In most cases, these have not
                been removed although pins that could tear the underlying paper have been removed.
                His additions to the volumes are noted in the descriptive list of account books.</p>
            <p>Samuel’s other account books, 1763-1789, record sales of general merchandise from his
                store. His customers include several free blacks. He also mentions the purchase of
                mills from John Ensign &amp; Son. An additional volume is entitled"Coppy of Notes of
                Hand" The inside inscription reads, "Notes in Hand the Property of Samuel Forbes of
                Canaan," and covers the dates 1785-1809.</p>
            <p>John Adam Sr.’s accounts, 1775-1794, the majority from Taunton, Massachusetts,
                illustrate his business in nail making and as owner of a slitting mill. He hires
                someone to improve his 1/16 part of the Easton furnace and has accounts with Simon
                and Joseph Tisdale, owners of the Mansfield Furnace. He also records, 1776-1777, the
                number of nails made of each type on any one day.</p>
            <p>Items Adam sold include nail rods, nails, horse shoes, and tacks, but the majority of
                entries are for general merchandise. Among his accounts is an early ledger kept by
                Ratcliffe Hellon, a shipbuilder of Taunton, from 1754-1767. How Adam acquired the
                ledger is unknown.</p>
            <p>Perhaps the most interesting volumes, number 11, contains this entry:"I begin on
                Saturday ye 8 of Febry 1794 to sett down a list of the books of acc’t that have been
                used by me &amp; for me since I moved frome Easton to Taunton in September
                1749."</p>
            <p>The first account book attributed to the younger John Adam is a ledger for the firm
                Adam &amp; Church, 1786-1806, the owners of a saw mill and a paper mill. Adam was
                also the agent and then a proprietor of Kent Ore Hill. The proceedings of the
                proprietors, 1790-1802, who incorporated in 1758, include copies of correspondence,
                deeds, contracts and articles of agreement. A ledger kept by the organization,
                1796-1806, includes Forbes &amp; Adam among their customers. A fourth volume
                assigned to John Adam contains additional paper and saw mill accounts, 1798-1799,
                and the accounts of Adam &amp; Beckley for coal, 1836-1837.</p>
            <p>Forbes &amp; Adam account and letter books range in date from 1783 to 1875 and
                consist of day books, an invoice book, waste books, ledgers, journals, and a pig
                iron book, among others. The records are for general merchandise bought from the
                company store, and for bar iron, nails, nail rods, rolled iron, paper and sawn
                lumber. The firm also sold anchors throughout the northeast.</p>
            <p>Of particular interest among these accounts is a volume entitled "Woman’s book,"
                1783-1823, recording the purchases of women, married and single, white and black,
                and their payments in butter, spun yarn, honey, weaving, cheese making and mending
                clothing, keeping school, house work and nursing. Most of the women are identified
                as being the wife of someone; on occasion their own first names never appear in the
                account.</p>
            <p>Also of interest is the number of free blacks who traded with the firm. When a volume
                has an"alphabet" or index, there is usually an entry under "N" for Negroes. Their
                accounts also include the label Negro after their names. In addition, many entries
                include the occupation of the customer and his town of residence, providing insight
                into the geographic span of the firm’s trade and the skilled and unskilled workers
                who lived in the area, including bloomers, diggers, and anchor smiths. Other
                customers included the Springfield (Massachusetts) Armory which purchased rolled
                iron to make gun barrels, and the Proprietors of Newgate Prison which purchased nail
                rods, presumably to have the inmates make nails.</p>
            <p>The purpose of an "alphabet" of accounts dated July 1800 (v. 34) was "to comprise the
                contents of Forbes &amp; Adams Books into small compass to find an account easy and
                soon." The inside cover and fly leaf of the volume is covered with detailed
                instructions as to what records were made, how the data was gathered, and into which
                new volumes the accounts appear. This is an unusual look into accounting practices
                of the 18th and early 19th centuries.</p>
            <p>Samuel F. Adam attended Yale College and accounts of his expenses while he was a
                student are included in his small ledger, dated 1785-1790. He and his brother
                Leonard were also involved in the iron industry, and their blotter, 1825-1833,
                includes the sale of a furnace crank, a steamboat shackle bar and piston rods, and
                anchors.</p>
            <p>The final Series contains seemingly unrelated items. A ledger that appears to have
                belonged to William Burrall, an early bloomery forge owner and merchant of Canaan,
                Conn. dates from 1771-1788. Two bound volumes of The Balance &amp; Columbian
                Repository, 1802, 1803, complete the collection.</p>




        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict>
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>There are no restrictions on access to the collection.</p>
        </accessrestrict>

        <userestrict>
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Use of the material requires compliance with the Connecticut Historical Society's
                Research Center regulations.</p>
        </userestrict>

        <prefercite>
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Item, Collection Title, Collection number (Box #, Folder #). Connecticut Historical
                Society, Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
        </prefercite>

        <processinfo>
            <head>Processing Details</head>
            <p>Collection was processed by Barbara Austen in 2008.</p>
            <p>EAD Finding Aid created June 2012.</p>

        </processinfo>

        <accruals>
            <head>Accruals</head>
            <p>The collection is closed.</p>
        </accruals>

        <controlaccess>
            <head>Subject Headings</head>

            <controlaccess>
                <head>Personal Names</head>

                <persname encodinganalog="700">Adam, Charles S.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Adam, John, 1714-1802.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Adam, John, 1755-1826.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Adam, Samuel F., 1783-1854.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Forbes, Samuel, 1729-1827</persname>
            </controlaccess>


            <controlaccess>
                <head>Corporate Names</head>
                <corpname encodinganalog="710">Forbes &amp; Adam (East Canaan, Conn.)</corpname>
            </controlaccess>

            <controlaccess>
                <head>Subjects</head>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Iron industry and trade -- Connecticut -- East
                    Canaan.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Merchants -- Connecticut -- East Canaan.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Iron mines and mining -- Connecticut -- Kent</subject>
            </controlaccess>



        </controlaccess>




        <dsc type="combined">
            <head>Contents:</head>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>I. Samuel Forbes accounts </unitid>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">1</container>
                        <unittitle>John and Samuel Forbes ledger, 1748-1760, for blacksmith work and
                            Pettibone &amp; Forbes ledger, 1786-1793, of iron ore. </unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">2</container>
                        <unittitle>"Real estate" transactions, 1755-1803. Includes entries for John
                            Forbes, John Adam and the Susquehanna Purchases. Also Charles S. Adam
                            diary-type and financial entries, <unitdate type="inclusive"
                                >1854-1869.</unitdate></unittitle>


                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">3</container>
                        <unittitle>"Day book No. 2," <unitdate type="inclusive"
                                >1763-1773.</unitdate> General merchandise sold at store, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">4</container>
                        <unittitle>"Ledger A", <unitdate type="inclusive">1771-1773.</unitdate>
                            Combines accounts and refers to next, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">5</container>
                        <unittitle>Day book, <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1772-1773.</unitdate>
                            General supplies sold at store, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">6</container>
                        <unittitle>"No. 2 Day book", <unitdate type="inclusive"
                                >1773-1776.</unitdate> General supplies sold at store; first time
                            nails are mentioned as being sold, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">7</container>
                        <unittitle>"Coppy of Notes of Hand," <unitdate type="inclusive"
                                >1785-1809.</unitdate>
                        </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">8</container>
                        <unittitle>"Waste book No. J," <unitdate type="inclusive">
                                1786-1789.</unitdate> General merchandise sold at store, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>II. John Adam Sr. accounts </unitid>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">9</container>
                        <unittitle>"Ledger No. 6," <unitdate type="inclusive">1774-1783.</unitdate>
                            Includes entries for John Adam, Adam &amp; Crocker, John Adam, Jr., the
                            nailery and the slitting mill. Most entries for general merchandise, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">10</container>
                        <unittitle>"Ledger 8", <unitdate type="inclusive">1775-1791.</unitdate>, for
                            nail rods, nails, tacks, and general merchandise, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">11</container>
                        <unittitle>Ledger, <unitdate type="inclusive">1776-1777,
                                1785-1794.</unitdate> Nails made, nails brought in, laborers, use of
                            slitting mill, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">12</container>
                        <unittitle>Ratcliffe Hellon shipbuilding account. </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>III. John Adam account books </unitid>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">13</container>
                        <unittitle>Ledger No. 2, Adam &amp; Church <unitdate type="inclusive"
                                >1786-1806.</unitdate> Accounts for paper mill and saw mill, </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">14</container>
                        <unittitle>Journal of proceedings of Kent Ore Hill, <unitdate
                                type="inclusive">1790-1802.</unitdate></unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">15</container>
                        <unittitle>Kent Ore Hill ledger, <unitdate type="inclusive"
                                >1796-1806.</unitdate>
                        </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">16</container>
                        <unittitle>Paper and saw mill accounts, 1798-1799; Adam &amp; Beckley
                            accounts of coal, <unitdate type="inclusive">1836-1837.</unitdate>
                        </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>IV. Forbes &amp; Adam, etc. account books, 1783-1875</unitid>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">17</container>
                        <unittitle>"Woman’s book" ledger. General merchandise, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1783-1823.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">18</container>
                        <unittitle>Day book. General merchandise, iron, nails, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1786-1788.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">19</container>
                        <unittitle>"Storage of iron left for to slitt into nail rods," 1786-1791;
                            Charles S. Adam diary-type and financial entries, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1884-1889.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">20</container>
                        <unittitle>"Invoice book," Items purchased for store, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1786-1792.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">21</container>
                        <unittitle>Ledger, General merchandise saw mill, paper mill, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1786-1794.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">22</container>
                        <unittitle>Pig Iron Book, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1791-1808.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">23</container>
                        <unittitle>"Journal No. J," 1792-1798. Includes entries for Washington
                            Slitting Mill and the saw mill; Charles S. Adam, 1839-1854 diary-type
                            and financial entries.</unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">24</container>
                        <unittitle>Receipt book, for bar iron, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1792-1798.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">25</container>
                        <unittitle>"Waste Book No. 1," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1793 February-November</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">26</container>
                        <unittitle>"Waste book No. 2," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1793-1794.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">27</container>
                        <unittitle>"Ledger A," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1793-1796.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">28</container>
                        <unittitle>"Ledger H (or II)," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1793-1800.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">29</container>
                        <unittitle>"Journal No. 1st," Manufactory of N[ail] Rods &amp; Rolled Iron
                            for Forbes &amp; Adam, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1795-1798.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">30</container>
                        <unittitle>"Coppies of letters from Forbes &amp; Adam to sundry persons,
                            since the 5th June 1795"; Charles S. Adam diary-type and financial
                            entries, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1876-1887.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">31</container>
                        <unittitle>"No. 14 Journal from 6 December 1796," 1796-1798; Charles S. Adam
                            diary-type and financial entries. </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">32</container>
                        <unittitle>Day book, "No. 15," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1798-1800.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">33</container>
                        <unittitle>"No. 2 Receipts for Bar Iron," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1798-1825.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">34</container>
                        <unittitle>"General Alphabet No. 2," To comprise the contents of Forbes
                            &amp; Adams Books into a small compass to find an account easy and soon, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1800 July.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">35</container>
                        <unittitle>"Ledger K," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1800-1808.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">36</container>
                        <unittitle>Bar Iron purchases, 1802-1805; Charles S. Adam diary-type and
                            financial entries, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1875.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">37</container>
                        <unittitle>Ledger, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1805-1817.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">38</container>
                        <unittitle>Day book, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1808-1809.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">39</container>
                        <unittitle>"List of balances of accounts on Forbes &amp; Adam Books taken
                                <unitdate type="inclusive">January 1811."</unitdate>
                        </unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">40</container>
                        <unittitle>"Ledger M," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1813-1828.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">41</container>
                        <unittitle>Ledger, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1813-1833.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">42</container>
                        <unittitle>Day book, Includes estate of John Adam accounts </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1826-1872.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">43</container>
                        <unittitle>"Alphabet of towns," </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">no date.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>V. Samuel F. Adam account books, 1785-1833 </unitid>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">44</container>
                        <unittitle>Small ledger, 1785-1790, Includes Samuel’s expenses at Yale,
                                <unitdate type="inclusive">1799-1803.</unitdate></unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">45</container>
                        <unittitle>S.F. &amp; L Adam’s blotter, <unitdate type="inclusive"
                                >1825-1833. </unitdate></unittitle>

                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>VI. Assorted volumes </unitid>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">46</container>
                        <unittitle>Ledger of William Burrall, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1771-1788.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">47</container>
                        <unittitle>The Balance &amp; Columbian Repository, vol. 1, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1802. </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <container type="Volume">48</container>
                        <unittitle>The Balance &amp; Columbian Repository, vol. 2, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">1803. </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>

        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
