<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002//EN" "ead.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="eadcbs9.xsl"?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtHi" url="http://www.chs.org/finding_aides/finding_aids/babcock.html">babcock</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Babcock Family papers</titleproper>
        <subtitle encodinganalog="245$b">A Guide to the collection at the Connecticut
                    Historical Society </subtitle>
        <author>Compiled by CHS Staff</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Connecticut Historical Society</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1 Elizabeth Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Hartford, CT 06105</addressline>
        </address>
        <p>Copyright 2011, Connecticut Historical Society</p>
        <date>March 2011</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Created by CHS Staff, <date>March 2011</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository:">
        <corpname>Connecticut Historical
                    Society,
                </corpname>
        <address>
          <addressline>Hartford, Connecticut</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <origination encodinganalog="100" label="Creator :">Babcock family.</origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title :">Babcock Family Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Dates : ">1788-1859</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Extent :">
        <extent>1 linear foot (2
                    boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Location:" altrender="Location :">Ms 14532</physloc>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546">English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
      <p>Elisha Babcock (1753-1821), his brother John Babcock, Jr. (1764-1843), and John's
                son, Sidney Babcock (1797-1884) all worked in the printing and publishing business
                in Connecticut. In addition to printing books, the Babcocks worked as publishers and
                wholesalers to booksellers out of state including New York, South Carolina,
                Louisiana and the West Indies. </p>
      <p>John Babcock, Sr. son of John and Sarah (Billings) Babcock, was born in Milton (now
                Quincy), Massachusetts on August 25, 1731. He married Rachel Adams in 1753. She was
                born on January 6, 1732 in Milton, and was a cousin to John Adams, the second
                President of the United States. They had ten children: Lucretia (August 13,
                1755-September 25, 1824), who married William Brewer of Wilbraham, Massachusetts; Mary (born
                August 20, 1757), who married Zenas Bliss of Springfield, Massachusetts on September
                25, 1824; Abigail (born February 11, 1762), who married Mr. Gardner of
                Massachusetts; Sarah (Sally), who married Ephraim Grant of Tolland, Connecticut;
                Rachel (born November 25, 1770), who married Dr. Nathaniel Hooker; Reuhama (or
                Ruhamah), who died unmarried; Samuel (born February 18, 1760), who married Miss Cone
                of Bolton, Connecticut; Andrew (April 19, 1773-March 29, 1789), who died unmarried
                at age seventeen; and two sons who joined him in the family business, John and
                Elisha. The Babcocks moved to Hartford soon after the Revolution, and John went into
                the printing business. John Babcock joined the second Church in Hartford in 1791 and
                became a Deacon. He died of cancer on January 4, 1796 at age 65, and he is buried in
                the Ancient Burying Ground in Hartford with his son Andrew. His wife Rachel Babcock
                died in Springfield on April 17, 1813 at the age of 81.</p>
      <p>John's eldest son, Elisha Babcock, was born in Milton, Massachusetts on August 10,
                1753. As a young man Elisha settled in Springfield, Massachusetts where he published
                the <emph render="italic">Hampshire Gazette</emph> for several years. He served during the Revolution, earning
                the rank of Major. In 1787, Elisha left Springfield for Hartford, Connecticut to
                establish a weekly paper with Joel Barlow (1754-1812), <emph render="italic">American Mercury</emph>, that for many years was the leading Democratic paper
                in the state. The paper published both literary and political pieces, and was
                closely associated with the Hartford Wits (originally called the Connecticut Wits).
                The group had formed in the late eighteenth century as a literary society at Yale
                College. The members were conservative federalists who wrote in verse satirizing an
                outmoded curriculum, society and politics. Members included Joel Barlow and John
                Trumbull. The Wits advocated a strong central government and attacked such
                proponents of democratic liberalism as Thomas Jefferson. Elisha continued as the
                proprietor and publisher of the paper for 37 years until his death. Elisha Babcock
                and Joel Barlow were also partners in the one of the first paper mills in
                Connecticut. Elisha Babcock died on April 7, 1821 at age 68. He is buried in
                Hartford at the Old South Cemetery of the Second Congregational Church with his
                wife, Dolly Babcock, who died on June 6, 1832 at the age of 75.</p>
      <p>Elisha's brother, John Babcock, was also born in Milton, Massachusetts in early 1764. He married Sidney Rogers (born 1752) of Philadelphia and he was
                connected to the Public Press of Philadelphia in the same year as the marriage. They
                had seven children, including Jane, the eldest who died unmarried in New Haven;
                Sidney the eldest son, who had six children of his own; William who married
                Elizabeth Jane Chisholm, a native of Virginia; Mary Ann, who married George Coxall
                of Island of Grenada, West Indies; and Richard Guyne, who died unmarried.</p>
      <p>John Babcock, Jr. came to Hartford about 1793 and started working as a printer and
                publisher of educational and juvenile books under the name of John Babcock &amp; Co.
                He moved his family and business to New Haven in 1803, where his firm continued to
                print and sell chapbooks, children's literature, hymnals and educational books,
                including several of Noah Webster's spellers. Babcock was in business with a New
                Haven bookseller known as Increase Cook &amp; Co. for several years until Cook's
                death in 1814.</p>
      <p>As his sons came of age, they joined the family business. At some point in the early
                1800s the name of the firm changed to Babcock &amp; Sons, when John formed a
                partnership with his sons Sidney Babcock and William R. Babcock. Younger sons Henry
                and Thomas also worked for the family business. Many of the daughters married men
                who did business with the Babcocks in one way or another. John's son-in-law, Zenas
                Bliss of Springfield, was in the paper business, and son-in-law George Coxall
                imported books to the West Indies.</p>
      <p>The firm of John Babcock &amp; Son was dissolved on April 2, 1825, although the name
                of the old firm was legally used until September of 1826. In 1825, John's sons
                Sidney, William R. and Henry L. Babcock formed a new firm, Babcock &amp; Co., to
                continue the book publishing and stationary business. John Babcock left New Haven,
                living in Baltimore and Washington until he died. Sons Sidney and Henry Babcock
                remained in New Haven, while John's middle son, William R. Babcock, continued to
                operate from Charleston, South Carolina. Thomas Babcock stayed in Connecticut and
                took over the printing business.</p>
      <p>John's eldest son Sidney Babcock was born in Hartford in 1797, and grew up in New
                Haven. He married Susan Thompson in Stratford, Connecticut, on February 7, 1820.
                Sidney lived in New Haven and managed the firm through trying economic times
                following the depression of 1837. Sidney Babcock died at his home on High Street in
                New Haven on July 29, 1884 at the age of 87.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520$a">
      <head>Scope and Content</head>
      <p>The Babcock papers include business and family correspondence covering the years
                1788-1859 from several members of the family who lived in Hartford and New Haven,
                Connecticut. The Babcocks were printers, publishers and booksellers. The bulk of the
                collection consists of the mercantile business papers of publisher Elisha Babcock,
                his brother John Babcock, and John's son, Sidney Babcock. They are represented as
                individuals and in business relationships, including Babcock &amp; Son, Cook &amp;
                Babcock, and Babcock &amp; Co. Each series includes Correspondence (primarily
                business, but with some personal content as well), Legal Records (including leases
                and deeds for property), and Financial Records. Represented in the Financial Records
                are both business and personal orders, bills and invoices, paid receipts, accounts,
                inventories, and promissory notes.</p>
      <p>The correspondence files contain letters of the family members and their customers
                and suppliers, some of whom were related to the family. Within John Babcock's
                correspondence is a personal letter written to his daughter Rachel in 1832, one to
                his son William in 1831, and another to his son Henry in 1833. </p>
      <p>Bills and receipts for items purchased by the Babcock family also appear in the
                papers. There are bills documenting the purchase of fabric such as Fustian, calico
                and mourning chintz, apron tapes and tamboring, and an 1803 bill from Elisha Faxon
                for silk, buttons and brown linen. A bill from "Mrs. Turner" for making a "cote" and
                a bill from Timothy Dodd for "Making a coat &amp; 3 Vests" as well as bills for
                repairing shoes, for cutting girls' hair, for veterinarian Dr. Asa Allyn including
                fourteen gallons of molasses used for worming a horse are included. There are also
                bills for repairing a cradle and an 1813 bill for the lease of a church pew at
                Trinity Episcopal Church in New Haven.</p>
      <p>Accounts document grocery purchases including molasses, rum, flour, tamarinds and
                pineapples and Louchong tea. They purchased dry goods such as silk gloves, tin
                graters, a coffee pot, wineglasses and chamber pots. There are bills for shad and
                "Turkinsland salt," as well as bills from the cooper who made the barrels to hold
                them. Several paid bills for children's schooling and for dancing lessons are among
                the papers, including bills from Miss Sally Goodwin of Hartford, Polley Butler (for
                schooling Miss Jane and Miss Rachel (Babcock) in 1796 and 1798), as well as a 1798
                bill to John Babcock from Mrs. Marsh for "Instructing your little daughter 12 wks."
                Also of note is a bill from Mr. John White, "Tuition, Miss Jane Babcock," and an
                invoice from Stephen Dodge for "schooling a boy".</p>
      <p>The correspondence also documents the business partnership of John Babcock and
                Increase Cook, a bookseller in New Haven, Connecticut. The names of notable New
                Haven citizens, such as J. Barbour, [Timothy] Dwight, and "Morse's father, Mr.
                Burr," are all mentioned in an 1803 letter.</p>
      <p>A series of letters written to Sidney Babcock from his brother-in-law and business
                partner, George Coxall, who lived in St. Bart's in the West Indies cover family,
                business, and local news and politics from 1829-1833, and 1837. An 1831 letter
                describes a revolt by slaves on Martinique where 300 were killed and plantations
                were burned. George Coxall was married to Sidney's sister, Mary Ann Babcock. Their
                two school-age daughters were living in New Haven under the guardianship of the
                Babcock family.</p>
      <p>The correspondence and business records document the daily activities of the book
                printing and publishing business including orders for linen and marbled papers used
                in book binding, bills for folding and sewing of books. Books were ordered from
                various booksellers around the state of Connecticut as well as in New York, South
                Carolina, and New Orleans, Louisiana. Linen was ordered from Simeon Butler of
                Northampton, Massachusetts and marbled papers were ordered from the Norwich,
                Connecticut firm Sherry and Porter, manufacturers and importers of "Ream Marble
                Paper"; samples of their marbled paper from 1802 may be found in John Babcock's
                correspondence. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>There are no restrictions on access to the collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Use of the material requires compliance with the Connecticut Historical Society's
                Research Center regulations.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Item, Collection Title, Collection number (Box #, Folder #). Connecticut Historical
                Society, Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo>
      <head>Processing Details</head>
      <p>Collection was processed by Elizabeth Blakelock in 2010.</p>
      <p>EAD Finding Aid created March 2011.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accruals>
      <head>Accruals</head>
      <p>The collection is closed.</p>
    </accruals>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject Headings</head>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Personal Names</head>
        <persname encodinganalog="600">Babcock, James -- Childhood and youth.</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700">Babcock, Charles.</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700">Babcock, Elisha.</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700">Babcock, James.</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700">Skinner, Whiting.</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subjects</head>
        <subject encodinganalog="650">Printers -- Connecticut -- Hartford.</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Geographic Names</head>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651">United States -- Politics and government.</geogname>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Contents:</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>I. Elijah Babcock</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1802-1813</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Promissory Notes, <unitdate type="inclusive">1790</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">1806</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Legal, Deed, <unitdate type="inclusive">1788</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Accounts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1795-1805</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Financial, Bills and Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1795-1806</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills, Receipts and Orders, <unitdate type="inclusive">1807-1820</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>II. John Babcock</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1796-1797</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1802</unitdate>
                            (Includes samples of marbled paper)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1803</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1804</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1805</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1807</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1809</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1813-1819</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1820-1824</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1831-1833</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreement, <unitdate type="inclusive">1796</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreement, <unitdate type="inclusive">1803-1826</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Lease, <unitdate type="inclusive">1813</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Deeds, <unitdate type="inclusive">1808-1819</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Contact, Partnership Dissolution, <unitdate type="inclusive">1825</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Promissory Note, <unitdate type="inclusive">1803</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Accounts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1798-1816</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills and Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1795-1796</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills and Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1797</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">26</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills and Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1798</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">27</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills and Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1799-1802</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">28</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills and Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1803</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">29</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills and Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1804-1813</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">30</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills and Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1814-1822</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>III. Sidney Babcock</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">31</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, Henry Babcock, <unitdate type="inclusive">1829-1868</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">32</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, George Coxall, <unitdate type="inclusive">1829-1833</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">1837</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">33</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1826-1834</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">34</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1837-1839</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">35</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1843</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">36</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, 184436</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">37</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1846</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">38</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1847-1849</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">39</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1850-1851</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">40</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1852</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">41</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1853-1856</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">42</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1857-1859</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">43</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate type="inclusive">1859-1869</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">44</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, Personal, <unitdate type="inclusive">1829-1832</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">45</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, <unitdate type="inclusive">1825</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">46</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, <unitdate type="inclusive">1826-1829</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">47</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, <unitdate type="inclusive">1839-1833</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">48</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, <unitdate type="inclusive">1834-1837</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">49</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, <unitdate type="inclusive">1840-1842</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">50</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, <unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1846</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">51</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, <unitdate type="inclusive">1847-1853</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">52</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Agreements, <unitdate type="inclusive">1855-1861</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">53</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Inventory, <unitdate type="inclusive">1840-1845</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">54</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Judgment</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">55</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Notice to Quit, <unitdate type="inclusive">1858</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">56</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Circular</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">57</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Decision, <unitdate type="inclusive">1835</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">58</container>
            <unittitle>Legal Lease, <unitdate type="inclusive">1820</unitdate>
                            21</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">59</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Accounts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1826-1858</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">60</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Advertisement, <unitdate type="inclusive">1858</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">61</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills, Receipts, Orders, Exchanges, <unitdate type="inclusive">1827-1836</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">62</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills, Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1838</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">63</container>
            <unittitle>Financial Bills, Receipts, <unitdate type="inclusive">1848-1859</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">64</container>
            <unittitle>Genealogy, printed</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
