<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002//EN" "ead.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="eadcbs9.xsl"?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtHi"
            url="http://www.chs.org/finding_aides/finding_aids/Bolles.html">Bolles</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Bolles Family Papers</titleproper>
                <subtitle encodinganalog="245$b">A Guide to the collection at the Connecticut
                    Historical Society </subtitle>
                <author>Compiled by CHS Staff</author>

            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Connecticut Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
<addressline>1 Elizabeth Street</addressline>
<addressline>Hartford, CT 06105</addressline>
</address>
                <p>Copyright 2012, Connecticut Historical Society</p>
                <date>November 26, 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Created by CHS Staff, <date>March 2006</date>.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">

        <did>
            <head>Collection Overview</head>
            <repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository:"><corpname>Connecticut Historical
                    Society,
                </corpname><address>
    <addressline>Hartford, Connecticut</addressline>
   </address>
            </repository>
            <origination encodinganalog="100" label="Creator :">Bolles Family</origination>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title :">Bolles Family Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Dates : ">1788-1829</unitdate>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Extent :"><extent> 0.5 linear foot (1
                    box)</extent></physdesc>
            <physloc label="Location:" altrender="Location :">Ms 30016</physloc>
            <langmaterial encodinganalog="546">English</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
            <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
            <p>Enoch and Hannah (Moore) Bolles lived in New London, Connecticut. Enoch was descended
                from John Bolles, a noted figure in the Rogerene religious movement in Connecticut.
                The couple had 14 children, all born in New London. Their third child, David Bolles
                (1743-1807) was a farmer, tanner and currier until becoming a Baptist minister,
                first in Hartford and later in Ashford, Connecticut. Asa Bolles (1746-1801) was the
                fifth child of Enoch and Hannah and he was a farmer and a Baptist deacon. </p>
            <p>John Bolles was the seventh child in the family. He was a successful merchant in
                Hartford and was noted for his piety and goodness. He walked to Baptist church
                services in Suffield before helping form the First Baptist Church in Hartford in
                1790. He married Lydia Taber with whom he had nine children, including George W. (b.
                1787), who became a doctor, Jeremiah (1791-1818) a merchant, and Edward John
                (1797-1882) also a merchant and a clerk in the First Baptist Church in Hartford.</p>


        </bioghist>

        <arrangement>
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection, a donation by Frederick W. Payne in 1919, has been arranged into
                three series according to the individual receiving or writing the letters or
                financial documents, with the father, John Bolles first, followed by his sons George
                and Jeremiah. </p>
        </arrangement>

        <scopecontent encodinganalog="520$a">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p> John Bolles received letters from his brother Nathan, a Baptist deacon who lived in
                West Springfield, Mass., between 1792 and 1794. The bulk of their correspondence
                dealt with their feelings of unworthiness before God, the importance of conversion,
                and their respective states of mind. Nathan evidently traded with John as he
                mentions purchasing rye, corn and peas for John and needing tea, molasses and rum in
                return. Letters from John Rathburn in New York City, 1794-1795, deal exclusively
                with trade, primarily about the markets for salt, flaxseed and beef. John Bolles
                received letters from his brother Nathan, a Baptist deacon who lived in West
                Springfield, Mass., between 1792 and 1794. The bulk of their correspondence dealt
                with their feelings of unworthiness before God, the importance of conversion, and
                their respective states of mind. Nathan evidently traded with John as he mentions
                purchasing rye, corn and peas for John and needing tea, molasses and rum in return.
                Letters from John Rathburn in New York City, 1794-1795, deal exclusively with trade,
                primarily about the markets for salt, flaxseed and beef.</p>
            <p>A significant number of letters were written to Benjamin Hastings of Westfield, Mass.
                The two men discussed such topics as duty to God, reformations and baptisms, finding
                peace, and accepting God. Hastings’ daughters evidently lived with Bolles while
                receiving an education and John mentions their well being in some of the later
                missives. </p>
            <p>In letters to his son, Edward, John also issued religious admonitions. He urged
                Edward to continue to strengthen his belief in God. Several letters implore Edward
                to return home to oversee his own store, which seems to have been thriving even in
                his absence. Against his father’s wishes, Edward resided with his Uncle Jesse Bolles
                in New London.</p>
            <p>Finally, John is represented by several bills, receipts and accounts from 1778-1794
                for such things as padding a saddle, shipping barrels of sugar, and shipping beef,
                flaxseed and rum.</p>
            <p>The bulk of the incoming correspondence of George Bolles consisted of pleas from
                Ephraim Robbins, a childhood friend, who desperately wanted to maintain a
                correspondence with George. The letters date from 1799-1807. Ephraim wrote
                extensively about his poor state of mind, his doubts about his “election”, and news
                of “Great awakenings”. George also received letters from his uncle Isaac Bolles and
                a cousin, Peter Bolles. These missives discuss books, redemption of the soul,
                “masonary orations” and business.</p>
            <p>Big brother George gave brotherly advice to his younger brother Edward, 1805-1818.
                George advised him to study and obey his parents. Once Edward established his store,
                George mentioned his attempts to purchase knives for him. In one intriguing letter,
                George talked about working on cadavers, specifically a Negro one. A much later
                letter, 1825, ordered a memorial stone for Jeremiah Crocker from Eliphalet Tomkins,
                and includes a drawing of the design. Financial records include bills for George’s
                work as a doctor.</p>
            <p>The third series includes Jeremiah Bolles’ letters to his brother Edward, 1806-1818.
                He advised Edward to continue his schooling and admonished him about eating too many
                sweets, particularly molasses. After 1815, Jeremiah mentioned the success of
                Edward’s store and reported that he needed knives and Jews harps to send him.</p>
            <p>The final folder in the collection contains letters written to and from various
                family members. A letter from Matthew Bolles to John in 1792 mentions the
                “Reformation in Ashford” where David was minister. Brother Asa Bolles discussed
                sending shirting to John in a letter dated 1791. The final letter is from Isaiah
                Bolles to his nephew Edward, 1810 about Edward’s returning home.</p>
        </scopecontent>

        <accessrestrict>
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>There are no restrictions on access to the collection.</p>
        </accessrestrict>

        <userestrict>
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Use of the material requires compliance with the Connecticut Historical Society's
                Research Center regulations.</p>
        </userestrict>

        <prefercite>
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Item, Collection Title, Collection number (Box #, Folder #). Connecticut Historical
                Society, Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
        </prefercite>

        <processinfo>
            <head>Proc essing Details</head>
            <p>Collection was processed by Barbara Austen in 2006.</p>
            <p>EAD Finding Aid created October 2013.</p>

        </processinfo>

        <accruals>
            <head>Accruals</head>
            <p>The collection is closed.</p>
        </accruals>

        <controlaccess>

            <controlaccess>
                <head>Personal Names</head>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Bolles, David</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Bolles, Edward John</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="600">Hastings, Benjamin</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Bolles, George W.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Bolles, Jeremiah</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Bolles, John</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Bolles, Nathan</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Rathburn, John</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Robbins, Ephraim</persname>
            </controlaccess>



            <controlaccess>
                <head>Subject Headings</head>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Conversion.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Faith.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Family.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Merchants.</subject>
            </controlaccess>

            <controlaccess>
                <head>Geographic Names</head>
                <geogname encodinganalog="651">Hartford, Conn.</geogname>
            </controlaccess>


        </controlaccess>




        <dsc type="combined">
            <head>Contents:</head>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>John Bolles Papers</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">1778-1818</unitdate>
                </did>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">1-2. </container>
                    <unittitle>John Bolles letters from brother Nathan Bolles, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1792-1794</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">3-4.</container>
                    <unittitle>John Bolles letters from John Rathburn, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1794-1795</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">5.</container>
                    <unittitle>John Bolles letters to brother David Bolles, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1785-1801</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">6-10.</container>
                    <unittitle>John Bolles letters to Benjamin Hastings, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1807-1812</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">11.</container>
                    <unittitle>John Bolles letters to son Edward Bolles, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1809-1818</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">12.</container>
                    <unittitle>John Bolles bills, receipts and accounts, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1778-1794</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>George W. Bolles Papers</unitid> <unitdate> type="inclusive">1799-1829</unitdate>
                </did>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">13-14.</container>
                    <unittitle>George Bolles letters from Ephraim Robbins,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate> type="inclusive">1799-1807</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">15.</container>
                    <unittitle>George Bolles letters, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate>1809-1810, 1825</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">16-17.</container>
                    <unittitle>George Bolles letters to brother Edward Bolles</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1805-1818</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">18.</container>
                    <unittitle>George Bolles accounts, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1824-1829</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid>Jeremiah Bolles and other Bolles family papers, </unitid><unitdate type="inclusive"> 1791-1818</unitdate>
                </did>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">19.</container>
                    <unittitle>Jeremiah Bolles letters to brother Edward Bolles</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1807-1818</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="Box">1</container>
                    <container type="Folder">20.</container>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence among various Bolles family members, </unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive">1791-1810</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
