<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002//EN" "ead.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="eadcbs9.xsl"?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtHi" url="http://www.chs.org/finding_aides/finding_aids/frinw1763.html">frinw1763</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">French and Indian War Papers</titleproper>
        <subtitle encodinganalog="245$b">A Guide to the French and Indian War Papers at the Connecticut
     Historical Society</subtitle>
        <author>Compiled by NHPRC Project Staff</author>
        <sponsor>Original EAD conversion sponsored by grant funding from the National Historical
     Publications and Records Commission. Grant # 98-101 </sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Connecticut Historical Society</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1 Elizabeth Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Hartford, CT 06105</addressline>
        </address>
        <p>Copyright 2010, Connecticut Historical Society</p>
        <date>December 2010</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <repository label="Repository :">
        <corpname>Connecticut Historical Society</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle label="Title :">French and Indian War Papers.</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates : ">1743 - 1763</unitdate>
      <origination label="Creator :">The Connecticut Historical Society</origination>
      <abstract label="Abstract :">Collection consists of enlistments and impressments; muster rolls
    and account rolls of those serving in the King George's War and later in the French and Indian
    War; transfers of wages and receipts for wages paid; accounts and receipts; military orders;
    correspondence; and journals, a note book, and an orderly book.</abstract>
      <physdesc label="Extent :">
        <extent>1 linear foot (2 boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc label="Location:" altrender="Location :">Ms FRINW</physloc>
    </did>
    <otherfindaid>
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>An index of catalog cards is available to aid access to this collection and material in other
    collections. Access is through writer, recipient and date. The card catalog is located in the
    Research Center reading room. </p>
      <p>Microfilm copy available.</p>
    </otherfindaid>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Contextual History</head>
      <p>King George’s War, 1744-1748, (known as the War of Austrian Succession in Europe) was one of a
    series of 18th century conflicts in which France and England, with their Indian allies, sought
    to control the continent. The first battle was the French capture of the English town of Canso
    on Nova Scotia. New England responded by raising 4,000 militia men and laying siege to and
    capturing Fortress Louisbourg, considered one of the strongest fortresses in French Canada.
    Louisbourg also served as the home port for privateers that attacked English trading and fishing
    vessels. Other conflicts in the “war” were little more than border skirmishes, although the
    death tolls were high on both sides. The Treaty of Aix-la-Chapelle which effectively ended the
    war in Europe also brought a stop to hostilities in North America, although it resolved nothing.
    In addition, the terms of the treaty returned Louisbourg to the French. The French and Indian
    War, 1754-1763, is the name given to the American theater of a massive conflict involving
    Austria, England, France, Great Britain, Prussia, and Sweden called the Seven Years War. The
    American conflict was precipitated by the French building Fort Dusquesne on the Ohio River, and
    area also claimed by the British. In 1754, the governor of Virginia sent twenty-one-year-old
    George Washington to demand the withdrawal of the French. The French refused and Washington,
    along with 150 men, tried to force them out, attacking a group of Fenchmen and killing ten of
    them, sparking the beginning of the French and Indian War. British troops under the command of
    General Edward Braddock joined George Washington at Fort Duquesne. Though the British
    outnumbered the French, the French and Indians nevertheless won the battle of Fort Duquesne.</p>
      <p> The bulk of the fighting that occurred during the French and Indian War took place along
    lakes George and Champlain, in the state of New York near the Canadian border. </p>
      <p>During 1755 the area of fighting expanded until it covered ground from Fort Dusquesne to Fort
    Niagara, Lake Champlain and as far as Nova Scotia. In autumn 1755 tensions rose further when the
    British captured two French ships, the Lys and the Alcide, off the coast of Nova Scotia. Britain
    and France finally declared war in May 1756, and so began the Seven Years' War. </p>
      <p>The French, under the command of the Marquis de Montcalm, captured and razed Britain's only
    fort on the Great Lakes: Fort Oswego. The French and their Indian allies raided towns and farms
    in New York and Pennsylvania and the English colonists retaliated by doing the same to Indian
    settlements in the Ohio Valley. The British did their part setting up a blockade of the French
    fortress of Louisbourg on Cape Breton Island from which point the French guarded the Saint
    Lawrence River. Meanwhile, at Lake George in New York, the British and their colonists held Fort
    William Henry throughout the winter of 1756-1757. </p>
      <p> But by the latter half of 1757 the outlook was bleak for the British. In August Montcalm
    returned with a large army and captured and burned Fort William Henry, following which the
    Indians massacred British and colonial prisoners. In September the British fleet, blockading
    Louisbourg and the Saint Lawrence River, was dispersed by a hurricane. </p>
      <p>But the tide again turned when William Pitt became Britain's Prime Minister. He increased the
    number of troops in North America and sent in several strong military leaders. Pitt ordered
    General James Abercromby to lead forces in attacks against Crown Point and Fort Ticonderoga, and
    to send smaller forces against Fort Frontenac and Fort Duquesne. The British suffered severe
    casualties at Ticonderoga, but were more successful at Frontenac. The French deserted Fort
    Duquesne as General John Forbes's troops approached.</p>
      <p>In the summer of 1759, General James Wolfe and his army scaled the cliffs of New France’s
    political capital, Quebec, and fought Montcalm's forces on the Plains of Abraham. Both Montcalm
    and Wolfe were killed in the battle, but it was a victory for the British. The French colonial
    government fled in May 1760 to the unfortified city of Montreal, where General Jeffrey Amherst
    arranged to have converge three armies. The French suffered from a lack of supplies and
    reinforcements caused mostly by a British blockade but in part by the relative apathy of the
    government in France. On September 8, 1760, Governor de Vaudreuil surrendered Montreal and
    Canada to Amherst. In the remaining years of the Seven Years' War, there was little military
    activity in North America. </p>
      <p>When the Treaty of Paris was signed on February 8, 1763, Britain was left with all of French
    Canada, with the exception of two small islands, most of French Louisiana east of the
    Mississippi River, and a small part of Spanish Florida. The French were allowed to maintain a
    high degree of autonomy, but the treaty left the British dominant in North America east of the
    Mississippi River. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520$a">
      <head>Scope and Content</head>
      <p>Although this collection consists primarily of materials created during the French and Indian
    War, there are in nearly every series some materials from the preceding King George's War. There
    are enlistments and impressments, muster rolls and account rolls of those serving in the war. of
    interest are several contracts signed by men who served On the Louisbourg expedition in Cape
    Breton as well as in later campaigns, authorizing the transfer of their wages to another
    individual (often Jonathan Trumbull) to pay for provisions and to serve the recipients'
    speculative interests. There are also several receipts for wages paid by Trumbull. Numerous accounts and receipts provide
    information about how much money was spent on specific food items and alcohol, guns, blankets,
    and the shoeing of horses. There are details of military orders; correspondence concerning
    intelligence (including concern over reports that the French were making snow shoes) and orders
    as well as letters to family. Finally, there are journals kept by men involved in the French and
    Indian War, an orderly book from Ticonderoga and a note book with color sketches and examples of
    various styles of penmanship.</p>
      <arrangement>
        <head>Arrangement</head>
        <p>Materials are organized into five series based largely on form: Enlisted Men, Finances,
     Orders, Correspondence, and Journals.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series I: Enlisted Men</emph> consists of impressments and voluntary
     enlistments, with a few documents regarding desertion or discharge due to illness or family
     emergency. More numerous are muster rolls of enlisted and impressed men.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series II: Finances</emph> consists of documents relating to the finances
     of war: transfers of wages to pay for provisions; account rolls; and accounts and receipts
     which include prices paid for specific foods as well as for guns, cartridges, blankets, et
     cetera.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series III: Orders</emph> consists of orders given to march and to
     provide provisions for active regiments.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series IV: Correspondence</emph> consists of correspondence regarding
     military intelligence, supplies, and descriptions of skirmishes. Includes some personal letters
     to family members.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series V:</emph> Journals consists of journals, a notebook, and an orderly book kept by men serving in the French and
    Indian War, as well as a journal from the 1745 expedition to Louisbourg to Cape Breton.</p>
        <p>Collection is arranged chronologically within in each series. </p>
      </arrangement>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>There are no restrictions on access to the collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Use of the material requires compliance with the Connecticut Historical Society's Research
    Center regulations.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Item, Collection Title, Collection number (Box #, Folder #). Connecticut Historical Society,
    Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo>
      <head>Processing Details</head>
      <p>Original EAD instance compiled by NHPRC project staff, September 1999. Updated to EAD 2002 in December 2010.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accruals>
      <head>Accruals</head>
      <p>The collection is open, but additional material is not expected.</p>
    </accruals>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject Headings</head>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Personal Names</head>
        <persname encodinganalog="700"> Booth, Joseph, 1736-1810. </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700"> Comstock, Christopher. </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700"> Hayward, Benjamin.</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700"> Judd, Philip. </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Geographic Names</head>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651"> United States History King George's War, 1744-1748. </geogname>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651"> United States History French and Indian War, 1755-1763. </geogname>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651"> Fort William Henry, N.Y., Capture of, 1757. </geogname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Genre Forms</head>
        <genreform encodinganalog="655"> Holographs; holographs, signed; pen and ink sketches.
    </genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Contents:</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>I. Enlisted and Impressed Men</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Enlistments, impressments, discharges, and desertions: legal documents concerning
       cases presented against deserters by attorney Matthew Griswold;
       impressments; and voluntary enlistments.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1748 - 1757</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Enlistments, impressments, discharges, and desertions: a call for able-bodied men
       signed by George Wyllys; voluntary enlistments; impressments; and a
       grievance signed by Jabez Chapman, complaining about his only son being
       pressed into service.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1758</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Enlistments, impressments, discharges, and desertions: voluntary enlistments;
       impressments; discharges for reasons of family emergency and madness; and a complaint of
       desertion against Prince Storr of Mansfield,
       CT.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1759 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from Captain
        Fitch's expedition to Cape Breton and Colonel
        Burr's regiment.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1743 - 1744</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes a commissary book listing men's names
       and the dates on which they were dismissed, died, deserted, were advanced, or exchanged;
       muster roll of Captain Nathaniel Farrand's regiment; list of officers on
       the Louisbourg expedition.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1745 - 1749</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes a list of men whose wages
        Simon Lothrop bought; muster roll of Captain John
        Pitkin's company; list of men from the military company in Colchester,
        CT.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1750 - 1756</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from the regiments of
        Nathaniel Cushman, George Holmes, Joseph
        Fitch, and Daniel Cone; list of men from Lebanon,
        CT.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1757</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from the regiments of
        Charles Dewey, Nathan Whiting, and
        Nathaniel Cushman; lists of men from Andover,
        Hebron, and Lebanon, CT; men killed, wounded, or
       missing at Ticonderoga.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1758</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from the regiments of
        Joshua Barker, Henry Champion, and
        Joseph Spencer; list of men from Lebanon,
       CT.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1758</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from the regiments of
        Samuel Dewey, Joseph Fitch, and Benjamin
        Day; lists of men from New Salem,
        Lebanon, Colchester,
        Wilmington, and Willington in East
        Haddam, CT.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>February 1759</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from the regiments of
        Jehebod Phelps, Caleb Chapman, and
        Daniel Cone; lists of men from Goshen and
        East Haddam, CT.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>March - April 1759</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from the regiment of
        Elijah Sprague; lists of captains.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1759 - 1760</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from the regiments of
        Jonathan Trumbull, William Clark, and from
        Marlborough, CT.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1761 - 1762</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: men in the regiment of John
        Cook; provisions requested by specific men; list of men from Andover,
        CT; list of officers.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1743 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Rolls of enlisted and impressed men: includes those from the regiments of
        George Holmes, Jabez Jones, Samuel
        Olmsted, and Samuel Gilbert.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1743 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>II. Finances</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Transfers of wages: Norman Morrison's authorization, from
        Louisbourg, to hand over to Mrs. Ann Morrison
       three hundred pounds of his wages earned as military <occupation>surgeon </occupation>on the
        Cape Breton expedition; receipts of wages received from
        Jonathan Trumbull for services in the expedition against
        Canada; orders from several men to pay Jonathan
        Trumbull wages earned during the above mentioned expedition.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1745 - 1747</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Transfers of wages: orders by several men who served on the expedition to
        Canada to hand over part or all of their wages, primarily to
        Jonathan Trumbull or Daniel Lothrop.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1748 - 1749</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Transfers of wages: orders by several men who served on the expedition to
        Canada to hand over part of all of their wages, primarily to
        Jonathan Trumbull or Daniel Lothrop; receipts of
       wages received.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>January - October 1750</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>Transfers of wages: orders by several men who served on the expedition to
        Canada to hand over part of all of their wages, primarily to
        Jonathan Trumbull.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>November - December 1750</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>Transfers of wages: contracts to pay unto another their wages earned during the
       expedition against Canada, signed by Benjamin
        Garret, Solomon Story, Nathaniel Brown,
       and William Billing; receipts of wages paid by Elisha
        Williams.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1748 - 1749</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>Transfers of wages: consists mostly of receipts of wages paid by Elisha
        Williams to men including Samuel Gilbert, William
        Wattle, Daniel Edwards, and Joseph
        Griswold.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1752 - 1753</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>Transfers of wages: order by Joseph Blackman to hand over his
       wages from the Canada expedition to Jonathan
        Trumbull; receipts for wages paid to men who served on the expedition against
        Canada.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1755</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>Transfers of wages: orders by several men who served on the expedition to
        Canada to hand over part of all of their wages to others, including
        Jonathan Trumbull, Jonathan Crocker, and
        Nathaniel Loomis.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1756 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>Account rolls and supply rolls regarding enlisted men: payroll lists from several
       regiments, and receipt of wages paid by Jonathan Trumbull.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1756 - 1757</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>Account rolls and supply rolls regarding enlisted men: abstracts of accounts from
       the regiments of Joseph Fitch, Samuel Elmer,
        Thomas Hobby, David Baldwin, and
       others.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1761</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">26</container>
            <unittitle>Account rolls and supply rolls regarding enlisted men: abstracts of accounts from
       the regiments of John Patterson, Israel Putnam,
        James Smedley, John Spaulding, and
       others.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1761</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">27</container>
            <unittitle>Account rolls and supply rolls regarding enlisted men: abstracts of accounts from
        Timothy Herlihy's regiment; payroll of Noah
        Humphrey's company; list of provisions for hospital stores.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1762 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">28</container>
            <unittitle>Account rolls and supply rolls regarding enlisted men: abstracts of accounts from
       the regiments of Robert Durkee, Hugh Ladlie,
        Samuel Whiting, and John Durkee.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1754 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Accounts and receipts: detailed receipts for kitchen provisions, munitions, and
       sundries.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1745 - 1752</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Accounts and receipts: detailed receipts for munitions, horse shoes, saddles,
       belts, and blankets.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1755</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Accounts and receipts: detailed receipts for munitions and horse supplies; includes
       Captain Gilbert's notes on deficiencies in provisions.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1756 - 1757</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Accounts and receipts: detailed accounts of guns impressed.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1758</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Accounts and receipts: account book kept by Nathaniel
       Porter.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1758 - June 1759</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Accounts and receipts: receipt book kept by David Seymour,
       consisting of provisions procured for the use of the sick.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1759</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Accounts and receipts: detailed receipts for kitchen provisions, munitions, and
       horse supplies.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1760 - 1761</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Accounts and receipts: detailed receipts for equipment, food, and
       munitions.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1745 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>III. Orders</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Orders issued by Jonathan Trumbull, Joshua
        West, William Olmsted, William Whiting,
       and others.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1757</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Orders issued by Jonathan Trumbull, Ephraim
        Fuller, Caleb Chapman, David Dickerson,
        Nathaniel Cushman, and others.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1758 - 1759</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Orders issued by Samuel Gray, Jeffrey
        Amherst, and others.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1760 - 1761</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Orders issued by Sanford Mason, Thomas
        Fitch, and others.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1754 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>IV. Correspondence</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence from such men as Thomas Wheeler,
        Josiah Willard, Robert Denison, and John
        Tully.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1744 - 1749</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence from such men as Benjamin Avery,
        James Grant, and James Innis.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1750 - 1755</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence from such men as Nathaniel Foot, Samuel
       Gilbert, Christopher Holmes, and Jared
       Spencer.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1756 - 1757</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence from such men as Joseph Spencer,
        Jared Spencer, Joshua Johnson, and Giles
        Wolcott.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1758 - 1759</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence from such men as Giles Wolcott, John
        Alden, Nathaniel Porter, and Eleazer
        Fitch.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1760 - 1762</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence from Giles Wolcott and a poem by
        Stephen Tilden.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1744 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>V. Journals</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>Philip Judd's journal kept during the voyage from
        New London to Cape Breton.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>June 1 - November 27, 1745</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>Note book, probably kept by Asa Greer, including color
       drawings and examples of various hands.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1754 - 1763</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>Orderly book from Ticonderoga, including mention of an inquiry
       into the behaviour of Lieutenant Chick.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1759</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>Print out from microfilm of the journal of Benjamin
       Hayward.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1757</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>Journal kept by Benjamin Hayward; includes accounts and notes
       on provisions.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1757</unitdate>
          </did>
          <note>
            <p>Note: Transcription available</p>
          </note>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>Journal kept by Benadam Gallup; includes lists of men fit for
       duty and orders.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1757 - 1759</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>Journal kept by Christopher Comstock; comments on what
       happened each day, including the arrival of supplies and men and occasional comments on what
       they ate for dinner.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1758 - 1759</unitdate>
          </did>
          <note>
            <p>Note: Transcription available</p>
          </note>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">26</container>
            <unittitle>Journal kept by Joseph Booth; includes religious notes,
       quotations, orders, and death.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1760</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
