<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002//EN" "ead.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="eadcbs9.xsl"?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtHi" url="http://www.chs.org/finding_aides/finding_aids/stone1889-2.html">stone1889-2</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">[Stone Family Papers] papers</titleproper>
        <subtitle encodinganalog="245$b">A Guide to the collection at the Connecticut
                    Historical Society </subtitle>
        <author>Compiled by CHS Staff</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Connecticut Historical Society</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1 Elizabeth Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Hartford, CT 06105</addressline>
        </address>
        <p>Copyright [2011], Connecticut Historical Society</p>
        <date>[January 2011]</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Created by CHS Staff, <date>[January 2011]</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository:">
        <corpname>Connecticut Historical Society, </corpname>
        <address>
          <addressline>Hartford, Connecticut</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <origination encodinganalog="100" label="Creator :">[Last, First]</origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title :">[Stone Family] Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Dates : ">[1747-1889]</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Extent :">
        <extent>[1] linear feet (2 boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract :">[Abstract]</abstract>
      <physloc label="Location:" altrender="Location :">Ms 100736</physloc>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546">English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
      <p>[The earliest of papers in the collection were penned by Stephen Stone who was a
                descendant from William Stone (b. ca. 1608), a signer of the Guilford Covenant and
                member of Rev. Henry Whitfield’s first company to sail to New Haven in 1639. Stephen
                wed Rebekah (Rebecca) Bishop and the couple bore Leman Stone (29 Dec. 1750-May 1847)
                and Joel Stone. The family originated in Guilford but later moved to South Farms in
                Litchfield (now Morris). This line of the Stone family was merged with another Stone
                line when Leman married Lois Stone. This family bore several children, including
                Ellen Stone, who married Frederick William Stone (1842-1913). Ellen and Frederick
                had two sons: Frederick Leman Stone and William Oliver Stone (26 Sept. 1830-15 Sept.
                1875). Lois (or Louisa) Stone (24 April 1753-3 Feb. 1832) married Leman Stone on 5
                July 1795. She was the daughter of Nathaniel Stone (1731- 4 Nov. 1815) and Lois
                Collins (9 March 1736-8 May 1795) who were married 2 Dec. 1761. Current research
                shows that Nathaniel and Lois also had a son named Timothy (1773-1826) (who would
                later become a deacon) and a daughter Rachel (b. 1765). Timothy married Eunice
                Parmalee [Parmele] (1778-1859) and had at least seven children. The most prominent
                child was the Reverend Collins Stone (12 Sept. 1812-24 Dec.1870). Collins was an
                1832 Yale graduate and was room-mates with his brother-in-law Rollin Sydney Stone
                (b. 1809, d. 1895 in Chatham Borough, New Jersey) who would marry Collins’s sister
                Urania Stone. Collins married Ellen Jane Gill on 30 April 1839 and they had five
                children. He was an instrumental teacher in deaf education, becoming an early
                instructor in 1833, and later, the fourth president of the American Asylum for the
                Deaf and Dumb in Hartford (later the American School for the Deaf) (ASD) in West
                Hartford. In between the two careers in Hartford, the family moved to Columbus, Ohio
                when Collins took the principalship of the Ohio Institution in 1852. However, the
                family met with despair there when two of Stone's daughters died. The family moved
                back to Hartford in 1863 when Collins took the principalship at the American Asylum.
                Shortly thereafter, Collins Stone's life ended when he was fatally injured on
                Sigourney Street in Hartford when the carriage he was driving was struck by a train
                on Christmas Eve, 1870. Of the five children of Collins and Ellen, Edward Collins
                "Ned" Stone (29 Jan. 1840-1878) carried on his father's position at the American
                Asylum and held it until his death. Edward married Mary Catherine Welles (b. 13 Dec.
                1843) on 26 July 1869 and the couple had at least two children including Jane
                "Jeannie" Welles Stone and Henrietta Ellen Stone. The Strong/Welles family lines
                converge in the collection here. Going back, we know that William Strong (28 July
                1785-10 Nov. 1841) married Naomi Terry (b. 25 Sept. 1787) on 13 Nov. 1838. The
                couple bore Jane Naomi Strong (1814-1885) and William Sumner Strong (b. 20 Feb.
                1820). Jane Naomi married Charles Pitkin Welles (1811-1876) and they raised Charles
                Thomas Welles (b. 23 April 1846) and Mary Catherine whom we have already discussed.
                The remainder of those people represented in the collection are seemingly
                genealogically unrelated to the above group. Maria Lewis is represented in the
                collection through several letters sent to her, care of William Turner, Esq. It can
                be assumed that this is William W. Turner (3rd principal of the American Asylum)
                however that link could not be proven at this time. A woman by the name of Margaret
                Maria Lewis is known, however, as being the first wife of Harvey Prindle Peet, who
                was an instructor and steward at the American Asylum as well as principal of the New
                York Institution. Capt. John Bennett and daughter Eliza C. Bennett of Hartford are
                represented in the collection through personal correspondence, including a letter
                written to Mrs. Bennett and daughters by Laurent "Louis" Clerc (26 December 1785 –
                18 July 1869), co-founder of the American Asylum. Further research may discover a
                connection between the Lewis, Bennett, and Stone families.]</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520$a">
      <head>Scope and Content</head>
      <p> [The provenance of this collection is unknown but it is possible that this
                collection is part of the Stone-Welles-Todd family papers (Ms. 77458) donated by a
                descendant, Mary W. Todd of West Hartford, in May 1977. This collection is focused
                around the correspondence and papers of the Bennett, Stone, Strong, Watkinson,
                Welles, and Turner families of the Hartford area. The earliest papers in the
                collection are from Stephen Stone and include a travel pass from 1747, his last will
                and testament, and a notarized note regarding a change in guardianship of Caty and
                Polly Stone in 1794. Leman Stone's papers include a property deed for land in South
                Farms (now Morris) Connecticut in 1776 and personal correspondence from his brother
                Stephen, and do his grand-daughter Louisa. Even though out of chronological order,
                the papers relating to the death of William Oliver Stone (great grandson of Leman
                Stone), include tributes to him written by staff at the National Academy of Design.
                Nathaniel and Lois Stone's personal correspondence (and transcriptions) are part of
                the collection and include their responses to the death of Lucy, their daughter.
                Rachel Stone's papers include personal correspondence (hand-written and typed
                transcriptions) to close family members and a very interesting declaration written
                at the age of 18 in which Rachel professes her love of Jesus Christ. Timothy Stone
                writes to his brother William about his experiences with near-death as well as the
                death of a daughter Lavinia. Timothy's son, the Rev. Collins Stone, writes of less
                anguishing matters and we find that much of his correspondence details his leaving
                of the ministry and the reasons why he wanted to teach the deaf. Also included in
                his papers are letters of recommendation, and licenses from the North Association of
                Hartford from 1840-1849 (regarding his ministerial practices). Correspondents
                include close family members, Chauncey Goodrich (Yale), Rev. H. Woodruff of Orange,
                and Lewis Weld. Conversely, Ellen Jane Gill's correspondence is from close friends
                and Collins. A sizable portion of the collection contains the letters of Edward
                Collins Stone and his wife Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone. His letters include, among
                other matters, discussions of his salary at the American Asylum, the solicitation of
                Edward for the position of principal at the Wisconsin Institute, and the fatal
                injuries his younger sister Alice received while in Ohio. Mary writes on personal
                matters, including the weather and travel, and also on the death of her husband.
                Mary's papers include receipts received while traveling around Stuttgart, Germany in
                1889. Jean "Jeannie" Welles receives numerous letters from her children, including
                one written on what appears to be birch-bark, and writes frequently to her uncle
                about daily life. The remainder of the collection includes inventories and a bond
                for real estate owned by William Strong, the frequent correspondence of Jane Naomi
                Strong (including several interesting certifications she received from her teacher
                after completing religious education classes), the very fragile letters of Jane
                Watkinson, and correspondence of the Bennett family of Hartford, including a letter
                from Laurent Clerc. Papers relating to the American Asylum seem to have been kept
                around the time of Edward Collins Stone's principalship at the American Asylum and
                not his fathers. The folder includes a transcript of a journal entry by Emily Peas
                (ca. 1849) who was studying to be a teacher and visited the American Asylum and
                describes lessons there. Also included are two copies of "The Daily News," a copied,
                hand-written daily newsletter of the American Asylum dating from Dec. 23-24, 1878
                which describe the loss of Edward Collins Stone. The collection ends with a folder
                of assorted letters and papers whose placement could not be determined at this time.
                Correspondents include Nancy &amp; Fanny Bliss, Emily Bond, Elliott Stone, Achsa
                Goodwin, and Calvin Terry.]</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Series I: [title]</emph> [Enter series info, using Roman Numerals
                for series numbers]</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Series II: [title]</emph> [Separate paragraphs for each
                series]</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>There are no restrictions on access to the collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Use of the material requires compliance with the Connecticut Historical Society's
                Research Center regulations.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Item, Collection Title, Collection number (Box #, Folder #). Connecticut Historical
                Society, Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo>
      <head>Processing Details</head>
      <p>Collection was processed by [Zac Mirecki] in [2010].</p>
      <p>EAD Finding Aid created [January 2011].</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accruals>
      <head>Accruals</head>
      <p>The collection is closed.</p>
    </accruals>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject Headings</head>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Personal Names</head>
        <persname encodinganalog="600">[Stone, Edward Collins, 1878-]</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600">[Stone, Collins, 1812-1870 ]</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600">[Clerc, Laurent, 1785-1869]</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700">[additional author].</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Family Names</head>
        <famname encodinganalog="600">[family - subject].</famname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Corporate Names</head>
        <corpname encodinganalog="610">[Stone Family Association].</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subjects</head>
        <subject encodinganalog="650">[American Asylum, at Hartford, for the Education and
                    Instruction of the Deaf and Dumb].</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650">[Deaf--Education].</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Geographic Names</head>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651"/>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Genre Forms</head>
        <genreform encodinganalog="655"/>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Contents:</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Stone Family</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
            <unittitle> Folder 1: Stephen Stone papers <unitdate type="inclusive">1747-1794</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 2: Leman Stone (1750-1847) papers <unitdate type="inclusive">1776-1843</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 3: Papers regarding the death of Wm. Oliver Stone
                                <unitdate type="inclusive">1875</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 4: Nathaniel Stone papers <unitdate type="inclusive">1794-1804</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 5: Lois [Collins] Stone papers <unitdate type="inclusive">ca. 1794</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 6: Rachel Stone papers <unitdate type="inclusive">1783-1828</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 7: Timothy Stone correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1825</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 8: Rollin Sydney Stone correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1822</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 9: Rev. Collins Stone papers <unitdate type="inclusive">1833-1871</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 10: Ellen Jane Gill correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1849-1855</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 11: Edward Collins Stone correspondence (FRAGILE)
                                <unitdate type="inclusive">1852-1859</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 12: Edward Collins Stone correspondence (FRAGILE)
                                <unitdate type="inclusive">1860-1871</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 13: Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1871-1877</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 14: Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1878-1881</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box" label="Box">2</container>
            <unittitle>Folder 1: Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1882-1886</unitdate> 1888- <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 2: Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">May -August 1889</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 3: Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">September -December 1889</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 4: Jane "Jeannie" [Welles] Stone correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1882-1889</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 5: Edward W. Welles correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1831-1835</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 6: William Strong papers <unitdate type="inclusive">1840</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">1843</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 7: Jane Naomi Strong correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1828-1836</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 8: Jane Naomi Strong correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1837-1838</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">1880</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 9: William Sumner Strong correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1870</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 10: Charles Thomas Welles correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 11: Jane Watkinson correspondence (FRAGILE) <unitdate type="inclusive">1799-1804</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 12: Maria Turner correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1822-1825</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 13: Bennett family correspondence <unitdate type="inclusive">1820</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">1825-1828</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 14: Papers relating to the American Asylum <unitdate type="inclusive">1878</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Folder 15: Assorted correspondence and papers <unitdate type="inclusive">1825-1889</unitdate>
                            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
