<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002//EN" "ead.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="eadcbs9.xsl"?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtHi"
            url="http://www.chs.org/finding_aides/finding_aids/Stone_family.html"
            >Stone_family</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Stone Family Papers, 1747-1889</titleproper>
                <subtitle encodinganalog="245$b">A Guide to the collection at the Connecticut
                    Historical Society </subtitle>
                <author>Compiled by CHS Staff</author>

            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Connecticut Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
<addressline>1 Elizabeth Street</addressline>
<addressline>Hartford, CT 06105</addressline>
</address>
                <p>Copyright 2011, Connecticut Historical Society</p>
                <date>June 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Created by CHS Staff, <date>June 2011</date>.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">

        <did>
            <head>Collection Overview</head>
            <repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository:"><corpname>Connecticut Historical
                    Society,
                </corpname><address>
    <addressline>Hartford, Connecticut</addressline>
   </address>
            </repository>
            <origination encodinganalog="100" label="Creator :">Stone family</origination>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title :">Stone Family Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Dates : ">1747-1889</unitdate>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Extent :"><extent>1 linear foot (2
                    boxes)</extent></physdesc>

            <physloc label="Location:" altrender="Location :">Ms 100736</physloc>
            <langmaterial encodinganalog="546">English</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
            <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
            <p>The earliest of papers in the collection were penned by Stephen Stone who was a
                descendant from William Stone (b. ca. 1608), a signer of the Guilford Covenant and
                member of Rev. Henry Whitfield’s first company to sail to New Haven in 1639. Stephen
                wed Rebekah (Rebecca) Bishop and the couple bore Leman Stone (29 Dec. 1750-May 1847)
                and Joel Stone. The family originated in Guilford but later moved to South Farms in
                Litchfield (now Morris). This line of the Stone family was merged with another Stone
                line when Leman married Lois Stone. This family bore several children, including
                Ellen Stone, who married Frederick William Stone (1842-1913). Ellen and Frederick
                had two sons: Frederick Leman Stone and William Oliver Stone (26 Sept. 1830-15 Sept.
                1875). </p>
            <p>Lois (or Louisa) Stone (24 April 1753-3 Feb. 1832) married Leman Stone on 5 July
                1795. She was the daughter of Nathaniel Stone (1731- 4 Nov. 1815) and Lois Collins
                (9 March 1736-8 May 1795) who were married 2 Dec. 1761. Current research shows that
                Nathaniel and Lois also had a son named Timothy (1773-1826) (who would later become
                a deacon) and a daughter Rachel (b. 1765). Timothy married Eunice Parmalee [Parmele]
                (1778-1859) and had at least seven children. The most prominent child was the
                Reverend Collins Stone (12 Sept. 1812-24 Dec.1870). Collins was an 1832 Yale
                graduate and was room-mates with his brother-in-law Rollin Sydney Stone (b. 1809, d.
                1895 in Chatham Borough, New Jersey) who would marry Collins’s sister Urania Stone.
                Collins married Ellen Jane Gill on 30 April 1839 and they had five children. (There
                are two connections to the Watkinson family of Hartford/Middletown here: Louisa
                Stone (1842-1913) (daughter of Collins and Ellen) married Edward Blair Watkinson
                (1813-1884) who was the son of Edward Watkinson (1783-1859). Also, Jane Watkinson
                Gill (1785-1859), whose papers are housed in the collection, was the mother of
                Collins' wife Ellen Jane Gill.) </p>
            <p>Collins was an instrumental teacher in deaf education, becoming an early instructor
                in 1833, and later, the fourth president of the American Asylum for the Deaf and
                Dumb in Hartford (later the American School for the Deaf) (ASD) in West Hartford. In
                between the two careers in Hartford, the family moved to Columbus, Ohio when Collins
                took the principalship of the Ohio Institution in 1852. However, the family met with
                despair there when two of Stone's daughters died. The family moved back to Hartford
                in 1863 when Collins took the principalship at the American Asylum. Shortly
                thereafter, Collins Stone's life ended when he was fatally injured on Sigourney
                Street in Hartford when the carriage he was driving was struck by a train on
                Christmas Eve, 1870. </p>
            <p>Of the five children of Collins and Ellen, Edward Collins “Ned” Stone (29 Jan.
                1840-1878) carried on his father's position at the American Asylum and held it until
                his death. Edward married Mary Catherine Welles (b. 13 Dec. 1843) on 26 July 1869
                and the couple had at least two children including Jane “Jeannie” Welles Stone and
                Henrietta Ellen Stone. The Strong/Welles family lines converge in the collection
                here. Going back, we know that William Strong (28 July 1785-10 Nov. 1841) married
                Naomi Terry (b. 25 Sept. 1787) on 13 Nov. 1838. The couple bore Jane Naomi Strong
                (1814-1885) and William Sumner Strong (b. 20 Feb. 1820). Jane Naomi married Charles
                Pitkin Welles (1811-1876) and they raised Charles Thomas Welles (b. 23 April 1846)
                and Mary Catherine whom we have already discussed.</p>
            <p>The remainder of those people represented in the collection are seemingly
                genealogically unrelated to the above group. </p>
            <p>Maria Lewis is represented in the collection through several letters sent to her,
                care of William Turner, Esq. It can be assumed that this is William W. Turner (3rd
                principal of the American Asylum) however that link could not be proven at this
                time. A woman by the name of Margaret Maria Lewis is known, however, as being the
                first wife of Harvey Prindle Peet, who was an instructor and steward at the American
                Asylum as well as principal of the New York Institution. </p>
            <p>Capt. John Bennett and daughter Eliza C. Bennett of Hartford are represented in the
                collection through personal correspondence, including a letter written to Mrs.
                Bennett and daughters by Laurent “Louis” Clerc (26 December 1785 – 18 July 1869),
                co-founder of the American Asylum. Further research may discover a connection
                between the Lewis, Bennett, and Stone families. </p>

        </bioghist>

        <scopecontent encodinganalog="520$a">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>Wherever possible, folders in this collection have been arranged in chronological
                order by birth year of the person whose papers they contain. Furthermore, folders
                have been arranged by family names and familial relation (with family lines grouped
                together and parents coming before their children). Items within folders have been
                arranged chronologically. </p>
            <p>The provenance of this collection is unknown but it is possible that this collection
                is part of the Stone-Welles-Todd family papers (Ms. 77458) donated by a descendant,
                Mary W. Todd of West Hartford, in May 1977. </p>
            <p>This collection is focused around the correspondence and papers of the Bennett,
                Stone, Strong, Watkinson, Welles, and Turner families of the Hartford area. The
                earliest papers in the collection are from Stephen Stone and include a travel pass
                from 1747, his last will and testament, and a notarized note regarding a change in
                guardianship of Caty and Polly Stone in 1794. Leman Stone's papers include a
                property deed for land in South Farms (now Morris) Connecticut in 1776 and personal
                correspondence from his brother Stephen, and do his grand-daughter Louisa. Even
                though out of chronological order, the papers relating to the death of William
                Oliver Stone (great grandson of Leman Stone), include tributes to him written by
                staff at the National Academy of Design. Nathaniel and Lois Stone's personal
                correspondence (and transcriptions) are part of the collection and include their
                responses to the death of Lucy, their daughter. Rachel Stone's papers include
                personal correspondence (hand-written and typed transcriptions) to close family
                members and a very interesting declaration written at the age of 18 in which Rachel
                professes her love of Jesus Christ. </p>
            <p>Timothy Stone writes to his brother William about his experiences with near-death as
                well as the death of a daughter Lavinia. Timothy's son, the Rev. Collins Stone,
                writes of less anguishing matters and we find that much of his correspondence
                details his leaving of the ministry and the reasons why he wanted to teach the deaf.
                Also included in his papers are letters of recommendation, and licenses from the
                North Association of Hartford from 1840-1849 (regarding his ministerial practices).
                Correspondents include close family members, Chauncey Goodrich (Yale), Rev. H.
                Woodruff of Orange, and Lewis Weld. Conversely, Ellen Jane Gill's correspondence is
                from close friends and Collins. </p>
            <p>A sizable portion of the collection contains the letters of Edward Collins Stone and
                his wife Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone. His letters include, among other matters,
                discussions of his salary at the American Asylum, the solicitation of Edward for the
                position of principal at the Wisconsin Institute, and the fatal injuries his younger
                sister Alice received while in Ohio. Mary writes on personal matters, including the
                weather and travel, and also on the death of her husband. Mary's papers include
                receipts received while traveling around Stuttgart, Germany in 1889. Jean “Jeannie”
                Welles receives numerous letters from her children, including one written on what
                appears to be birch-bark, and writes frequently to her uncle about daily life. The
                remainder of the collection includes inventories and a bond for real estate owned by
                William Strong, the frequent correspondence of Jane Naomi Strong (including several
                interesting certifications she received from her teacher after completing religious
                education classes), the very fragile letters of Jane Watkinson, and correspondence
                of the Bennett family of Hartford, including a letter from Laurent Clerc.</p>
            <p>Papers relating to the American Asylum seem to have been kept around the time of
                Edward Collins Stone's principalship at the American Asylum and not his fathers. The
                folder includes a transcript of a journal entry by Emily Peas (ca. 1849) who was
                studying to be a teacher and visited the American Asylum and describes lessons
                there. Also included are two copies of “The Daily News,” a copied, hand-written
                daily newsletter of the American Asylum dating from Dec. 23-24, 1878 which describe
                the loss of Edward Collins Stone. The collection ends with a folder of assorted
                letters and papers whose placement could not be determined at this time.
                Correspondents include Nancy &amp; Fanny Bliss, Emily Bond, Elliott Stone, Achsa
                Goodwin, and Calvin Terry. </p>

        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict>
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>There are no restrictions on access to the collection.</p>
        </accessrestrict>

        <userestrict>
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Use of the material requires compliance with the Connecticut Historical Society's
                Research Center regulations.</p>
        </userestrict>

        <prefercite>
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Item, Collection Title, Collection number (Box #, Folder #). Connecticut Historical
                Society, Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
        </prefercite>

        <processinfo>
            <head>Processing Details</head>
            <p>Collection was processed by Zac Mirecki in 2010.</p>
            <p>EAD Finding Aid created June 2011.</p>

        </processinfo>

        <accruals>
            <head>Accruals</head>
            <p>The collection is closed.</p>
        </accruals>

        <controlaccess>
            <head>Subject Headings</head>

            <controlaccess>
                <head>Personal Names</head>

                <persname encodinganalog="700">Stone, Collins, 1812-1870. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Watkinson, Louisa Stone, 1843-1913.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Watkinson, Edward Blair, 1813-1884. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Stone, Ellen Jane Gill.</persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Stone, Edward C., 1840-1878. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Williams, Catherine Stone, 1845-1909. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Stone, Rollin Sidney, 1809-1895. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="700">Stone, Mary Wells, b. 1843. </persname>

            </controlaccess>

            <controlaccess>
                <head>Family Names</head>
                <famname encodinganalog="600">Stone Family.</famname>
            </controlaccess>



            <controlaccess>
                <head>Subjects</head>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Stone, Collins, 1812-1870. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Watkinson, Louisa Stone, 1843-1913. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Watkinson, Edward Blair, 1813-1884. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Stone, Ellen Jane Gill. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Stone, Edward C., 1840-1878. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Williams, Catherine Stone, 1845-1909. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Stone, Mary Wells, b. 1843 </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Stone, Rollin Sidney, 1809-1895. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">American School, at Hartford, for the Deaf.</subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="650">Family --Connecticut. </subject>
            </controlaccess>



        </controlaccess>




        <dsc type="combined">
            <head>Contents:</head>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unitid> Papers </unitid>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 1 </container>
                        <unittitle> Stephen Stone papers, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1747-1794 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 2 </container>
                        <unittitle> Leman Stone (1750-1847) papers, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1776-1843 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 3 </container>
                        <unittitle> Papers regarding the death of Wm. Oliver Stone, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1875 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 4 </container>
                        <unittitle> Nathaniel Stone papers, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1794-1804 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 5 </container>
                        <unittitle> Lois [Collins] Stone papers, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> ca. 1794 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 6 </container>
                        <unittitle> Rachel Stone papers, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1783-1828, undated </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 7 </container>
                        <unittitle> Timothy Stone correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1825 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 8 </container>
                        <unittitle> Rollin Sydney Stone correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1822 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 9 </container>
                        <unittitle> Rev. Collins Stone papers, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1833-1871 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 10 </container>
                        <unittitle> Ellen Jane Gill correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1849-1855, undated </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 11 </container>
                        <unittitle> Edward Collins Stone correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1852-1859 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 12 </container>
                        <unittitle> Edward Collins Stone correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1860-1871 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 13 </container>
                        <unittitle> Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1871-1877 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 1 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 14 </container>
                        <unittitle> Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1878-1881 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 1 </container>
                        <unittitle> Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1882-1886, 1888-1889 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 2 </container>
                        <unittitle> Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> May-August 1889 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 3 </container>
                        <unittitle> Mary Catherine [Welles] Stone correspondence </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> September-December 1889 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 4 </container>
                        <unittitle> Jane “Jeannie” [Welles] Stone correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1882-1889 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 5 </container>
                        <unittitle> Edward W. Welles correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1831-1835 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 6 </container>
                        <unittitle> William Strong papers, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1840, 1843 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 7 </container>
                        <unittitle> Jane Naomi Strong correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1828-1836 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 8 </container>
                        <unittitle> Jane Naomi Strong correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1837-1838, 1880 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 9 </container>
                        <unittitle> William Sumner Strong correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1870 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 10 </container>
                        <unittitle> Charles Thomas Welles correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1889 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 11 </container>
                        <unittitle> Jane Watkinson correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1799-1804 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 12 </container>
                        <unittitle> Maria Turner correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1822-1825 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 13 </container>
                        <unittitle> Bennett family correspondence, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1820, 1825-1828 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 14 </container>
                        <unittitle> Papers relating to the American Asylum, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1878, undated </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="Box"> 2 </container>
                        <container type="Folder"> 15 </container>
                        <unittitle> Assorted correspondence and papers, </unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1825-1889, undated </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>

        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
