<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002//EN" "ead.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="eadcbs9.xsl"?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtHi" url="http://www.chs.org/finding_aides/finding_aids/wellg1878.html">wellg1878</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="245$a">Gideon Welles Papers</titleproper>
        <subtitle encodinganalog="245$b">A Guide to the Gideon Welles Papers at the Connecticut
     Historical Society</subtitle>
        <author>Compiled by CHS Staff</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Connecticut Historical Society</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1 Elizabeth Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Hartford, CT 06105</addressline>
        </address>
        <p>Copyright 2010, Connecticut Historical Society</p>
        <date>December 2010</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <repository label="Repository :">
        <corpname>Connecticut Historical Society</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle label="Title :">Gideon Welles Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates : ">1758 - 1814</unitdate>
      <origination label="Creator :">Gideon Welles</origination>
      <abstract label="Abstract :">Collection consists of mixed personal and official correspondence,
    diaries, accounts with the Hartford Fire Insurance Company, Naval Commissions, Ephemera and
    Printed Political Material.</abstract>
      <physdesc label="Extent :">
        <extent>5 linear feet (10 boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Location:" altrender="Location :">Ms Wellg1878</physloc>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546">English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <otherfindaid>
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>An index of catalog cards is available to aid access to this collection and material in other
    collections. Access is through writer, recipient and date. The card catalog is located in the
    Research Center reading room. </p>
      <p>Microfilm copy available.</p>
    </otherfindaid>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
      <p>Gideon Welles, Secretary of the Navy, <date>1861-1869</date>, was born in Glastonbury, CT, on
    July 1, 1802. Educated at the Episcopal Academy in Cheshire, CT, and at the American Literary,
    Scientific and Military Academy in Norwich, VT (now Norwich University, Northfield, VT), Welles
    later read law in Hartford under William W. Ellsworth. However, preferring political and
    literary pursuits, he never practiced. </p>
      <p>In <date>1826 </date>Welles was elected to the Connecticut General Assembly from Glastonbury,
    serving from 1827 to 1835. As a legislator he worked to outlaw imprisonment for debt and to
    abolish property and religious qualifications for those serving as witnesses in court.</p>
      <p>In 1826 Welles also became part-owner and editor of the <emph render="italic">Hartford
     Times</emph>, a leading Jacksonian organ in the state. A skilled political organizer and
    journalist, he used his editorial and legislative positions to promote the initially unpopular
    Jacksonian Democracy in Connecticut. Welles was also instrumental in carrying the state for
    Jackson in the presidential contest of 1832, and for Van Buren four years later. He was rewarded
    with the postmastership of Hartford, a powerful patronage position, which he held from 1836 to
    1841. </p>
      <p>Through the influence of his associate on the <emph render="italic">Times</emph>, U. S.
    Senator John M. Niles, Welles was appointed chief of the Bureau of Provisions and Clothing
    during the Polk administration. He was the only civilian to head a bureau in the U. S. Navy
    Department. Serving throughout the Mexican War, Welles brought an unwonted efficiency to the
    Bureau's administration and eliminated much of the graft which had previously characterized its
    operations.</p>
      <p>While not an ardent abolitionist, Welles was personally opposed to slavery and to its
    extension into the territories. In the presidential contest of 1848, he gave quiet encouragement
    to the Free Soil candidacy of his old associate, Martin Van Buren. By 1854 Welles had broken
    both with the Democratic administration and the pro-Administration <emph render="italic">Hartford Times</emph> over the Kansas Nebraska Act, joining with other free soil Democrats in
    opposition to the extension of slavery into Kansas. </p>
      <p>A founder of the Republican Party in Connecticut (1855-6), Welles was its first candidate for
    governor. While he failed to win election, partly from his refusal to court support from the
    Know-Nothing Party, his strong showing won him a place on the Republican National Committee
    (1856-1864). In that role he exercised a strong influence on the drafting of the national
    Republican platforms of 1856 and 1860. He was also instrumental in founding the <emph render="italic">Hartford Evening Press</emph> to promote the interests of the new party. Welles
    wrote many of its editorials and political articles.</p>
      <p>Appointed Secretary of the Navy in 1861, Welles proved to be a firm, efficient and energetic
    administrator. Under his direction, the department was singularly free from corruption and
    political favoritism. Versed in international law, Welles, with Charles Sumner, also provided a
    useful counterweight in the Cabinet to the sometimes ill-conceived policies of Secretary of
    State William H. Seward. With Montgomery Blair and Edward Bates, Welles represented the
    conservative position in Lincoln's Cabinet on matters of constitutional law.</p>
      <p>Welles was an early and enthusiastic advocate of an ironclad navy. His energetic promotion of
    the plans of John Erickson led to the construction of the Monitor and ultimately to a highly
    effective ironclad steam navy. Welles was also an early advocate of giving protection and
    employment in the navy yards and aboard ship to runaway slaves, with pay equivalent to their
    white counterparts, and he supported the President's emancipation measures.</p>
      <p>Welles also backed the President's moderate reconstruction policies, agreeing with Lincoln
    that the Union was indissoluble and that the states, as such, had never left the Union. Under
    Johnson he continued to oppose Congressional reconstruction on constitutional grounds, while
    deploring the President's often tactless and inept attempts to carry out Lincoln's policies. By
    1868 he had returned to the Democratic fold. In 1872 he was acting with the Liberal Democrats,
    though he had little enthusiasm for their presidential candidate, Horace Greeley.</p>
      <p>From 1869 until his death in l878 Welles wrote numerous political and historical articles,
    including a series of wartime recollections which appeared in The Atlantic and Galaxy. The
    latter, gathered into a volume entitled <emph render="italic">Lincoln and Seward</emph>,
    exploded the growing myth that Seward and not the President was the directing force in the
    Lincoln administration. Welles' extensive Civil War diaries are also an important historical
    source.They must be read, though, with caution. Welles revised the manuscript extensively, and
    neither of the published versions (1911 and 1960) are entirely accurate, nor do they adequately
    reflect the original and subsequent revisions.</p>
      <p>No orator, Welles tended to avoid the limelight. But like his rival and sometimes uneasy ally,
    Thurlow Weed, Welles exerted tremendous influence on the political world through his incisive
    editorial writing and his able and untiring "behind the scenes" political activity. A man of
    single-minded integrity, and of unwavering loyalty to both his principles and the
    administrations under which he served, Welles exercised an incalculable influence on the
    political life of mid-nineteenth century America.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520$a">
      <head>Scope and Content</head>
      <p>Collection consists largely of correspondence, drafts of letters and supporting material
    written in both personal and official roles. Such correspondence is arranged chronologically. Of
    note are three letter books kept while Welles was Secretary of the Navy. Other naval material
    consists of commissions to sailors from presidents Madison to Van Buren.</p>
      <p>Two slim diaries or commonplace books written by Welles in his youth and a collection of
    menus, invitations and other societal notices (Series VI: Ephemera) constitute the rest of
    Welles' personal material in this collection.</p>
      <arrangement>
        <head>Arrangement</head>
        <p>Materials are organized into eight series based largely on form.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series I: Correspondence</emph> consists of letters to and from Gideon
     Welles, written and received in many of his professional roles. Correspondence is arranged
     chronologically following previous arrangement and contains mixed personal and business matter.
     Three letter books compiled in 1861 when Welles was Secretary of the Navy are included in this
     series.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series II: Printed Political Material</emph> consists of notices,
     adjudications, pamphlets, resolutions, and similar items.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series III: Ephemera</emph> consists of printed and handwritten
     invitations, obituaries, and other societal notices.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series IV: Insurance Records</emph> consists of policies, receipts for
     payment, accounts and summaries of account information of Welles' dealings with the Hartford
     Fire insurance Co.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series V: Drafts of Letters</emph> consists of drafts of letters and
     documents used in the compilation of those drafts. Drafts are undated but were predominantly
     written in the 1850s.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series VI:Naval Commissions</emph> consists of Commissions to the Navy
     issued by Presidents Madison through Van Buren. Commissions are arranged chronologically under
     issuing president, rather than by name of sailor.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series VII: Diaries</emph> consists of two volumes containing journal
     entries, jottings and quotations.</p>
        <p><emph render="bold">Series VIII: Transcriptions</emph> comprises transcriptions of the letter
     books and correspondence in Series I.</p>
        <p>Collection is arranged chronologically within in each series. </p>
      </arrangement>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>There are no restrictions on access to the collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Use of the material requires compliance with the Connecticut Historical Society's Research
    Center regulations. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Item, Collection Title, Collection number (Box #, Folder #). Connecticut Historical Society,
    Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo>
      <head>Processing Details</head>
      <p>Original EAD instance compiled in April 1999. Updated to EAD 2002 in December 2010.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accruals>
      <head>Accruals</head>
      <p>The collection is open, but additional material is not expected.</p>
    </accruals>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject Headings</head>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Personal Names</head>
        <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Blair, Francis Preston, </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Blair, Montgomery, </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Buckingham, William Alfred, </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Wright, Silas, </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Geographic Names</head>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh"> United States History Civil War, 1861-1865 Naval
     operations. </geogname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Genre Forms</head>
        <genreform encodinganalog="655"> Holographs; holographs, signed; typescripts; printed forms
     completed in manuscript; printed material. </genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Contents:</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>I. Correspondence</unitid>
        </did>
        <note>
          <p> Transcriptions of the Letter books may be found in Box 8. Other transcriptions of
      Correspondence in this series are located in Boxes 9 and 10. </p>
        </note>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Volume">1</container>
            <unittitle>Letter book, compiled when Secretary of the Navy.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>March 8, 1861 - July 22, 1861</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Volume">2</container>
            <unittitle>Letter book, compiled when Secretary of the Navy.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>July 22, 1861 - February 19, 1862</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Volume">3</container>
            <unittitle>Letter book, compiled when Secretary of the Navy.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>February 20, 1862 - June 21, 1862</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and supporting documents: 1768-1819. Includes diploma of Yale
       Medical College</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1768 - 1819</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and supporting documents; principally relating to roles in the
       Connecticut Assembly and the House of Representatives.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1820 - 1827</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and supporting documents: includes some transcriptions.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1827 - 1829</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1830 - 1832</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence; largely of a personal nature.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1833 - 1834</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence; largely of a personal nature.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1835</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1836</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1837 - 1839</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1840 - 1842</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1843 - 1845</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and drafts of letters out.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1846 - 1847</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and drafts of letters out; includes an "ode to Christmas" and drafts
       to Martin Van Burren.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1848 - 1849</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and drafts of letters out.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1850 - 1851</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and drafts of letters out.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1852 - 1853</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and drafts of letters out.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1854 - 1855</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1856</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1857</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1858</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence; including published material of the Republican National
       Committee.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1859 - 1860</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>January - April, 1861</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>May - December, 1861</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1862</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1863</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1864</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1865</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1866 - 1867</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1868 - 1869</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1870 - 1872</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1873 - 1878</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Letters to Gideon Welles; undated, ordered by surname of sender.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18--?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
            <container type="Folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence on the candidature of Judge Welles.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18--?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>II. Printed Political Material</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Printed political material.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[183-? - 186?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Printed political material.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[183-? - 186?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Printed political material.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[183-? - 186?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Printed political material; includes a number of railroad maps.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[186-?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>(empty)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Draft of an article on Connecticut politics</unittitle>
            <unitdate/>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Draft of an article on Connecticut politics</unittitle>
            <unitdate/>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Draft of an article on Connecticut politics</unittitle>
            <unitdate/>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>III. Ephemera</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Ephemera: Invitations and notices.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[186-?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Ephemera: Invitations; including National Inauguration Ball.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[183-? - 186?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
            <container type="Folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Ephemera: Invitations, notices and obituaries.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[186-?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Ephemera: Invitations and notices.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[186-?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Ephemera: Menus.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[186-?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>IV. Insurance Records</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Insurance records.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1834 - 1877</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>V. Drafts of Letters</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters and supporting material.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18-]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters and supporting material.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18-]; predominant [185-]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters and supporting material.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18-]; predominant [185-]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters and supporting material.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18-]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters and supporting material.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18-]; predominant [185-]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18-]; predominant [185-]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[185-?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
            <container type="Folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[185-?]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Drafts of letters</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18-]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Document (letter) fragments</unittitle>
            <unitdate>[18-]</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>VI. Naval Commissions</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>James Madison</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1809 - 1817</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>James Monroe</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1817 - 1823</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>James Monroe</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1817 - 1823</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>John Quincy Adams</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1823 - 1827</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Andrew Jackson</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1829</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Martin Van Buren</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1838</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">6</container>
            <container type="Folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Register of Conveyances for the State of South Carolina. Includes a grant of
       Alderano Cybo Malaspina to Valleriano Panizza.</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1803</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>VII. Diaries</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">7</container>
            <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1822 </unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">7</container>
            <unittitle>Commonplace book</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1823</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>VIII. Transcriptions</unitid>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">8</container>
            <unittitle>Letter books</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="Box">9-10</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
