<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
 <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" langencoding="iso639-2b">
 <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-MaBoHNE" url="http://www.historicnewengland.org/collections-archives-exhibitions/collections-access/collection-object/capobject?gusn=GUSN-171963">MS006</eadid>
 <filedesc>
 <titlestmt>
 <titleproper type="filing">Bowen family papers: finding aid</titleproper>
 <author>Processed by Historic New England staff, interns, and volunteers</author>
 </titlestmt>
 <publicationstmt>
 <date>2014</date>
 <publisher>Historic New England</publisher>
 <address>
 <addressline>Library &amp; Archives</addressline>
 <addressline>141 Cambridge Street</addressline>
 <addressline>Boston, Mass. 02114</addressline>
 </address>
 </publicationstmt>
 </filedesc>
 <profiledesc>
 <creation>This finding aid was generated from collection records developed by Historic New England staff, interns, and volunteers.</creation>
 <langusage>Description is in <language>English.</language></langusage>
 <descrules>Finding aid is DACS-compliant.</descrules>
 </profiledesc>
 </eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
 <titlepage>
 <titleproper>Bowen family papers: finding aid</titleproper>
 <num>Collection number: MS006</num>
 <publisher>Historic New England</publisher>
 <address>
 <addressline>Library &amp; Archives</addressline>
 <addressline>141 Cambridge Street</addressline>
 <addressline>Boston, Mass. 02114</addressline>
 </address>
 <p>Processed by Historic New England staff, interns, and volunteers.</p>
 <p>Date Completed: <date>2014</date></p>
 <p>Encoded by automated process. </p>
 <p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Please contact the Library and Archives.</p>
 </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
 <did>
 <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
 <unittitle label="Title">Bowen family papers</unittitle>
 <unitdate type="inclusive">1774-1986, undated</unitdate>
 <unitid label="Collection Code">MS006</unitid>
 <origination label="Creator">
 <persname>Bowen family</persname>
 </origination>
 <physdesc label="Extent">
 <extent>Family papers: 4.8 linear ft. (11 file boxes, 1 half file box) plus 2 folio boxes, 1 multi-purpose box, 7 oversize folders</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <repository label="Repository">
 <corpname>Historic New England</corpname>
 <address>
 <addressline>Library &amp; Archives</addressline>
 <addressline>141 Cambridge Street</addressline>
 <addressline>Boston, Mass. 02114</addressline>
 </address>
 </repository>
 <abstract label="Abstract">Account books, bills and receipts, and other financial records; address books; biographical and genealogical material; contracts, deeds, and other legal documents; correspondence and invitations; journals and notebooks; photographic material; printed material; ration books; site plans and specifications; clippings; etc.; reflecting the personal, social, and professional lives of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut, and life at Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut.</abstract>
 <langmaterial label="Languages and Scripts">Materials in English.</langmaterial>
 </did>
 <otherfindaid>
 <p>An electric finding aid is available through Historic new England's Collections Access Portal. A paper finding aid is available in the Library and Archives.</p>
 </otherfindaid>
 <relatedmaterial>
 <head>Related Materials at Historic New England</head>
 <p>General architectural and cartographic collection (AR001), Historic New England, Library &amp; Archives. Photostats of building specifications and receipts relating to Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut (Architecture Box 3, Folders 6A and 6B).</p>
 <p>Portable Desk (1974.370), Historic New England, Library &amp; Archives. Elizabeth Tappan's portable desk.</p>
 <p>Doll (2000.440), Historic New England, Library &amp; Archives. Grace Aspinwall's doll.</p>
 <p>Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Conn., Historic New England properties photographic collection (PC006.ROS), Historic New England, Library &amp; Archives.</p>
 </relatedmaterial>
 <relatedmaterial>
 <head>Related Materials at Other Institutions</head>
 <p>Hamilton Holt (Rollins Digital Collections). Archives and Special Collection, Olin Library, Rollins College, Winter Park, Florida.</p>
 <p>Bowen Family, Papers, c.1847-c.1934 (Manuscript Collections). American Antiquarian Society, Worcester, Massachusetts.</p>
 </relatedmaterial>
 <descgrp>
 <head>Important Information for Users of the Collection</head>
 <accessrestrict>
 <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
 <p>This collection is available for research. Unrestricted except for #OB.2.3-OB.2.5, which contain fragile material and require handling by Library and Archives staff only; and #4.16, which has been temporarily removed for preservation purposes. Note: due to age and other conditions affecting materials, the whole of the collection requires handling with care.</p>
 </accessrestrict>
 <userestrict>
 <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
 <p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Please contact the Library and Archives.</p>
 </userestrict>
 <phystech>
 <head>Physical and Technical Access</head>
 <p>OB.2.3, OB.2.4, and OB.2.5 contain fragile material and require handling by Library and Archives staff only.</p>
 </phystech>
 <phystech>
 <head>Conservation Note</head>
 <p>Please see the Scope and Content Note.</p>
 </phystech>
 <prefercite>
 <head>Preferred Citation</head>
 <p>Item identification. Box #, folder #. Bowen family papers (MS006). Historic New England, Library &amp; Archives.</p>
 </prefercite>
 <acqinfo>
 <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
 <p>Purchased from the Bowen family, 1971.</p>
 </acqinfo>
 <accruals>
 <head>Accruals</head>
 <p>Accruals are not expected.</p>
 </accruals>
 <appraisal>
 <head>Appraisal, Destruction, and Scheduling Note</head>
 <p>The following item has been removed from the collection and transferred to the Historic New England Library and Archives library collection because it is a duplicate item: Bowen, Herbert Wolcott (1926). Recollections Diplomatic and Undiplomatic. New York City, New York: Grafton Press.</p>
 </appraisal>
 <custodhist>
 <head>Custodial History</head>
 <p>1971: Purchase of Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut, and all its contents from the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut. 1973 (June 20): Gift of Karen N. McFarlan (Mrs. F. Warren McFarlan) of Belmont, Massachusetts [account book and letter] (#1.1-2.4). 1983: Gift of Henry Bowen White of Manchester, Massachusetts [invitations, photographs, and printed material] (#3.5, 4.16, 6.22, 10.31, 11.1, 11.3, OB.2.5). 1985 (July 5): Gift of Karen N. McFarlan (Mrs. F. Warren McFarlan) of Belmont, Massachusetts [correspondence] (#1.3). 1986: Gift of William Darr [correspondence] (#1.20). 1986: Subsequent material added from Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [photograph album] (#FB.2.1). 1987: Gift of Continental Insurance Company of New York [photographic and printed material] (#7.1, 8.17, 8.25, 8.29, OB.3.9). 1992: Subsequent material added from Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [invitations] (#6.22). 2005 (September 27): Gift of anonymous donor [printed material] (#5.1-5.5, 6.3). 2005 (July 1): Purchased from Hamilton Holt (1872-1951) [family papers] (Series IV, unprocessed). 2006: Subsequent material added from Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [photograph] (#10.19). Undated: Gift of Paul Archer [biographical material] (#6.8). Undated: Gift of Jane McClellan [correspondence] (#1.3). 1974: Gift of Henry Bowen White [papers removed from lap desk] (#6.28) [SPNEA #1974.370].</p>
 </custodhist>
 <processinfo>
 <head>Processing Information</head>
 <p>1983: Originally processed by Deborah Shea, intern. 2013 October: Updated by Bridgette A. Woodall, project archivist; with assistance from Jennifer Pustz, museum historian.</p>
 </processinfo>
 </descgrp>
 <bioghist>
 <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
 <p>Born October 22, 1724, Matthew Bowen (1724-1806) was of the fifth generation of Bowens in America; he was the son of Henry and Margaret (Davis) Bowen. Bowen engaged in several professions such as surveyor, constable, farmer, saddler, storekeeper, and landowner; he was also an active church member and served on numerous town committees. During the American Revolutionary War (1775-1783), he served as a Captain in the Connecticut militia and fought in the Rhode Island Campaign of August 29, 1778. On October 4, 1750, he married Mary Dana (1727-1813), daughter of Isaac and Sarah (Winchester) Dana of Pomfret, Connecticut. Matthew and Mary resided in Woodstock, Connecticut, and had eight children.
 
 William Bowen (1763-1837), sixth child of Matthew and Mary (Dana) Bowen, was born on December 28, 1763. Among other professions, he was a farmer, landowner, saddler, tavern keeper, merchant, postmaster, and meat packer. During the War of 1812 (1812-1815), he supplied the United States government with salted meats; he also shipped goods to the West Indies. William Bowen was instrumental in establishing two small businesses: Bowen and Lyon in 1798 and the Arnold Manufacturing Company in 1814. In 1801, he became a founder of the Woodstock Academy in Woodstock, Connecticut. Also, he was active in the First Ecclesiastical Society of South Woodstock, Connecticut, and held several civic posts. On December 25, 1788, he married Mary Chandler (1760-1834), daughter of Peter and Mary (Hodges) Chandler of Pomfret, Connecticut. William and Mary had five children.
 
 George Bowen (1789-1846), first child of William and Mary (Chandler) Bowen, was born on June 8, 1789. He inherited his father's store and tavern business and grew the business to include the sale of hardware supplies and medicines. He was active in the Woodstock Academy school board and was an officer of the Agricultural Society in Windham County, Connecticut. Also, he served as Postmaster-General, Justice of the Peace, and Selectman, among other civic duties. During the War of 1812 (1812-1815), he served as a lieutenant in the Connecticut militia and was sent to defend New London, Connecticut. On October 13, 1812, he married Lydia Wolcott Eaton (1793-1864), daughter of Eliot and Elizabeth (Davis) Eaton of Dudley, Massachusetts. George and Lydia had four children.
 
 Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896), first child of George and Lydia Wolcott (Eaton) Bowen, was born on September 11, 1813. He was educated at Woodstock and Dudley Academies and later worked in his father's store. At age twenty, he moved to New York City and joined the dry goods firm of Arthur Tappan and Company. Five years later, he formed his own firm of Bowen and McNamee (reorganized as Bowen, Holmes and Company in 1859) where he sold silks, ribbons, and dry goods. On June 6, 1844, he married Lucy Maria Tappan (1825-1863). In 1845, Bowen commissioned the construction of Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut, wehre the family summered. An impressive home at 90 Willow Street in Brooklyn Heights, New York, was their residence the rest of the year. Bowen was also a founding member of the Congregational Church Building Society in which he was a generous contributor to the construction of new churches in Connecticut, New York, Ohio, and Washington, D.C. Surviving public ridicule for not supporting the 1850 "Fugitive Slave Law," Bowen and McNamee prospered and expanded. The firm held on through the Panic of 1857 but in 1861, just shortly after reorganizing as Bowen, Holmes and Company, the firm went bankrupt with the onset of the American Civil War (1861-1865); Bowen subsequently retired from the dry goods business. By this time he was already engaged in other business ventures which included founding the Independent newspaper in 1848, a publication that encouraged the dissemination of Congregational values, and establishing the Continental Insurance Company in 1853. Both the Independent and Continental Insurance would continue to serve as sources of employment and income for later generations of the family. As a major benefactor of Woodstock, Connecticut, Bowen endowed Woodstock Academy and contributed to its reconstruction, donated trees to plant on Woodstock Common, and presented Roseland Park to the to wn during the national Centennial of 1876. Henry and Lucy had ten children before Lucy's death in 1863. On December 25, 1865, Henry Chandler Bowen married his second wife, Ellen Holt (1834-1903), daughter of Hiram and Mary (Chandler) Holt of Pomfret, Connecticut; they had one son, Paul Holt Bowen (1868-1895). Roseland Cottage experienced a rejuvenation following their marriage and Henry Bowen subsequently became well-known for reviving the celebration of the Fourth of July as a patriotic holiday.
 
 Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen (1825-1863) was the daughter of Lewis and Susanna (Aspinwall) Tappan of Brooklyn, New York. Her father, Lewis Tappan, was born in Northampton, Massachusetts, and her mother in Brookline, Massachusetts. Lewis Tappan was a passionate voice in the abolition movement. 
 
 Edward Eaton Bowen (1815-1887), second child of George and Lydia Wolcott (Eaton) Bowen, was born on September 20, 1815. He inherited the family business from his father and likewise, served as Postmaster. Later, he gave up the family business and moved to Brooklyn, New York, where he joined the dry goods firm of Ely, Clapp and Bowen (renamed Ely, Bowen and McConnell). After retiring from the dry goods industry, he became Deputy Collector of the Internal Revenue, Third District of Brooklyn and later ventured into banking. On June 14, 1836, he married Sophronia Tennent (1818-1899), daughter of George Benjamin and Mary Meekem (Tennent) Atwell of Enfield, Connecticut. Edward and Sophronia had six children.
 
 Henry ("Harry") Elliot Bowen (1845-1919), first child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born on March 31, 1845. He attended Brooklyn Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, New York, and Eastman Business College in Poughkeepsie, New York. He worked as a bank clerk, a stock broker, and as publisher and managing editor of the Brooklyn Daily Union newspaper. Bowen also spent twenty-five years as a solicitor in the advertising department of the New York Herald. "Harry" founded the Fresh Air Fund to give underprivileged children in New York a chance to experience the rural outdoors. He also raised funds for concerts in Prospect Park and was involved in fighting corruption in Brooklyn politics. On December 14, 1869, he married Elizabeth White (1848-1942), daughter of John Lincoln and Susan Rand (White) Plummer of Brooklyn, New York. Henry and Elizabeth had five children.
 
 Edward Augustus Bowen (1847-1926), second child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born on January 31, 1847. Also known as "Ned," Edward was educated at home and attended the Brooklyn Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, New York. Later, he attended the Eastman Business College in Poughkeepsie, New York. After graduation, he worked as a clerk for several businesses until he became a junior partner in the stock brokerage firm of Smith, Seaver and Bowen. In 1870, when the firm dissolved, "Ned" gave up full-time employment and pursued his interests in travel and genealogy. He managed the accounts for Roseland Cottage, traveled extensively, and offered support to several members of his family. In 1897, he published, Lineage of the Bowens of Woodstock, Connecticut. Edward Augustus Bowen died on May 12, 1926.
 
 Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt (1848-1925), third child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born on July 26, 1848. From 1863 to 1865, she attended Miss Porter's School in Farmington, Connecticut. On October 12, 1871, she married George Chandler Holt (1843-1931), brother of Ellen Holt (1834-1903). Mary Louisa (Bowen) and George Chandler Holt had six children. Her daughters Sylvia and Constance Holt were the last members of the Bowen family to live full-time at Roseland Cottage. 
 
 Grace Aspinwall (Bowen) Hardy (1850-1940), fourth child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born on February 4, 1850. She was educated at Brooklyn Heights Seminary in New York City, New York, and Miss Porter's School in Farmington, Connecticut. Between 1871 and 1895 she took five major trips to Europe with members of her family. In 1898, she married Arthur Sherburne Hardy, a professor of mathematics at Dartmouth College. At the time of their marriage, Hardy was serving as a U. S. Minister to Persia and later served as Minister to Spain and Switzerland.
 
 Clarence Winthrop Bowen (1852-1935), fifth child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born on May 22, 1852. From 1869 to 1873, he attended Yale College. Following graduation, he spent a year at Yale Divinity School before he abandoned his goal of becoming a minister. Bowen went on to earn a Masters and Ph.D in history from Yale College in 1876 and 1882, respectively. He worked as a reporter for the New York Herald Tribune became publisher and owner of the Independent newspaper, contributed to Century Magazine, and published several books on national politics and history. In 1887, he was appointed Secretary of the Committee on the Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of George Washington as President of the United States. From 1907 to 1931, he served as President of the New York Genealogical and Biographical Society. Also, he was a founding member of the American Antiquarian Society, the American Historical Society, and the Connecticut Historical Society. Clarence was the author of The Boundary Disputes of Connecticut (1882) and Woodstock: An Historical Sketch (1887). On January 28, 1892, he married Roxana Atwater Wentworth (1854-1935), daughter of John and Roxanna Marie (Loomis) Wentworth of Troy, New York; they had one daughter, Roxana Wentworth Bowen (born 1895). Clarence Bowen died on November 2, 1935. 
 
 Alice Linden (Bowen) Richardson (1854-1948), sixth child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born on March 9, 1854. Like her sisters, she was educated at Miss Porter's School in Farmington, Connecticut, and went on to further education in Berlin, Germany, and Gothic Hall Ladies School in Stamford, Connecticut. Alice also did a great deal of traveling with her family before marriage. On September 6, 1877, she married Rufus Byam Richardson (1845-1914); they had four children. Richardson received a Ph.D. from Yale and had a teaching career that took the family from Indiana University to Dartmouth College. The couple also lived overseas during the time in which he served as the director of the American School of Classical Studies in Athens, Greece. Alice also did some writing and had stories published in the Independent. 
 
 Herbert Wolcott Bowen (1856-1927), seventh child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born February 29, 1856. Like his brothers he was educated at Brooklyn Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, New York, but at age sixteen he went to Europe for two years of study in French, German, and Greek. From 1874-1878, he attended Yale College where he was one of the founders of the "Wolf's Head" senior society and a co-founder of the Yale News, the first college newspaper in the country. Although he did not graduate with his class, he was awarded an honorary Master's degree in 1903. In 1881, Herbert received an L.L.B. in law and political science from Columbia Law School. Later that year, he was admitted to the New York State bar and practiced law with his brother-in-law, George Chandler Holt (1843-1931). His diplomatic career began in 1890; he served in Spain, Persia, and Venezuela, but returned to Woodstock in 1905 when his career as a diplomat ended. Bowen was married twice: first wife, Augusta Floyd Vingut; second wife, Carolyn Mae Clegg (1877-1949). Herbert Wolcott Bowen died on May 29, 1927. 
 
 John Eliot Bowen (1858-1890), eighth child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born on June 8, 1858. He studied at Brooklyn Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, New York, and Woodstock Academy in Woodstock, Connecticut. In 1881, John graduated from Yale College, where he helped found the University Club. After graduation he traveled extensively in Europe and the Middle East. John received his Ph.D in political science from Columbia University in 1886. He became managing editor of the Independent newspaper and a published author, in addition to being an active sportsman and a talented polo player. On January 3, 1890, two days before his wedding, he died of typhoid fever.
 
 Franklin Davis Bowen (1860-1940), ninth child of Henry Chandler and Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen, was born on October 29, 1860. Like his brothers, he attended Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, New York, after which he was prepared for college by a private tutor. In 1884, he graduated from Yale College, where he participated in the Glee Club, played second violin in the University Orchestra, and played on the Lacrosse Team. Frank also helped found the "Wolf's Head" senior society. He spent the next ten years working for the Independent newspaper followed by an early retirement and active travel and time at Woodstock. Frank did not marry and died in 1940.
 
 Paul Holt Bowen (1868-1895), only child of Henry Chandler and Ellen (Holt) Bowen, was born on September 25, 1868. He attended Brooklyn Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, New York. In 1887, he entered the Science Department at Dartmouth College; he withdrew owing to ill health. On April 8, 1893, he married Emily Vivian (1896-1925), daughter of William Henry and Emily Caroline (Varney) Hyde of Alessandro, California; they had one child, Pauline Holt Bowen (born 1895). On January 17, 1895, Paul Holt Bowen died of consumption (tuberculosis).
 
 George Chandler Holt (1843-1931), brother of Ellen (Holt) Bowen (1834-1903) and husband of Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt (born 1848), was born December 31, 1843. In 1866, he graduated from Yale College and was chosen by his classmates to give the Class Oration. Holt graduated from Columbia Law School in 1869 and married Mary Louisa (Bowen) on October 12, 1871; they had six children.
 
 Gardner Richardson (1884-1972), third child of Alice Linden (Bowen) Richardson (1854-1948) and Rufus Byam Richardson (1845-1914), was born on February 8, 1884. In 1905, he graduated from Yale College and spent four years working at the Independent newspaper. He became interested in serving as a diplomat and worked for a series of foreign agencies, including The American Ambulance Corps in Paris (1915), the Commission for Relief in Belgium (1916), the American Relief Administration in Vienna (1929-early 1930s), and the American Legation at Bern. On American shores, he worked for the Department of Foreign and Domestic Commerce in Washington, DC. On November 24, 1927, he married Dorothea Boyd (1894-1981) of Toronto, Canada; they had two children.</p>
 </bioghist>
 <bibliography>
 <head>Sources</head>
 <bibref>Material within MS006.</bibref>
 <bibref>Roseland Cottage Research Files.</bibref>
 <bibref>Bowen, Edward Augustus. (1897). Lineage of the Bowens of Woodstock, Connecticut. Cambridge, Massachusetts: Riverside Press. Google Books edition.</bibref>
 <bibref>Library of Congress. Library of Congress Authorities. Retrieved from http://authorities.loc.gov/.</bibref>
 <bibref>Henry Holt (American football), Wikipedia: The Free Encyclopedia, last modified February 21, 2013, http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Holt_(American_football).</bibref>
 </bibliography>
 <scopecontent>
 <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
 <arrangement>
 <head>Arrangement</head>
 <p>The collection is arranged in four series: I. Papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut. II. Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut. III. Photographic material of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut. IV. Additional papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut. Collection housing/storage code: #x.x=file box (i.e., #1.2= file box 1, folder 2); C=carton; FB=folio box; FF=fragile files; MB=multi-purpose box; OB=oversize box/folder; OV=oversize volume; VF=vertical files/flat files.</p>
 </arrangement>
 <p>Processing/updating the collection and making the finding aid accessible online were made possible through grants from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (Award Number: NAR13-RH-50051-13), the Bedford Family Foundation, and an anonymous donor.</p>
 <p>The Bowen family papers (MS006) reflect the life and work of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut, and life at Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut, during the mid-nineteenth century through the early twentieth century. The collection is largely comprised of the papers of Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896) and his descendants; records relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut; and photographic material of the Bowen family. The collection is arranged in four series.</p>
 <p>Background: In 1971, Historic New England purchased Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut, from the Bowen family. The papers within the house at the time of purchase formed the bases of the collection: Bowen family papers, 1775-1965 (now MS006). In 1983, Deborah Shea, an intern and student in the Graduate Program in Archives Management at the University of Massachusetts in Boston, Massachusetts, processed the papers and created the original finding aid. Shea arranged the collection into three sub-groups.</p>
 <p>Sub-group I. Bowen Family Papers. The subgroup included account books, cash books, bills and receipts, and other financial papers; correspondence, invitations, letters, and notes; property abstracts, contracts, and deeds; site plans; estate inventories, wills, and other probate records; address books and a travel journal; printed material; objects; and clippings. The subgroup was arranged chronologically, by generation, in sixteen series: Series 1. Papers of Matthew Bowen, Series 2. Papers of George Bowen, Series 3. Papers of Henry Chandler Bowen (Sub-series A. Legal Papers, Series 3, Sub-series B. Financial Papers, Series 3, Sub-series C. Auctioneer's Catalogues, Sub-series D. Printed Matter), Series 4. Papers of Lucy Bowen, Series 5. Papers of Edward A. Bowen, Series 6. Papers of Mary (Bowen) Holt, Series 7. Papers of Clarence Bowen, Series 8. Papers of Herbert W. Bowen, Series 9. Papers of John Eliot Bowen, Series 10. Papers of Franklin Bowen, Series 11. Papers of Ellen (Holt) Bowen, Series 12. Papers of George C. Holt, Series 13. Papers of Constance Holt, Series 14. Papers of Sylvia Holt, Series 15. Papers of Gardner Richardson, Series 16. Miscellany.</p>
 <p>Sub-group II. Photographs on paper, wood, and tintypes. The subgroup included photographsand a cut-out photograph mounted on wood. The subgroup was arranged in six series: Series A. Photographs on paper: Portraits, Series B. Photographs on paper: Groups and Miscellaneous, Series C. Photographs on paper: Architecture, Series D. Photographs on paper: Scenery, Series E. Tintypes: Portraits, Series F. Tintypes: Groups.</p>
 <p>Sub-group III. Papers Pertaining to the Construction of "Roseland Cottage." The subgroup included contracts and drafts of contracts; building specifications; architectural plans; correspondence; bills, receipts, and related financial accounts; printed material; clippings; and photographic material. The subgroup was arranged in seven series: Series 1. Contracts and Specifications, Series 2. Correspondence to Henry C. Bowen, Series 3. Plans for the Addition to the Barn, Series 4. Financial Records: Henry C. Bowen, Series 5. Financial Records: Lewis Chamberlin, Series 6. Financial Records: Edwin Eaton, Series 7. Miscellany.</p>
 <p>When fully processed, the collection comprised 12 file boxes (approx. 5 linear ft.). Architectural papers related to Roseland Cottage, found among the papers of Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896) (Sub-group I, Series 3), were removed and placed into a separate sub-group: Sub-group III. Oversize material, which was comprised of newspapers (Sub-group I, Series 3, Sub-series D and Sub-group I, Series 16), was removed and housed within the vertical files/flat files. Photostats of building specifications and receipts for Roseland Cottage were separated from the collection and housed in Architecture Box 3, Folders 6A and 6B (now AR001). Additionally, three Goodspeeds catalogs, a Lippincott's Magazine, and the Connecticut Quarterly were separated from the collection as were other magazines, printed material, and four "magic lantern' slides; current location is unspecified.</p>
 <p>Update: In 2013-2014, through a National Historical Publications and Records Commission grant (Award Number: NAR13-RH-50051-13: "Family Manuscript Collections: Expanding Online Access to New England Heritage Project"), twenty-six Historic New England manuscript collections of family papers were re-evaluated and processed/reprocessed to meet current archival standards and "best practices;" corresponding finding aids were created/updated to be DACS-compliant and converted into electronic Microsoft Word document form; and the finding aids were made accessible/searchable online through the use of the MINISIS M2A archival database of the MINISIS Collections Management System. The Bowen family papers (MS006) were part of the grant project.</p>
 <p>Since 1983, following the initial processing of the collection and creation of the original finding aid, subsequent acquisitions/accessions had been integrated into the collection; material was periodically rehoused, renumbered, and/or removed/separated from the collection; and notations and additional pages were inserted into the finding aid. Additionally, the collection was not uniformly numbered throughout; several folders were unlabeled; boxes were overstuffed; materials improperly housed; and an accumulation of material was unprocessed.</p>
 <p>During the 2013-2014 collection reprocessing/updating, the 1983 arrangement scheme was updated; most of the original folder titles were maintained (appropriate headings and folder titles were supplied, as applicable); discrepancies between actual folder titles and the original 1983 finding aid were corrected; related folders were combined or rearranged, as applicable; the accumulated unprocessed material (prior to 2005) was incorporated into the collection; scope and content notes were updated to reflect the changes; and additional research was added to the biographical/historical sketch and genealogy. Preservation issues were identified and basic preservation methods were applied, as applicable; rusted, loose, and otherwise dangerous fasteners (i.e., paperclips, staples, pins, etc.) were removed, as applicable; fragile and vulnerable materials (i.e., acidic material; adhesive tape; fragments; clippings and newsprint; small and loose items; weak and/or damaged materials; etc.) were noted and preservation photocopies and/or enclosures were made for the materials (or materials were interleafed within file boxes), as applicable; papers throughout the collection were removed from envelopes (if applicable), unfolded, flattened, and related pages were noted with corresponding information in brackets ([x-1/3], [x-2/3], [x-3/3]; and objects, oversize material, and photographic material were rehoused appropriately (or materials were interleafed within file boxes), as applicable. The collection was rehoused (in acid-free folders and boxes), numbered, labeled, barcoded, and stored accordingly; subsequent accessions were tracked and noted with their corresponding items; missing items were noted; and related collections held by Historic New England and other repositories were researched and noted. The original 1983 paper document finding aid was updated to be DACS-compliant, as applicable; converted into an electronic 2010-2013 Microsoft Word document finding aid (with corresponding paper finding aid); and entered into the collection record in the MINISIS M2A online database.</p>
 <p>2013 extent of collection (prior to updating): 3 cartons (letter-wise)= 3.75 linear feet; 12 file boxes (legal-size)= 5.01 linear feet; 02 file boxes (letter-size)= 0.83 linear feet; 2 multi-purpose boxes; Vertical files/flat files. Note: Yale linear footage calculator: approximately 9.59 linear feet (3 cartons, 14 file boxes), plus 2 multi-purpose boxes and vertical files.</p>
 </scopecontent>
 <controlaccess>
 <head>Indexing Terms</head>
 <persname>Aspinwall, Peter</persname>
 <persname>Aspinwall, William</persname>
 <persname>Atwell, George Benjamin</persname>
 <persname>Atwell, Mary Meekem (Tennent)</persname>
 <persname>Barney, Hiram</persname>
 <persname>Barney, Edward A.</persname>
 <persname>Barney, Susan E. (Tappan)</persname>
 <persname>Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Augusta Floyd (Vingut)</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Carolyn Mae (Clegg), 1877-1949</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Clarence Winthrop, 1852-1935</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Edward A., 1847-1926</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Edward Eaton, 1815-1887</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Elizabeth White (Plummer), 1848-1922</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Ellen (Holt), 1834-1903</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Emily Vivian (Hyde), 1869-1925</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Ethel Plummer, 1879-</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Francis</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Franklin Davis, 1860-1940</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, George, 1789-1846</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Henry</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Henry Chandler, 1813-1896</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Henry Elliot, 1845-1919</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Herbert Wolcott, 1856-1927</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, John Eliot, 1858-1890</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Lucy Maria (Tappan), 1825-1863</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Lydia Wolcott (Eaton), 1793-1864</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Margaret (Davis)</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Mary (Chandler), 1760-1834</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Mary (Dana), 1727-1813</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Matthew, 1724-1806</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Paul Holt, 1868-1895</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Pauline, 1895-</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Roxana Atwater (Wentworth), 1854-1935</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, Sophronia Tennent (Atwell), 1818-1899</persname>
 <persname>Bowen, William, 1763-1837</persname>
 <persname>Browning, Elizabeth Barrett, 1806-1861</persname>
 <persname>Chamberlin, Lewis</persname>
 <persname>Chandler, Eleanor "Nellie"</persname>
 <persname>Chandler, Frances</persname>
 <persname>Chandler, Mary (Hodges)</persname>
 <persname>Chandler, Peter</persname>
 <persname>Dana, Isaac</persname>
 <persname>Dana, Sarah (Winchester)</persname>
 <persname>Dexter, Samuel</persname>
 <persname>Eaton, Edwin</persname>
 <persname>Eaton, Eliot</persname>
 <persname>Eaton, Elizabeth (Davis)</persname>
 <persname>Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790</persname>
 <persname>Fremont, John Charles, 1813-1890</persname>
 <persname>Grenfell, Wilfred</persname>
 <persname>Hardy, Arthur Sherburne, 1847-1930</persname>
 <persname>Hardy, Grace Aspinwall (Bowen), 1850-1940</persname>
 <persname>Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Alexina C.</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Constance, 1879-1968</persname>
 <persname>Holt, George C. (George Chandler), 1843-1931</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Hamilton, 1872-1951</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Henry Chandler, 1881-1955</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Hiram</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Mary (Chandler)</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Mary Louisa (Bowen), 1848-1925</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Stuart, 1876-1900</persname>
 <persname>Holt, Sylvia, 1889-1945</persname>
 <persname>Howe, Julia Ward, 1819-1910</persname>
 <persname>Hyde, Emily Caroline (Varney)</persname>
 <persname>Hyde, William Henry</persname>
 <persname>McClellan, John</persname>
 <persname>McFarlan, Karen N.</persname>
 <persname>McKinley, William, 1843-1901</persname>
 <persname>Medlar, Clara Soule, 1833 or 1834-1902</persname>
 <persname>Mellon, Anna</persname>
 <persname>Monroe, Edward Thayer</persname>
 <persname>Penfield, William Lawrence, 1846-1909</persname>
 <persname>Plummer, John Lincoln</persname>
 <persname>Plummer, Susan Rand (White)</persname>
 <persname>Prentier, John H.</persname>
 <persname>Proctor, Edna Dean, 1829-1923</persname>
 <persname>Reed, Grace (Holt), 1874-1937</persname>
 <persname>Richardson, Alice Linden (Bowen), 1854-1948</persname>
 <persname>Richardson, Dorothea (Boyd), 1894-1981</persname>
 <persname>Richardson, Gardner, 1884-1972</persname>
 <persname>Richardson, Rufus B. (Rufus Byam), 1845-1914</persname>
 <persname>Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962</persname>
 <persname>Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945</persname>
 <persname>Scott, Winfield, 1786-1866</persname>
 <persname>Stoddard, Evelyn</persname>
 <persname>Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1811-1896</persname>
 <persname>Stuart, Jane S., d. 1916</persname>
 <persname>Tappan, Arthur, 1786-1865</persname>
 <persname>Tappan, Charles</persname>
 <persname>Tappan, Elizabeth</persname>
 <persname>Tappan, Lewis, 1788-1873</persname>
 <persname>Tappan, Susanna (Aspinwall)</persname>
 <persname>Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972</persname>
 <persname>Underwood, Samuel</persname>
 <persname>Vereker, Gordon</persname>
 <persname>Vereker, Roxanna Wentworth (Bowen), 1895-</persname>
 <persname>Warren, Fuller, 1905-1973</persname>
 <persname>Washington, George, 1732-1799</persname>
 <persname>Wells, Joseph Collins, 1813-1860</persname>
 <persname>Wentworth, John, 1737-1820</persname>
 <persname>Wentworth, Roxanna Marie (Loomis)</persname>
 <persname>White, Henry Bowen</persname>
 <persname>Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892</persname>
 <corpname>Agricultural Society of Windham County (Conn.)</corpname>
 <corpname>American Ambulance Corps (Paris, France)</corpname>
 <corpname>American Antiquarian Society</corpname>
 <corpname>American Historical Society</corpname>
 <corpname>American Relief Administration</corpname>
 <corpname>American School of Classical Studies at Athens</corpname>
 <corpname>Arnold Manufacturing Company</corpname>
 <corpname>Arthur Tappan and Company</corpname>
 <corpname>Bowen and Lyon</corpname>
 <corpname>Bowen and McNamee</corpname>
 <corpname>Bowen, Holmes and Company</corpname>
 <corpname>Brooklyn Heights Seminary</corpname>
 <corpname>College of William and Mary</corpname>
 <corpname>Columbia University</corpname>
 <corpname>Columbia University. School of Law</corpname>
 <corpname>Commission for Relief in Belgium</corpname>
 <corpname>Committee on the Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of George Washington as President of the United States</corpname>
 <corpname>Congregational Church Building Society</corpname>
 <corpname>Connecticut Historical Society</corpname>
 <corpname>Continental Insurance Company of New York</corpname>
 <corpname>Dartmouth College</corpname>
 <corpname>Department of Foreign and Domestic Commerce (Washington, DC)</corpname>
 <corpname>Eastman National Business College (Poughkeepsie, N.Y.)</corpname>
 <corpname>Ely, Bowen and McConnell</corpname>
 <corpname>Ely, Clapp and Bowen</corpname>
 <corpname>First Ecclesiastical Society of South Woodstock (South Woodstock, Conn.)</corpname>
 <corpname>Fresh Air Fund</corpname>
 <corpname>Gothic Hall Ladies School (Stamford, Conn.)</corpname>
 <corpname>Indiana University</corpname>
 <corpname>Judiciary Committee of the Connecticut Legislature</corpname>
 <corpname>Lawyers' Club (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
 <corpname>Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
 <corpname>Miss Porter's School (Farmington, Conn.)</corpname>
 <corpname>New York Genealogical and Biographical Society</corpname>
 <corpname>Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn</corpname>
 <corpname>Putnam Rotary Club (Putnam, Conn.)</corpname>
 <corpname>Rollins College</corpname>
 <corpname>Smith, Seaver and Bowen</corpname>
 <corpname>Southern Railway (U.S.)</corpname>
 <corpname>United States. Legation (Switzerland)</corpname>
 <corpname>Woodstock Academy (Conn.)</corpname>
 <corpname>Yale College (1718-1887)</corpname>
 <corpname>Yale University. Divinity School</corpname>
 <geogname>Athens (Periféreia Protevoúsis, Greece)</geogname>
 <geogname>Barcelona (Barcelona province, Catalonia, Spain)</geogname>
 <geogname>Belgium</geogname>
 <geogname>Belmont (Middlesex county, Massachusetts)</geogname>
 <geogname>Berlin (Berlin state, Germany)</geogname>
 <geogname>Bern canton (Switzerland) [canton]</geogname>
 <geogname>Brookline (Norfolk county, Massachusetts)</geogname>
 <geogname>Brooklyn (New York City, New York state) [borough]</geogname>
 <geogname>Chaplin (Windham county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>Caracas (Distrito Federal, Venezuela)</geogname>
 <geogname>Dudley (Worcester county, Massachusetts)</geogname>
 <geogname>Enfield (Hartford county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>Farmington (Hartford county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>Florence (Firenze province, Tuscany, Italy)</geogname>
 <geogname>Hague, The (South Holland, Netherlands)</geogname>
 <geogname>Liverpool (Liverpool urban district, Merseyside, England, United Kingdom)</geogname>
 <geogname>Middle East [general region]</geogname>
 <geogname>Naples (Napoli province, Campania, Italy)</geogname>
 <geogname>New London (New London county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>New York City (New York state)</geogname>
 <geogname>Northampton (Hampshire County, Massachusetts)</geogname>
 <geogname>Paris (Ville de Paris department, Île-de-France, France)</geogname>
 <geogname>Persia (Asia) [historical region]</geogname>
 <geogname>Pomfret (Windham county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>Poughkeepsie (Dutchess county, New York state)</geogname>
 <geogname>Putnam (Windham county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>Rome (Roma province, Latium, Italy)</geogname>
 <geogname>Roseland Park (Windham county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>Stamford (Fairfield county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>Toronto (Toronto Metropolitan Area, Ontario, Canada)</geogname>
 <geogname>Troy (Rensselaer county, New York state)</geogname>
 <geogname>Vienna (Vienna state, Austria)</geogname>
 <geogname>Wales (United Kingdom) [country]</geogname>
 <geogname>Williamsburg (Williamsburg Indep. City, Virginia)</geogname>
 <geogname>Winter Park (Orange county, Florida)</geogname>
 <geogname>Woodstock (Windham county, Connecticut)</geogname>
 <geogname>Worcester (Worcester county, Massachusetts)</geogname>
 <subject>Tuberculosis</subject>
 <subject>Typhoid fever</subject>
 <subject>United States. History. Civil War, 1861-1865</subject>
 <subject>United States. History. Revolution, 1775-1783</subject>
 <subject>United States. History. War of 1812</subject>
 <subject>Woodstock (Conn.). History</subject>
 <subject>Fourth of July</subject>
 <subject>Bowen Family House (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</subject>
 <subject>Roseland Cottage (Woodstock, Conn.)</subject>
 <subject>abolitionists</subject>
 <subject>account books</subject>
 <subject>address books</subject>
 <subject>architects</subject>
 <subject>authors</subject>
 <subject>bills (legislative records)</subject>
 <subject>black-and-white photographs</subject>
 <subject>books</subject>
 <subject>business (commercial function)</subject>
 <subject>businessmen</subject>
 <subject>cabinet photographs</subject>
 <subject>card photographs (photographs)</subject>
 <subject>cartes-de-visite (card photographs)</subject>
 <subject>clippings (information artifacts)</subject>
 <subject>color photographs</subject>
 <subject>contracts</subject>
 <subject>correspondence</subject>
 <subject>deeds</subject>
 <subject>ephemera</subject>
 <subject>estate inventories</subject>
 <subject>family papers</subject>
 <subject>financial records</subject>
 <subject>genealogies</subject>
 <subject>Gothic Revival</subject>
 <subject>invitations</subject>
 <subject>journals (accounts)</subject>
 <subject>lawyers</subject>
 <subject>legal documents</subject>
 <subject>letters (correspondence)</subject>
 <subject>memorabilia</subject>
 <subject>merchants</subject>
 <subject>military personnel</subject>
 <subject>newspapers</subject>
 <subject>notebooks</subject>
 <subject>notes</subject>
 <subject>obituaries</subject>
 <subject>orators</subject>
 <subject>pamphlets</subject>
 <subject>personal correspondence</subject>
 <subject>personal papers</subject>
 <subject>photograph albums</subject>
 <subject>photographs</subject>
 <subject>photographic materials</subject>
 <subject>poems</subject>
 <subject>politicians</subject>
 <subject>probate records</subject>
 <subject>professional papers</subject>
 <subject>publications</subject>
 <subject>receipts (financial records)</subject>
 <subject>ration books</subject>
 <subject>site plans</subject>
 <subject>speeches</subject>
 <subject>swatches</subject>
 <subject>tintypes (prints)</subject>
 <subject>travel</subject>
 <subject>wills</subject>
 <subject>writings (document genre)</subject>
 </controlaccess>
 <dsc type="combined">
 <head>Collection Inventory</head>
 <c01>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1774-1986, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Family papers (7 file boxes, 1 folio box, 5 oversize folders)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Series I, Papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut, 1774-1986, undated (#1.1-5.5, 6.1-6.24, 6.28, 7.1-7.6, FB.1.1-FB.1.2, OB1.3, OB.2.3-OB.2.5, OB.3.7), contains the personal and professional papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut. Included in the series are account books; address books; auctioneer estate catalogs; bills and receipts; biographical and genealogical material; cash books; contracts and agreements; correspondence and notes; financial records; guest books; invitations; journals and notebooks; legal documents; memorabilia; newspapers, clippings, and other printed material; probate records; ration books; site plans; wills; etc. The series also contains materials relating to the Committee on the Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of George Washington as President of the United States; the Congregational Church Building Society; the First Ecclesiastical Society of South Woodstock, Connecticut; Woodstock Academy in Woodstock, Connecticut; the paintings of artist Clara Soule (1834-1902) at Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut; and the purchase of &amp;quot;Dexter Lot&amp;quot; from Samuel Dexter in Woodstock, Connecticut. The series is arranged in twenty subseries.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301; HGO-02-105-A-E-302; HGO-02-105-A-E-101; HGO-02-105-A-E-106</container>
 </did>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Clarence Winthrop Bowen (1852-1935)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1886-1915</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries A, Papers of Clarence Winthrop Bowen (1852-1935), 1886-1915 (#4.11-4.16, 6.1-6.2), contains 1889 memorabilia (including invitations and banquet material) from Bowen's work as secretary for the Committee on the Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of George Washington as President of the United States held in New York City, New York, and two of Bowen's published works: Woodstock: An Historical Sketch and &amp;quot;Charter of Connecticut.&amp;quot; The &amp;quot;Charter of Connecticut&amp;quot; is inscribed: 'To Edward Augustus Bowen from Clarence Winthrop Bowen, Woodstock, September 27, 1914&amp;quot; and Woodstock [copy 1] is inscribed: &amp;quot;Mary Bowen Holt from Clarence Winthrop Bowen, September 22, 1886.' Also included in the subseries is Bowen's 1915 baccalaureate address delivered at the 222nd annual commencement of the College of William and Mary in Williamsburg, Virginia. The subseries is arranged chronologically by committee material, followed by printed material.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Committee on the Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of George Washington as President of the United States</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1889</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Memorabilia (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #4.12 and 4.13 for items removed</abstract>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Invitation to reception at the Lawyers Club, New York City, New York, April 29; includes ribbon ties</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.01.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1889</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 11</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #4.12 and 4.13 for items removed</abstract>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Invitation to Centennial Celebration, New York City, New York, April 29 - May 1; includes envelope</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.01.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1889</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 12</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Item removed from #4.11
 NOTE: See #4.13 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Banquet materials from the Metropolitan Opera House, New York City, New York, April 30</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.01.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1889</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 13</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Items removed from #4.11
 NOTE: See #4.12 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1886-1915</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Publications (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Woodstock: An Historical Sketch [softcover]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.02.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1886</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 14</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Woodstock: An Historical Sketch [hardcover] [copy 1]; includes inscription</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.02.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1886</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 15</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Woodstock: An Historical Sketch [hardcover] [copy 2]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.02.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1886</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 16</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>&amp;quot;Charter of Connecticut,&amp;quot;; includes inscription</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.02.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1914</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Baccalaureate address delivered at the College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia, June 10</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.01.02.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1915</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Edward Augustus Bowen (1847-1926)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1866-1926</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries B, Papers of Edward Augustus Bowen (1847-1926), 1866-1926 (#3.1-3.4, 4.2-4.9),
 contains an account book; two cash books relating to Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut; correspondence (including an 1867 letter from Edna Dean Proctor (1829-1923), governess, with a clipping in Russian, #4.2); printed material (including a 1903 letter from judge William L. Penfield, 1846-1909, #4.4); a travel journal describing Bowen's &amp;quot;tug trip&amp;quot; to Liverpool in England, United Kingdom, in the winter of 1880 and his sightseeing excursions in Florence, Rome, and Naples, in Italy; and several wills and drafts of wills. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Account book</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1866-1908</unitdate>
 <container>Box 3, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Cash book re: Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1896-1903</unitdate>
 <container>Box 3, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Cash book re: Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut; includes loose items</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1903-1914</unitdate>
 <container>Box 3, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Correspondence; includes 1867 letter from Edna Dean Proctor (1829-1923), and clipping in Russian</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1909-1924</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1887-1911</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Publications (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Celebration of Christmas 1887 at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York; includes inscription: &amp;quot;Edward A. Bowen from Henry C. Bowen&amp;quot;</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.05.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1887</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>&amp;quot;Opening Argument and Reply for the United States,&amp;quot; presented to the Arbitration Tribunal of The Hague, Netherlands, November; includes 1903 letter from William L. Penfield (1846-1909)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.05.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1903</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>My four Great Gandmothers</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.05.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>ca. 1911</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Travel journal re: trip to Europe</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>1880-1888</unitdate>
 <container>Box 3, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Wills</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>1918-1922</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Wills [3 copies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.09</unitid>
 <unitdate>1926</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Wills, drafts [6 copies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.10</unitid>
 <unitdate>1926</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Wills; includes pages from wills [photocopies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.02.11</unitid>
 <unitdate>1918-1919, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #6.18 for item removed [Henry Chandler Bowen family genealogy chart, undated].</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Edward Eaton Bowen (1815-1887)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845-1878</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries C, Papers of Edward Eaton Bowen (1815-1887), 1845-1878 (#1.19), contains 
 receipts for the transportation and purchase of goods.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Receipts re: transportation and purchase of goods</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.03.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845-1878</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 19</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Ellen (Holt) Bowen (1834-1903)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1865-1898, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries D, Papers of Ellen (Holt) Bowen (1834-1903), 1865-1898, undated (#6.7, 7.2, 7.4), contains two address books and a note describing Bowen's 1865 wedding dress. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301; HGO-02-105-A-E-302</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Address book, May</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.04.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1898</unitdate>
 <container>Box 7, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Address book</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.04.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 7, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Note re: description of wedding dress, December 28</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.04.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1865</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Franklin Davis Bowen (1860-1940)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1940</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries E, Papers of Franklin Davis Bowen (1860-1940), 1940 (#6.6), contains a 1940 will.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Will [photocopy]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.05.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1940</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of George Bowen (1789-1846)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries F, Papers of George Bowen (1789-1846), 1845 (#1.2), contains financial records regarding tool repairs and the purchase of bolts.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Financial records re: tool repairs and purchase of bolts, September -November</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.06.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>1833-1896</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (2 file boxes, 1 oversize folder)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries G, Papers of Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896), 1833-1896 (#1.3-1.18, 2.2-2.3, OB.1.3), is divided into three categories: correspondence, financial records, and legal documents. The correspondence is comprised of a letter to a John McClellan regarding the &amp;quot;hero of Tippecanoe,&amp;quot; and correspondence with a John H. Prentier regarding the gift of a handmade quilt from Prentier's mother. The financial records include account books; bills and receipts; and related financial papers. Bowen's account books detail daily business dealings; household expenses; landscaping projects; tuition payments; donations to church and civic activities; building transactions related to Roseland Cottage; etc.; and reflect Bowen's meticulous record keeping activities, which began while in the employment of Arthur Tappan (1786-1865) in New York City, New York. The account book from 1848 to 1871 (#2.2), contains expenditures relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage (pages, 12-15); payments to contractor Edwin Eaton of Chaplin, Connecticut (page 10); and payments to architect Joseph Collins Wells (1814-1860) of Brooklyn, New York (page 18). Also included in the financial records is an embroidered silk swatch with receipt (#1.6); a receipt for trees donated and planted on Woodstock Common in Woodstock, Connecticut (#1.8); tuition bills for Woodstock Academy in Woodstock, Connecticut (#1.9); and material relating to the Congregational Church Building Society (including account books, collection funds, subscriptions, etc.). An 1896 issue of Church-Building Quarterly (#1.13), with a tribute to Bowen (pages 70-77), is also included in the financial records along with two 1896 auctioneer estate catalogs which feature furniture, artwork, and the library collection from the Bowen family property at 90 Willow Street in New York City, New York. The legal documents include a contract for land purchased at 90 Willow Street in Brooklyn, New York; an 1867 will of Samuel Dexter; an1895 will of Bowen; and an 1896 estate inventory for Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut. Also included in the legal documents is material related to the purchase of &amp;quot;Dexter Lot&amp;quot; in Woodstock, Connecticut (including a site plan and correspondence with Samuel Dexter, Bowen, and the First Ecclesiastical Society of South Woodstock in South Woodstock, Connecticut). The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type, then by topic, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301; HGO-02-105-A-E-106</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Correspondence: letter to John McClellan re: hero of Tippecanoe, June 5 [photocopy]; includes letter with transcription from John H. Prentier re: thank you gift, September 14</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1840-1856</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Financial records</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1833-1896</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Financial records (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Account books; includes account pages [photocopies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1833-1852</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Account book</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1837-1841</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Account book; includes loose items</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1848-1871</unitdate>
 <container>Box 2, Foler 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Account book; includes loose items</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1870-1893</unitdate>
 <container>Box 2, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Auctioneer's estate catalogs</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1896</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 10</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Congregational Church Building Society, account book re: Society collection funds; includes 1851 account book re: Society subscriptions</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>1837-1851</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 11</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Congregational Church Building Society, financial records; includes pages from account book [photocopies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>1850-1891</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 12</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Congregational Church Building Society, printed material, Church and Building Quarterly; includes tribute to Bowen</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.08</unitid>
 <unitdate>1896</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 13</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Household accounts, general accounts; includes embroidered silk swatch and receipt</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.09</unitid>
 <unitdate>1837-1869</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Household accounts, food expenses</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.10</unitid>
 <unitdate>1847-1850</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Household account, landscape projects, February-November</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.11</unitid>
 <unitdate>1847-1853</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Household accounts: Woodstock Academy, Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.12</unitid>
 <unitdate>1873</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See also #6.24 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Receipts for shipping</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.13</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845-1850</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 14</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Receipt for highway tax</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.02.14</unitid>
 <unitdate>1848</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 15</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Legal documents</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1853-1896</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Legal documents (1 file box, 1 oversize folder)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Abstract of title to land in the City of Brooklyn, Kings County, New York, re: property at 90 Willow Street, 1876</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.03.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1876</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 16</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #6.19 for item removed [letter re: key to Roseland Cottage safe].
 NOTE: See # OB.1.3 for item removed.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers re: &amp;quot;Dexter Lot,&amp;quot;; includes 1867 will of Samuel Dexter</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.03.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1853-1867</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 17</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Site plan re: tract of land purchased from John McClellan in Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.03.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1872</unitdate>
 <container>Box OB.1, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Item removed from #1.16.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Probate records; includes 1895 will and 1896 estate inventory [photocopies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.07.03.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1895-1896</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Henry Elliot Bowen (1845-1919)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.08</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>i720Subseries H, Papers of Henry Elliot Bowen (1845-1919), undated (#4.1), contains an undated address book.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Address book</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.08.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Herbert Wolcott Bowen (1856-1927)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.09</unitid>
 <unitdate>1884-1926</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries I, Papers of Herbert Wolcott Bowen (1856-1927), 1884-1926 (#5.1-5.3, 5.5, 6.3-6.4), contains several of Bowen's published works; Yale Faculty in the Days of '78 contains inscription: &amp;quot;For Darling Sylvia from Herbert Wolcott Bowen, 1923.&amp;quot; A 1907 letter regarding the shipment of materials to Caracas, Venezuela, is attached to the inside cover of Passing Thoughts [copy 1] (#5.1). Also included in the subseries is a 1925 brief regarding a proposed bill on bathing, boating and fishing in natural lakes and ponds, presented to the Judiciary Committee of the Connecticut Legislature (#6.3). The subseries is arranged chronologically.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.09.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1884-1926</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Publications (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Verses</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.09.01.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1884</unitdate>
 <container>Box 5, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>International Law: A Simple Statement of Its Principles; includes loose items</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.09.01.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1896</unitdate>
 <container>Box 5, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Passing Thoughts [2 copies]; includes letter re: shipment of materials to Caracas, Venezuela, May 18 [copy 1, front cover]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.09.01.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1902-1907</unitdate>
 <container>Box 5, folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Smoke-Rings; includes brief re: proposed bill on bathing, boating and fishing in natural lakes and ponds presented to the Judiciary Committee of the Connecticut Legislature, February 12</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.09.01.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1921-1925</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Yale Faculty in the Days of '78 [2 copies]; includes inscription</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.09.01.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1923</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Recollections Diplomatic and Undiplomatic</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.09.01.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>1926</unitdate>
 <container>Box 5, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of John Eliot Bowen (1858-1890)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.10</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (3 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries J, Papers of John Eliot Bowen (1858-1890), 1890 (#3.5, 5.4, 6.5), contains pamphlets with Bowen's obituary, printed by the Independent newspaper, and a published memorial of Bowen's life printed privately by his siblings. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Pamphlets: Independent newspaper, obituary for John Eliot Bowen, January 9 [6 copies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.10.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: Memorial of John Eliot Bowen [copy 1]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.10.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890</unitdate>
 <container>Box 3, folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: Memorial of John Eliot Bowen [copy 2]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.10.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890</unitdate>
 <container>Box 5, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen (1825-1863)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.11</unitid>
 <unitdate>1849-1862</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries K, Papers of Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen (1825-1863), 1849-1862 (#1.20-1.21), contains a series of correspondence between Bowen and orator Henry Ward Beecher (1813-1887). Also included in the subseries is a receipt for clothing. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Correspondence: Henry Ward Beecher (1813-1887) [photocopies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.11.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1860-1862</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 20</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Receipt re: purchase of clothing</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.11.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1849</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 21</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Matthew Bowen (1724-1806)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.12</unitid>
 <unitdate>1774-1973, predominant 1774-1789</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries L, Papers of Matthew Bowen (1724-1806), 1774-1973 (bulk, 1774-1789) (#1.1, 2.4), contains an account book reflecting Bowen's lending and borrowing activities as a tradesman. Also included in the subseries is a letter from Karen N. McFarlan (Mrs. F. Warren McFarlan) of Belmont, Massachusetts, regarding her donation of the account book to Historic New England. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Account book; includes loose items</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.12.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1774-1928, predominant 1774-1789</unitdate>
 <container>Box 2, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #1.1 for item removed.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Letter from Karen N. McFarlan (Mrs. F. Warren McFarlan) of Belmont, Massachusetts, re: donation of the Matthew Bowen account book, June 20</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.12.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1973, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 1, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Item removed from #2.4.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Constance Holt (1879-1968)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.13</unitid>
 <unitdate>1943-1968</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries M, Papers of Constance Holt (1879-1968), 1943-1968 (#6.13-6.14), contains a 1968 will and World War II (1939-1945) ration books for food and heating oil. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Ration books</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.13.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1943-1945</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, folder 13</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Will, March 13 [photocopy]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.13.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1968</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 14</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of George Chandler Holt (1843-1931)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.14</unitid>
 <unitdate>1894-1929, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries N, Papers of George Chandler Holt (1843-1931), 1894-1929, undated (#6.8-6.12), contains a poem and two published works by Holt. The subseries also includes a bibliographical sketch for George Chandler Holt and for Hamilton Holt (1872-1951). The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Biographical sketches: George Chandler Holt (1843-1931) and Hamilton Holt (1872-1951) [photocopies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.14.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Poem: &amp;quot;Volubilities of a Vegetarian,&amp;quot; December 31</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.14.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1923</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.14.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1894-1929</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>publications (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Lynching and Mobs, September 6</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.14.03.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1894</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 10</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Descendants and Relatives of Hiram Holt and Marian Chandler Holt</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.14.03.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1921</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 11</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Old Chandler Farm in Pomfret</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.14.03.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1929</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 12</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Henry Chandler Holt (1881-1955)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.15</unitid>
 <unitdate>1905-1911</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries O, Papers of Henry Chandler Holt (1881-1955), 1905-1911 (#6.15), contains a 1905 letter from the Southern Railway Company to Holt and a 1911 issue of the Yale '94 Gazette.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: Yale '94 Gazette, November; includes letter from Southern Railway Company, December 2</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.15.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1905-1911</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 15</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt (1848-1925)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.16</unitid>
 <unitdate>1924-1925</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries P, Papers of Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt (1848-1925), 1924-1925 (#4.10), contains wills from 1924 and 1925.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Wills</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.16.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1924-1925</unitdate>
 <container>Box 4, Folder 10</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Sylvia Holt (1889-1945)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.17</unitid>
 <unitdate>1932</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries Q, Papers of Sylvia Holt (1889-1945), 1932 (#6.16), contains a 1932 will.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Will, February 4 [photocopy]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.17.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1932</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 16</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers of Gardner Richardson (1884-1972)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.18</unitid>
 <unitdate>1965</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Personal papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries R, Papers of Gardner Richardson (1884-1972), 1965 (#6.17), contains two extracts of Richardson's 1965 address entitled, &amp;quot;Roseland Park and Henry C. Bowen,&amp;quot; delivered at the Putnam Rotary Club in Putnam, Connecticut.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: &amp;quot;Roseland Park and Henry C. Bowen,&amp;quot; extracts from an address delivered at the Putnam Rotary Club, Putnam, Connecticut, February 23 [2 copies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.18.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1965</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 17</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Genealogical material</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19</unitid>
 <unitdate>1850, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Genealogy (2 file boxes, 1 folio box, 1 oversize folder)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries S, Genealogical material, 1850, undated (#6.18, 7.5-7.6, FB.1.1-FB.1.2, OB.3.7), contains two volumes noted as &amp;quot;ancestral tablets,&amp;quot; which trace the Bowen family genealogy from the William Towne family; handwritten genealogical notes; an undated genealogical chart of the Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896) family; an 1850 census record for the Bowen family; a bound volume of the Bowen family genealogy with corresponding index; and an undated genealogical chart tracing the descendants of Bowen of Slade in Wales, Great Britain, United Kingdom. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301; HGO-02-105-A-E-302; HGO-02-105-A-E-101; HGO-02-105-A-E-106</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Genealogy</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.01</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>6 folders</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 18; Box 7, Folders 5-6; Box FB.1, Folders 1-2; Box OB.1, Folder 2</container>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Ancestral tablets, William Towne family, book 1 (1601-1896)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.01.01</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <container>Box 7, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Ancestral tablets, William Towne family, book 2 (1601-1864)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.01.02</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <container>Box 7, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family genealogical material; includes Henry Chandler Bowen family genealogical chart and Bowen family census record [photocopy]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.01.03</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 18</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family record (1631-1874)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.01.04</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <container>Box FB.1, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family reocrd (1631-1874), index of places; includes loose items</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.01.05</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <container>Box FB.1, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen of Slade, Oxwich Parish, Gower, Glamorganshire, Wales, Great Britain, family genealogical chart</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.01.06</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <container>Box OB.1, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Ancestral tablets: William Towne family, book 1 (1601-1896)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 7, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #OB.2.5 for item removed [1896 newspaper]</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Ancestral tablets: William Towne family, book 2 (1601-1864)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 7, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family genealogical chart: Bowen of Slade, Oxwich Parish, Gower, Glamorganshire, Wales, Great Britain, United Kingdom</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box OB.3, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family genealogical material; includes undated Henry Chandler Bowen family genealogical chart and Bowen family census record [photocopy]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1850, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 18</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Henry Chandler Bowen family: genealogical chart removed from #4.9
 NOTE: 1850 census material removed from #6.23</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family record (1631-1874)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box FB.1, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #FB.1.2 for items removed [index and loose material]</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family record (1631-1874), index of places; includes loose material</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.19.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box FB.1, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Items removed from #FB.1.1</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other Bowen family papers</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20</unitid>
 <unitdate>1806-1986, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Family papers (3 file boxes, 3 oversize folders)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries T, Other family papers, 1806-1986, undated (#2.1, 6.19-6.24, 6.28, 7.1, 7.3, OB.2.3-OB.2.5), contains a note referencing the key to the Roseland Cottage safe; correspondence regarding the paintings of artist Clara Soule (1834-1902); fragments of correspondence and financial records; a guest book from Roseland Cottage, which contains an 1894 ribbon for a summer outing; invitations to a circa 1890 Jenny Lind concert and an 1891 Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage; a notebook entitled, &amp;quot;Nathan Martins' Book of Woodstock, Connecticut, 1806,&amp;quot; which contains handwritten poems, other writings, and mathematical calculations; and printed material. Also included in the subseries are items removed from the lap desk of Elizabeth Tappan (dates unknown), which is held by Historic New England (#6.28). Contents of the lap desk include a calling/visiting card for an Ethel P. Bowen (dates unknown); a trade card for a Brooklyn wig maker; invitations to a &amp;quot;Boy's Prayer Meeting;&amp;quot; a 1922 Valentine to a &amp;quot;Mrs. White of Boston;&amp;quot; and a handwritten verse and envelope addressed to Henry Bowen White (dates unknown). The subseries is arranged alphabetically by record type, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301; HGO-02-105-A-E-302; HGO-02-105-A-E-106</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Correspondence: letter re: key to safe at Roseland Cottage</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 19</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Item removed from #1.16.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Correspondence: letters re: paintings of Clara Soule (1834-1902), July 25</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1986</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 20</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Financial records, unidentified</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1847-1853</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 21</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Guest book: Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut Guest book: Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1870-1984; includes loose items and a ribbon: &amp;quot;C.E.A. Summer Outing, Roseland Park, August 23, 1984&amp;quot;</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1870-1984</unitdate>
 <container>Box 7, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Invitations re: parties at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890-1891</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 22</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Notebook: Nathan Martins' book of Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>1806</unitdate>
 <container>Box 2, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other papers, fragments; includes clipping</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>1851-1986, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 23</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #6.18 for item removed [1850 Bowen family census].</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other papers: items removed from the lap desk of Elizabeth Tappan (dates unknown)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.08</unitid>
 <unitdate>1922, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, folder 28</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See SPNEA furniture collection #1974.370, Museum Collection, for Elizabeth Tappan's portable desk</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: Windham County Transcript, &amp;quot;The Great Celebration,&amp;quot; July 6; includes speeches by Henry Ward Beecher, Theodore Tilton, Governors Buckingham and Cleveland</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.09</unitid>
 <unitdate>1865</unitdate>
 <container>Box OB.2, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: CONTAINS FRAGILE MATERIAL.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: Independent newspaper, twenty-first year commemorative issue, December 2</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.10</unitid>
 <unitdate>1869</unitdate>
 <container>Box OB.2, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: CONTAINS FRAGILE MATERIAL.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: Woodstock Centennial Recorder, September 10; includes historical address delivered by Clarence Winthrop Bowen (1852-1935)</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.11</unitid>
 <unitdate>1886</unitdate>
 <container>Box OB.2, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: CONTAINS FRAGILE MATERIAL.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: Independent newspaper, February 20</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.12</unitid>
 <unitdate>1896</unitdate>
 <container>Box OB.2, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Item removed from #7.6.
 NOTE: CONTAINS FRAGILE MATERIAL.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: Continental Insurance Company of New York, 1853-1905: A Historical Sketch</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.13</unitid>
 <unitdate>1905</unitdate>
 <container>Box 7, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Printed material: bylaws and charter of the Woodstock Academy, Woodstock, Connecticut, September [3 copies]; includes Woodstock Academy Gleaner</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.01.20.14</unitid>
 <unitdate>1901-1934</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 24</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See also #1.9 for related material.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 </c01>
 <c01>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845-1969, undated, predominant 1845-1851</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Business records (3 file boxes, 1 oversize folder)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Series II, Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1845-1969, undated (bulk: 1845-1851) (#6.25-6.27, 8.1-8.17, 12.15, OB.3.8), is divided into four categories: contracts and specifications; correspondence; financial records; and other material. The contracts and specifications include two drafts and a signed agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896) and contractor Samuel Underwood regarding construction materials for Roseland Cottage and an adjoining barn; specifications of architect Joseph Collins Wells (1814-1860) regarding the carpentry and masonry work for Roseland Cottage and the barn; and floor plans for an addition to the barn. The correspondence contains letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896) regarding the construction of Roseland Cottage. Among the letters are contractor Samuel Underwood's request to be released from his contract; letters from contractor Edwin Eaton detailing the work progress on the construction of Roseland Cottage; and Eaton's letters regarding his decision to hire a Mr. Taylor of Brooklyn, New York, to complete the masonry work and a Mr. Joy of Worcester, Massachusetts, as foreman. Included in the financial records are bills and receipts; drafts of checks; payment made to laborers; and payments for the purchase of construction supplies for Roseland Cottage, which were kept by Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896), Lewis Chamberlin, and Edwin Eaton. Also included in the series is a collection of papers entitled, &amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; which describes the rooms and interior furnishings at Roseland Cottage as recalled by an Anna Mellon; photographs taken of paintings that were once inside Roseland Cottage (including several portraits of Benjamin Franklin, 1706-1790); and clippings reflecting life at Roseland Cottage. The series is arranged alphabetically by record type, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-301; HGO-02-105-A-E-302; HGO-02-105-A-E-106</container>
 </did>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen and contractor, Samuel Underwood, re: construction of a house and barn, October 13, 1845 [2 copies]; includes drafts [2 copies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.01.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 25</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Specifications of Joseph C. Wells, architect, re: carpentry [2 copies] and masonary work [1 copy] on the house, 1845</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.01.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 26</container>
 <abstract>Bowen family papers (MS006)
 
 Series II, Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1845-1969, undated (bulk: 1845-1851) (#6.25-6.27, 8.1-8.17, OB.1.4-OB.1.5), contains agreements and contracts (includes drafts); bills and receipts; building and construction specifications; correspondence; design and floor plans; drafts of checks; work account records; photographs; clippings; and a collection of papers describing the rooms at Roseland Cottage. The series is divided into three sections: contracts and specifications, financial records, and other materials. Contracts and specifications includes two drafts and a signed agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen and contractor, Samuel Underwood, regarding the furnishing of materials for construction of Roseland Cottage and an adjoining barn; specifications of architect, John C. Wells, for the carpentry and masonry work at Roseland Cottage and for the construction of the barn; and design and floor plans for the addition to the barn. The correspondence contains letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen relating to the construction work on Roseland Cottage. Several of the letters are from contractor, Samuel Underwood, requesting to be released from his contract; and other letters are from contractor, Edwin Eaton, detailing the work progress on the construction of Roseland Cottage and his decision to hire a Mr. Taylor of Brooklyn, New York, to complete the masonry work and a Mr. Joy of Worcester, Massachusetts, as foreman. The financial records include bills and receipts; drafts of checks; and work account records regarding the payment of laborers and the purchase of supplies associated with the construction of Roseland Cottage; the records were kept by Henry Chandler Bowen, Lewis Chamberlin, and Edwin Eaton. A collection of papers referred to as &amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; describing the interior furnishings and rooms at Roseland Cottage, as recalled by Anna Mellon; photographs of a collection of paintin gs at Roseland Cottage (includes several photographs of Benjamin Franklin); and newspaper clippings relating to Roseland Cottage and its inhabitants, comprise the section of other materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by section, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Specifications of Joseph C. Wells, architect, re: construction of the barn, 1845</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.01.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 27</container>
 <abstract>Bowen family papers (MS006)
 
 Series II, Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1845-1969, undated (bulk: 1845-1851) (#6.25-6.27, 8.1-8.17, OB.1.4-OB.1.5), contains agreements and contracts (includes drafts); bills and receipts; building and construction specifications; correspondence; design and floor plans; drafts of checks; work account records; photographs; clippings; and a collection of papers describing the rooms at Roseland Cottage. The series is divided into three sections: contracts and specifications, financial records, and other materials. Contracts and specifications includes two drafts and a signed agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen and contractor, Samuel Underwood, regarding the furnishing of materials for construction of Roseland Cottage and an adjoining barn; specifications of architect, John C. Wells, for the carpentry and masonry work at Roseland Cottage and for the construction of the barn; and design and floor plans for the addition to the barn. The correspondence contains letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen relating to the construction work on Roseland Cottage. Several of the letters are from contractor, Samuel Underwood, requesting to be released from his contract; and other letters are from contractor, Edwin Eaton, detailing the work progress on the construction of Roseland Cottage and his decision to hire a Mr. Taylor of Brooklyn, New York, to complete the masonry work and a Mr. Joy of Worcester, Massachusetts, as foreman. The financial records include bills and receipts; drafts of checks; and work account records regarding the payment of laborers and the purchase of supplies associated with the construction of Roseland Cottage; the records were kept by Henry Chandler Bowen, Lewis Chamberlin, and Edwin Eaton. A collection of papers referred to as &amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; describing the interior furnishings and rooms at Roseland Cottage, as recalled by Anna Mellon; photographs of a collection of paintin gs at Roseland Cottage (includes several photographs of Benjamin Franklin); and newspaper clippings relating to Roseland Cottage and its inhabitants, comprise the section of other materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by section, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Plans for addition to the barn, undated [photocopies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.01.04</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <container>Box OB.1, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract>Bowen family papers (MS006)
 
 Series II, Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1845-1969, undated (bulk: 1845-1851) (#6.25-6.27, 8.1-8.17, OB.1.4-OB.1.5), contains agreements and contracts (includes drafts); bills and receipts; building and construction specifications; correspondence; design and floor plans; drafts of checks; work account records; photographs; clippings; and a collection of papers describing the rooms at Roseland Cottage. The series is divided into three sections: contracts and specifications, financial records, and other materials. Contracts and specifications includes two drafts and a signed agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen and contractor, Samuel Underwood, regarding the furnishing of materials for construction of Roseland Cottage and an adjoining barn; specifications of architect, John C. Wells, for the carpentry and masonry work at Roseland Cottage and for the construction of the barn; and design and floor plans for the addition to the barn. The correspondence contains letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen relating to the construction work on Roseland Cottage. Several of the letters are from contractor, Samuel Underwood, requesting to be released from his contract; and other letters are from contractor, Edwin Eaton, detailing the work progress on the construction of Roseland Cottage and his decision to hire a Mr. Taylor of Brooklyn, New York, to complete the masonry work and a Mr. Joy of Worcester, Massachusetts, as foreman. The financial records include bills and receipts; drafts of checks; and work account records regarding the payment of laborers and the purchase of supplies associated with the construction of Roseland Cottage; the records were kept by Henry Chandler Bowen, Lewis Chamberlin, and Edwin Eaton. A collection of papers referred to as &amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; describing the interior furnishings and rooms at Roseland Cottage, as recalled by Anna Mellon; photographs of a collection of paintin gs at Roseland Cottage (includes several photographs of Benjamin Franklin); and newspaper clippings relating to Roseland Cottage and its inhabitants, comprise the section of other materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by section, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Work accounts re: laborers, September 1845 - November 1851; includes Lewis Chamberlin's work account</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.03.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845-1851</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract>Bowen family papers (MS006)
 
 Series II, Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1845-1969, undated (bulk: 1845-1851) (#6.25-6.27, 8.1-8.17, OB.1.4-OB.1.5), contains agreements and contracts (includes drafts); bills and receipts; building and construction specifications; correspondence; design and floor plans; drafts of checks; work account records; photographs; clippings; and a collection of papers describing the rooms at Roseland Cottage. The series is divided into three sections: contracts and specifications, financial records, and other materials. Contracts and specifications includes two drafts and a signed agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen and contractor, Samuel Underwood, regarding the furnishing of materials for construction of Roseland Cottage and an adjoining barn; specifications of architect, John C. Wells, for the carpentry and masonry work at Roseland Cottage and for the construction of the barn; and design and floor plans for the addition to the barn. The correspondence contains letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen relating to the construction work on Roseland Cottage. Several of the letters are from contractor, Samuel Underwood, requesting to be released from his contract; and other letters are from contractor, Edwin Eaton, detailing the work progress on the construction of Roseland Cottage and his decision to hire a Mr. Taylor of Brooklyn, New York, to complete the masonry work and a Mr. Joy of Worcester, Massachusetts, as foreman. The financial records include bills and receipts; drafts of checks; and work account records regarding the payment of laborers and the purchase of supplies associated with the construction of Roseland Cottage; the records were kept by Henry Chandler Bowen, Lewis Chamberlin, and Edwin Eaton. A collection of papers referred to as &amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; describing the interior furnishings and rooms at Roseland Cottage, as recalled by Anna Mellon; photographs of a collection of paintin gs at Roseland Cottage (includes several photographs of Benjamin Franklin); and newspaper clippings relating to Roseland Cottage and its inhabitants, comprise the section of other materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by section, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bills and receipts re: supplies, October-November 1846</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.03.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract>Bowen family papers (MS006)
 
 Series II, Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1845-1969, undated (bulk: 1845-1851) (#6.25-6.27, 8.1-8.17, OB.1.4-OB.1.5), contains agreements and contracts (includes drafts); bills and receipts; building and construction specifications; correspondence; design and floor plans; drafts of checks; work account records; photographs; clippings; and a collection of papers describing the rooms at Roseland Cottage. The series is divided into three sections: contracts and specifications, financial records, and other materials. Contracts and specifications includes two drafts and a signed agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen and contractor, Samuel Underwood, regarding the furnishing of materials for construction of Roseland Cottage and an adjoining barn; specifications of architect, John C. Wells, for the carpentry and masonry work at Roseland Cottage and for the construction of the barn; and design and floor plans for the addition to the barn. The correspondence contains letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen relating to the construction work on Roseland Cottage. Several of the letters are from contractor, Samuel Underwood, requesting to be released from his contract; and other letters are from contractor, Edwin Eaton, detailing the work progress on the construction of Roseland Cottage and his decision to hire a Mr. Taylor of Brooklyn, New York, to complete the masonry work and a Mr. Joy of Worcester, Massachusetts, as foreman. The financial records include bills and receipts; drafts of checks; and work account records regarding the payment of laborers and the purchase of supplies associated with the construction of Roseland Cottage; the records were kept by Henry Chandler Bowen, Lewis Chamberlin, and Edwin Eaton. A collection of papers referred to as &amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; describing the interior furnishings and rooms at Roseland Cottage, as recalled by Anna Mellon; photographs of a collection of paintin gs at Roseland Cottage (includes several photographs of Benjamin Franklin); and newspaper clippings relating to Roseland Cottage and its inhabitants, comprise the section of other materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by section, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bills and receipts re: Joseph C. Wells, architect, November 20, 1846 and July 12, 1850</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.03.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846-1850</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract>Bowen family papers (MS006)
 
 Series II, Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1845-1969, undated (bulk: 1845-1851) (#6.25-6.27, 8.1-8.17, OB.1.4-OB.1.5), contains agreements and contracts (includes drafts); bills and receipts; building and construction specifications; correspondence; design and floor plans; drafts of checks; work account records; photographs; clippings; and a collection of papers describing the rooms at Roseland Cottage. The series is divided into three sections: contracts and specifications, financial records, and other materials. Contracts and specifications includes two drafts and a signed agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen and contractor, Samuel Underwood, regarding the furnishing of materials for construction of Roseland Cottage and an adjoining barn; specifications of architect, John C. Wells, for the carpentry and masonry work at Roseland Cottage and for the construction of the barn; and design and floor plans for the addition to the barn. The correspondence contains letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen relating to the construction work on Roseland Cottage. Several of the letters are from contractor, Samuel Underwood, requesting to be released from his contract; and other letters are from contractor, Edwin Eaton, detailing the work progress on the construction of Roseland Cottage and his decision to hire a Mr. Taylor of Brooklyn, New York, to complete the masonry work and a Mr. Joy of Worcester, Massachusetts, as foreman. The financial records include bills and receipts; drafts of checks; and work account records regarding the payment of laborers and the purchase of supplies associated with the construction of Roseland Cottage; the records were kept by Henry Chandler Bowen, Lewis Chamberlin, and Edwin Eaton. A collection of papers referred to as &amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; describing the interior furnishings and rooms at Roseland Cottage, as recalled by Anna Mellon; photographs of a collection of paintin gs at Roseland Cottage (includes several photographs of Benjamin Franklin); and newspaper clippings relating to Roseland Cottage and its inhabitants, comprise the section of other materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by section, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other bills and receipts, November 1846 - September 1850; includes payment receipts re: Lewis Chamberlin and Edwin Eaton, contractor</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.03.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846-1850</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract>Bowen family papers (MS006)
 
 Series II, Papers relating to the construction of Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1845-1969, undated (bulk: 1845-1851) (#6.25-6.27, 8.1-8.17, OB.1.4-OB.1.5), contains agreements and contracts (includes drafts); bills and receipts; building and construction specifications; correspondence; design and floor plans; drafts of checks; work account records; photographs; clippings; and a collection of papers describing the rooms at Roseland Cottage. The series is divided into three sections: contracts and specifications, financial records, and other materials. Contracts and specifications includes two drafts and a signed agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen and contractor, Samuel Underwood, regarding the furnishing of materials for construction of Roseland Cottage and an adjoining barn; specifications of architect, John C. Wells, for the carpentry and masonry work at Roseland Cottage and for the construction of the barn; and design and floor plans for the addition to the barn. The correspondence contains letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen relating to the construction work on Roseland Cottage. Several of the letters are from contractor, Samuel Underwood, requesting to be released from his contract; and other letters are from contractor, Edwin Eaton, detailing the work progress on the construction of Roseland Cottage and his decision to hire a Mr. Taylor of Brooklyn, New York, to complete the masonry work and a Mr. Joy of Worcester, Massachusetts, as foreman. The financial records include bills and receipts; drafts of checks; and work account records regarding the payment of laborers and the purchase of supplies associated with the construction of Roseland Cottage; the records were kept by Henry Chandler Bowen, Lewis Chamberlin, and Edwin Eaton. A collection of papers referred to as &amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; describing the interior furnishings and rooms at Roseland Cottage, as recalled by Anna Mellon; photographs of a collection of paintin gs at Roseland Cottage (includes several photographs of Benjamin Franklin); and newspaper clippings relating to Roseland Cottage and its inhabitants, comprise the section of other materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by section, and thereunder chronologically.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Contracts and specifications</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.08</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Business records (1 file box, 1 oversize folder)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Agreement between Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896) and Samuel Underwood re: construction of a house and barn, October 13; includes typewritten copy and draft [2 copies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.08.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 25</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #6.26 for items removed [specifications]</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Specifications of Joseph Collins Wells (1814-1860), re: carpentry [2 copies] and masonry work on the house</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.08.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, Folder 26</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Items removed from #6.25.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Specifications of Joseph Collins Wells (1814-1860), re: construction of the barn</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.08.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <container>Box 6, folder 27</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Site plans for addition to the barn [photocopies]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.08.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box OB.3, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Correspondence: letters received by Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896) re: construction progress on the house, November-May</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.09</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845-1848</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 15</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Contains oversize material.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Financial records of Henry Chandler Bowen</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.10</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845-1851</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Financial records (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Work accounts re: laborers, September-November; includes Lewis Chamberlin's work account</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.10.01</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bills and receipts re: supplies, October-November</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.10.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bills and receipts re: architect, Joseph Collins Wells (1814-1860), November 20 and July 12</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.10.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846-1850</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other bills and receipts, November-September; includes payment receipts re: Lewis Chamberlin and Edwin Eaton</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.10.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846-1850</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Financial records of Lewis Chamberlin</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.11</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845-1846</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Financial records (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other bills and receipts re: supply purchases and laborer payments, September-November</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.11.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1845</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Work accounts re: payment of laborers, May 30</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.11.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Financial papers of Edwin Eaton</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.12</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846-1847</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Financial records (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bills and receipts re: shipping, February-November</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.12.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Drafts of checks to laborers, February-December</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.12.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bills and receipts re: supply purchases for hardware, nails, screws, and lumber, April-July</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.12.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Work accounts re: payment of laborers, April-May</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.12.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846-1847</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 10</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other bills and receipts, June-September</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.12.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 11</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Work accounts re: bills submitted by laborers, September</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.12.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 12</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Work accounts re: payment of board by laborers, September-December</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.12.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 13</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Financial records, other: other bills and receipts re: construction of house</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.13</unitid>
 <unitdate>1847</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 14</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other materials</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.14</unitid>
 <unitdate>1938-1969, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Family papers (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Clippings re: life at Roseland Cottage</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.14.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1938-1969</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 15</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>&amp;quot;Reminiscences of Roseland Cottage,&amp;quot; memories of Roseland Cottage as recalled by Anna Mellon</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.14.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 16</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photographs of the paintings at Roseland Cottage</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.02.14.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 17</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 </c01>
 <c01>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photographic material of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1860-1965, undated, predominant 1860-1935</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Photographic materials (5 file boxes, 1 folio box, 1 multi-purpose box, 1 oversize folder)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Series III, Photographic material of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut, 1860-1965, undated (bulk, 1860-1935) (#8.18-12.14, FB.2.1, MB.1.1-MB.1.2, OB.3.9), contains portraits and group photographs; black and white photographs; color photographs; cabinet photographs; carte de visite; a mounted photograph; a hand-tinted and retouched photograph; a wood cut-out; tintypes; three photograph albums; and related letters. The series is arranged in four subseries.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-302; HGO-02-105-A-E-101; HGO-02-105-A-E-106</container>
 </did>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photographs: portraits</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1862-1935, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Photographs (3 file boxes, 1 oversize folder)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries A, Photographs: portraits, 1862-1935, undated (#8.18-10.12, OB.3.9), contains black and white photographs and color photographs of individual members of the Bowen family and friends of the family; a mounted photograph (#8.29) and hand-tinted, retouched photograph (#8.25) of Henry Chandler Bowen (1813-1896); and a wood cut-out (possibly of George Chandler Holt, 1843-1931) (#8.30) of an unidentified Bowen family member. Also included in the subseries is an 1897 photograph of Herbert Wolcott Bowen (1856-1927) after his appointment as U.S. Consulate-General in Barcelona, Spain (#8.27); an undated photograph of Grace Aspinwall (Bowen) Hardy (1850-1940) with her doll, Lena Rivers, which is held by Historic New England (#9.7); an undated photograph of orator Henry Ward Beecher (1813-1887) (#8.19); a 1935 signed photograph of a Wilfred Grenfell (#9.5); an signed photograph of an Edward Thayer Monroe (#10.3); and an photograph of the Bowen family nurse, Jane S. Stuart (d. 1916) (#10.8). Additionally, the subseries contains a 1949 photograph taken by the U.S. Navy of Hamilton Holt (1872-1951), Governor Fuller Warren (1905-1973), and President Harry S Truman (U.S. President, 1945-1953), while attending an educators meeting in Florida on March 8 and an undated clipping with a photograph of Hamilton Holt (1872-1951), President Franklin Delano Roosevelt (U.S. President, 1933-1945), and First Lady (Anna) Eleanor Roosevelt (1884-1962) at Rollins College in Winter Park, Florida, (#9.11). The subseries is arranged alphabetically by surname; when applicable, women are identified by married name.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-302; HGO-02-105-A-E-106</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Barney, Susan E. (Tappan) (dates unknown) [4 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1887, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 18</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Beecher, Henry Ward (1813-1887) [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 19</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Clarence Winthrop (1852-1935) [5 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1901, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 20</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See also #11.10 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Edward Augustus (1847-1926) [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1871-1872, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 21</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Ellen (Holt) (1834-1903) [4 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1884, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 22</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Francis (dates unknown) [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 29</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Franklin Davis (1860-1940) [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 23</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, George (1789-1846) [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.08</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 24</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Henry Chandler (1813-1896) [5 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.09</unitid>
 <unitdate>1891-1893, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 25</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Henry Chandler Bowen, hand-tinted and retouched photograph removed from #8.30</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Henry Chandler (1813-1896), mounted photograph [1photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.10</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 30</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #8.25 for item removed [hand-tinted and retouched photograph]</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Henry Elliot (1845-1919) [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.11</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 26</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Herbert Wolcott (1856-1927), U.S. Consulate-General, Barcelona, Spain, October 15 [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.12</unitid>
 <unitdate>1897</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 27</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, John Eliot (1858-1890) [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.13</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 8, Folder 28</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Lucy Maria (Tappan) (1825-1863) [4 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.14</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Lydia Wolcott (Eaton) (1793-1864) [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.15</unitid>
 <unitdate>1862</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Paul Holt (1868-1895) [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.16</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Roxana Atwater (Wentworth) (1854-1935) [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.17</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Grenfell, Wilfred (dates unknown); includes signature [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.18</unitid>
 <unitdate>1935</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Hardy, Arthur Sherburne (1847-1930) [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.19</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Hardy, Grace Aspinwall (Bowen) (1850-1940): holding doll, Lena Rivers [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.20</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See SPNEA textiles and household objects collection #2000.440, Museum Collection, for Grace Aspenwall's doll, Lena Rivers</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Constance (1879-1968) [1 of 2] [6 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.21</unitid>
 <unitdate>1883-1905, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Constance (1879-1968) [2 of 2] [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.22</unitid>
 <unitdate>1883-1905, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Group photograph with Constance Holt, undated, removed from #11.1</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, George Chandler (1843-1931) [5 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.23</unitid>
 <unitdate>1895, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 10</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>[Possibly Holt, George Chandler (1843-1931)], wood cut-out</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.23a</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box OB.3, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Item removed from #10.12</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Hamilton (1872-1951); includes 1949 U.S. Navy photograph and undated clipping [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.24</unitid>
 <unitdate>1949, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 11</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Henry Chandler (1881-1955) [10 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.25</unitid>
 <unitdate>1885-1897, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 12</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Mary Louisa (Bowen) (1848-1925) [1 of 2] [9 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.26</unitid>
 <unitdate>1867-1887, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 13</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Mary Louisa (Bowen) (1848-1925) [2 of 2] [4 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.27</unitid>
 <unitdate>1867-1887, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 14</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Stuart (1876-1900) [1 of 2] [6 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.28</unitid>
 <unitdate>1877-1898, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 15</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Stuart (1876-1900) [2 of 2] [7 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.29</unitid>
 <unitdate>1877-1898, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 9, Folder 16</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Sylvia (1889-1945) [1 of 2] [8 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.31</unitid>
 <unitdate>1893-1901, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Sylvia (1889-1945) [2 of 2] [6 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.32</unitid>
 <unitdate>1893-1901, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Monroe, Edward Thayer (dates unknown); includes signature [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.33</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Reed, Grace (Holt) (1874-1937) [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.34</unitid>
 <unitdate>1888-1921</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Photograph of Grace (Holt) Reed, ca.1903, removed from #11.1</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Richardson, Alice Linden (Bowen) (1854-1948) [2 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.35</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Richardson, Gardner (1884-1972) [5 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.36</unitid>
 <unitdate>1888-1899, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Richardson, Rufus Byam (1845-1914) [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.37</unitid>
 <unitdate>1904</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Stuart, Jane S. (d. 1916), nurse [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.38</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Item removed from #10.12</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Tappan, Arthur (1786-1865) [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.39</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Tappan, Charles (dates unknown) [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.40</unitid>
 <unitdate>1874</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 10</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Tappan, Lewis (1788-1873) [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.41</unitid>
 <unitdate>1838, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 11</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Unidentified [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.01.42</unitid>
 <unitdate>1866, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 12</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #10.8 and OB.3.9 for items removed</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photographs: groups</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1866-1965, undated, predominant 1886-1898</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Photographs (2 file boxes)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries B, Photographs: groups, 1866-1965, undated (bulk, 1886-1898) (#10.13-10.31, 11.1-11.14), contains black and white photographs, color photographs, and related letters. The subseries includes group photographs of the Bowen family with such acquaintances as orator Henry Ward Beecher (1813-1887) (#10.13); author Harriet Beecher Stowe (1811-1896) (#10.13); and family nurse, Henrietta (#10.28). Also included in the subseries are photographs of Roseland Park and Roseland Cottage in Woodstock, Connecticut; events at the Bowen family house located at 90 Willow Street in Brooklyn, New York; two undated hunting party photographs taken by Nellie Chandler (dates unknown) at Roseland Park in Woodstock, Connecticut (#11.6); Herbert Wolcott Bowen's (1856-1927) house in Woodstock, Connecticut (#11.14); and the Aspinwall houses in Brookline, Massachusetts (#11.11). Additionally, the subseries contains photographs of several Fourth of July celebrations held at Roseland Cottage, which include group photographs with President Benjamin Harrison (U.S. President, 1889-1893) (#11.1-11.2); President William McKinley (U.S. President, 1897-1901) (#11.3, 11.9); and Julia Ward Howe (1819-1910) (#10.31), author of the &amp;quot;Battle Hymn of the Republic.&amp;quot; An 1886 photograph of Clarence Winthrop Bowen (1852-1935) delivering an Independence Day address in Roseland Park (#11.10), and photographs of the U.S. flag flown out front of Roseland Cottage during the Independence Day celebrations (#11.14) are also included in the Fourth of July celebration photographs. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by surname, followed by general Bowen family photographs, and then by other photographs; when applicable, women are identified by married name.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-302</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Beecher, Henry Ward and Harriet Beecher Stowe [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 13</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Clarence Winthrop; Fanny Chandler; Alice Linden (Bowen) Richardson; and others; includes letter from Fanny Chandler [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1866-1937</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 14</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Clarence Winthrop; and Alice Linden (Bowen) Richardson [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 15</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Clarence Winthrop; Edward Augustus Bowen; Grace Aspinwall (Bowen) Hardy; and Evelyn Stoddard [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, folder 16</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See also #FB.2.1 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Ellen (Holt) and Paul Holt Bowen [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1888</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 17</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Franklin Davis; Herbert Wolcott Bowen; and John Eliot Bowen [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>1866</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 18</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Henry Chandler; Lucy Maria (Tappan) Bowen; and Henry Elliot Bowen [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 19</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Lucy Maria (Tappan) and Franklin Davis Bowen [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.08</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, folder 20</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Paul Holt and George McClellan [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.09</unitid>
 <unitdate>1886-1889</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 21</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Alexina C. and John Eliot Holt [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.10</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 22</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Constance; Grace Holt; and Sylvia Holt [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.11</unitid>
 <unitdate>1894</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 23</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, George Chandler and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt: at home in Spuyten Duyvil, New York [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.12</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 24</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Hamilton and Grace (Holt) Reed [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.13</unitid>
 <unitdate>1877</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 25</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Henry Chandler and Sylvia Holt [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.14</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 26</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Mary Louisa (Bowen) and Sylvia Holt [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.15</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 27</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Sylvia Holt and nurse, Henrietta [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.16</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 28</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Reed, Grace (Holt) and Lucy Richardson [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.17</unitid>
 <unitdate>1897</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 29</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Vereker, Roxanna Wentworth (Bowen) (born 1895) and Gordon Vereker; includes letter [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.18</unitid>
 <unitdate>1949</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 30</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: Christmas at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York; includes Julia Ward Howe [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.19</unitid>
 <unitdate>1887, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 10, Folder 31</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #11.1 and 11.3 for items removed</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes U.S. President Benjamin Harrison [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.20</unitid>
 <unitdate>1887-1889</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Items removed from #10.31.
 NOTE: See #11.14 for related material.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes U.S. President Benjamin Harrison [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.21</unitid>
 <unitdate>1889</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #11.14 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes U.S. President William McKinley [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.22</unitid>
 <unitdate>1891-1892</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Items removed from #10.31.
 NOTE: See #11.9 and 11.14 for related material.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.23</unitid>
 <unitdate>1893, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #11.14 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.24</unitid>
 <unitdate>1898</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: hunting party at Roseland Park, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes Nellie Chandler photographs [3 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.25</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #11.8 for item removed</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: hunting party at Roseland Park, Woodstock, Connecticut [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.26</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: picnic at Roseland Park, Woodstock, Connecticut [1 photograph]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.27</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: Item removed from #11.6 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen family: tea at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York; includes U.S. President William McKinley at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [2 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.28</unitid>
 <unitdate>1891, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #11.3 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Unidentified; includes Clarence Winthrop Bowen (1852-1935), Centennial address [10 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.29</unitid>
 <unitdate>1890-1965</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 10</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #8.20 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other photographs: William Aspinwall house on Washington Street, Brookline, Massachusetts, southwest view; includes Peter Aspinwall house, Brookline, Massachusetts [4 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.30</unitid>
 <unitdate>1867, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 11</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other photographs: Bowen family residence at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York [1 of 2] [4 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.31</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 12</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other photographs: Bowen family residence at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York [2 of 2] [8 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.32</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 13</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Other photographs: Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes U.S. flag and Herbert Wolcott Bowen house, Woodstock, Connecticut [15 photographs]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.02.33</unitid>
 <unitdate>1952-1959, undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 11, Folder 14</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See #11.1-11.4 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Tintypes</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1872-1875, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Tintypes (1 file box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries C, Tintypes, 1872-1875, undated (#12.1-12.14), contains tintypes of Bowen family members and is divided into two categories: portraits and groups. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by surname, first by portraits, then by groups; when applicable, women are identified by married name.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-302</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Portraits</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1872-1873, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Tintypes (5 folders)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Barney, Susan E. (Tappan) (dates unknown) [2 items]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.01.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Clarence Winthrop (1852-1935) [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.01.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Hamilton (1872-1951) [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.01.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1872-1873</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 3</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Mary Louisa (Bowen) (1848-1925) [5 items]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.01.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 4</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Hulett, [Don A. or Lewis Tappan] [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.01.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 5</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Groups</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1872-1875, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Tintypes (9 folders)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Barney, Susan E. (Tappan) and family [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 6</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Clarence Winthrop; Edward Augustus Bowen; [Henry Elliot Bowen or George Chandler Holt] [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 7</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Bowen, Edward Augustus; Grace Aspinwall (Bowen) Hardy; Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt; and Alice L. (Bowen) Richardson [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 8</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Hardy, Grace Aspinwall (Bowen); Hamilton Holt; and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt [2 items]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1872-1873</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 9</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, George Chandler and Hamilton Holt [2 items]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1872-1873</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Foler 10</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, George Chandler; Hamilton Holt; and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 11</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, George Chandler and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt [2 items]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.07</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 12</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Holt, Hamilton and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.08</unitid>
 <unitdate>1872-1873</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 13</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 <c04>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Hulett, Margaret and J.A. Tappan [1 item]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.03.02.09</unitid>
 <unitdate>1875</unitdate>
 <container>Box 12, Folder 14</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c04>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photograph albums</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.04</unitid>
 <unitdate>1860-1880, undated</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Photograph albums (1 folio box, 1 multi-purpose box)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Subseries D, Photograph albums, 1860-1881, undated (#FB.2.1, MB.1.1-MB.1.2), contains three photograph albums. The Bowen, Barney, and Holt family album (#FB.2.1) is comprised of approximately one hundred black and white cabinet size and carte de visite photographs. The album contains photographs of Bowen family members, friends, and celebrities (including military heroes such as U.S. Generals John Charles Fremont, 1813-1890 and Winfield Scott, 1786-1866; and a collage of U.S. Generals: Anderson, Banks, Butler, Dix, Fremont, Lyon, McClellan, Scott, and Wool). Also included are a photograph of Edward Augustus Bowen's (1847-1926) horse, Ruby; Hiram Barney's (dates unknown) house, Cedar Knolls, located at Spuyten Duyvil, New York; and friends of Edward A. Barney (dates unknown) from the Eastman School in Poughkeepsie, New York (including a group playing polo). The Bowen, Barney, and Tappan family album (#MB.1.1) is comprised of approximately thirty-nine black and white carte de visite photographs. The album contains portraits of Bowen family members, Bowen friends, and celebrities. Also included is a photograph of the Bowen family governess, Edna Dean Proctor (1829-1923); a photograph of Grace Aspinwall (Bowen) Hardy (1850-1940) with her doll, Lena Rivers, which is held by Historic New England; carte de visite photographs of poet Elizabeth Barrett Browning (1806-1861); a cartoon of a child receiving a haircut; and a carte de visite of &amp;quot;Mother and Child&amp;quot; with the poem &amp;quot;Motherless Child&amp;quot; by John Greenleaf Whittier (1807-1892). The Holt family album (#MB.1.2) is comprised of approximately twenty-six black and white carte de visite photographs. The album contains portraits of Holt family members; most are of children. Also included is an 1877 photograph of Grace (Holt) Reed (1874-1937) with several of her dolls taken on February 8.</abstract>
 <container>HGO-02-105-A-E-101</container>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Album: Bowen, Barney, and Holt families [100 items]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.04.01</unitid>
 <unitdate>1860-1880</unitdate>
 <container>Box FB.2, Item 1</container>
 <abstract>NOTE: See also #10.16 for related material</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Album: Bowen, Barney, and Tappan families [39 items]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.04.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 <container>Box MB.1, Item 1</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Album: Holt family [26 items]</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.04.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>1873-1877</unitdate>
 <container>Box MB.1, Item 2</container>
 <abstract/>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photographs on paper, portraits</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.12.01</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>26 folders (82 items)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>The majority of this series is comprised of portraits of members of the Bowen, Holt, Richardson, and Tappan families, in addition to a small number of unknown or unrelated persons. Most of these photographs are undated.</abstract>
 <container/>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photographs on paper, groups, 1846-1965</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.12.02</unitid>
 <unitdate>1846-1965</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>15 folders (32 items)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>This series includes group portraits of members of the Bowen and Holt families, as well as some unknown or unrelated persons. Most of these photographs are undated.</abstract>
 <container/>
 </did>
 <c03>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Group portrait of seven men, seated, facing front, on the porch, Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1892</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.12.02.003</unitid>
 <unitdate>1892</unitdate>
 <container/>
 <abstract>The men are identified on the verso as: Senator Platt, Attorney General Miller, Secretary Tracy, Elliott F. Shepard, Senator Frye, J.P. Morgan, Commissioner for the Indians, Henry Chandler Bowen.</abstract>
 </did>
 </c03>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photographs on paper, architecture, 1855</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.12.03</unitid>
 <unitdate>ca. 1855</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>2 folders (6 items)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>This series includes photographs of the Aspinwall House and Roseland Cottage. These photographs are undated.</abstract>
 <container/>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Photographs on paper, scenery</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.12.04</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>0 items</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Tintypes, portraits, 1850-1900</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.12.05</unitid>
 <unitdate>1850-1900</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>5 folders (10 items)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>This series includes tintypes of members of the Tappan, Bowen, and Holt families. These photographs are undated.</abstract>
 <container/>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Tintypes, groups, 1870-1900</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.12.06</unitid>
 <unitdate>1870-1900</unitdate>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>9 folders (12 items)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>This series includes tintypes of members of the Tappan, Bowen, and Holt families photographed in groups. Most of these photographs are undated.</abstract>
 <container/>
 </did>
 </c02>
 <c02>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Miscellany, undated</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.03.12.07</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>4 folders (approx. 20 items)</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>This series includes Anna Mellon's recollections of the interior furnishings of the rooms at Roseland Cottage, newspaper clippings related to Roseland Cottage and its residents, photographs of paintings at Roseland Cottage and miscellaneous bills related to its construction.</abstract>
 <container/>
 </did>
 </c02>
 </c01>
 <c01>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Additional papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.04</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <physdesc>
 <extent>Family papers: 4.25 linear ft. - unprocessed (3 cartons, 3 file boxes), plus 1 folio box, and 1 oversize box</extent>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract>Series IV, Additional papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut (unprocessed), contains material purchased by Historic New England from Hamilton Holt (1872-1951) in 2005, which will be processed at a later date.</abstract>
 <container/>
 </did>
 </c01>
 <c01>
 <did>
 <unittitle>Temporary</unittitle>
 <unitid>MS006.TMP</unitid>
 <unitdate/>
 <physdesc>
 <extent/>
 </physdesc>
 <abstract/>
 <container/>
 </did>
 </c01>
 </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>
