<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="wcsu_as.xsl"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-ctdabn" url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/anderson.xml">anderson</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Marian Anderson Collection<num>MS 068</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections</publisher><address><addressline>Haas Library</addressline><addressline>181 White St</addressline><addressline>Danbury 06810</addressline><addressline>stevensb@wcsu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-01-17 17:32:21 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Marian Anderson Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>MS 068</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1937/1950" type="inclusive">1937-1980</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f18ad3a3edd05aa63ec7813c41aea05b">This is a small collection of Marian Anderson memorabilia. Anderson was a world-renowned contralto in the 20th century and a long-time resident of Danbury, CT.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_4be36ebf145f030d24cbe187f0f18f36">English</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_05ef357de4c5ea3fa6a76ec5366bd1a3">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This Collection is arranged chronologically by material type</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Series</head>
      <item>Programs</item>
      <item>Photographs</item>
      <item>Phonographic Recordings</item>
    </list>
  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e9c9a3a9078cc6c987a608cf50e231bd">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Collection is open for research without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_be530cd3636718caed6dd7235e979b06">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the Ruth A. Haas Library Archives and Special Collections. E-mail: stevensb@wcsu.edu</p>  </userestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_09bb3e2d7776c3e87e4da6119734811a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains concert and tour programs from Marian Anderson's performances, publicity photographs, and original phonographic recordings (including 78 RPMs), focusing on the years of 1935-1965. Also included are several books about Marion Anderson, including her autobiography.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b96cf8ba44cdcc6eaa97b72ca8c35686">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Marian Anderson (1897-1993) was a contralto widely held to be one of the twentieth century's greatest singers and a civil rights advocate. She was originally from Philadelphia who started singing in choir. After high school, Anderson applied to an all-white music school, the Philadelphia Music Academy, but was rejected because of her race. In 1925 Anderson won first prize in a competition sponsored by the New York Philharmonic which provided her an opportunity to perform in concert with that orchestra. Anderson's performance was very well received and launched her professional career. New York became her home over the next several years. Because of the career limitations posed by racial bigotry in her own country, Anderson performed in Europe in 1930, achieving significant success which she was able to capitalize on when returning to the U.S. in the middle 1930s. She met her long-time manager, Sol Hurok, in 1935. In 1939, the Daughters of the American Revolution refused to allow Anderson to sing at Constitution Hall; the uproar from civil rights groups and others resulted in Anderson's famous performance to 75,000 people at the Lincoln Memorial. The 1930s also saw the beginning of her long recording association with RCA/Victor Records. Her preferred accompanist for much of her career was pianist Franz Rupp. In 1943, Anderson married Orpheus Fischer in Connecticut and lived in the Mill Plain area of Danbury at 'Mariana Farm.' She was active in the community and frequently performed at Danbury High School and at civic events. In 1993, Anderson died in Portland, Oregon, with family at the age of 96.</p><p>Basic Chronology of Anderson's career:</p><p>1922 (Columbus Ohio) Marian Anderson sang at the meeting of the National Association of Negro Musicians, where she received the Association's scholarship for the year.</p><p>10 December 1923 (Camden, NJ) Anderson made her first record for Victor Talking Records</p><p>23 April 1924 (New York City Town Hall) Anderson gave a recital that was poorly attended and for which she received some negative reviews. Anderson realized that she hadn't been properly prepared and considered giving up music for a time </p><p>1925 Anderson entered a voice competition, against more than 300 other singers, where she won the first prize - which included a performance with the New York Philharmonic Orchestra in Lewisohn Stadium on 26 August 1925.</p><p>October 1927 Anderson made her first trip to England to study German lieder with Maestro Raymond Muehlen in Sussex.</p><p>September 1928 Anderson returned to the United States for scheduled performances</p><p>1928 Anderson  recorded for Gramophone, Inc. (later EMI Records) in England, (it appears that she did not sign a formal contract with RCA Victor in the United States until sometime in the 1930s; the earliest account and royalty statements in the Marian Anderson Papers date from 1936).</p><p>1930 Anderson  went to Germany to for more training</p><p>1931 Anderson was invited to Sweden and Norway for a concert tour, which, though short, proved to be successful. </p><p>6 November 1933 Anderson sang for composer Jean Sibelius. </p><p>December 1933 Anderson was told abruptly that she would not be allowed to continue her scheduled concerts in Denmark, with the reason that "foreign artists" were taking too much currency out of the country, however the underlying reason was racism propagated by the Nazi party. </p><p>1934 Anderson made her Paris debut. At one of her concerts in Paris that summer she was heard by concert manager Sol Hurok of New York.</p><p>15 July 1934 Anderson signs with Hurok. </p><p>1934-1935 Anderson toured Europe with great success. She visited eastern European capitals and Russia and returned again to Scandinavia, where "Marian fever" had spread.</p><p>December 1935 Anderson returned to the United States </p><p>19 February 1936, after concerts at Town Hall in New York and at the Academy of Music in Philadelphia, Anderson performed for the first time at the White House. </p><p>1936 Anderson returned again to Europe for the winter season. </p><p>1937 and 1938 Anderson toured South America </p><p>January 1939 Sol Hurok attempted to book Anderson in concert at Constitution Hall in Washington, D.C.</p><p>9 April 1939 Anderson gives an open-air concert in front of the Lincoln
Memorial on Easter, arranged through Secretary of the Interior Harold Ickes. More than 75, 000 people heard her sing in person there, and millions more heard her voice in a radio broadcast of the event.</p><p>June 1939 Anderson was again a guest at the Roosevelt White House, this time at a formal concert for the King and Queen of England. </p><p>2 July 1939, Eleanor Roosevelt presented Marian Anderson with the Spingarn Medal of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.</p><p>October 1940 Anderson began performing with pianist Franz Rupp, who remained with her for the duration of her career. </p><p>1940 Anderson buys a farm in Danbury, Connecticut. </p><p>1941 Anderson received the Philadelphia Award in 1941, which included a $10, 000 prize, money that Anderson used to establish the Marian Anderson Scholarship Fund to assist the vocal training of young singers. </p><p>1941-1945 During WWII Anderson performed for servicemen and women and cooperated with the U.S. Office of War Information. </p><p>24 July 1943 Anderson married architect Orpheus Hodge Fisher, in a private ceremony performed by Methodist minister Jack Grenfell. </p><p>1943 The first award from Anderson's fund was given, and continued annually through 1972, when the fund was discontinued. Anderson had no role in judging the awards. </p><p>June 1948 Anderson underwent surgery to remove a benign cyst from her esophagus. </p><p>1949 Anderson returned to Europe for a concert tour</p><p>January 1955 Anderson was invited by Rudolf Bing of the Metropolitan Opera to perform the role of Ulrica in Giuseppe Verdi's Un Ballo in Maschera. Anderson was the first African-American to sing a role in a Met production</p><p>1955  Anderson toured Israel for the first time </p><p>January 1957 Anderson sang at the inauguration of President Dwight W. Eisenhower </p><p>1957 Anderson was sent on a tour of the Far East as a goodwill ambassador by the United States Department of State. On this tour she visited Japan, Korea, the Philippines, Thailand, India, and Pakistan. </p><p>30 December 1957 A documentary of Anderson's goodwill trip was aired on CBS's "See it Now" television series.  </p><p>July 1958 Eisenhower appointed Anderson an alternate delegate to the General Assembly of the United Nations where she served for one session.</p><p>April 1959 Anderson was appointed by Eisenhower to consult on original plans for the National Cultural Center, later renamed the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts. </p><p>20 January 1961 Anderson sang for the inauguration of President John F. Kennedy. </p><p>6 December 1963 Anderson was awarded a Presidential Medals of Freedom by President Johnson, though she had been nominated for the award by President Kennedy. </p><p>21 to 28 May 1961 Anderson visited the Soviet Union as a member of the Second Informal United States-Soviet Conference held in Crimea.
October 1964 through April 1965 was Anderson's farewell tour. It began in Constitution Hall in Washington, D.C., and ended on the stage of Carnegie Hall in New York.</p><p>28 June 1965 Anderson performanced in Philadelphia at the Robin Hood Dell with her nephew James De Preist conducting the Robin Hood Dell Orchestra.</p><p>1966 Anderson was appointed a member of the National Council on the Arts by President Johnson</p><p>2 May 1972 Anderson spoke at the dedication ceremonies of the Eleanor Roosevelt Wings of the Franklin D. Roosevelt Library at Hyde Park, New York. </p><p>1976 Anderson received many requests to perform at celebrations for the Bicentennial of the Declaration, and most notably appeared at Philadelphia's fourth of July ceremonies. </p><p>17 October 1978 Anderson was presented with a Congressional Medal by President Jimmy Carter.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Opera--United States--20th century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Academy of Music (New York, N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans--Civil rights--History--20th century</subject>
    <persname rules="local" source="local">Anderson, Marian</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="library of congress name authority file">Hurok, Sol, 1888-1974</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="library of congress name authority file">Rupp, Franz, 1901-1992</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_58913e94950dc9a870fe5076044fe50d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_eb4ddf21817ccf378e41016fd73d3fc3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Signed Photographs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1950" type="inclusive">1930-1950s</unitdate><container altrender="Half Document Box, Legal Size" id="aspace_0053ece1da7464a09316d3c7988481bd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5514ca73b595bb6a651470aa0ba4cf1d" parent="aspace_0053ece1da7464a09316d3c7988481bd" type="folder">1</container><container id="aspace_6be1155a7ccebec79201326bec220f28" parent="aspace_5514ca73b595bb6a651470aa0ba4cf1d" type="item">1-2</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5219" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson, autographed snapshot" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson, autographed snapshot</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5221" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson, publicity photo 1950s" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson, publicity photo 1950s</p></daodesc></dao></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c456381180412006b98d0067eff9f1fb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publicity shots</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">1950-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Half Document Box, Legal Size" id="aspace_316882b5bb60b5d5bfe39f850c1f4fcb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_68f1d7bbf10190e68b9b82ae817b5ae5" parent="aspace_316882b5bb60b5d5bfe39f850c1f4fcb" type="folder">1</container><container id="aspace_284ba5c66bb705456867bb4ac0593c55" parent="aspace_68f1d7bbf10190e68b9b82ae817b5ae5" type="item">3-4</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5220" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson, publicity shot, 1944" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson, publicity shot, 1944</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5222" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson, publicity photo, ca. 1950" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson, publicity photo, ca. 1950</p></daodesc></dao></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_bf6b431cb09fe1312fbfc18936866ac4" level="Series"><did><unittitle>Programs/Fliers/Clippings/Books</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_ac050a5786a4643700a36f7054c6f183" level="file"><did><unittitle>Concert Programs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1976" type="inclusive">1935-1957, 1976</unitdate><container altrender="Half Document Box, Legal Size" id="aspace_80161036e0cfeed665c459f8c023cff9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a3e5cce42d75ccb9bb3b7d6bc0eaaadd" parent="aspace_80161036e0cfeed665c459f8c023cff9" type="folder">2</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5226" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson, Polteama Argentino" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson, Polteama Argentino</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5224" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson - A Greater Artist than Ever, program" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson - A Greater Artist than Ever, program</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5225" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson at Carnegie Hall, program" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson at Carnegie Hall, program</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5230" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson at the Forum, Harrisburg, PA" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson at the Forum, Harrisburg, PA</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5228" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Academy of Music, Philadelphia, Jan. 11, 1955 (with Autograph)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Academy of Music, Philadelphia, Jan. 11, 1955 (with Autograph)</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5227" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson at the Bushnell in Hartford, CT" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson at the Bushnell in Hartford, CT</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5229" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Ticket for the Danbury Bicentennial Concert" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Ticket for the Danbury Bicentennial Concert</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_790bb3f23d12480c9a559f28e8340b25"><head>General</head><p>Includes:
Carnegie Hall, New York City, March 9, 1935</p><p>Politeama Agentino, 1938</p><p>Academy of Music, New York City. Dec. 7, 1939</p><p>Carnegie Hall, New York City, Jan. 3, 1942</p><p>Academy of Music, Philadelphia, Jan. 12, 1942</p><p>The Forum, Harrisburg, PA, Oct. 8, 1946</p><p>Academy of Music, Philadelphia, Jan. 11, 1955 (with Autograph)</p><p>The Bushnell, Hartford, Feb. 19, 1957 </p><p>Ticket for the Danbury Bicentennial Concert, June 1976</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_dd3b369f15d8bcbb7cee73729c4cf6ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Musical America flier for Marian Anderson</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container altrender="Half Document Box, Legal Size" id="aspace_f0f64ac021fbd1ed8bccf460034cd99c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ca038ebc93fad88a1b4351ccfda972dd" parent="aspace_f0f64ac021fbd1ed8bccf460034cd99c" type="folder">2.1</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5223" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reigning Sensation, Musical America ad" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Reigning Sensation, Musical America ad</p></daodesc></dao></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8e7de8ca7c8cf43294102dfbd3678f53" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Decade of Song in America, Tour Program</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container altrender="Half Document Box, Legal Size" id="aspace_bef4d34622d1d6a5094ef28a815adb09" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7bfeb7eced9e1040a16fc45509d7990b" parent="aspace_bef4d34622d1d6a5094ef28a815adb09" type="folder">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3bdea45a58dbd7193e159e8e27a6d485" level="file"><did><unittitle>S. Hurok Presents Marian Anderson, Tour Program</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container altrender="Half Document Box, Legal Size" id="aspace_73a0aaa95a04e32620fa00080253c2be" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d1705fa19cb76a2f7e25975b6752a49d" parent="aspace_73a0aaa95a04e32620fa00080253c2be" type="folder">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_493deed66d64d904f6437759c55ee49d" level="file"><did><unittitle>My Lord, what a morning: an autobiography by Marian Anderson</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_8ca92e83cd0eaefc85a7e5751c3c51e5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_0c201ce24b43570d6d23ee1596ab5669" parent="aspace_8ca92e83cd0eaefc85a7e5751c3c51e5" type="item">10</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5246" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="My Lord, what a morning (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>My Lord, what a morning (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_5911975bedd34f78448cc258c760eff0"><head>General</head><p>1st Edition, Viking: New York.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_c699e63ec4346cd9b1de60fbc7a979fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marian Anderson related clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1997" type="inclusive">1959-1997</unitdate><container altrender="Half Document Box, Legal Size" id="aspace_3c4d5b581941cb58f3c781283c681d09" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_225092eb9e4d1fae1760f3c97ad17765" parent="aspace_3c4d5b581941cb58f3c781283c681d09" type="folder">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_a9892c9d84513accbf9c4223fe0b9d5b"><head>General</head><p>These are copies of clippings compiled by Truman Warner and assembled in this collection to convenience the researcher.  Most of the clippings are from the Danbury News-Times.</p></odd></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_054106798d0d8953703c5aaaa6904d24" level="Series"><did><unittitle>Phonograph Recordings</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_86438b262d87353d5cf3956c7ba7f47b" level="file"><did><unittitle>City Called Heaven b/w Lord I Can't Stay Away and Heaven, Heaven RCA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1940" type="inclusive">193-?</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_fdef063cb74c9764116beb1383bb561f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_7013f20ddb5a016392bdbeb327c61a98" parent="aspace_fdef063cb74c9764116beb1383bb561f" type="item">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_9bf09b6bb8e9af1f7743c7271654a9df"><head>General</head><p>12" 78 RPM</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_11df68563465e41bca5e4ef7d3a85662" level="file"><did><unittitle>Come, Sweet Death, b/w Siciliana RCA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_89c3fa8185f89613d685bd05549a751c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_250b392f4bdd2f4b8c3df7878b49fa0a" parent="aspace_89c3fa8185f89613d685bd05549a751c" type="item">2</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5231" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Come, Sweet Death, b/w Siciliana RCA" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Come, Sweet Death, b/w Siciliana RCA</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_5afb6eea39963e1d4b6660cc2a4cc26b"><head>General</head><p>10" 78 RPM</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_716fc9abe8b3835fc7ffa2bf28d7b268" level="file"><did><unittitle>Songs and Spirituals</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_8f6c3cad0269b0b4c008df5854199d84" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_c31c4871521a447761efe60a16df2a8c" parent="aspace_8f6c3cad0269b0b4c008df5854199d84" type="item">2.1</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5232" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Songs and Spirituals by Marian Anderson (Cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Songs and Spirituals by Marian Anderson (Cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_9c5f53d76e949bfa7f555f0b955518e5"><head>General</head><p>4, 10" 78 RPM discs</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_1b3cf0ccd72293afd43fa11b576d1465" level="file"><did><unittitle>Negro Spirituals, 33 1/3, 10 inch</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_2f3e66f10958006727141f693245f15f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_fb40cf423dcd247be2d36f609299c157" parent="aspace_2f3e66f10958006727141f693245f15f" type="item">2.2</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5233" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Negro Spirituals (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Negro Spirituals (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_060adfd337a0169e3013dafbdabfe042"><head>General</head><p>Nobody knows the trouble I see</p><p>Hear de lam's a-aryin'</p><p>My Lord, what a morining</p><p>Where you there?</p><p>On my journey</p><p>The gospel train</p><p>Soon-a-will be done</p><p>Sinner, please</p><p>Honor, honor</p><p>Ride on, king Jesus</p><p>French pressing (La Voix de Son Maitre)</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_2f91eecc899a94f924a592084bc871f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Negro Spirituals, 45 RPM, 7inch</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">circa 1950</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_b82ebe1cfbdac3c99a29baa5e31f5562" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_6115d148a9729aa93cd9c4b6f218c47e" parent="aspace_b82ebe1cfbdac3c99a29baa5e31f5562" type="item">2.3</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5234" xlink:role="audio-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson, Negro Spirituals (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson, Negro Spirituals (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_6e72a8f50937e90691d74234ee288097"><head>General</head><p>Sometimes I feel like a motherless child</p><p>Dere's no hidin' place down dere</p><p>Ev'ry time I feel de spirit</p><p>I know de Lord's laid His hands on me</p><p>Tramping</p><p>French pressing (La Voix de Son Maitre) with picture sleave.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_bab4a6487b949f11b4f3f33fbc141db8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Softly Awakes my Heart and other melodies, 45 RPM, 7 inch</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1955" type="inclusive">circa 1950</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_16da29cd91fc0a3990e7f3fea0b0ec22" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_db66c73c9d527e23d6b5072d2e8abe7a" parent="aspace_16da29cd91fc0a3990e7f3fea0b0ec22" type="item">2.4</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5235" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Softly Awakes my Heart and other melodies (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Softly Awakes my Heart and other melodies (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_98dd177e50505a4b829b49a5ac3c4b37"><head>General</head><p>Softly awakes my heart</p><p>I don't feel noways tired</p><p>Plaisir d'amour</p><p>Deep river</p><p>English pressing (EMI)</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_08a9c018944591b1b2d128fdff1266cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alto Rhapsody RCA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_edcd47a931ecb3250853139e26495a64" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_68dfbd1135964eb09c07378e57d369db" parent="aspace_edcd47a931ecb3250853139e26495a64" type="item">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_0f716e4d7637dee48d7d5e498a435fa6"><head>General</head><p>33 1/3" LP
Tracks: Alto Rhapsody; Kinder Toten Lieder</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_3a1c598d9d49c8cab142d2fde7d72cd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Beloved Schubert Songs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_d9d1765e84619f9a01103c9bcc6e25d5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_7882d03bdfe45609fb3ecf8534d01a89" parent="aspace_d9d1765e84619f9a01103c9bcc6e25d5" type="item">2.5</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5245" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson sings beloved Schubert songs (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson sings beloved Schubert songs (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_394cbeb6bb92c95e2c23b3486d1b2377"><head>General</head><p>10", 33 1/3 EP</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_29caaf39130fb71284896ba8ce6a32d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Great Spirituals RCA ERA-62</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">195-?</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_7c6f96ab5a956108b93a80431235bc52" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_17be3fdf5cab79ca286f8f45cae8fc6e" parent="aspace_7c6f96ab5a956108b93a80431235bc52" type="item">4</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5236" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Great Spirituals (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Great Spirituals (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_05d5cfcb2e417c4acaa7656327c678cf"><head>General</head><p>45RPM EP
Side 1: Nobody Knows the Touble I See, Hear de Lam's A-Cryin'
Side 2: Soon-A Will be Done, Where you There?</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_26ab907eeaa51a1bb363046fd5a738a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ave Maria and Other Shubert Songs RCA ERA-19</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">195-?</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_a2e42e19a5b73073b9d748e325e7fe08" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_28b3ecf76688b68b0504d58c887fb261" parent="aspace_a2e42e19a5b73073b9d748e325e7fe08" type="item">5</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5237" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Ave Maria (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Ave Maria (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_2300be412096efb204e8975f3c432d14"><head>General</head><p>45 RPM EP
Tracks: Ave Maria, Die Forelle, Wohin, Der Erlkonig,</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ef34e69909c0d8bd267133ff5196b21f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christmas Carols RCA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_33c1e957bfccbb06c9fba0ac9627ea0a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_c79ef910d3ee1ead20d54fad9b9c3520" parent="aspace_33c1e957bfccbb06c9fba0ac9627ea0a" type="item">6</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5238" xlink:role="Image-Service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Marian Anderson Christmas Carols (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marian Anderson Christmas Carols (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_e83b6457f2bf3c7b542fdb25602fca3c"><head>General</head><p>33 1/3" LP</p><p>Tracks: We Wish You a Merry Christmas; Silent Night; Deck the Halls; Angel's Song; The First Noel; Ave Maria; God Rest You Merry, Gentlemen; It Came Upon a Midnight Clear; Joy to the World!; O Sanctissima; Jingle Bells; Away in a Manger; The Twelve Days of Christmas</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc8f684eb4f17c9f6e2022802d12e4db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Snoopycat: the adventures of Marian Anderson's cat Snoopy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_ef9ee76e1e7765809d6edd17b678465b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_ef94bde35a8aabbe184cedb241ccd65e" parent="aspace_ef9ee76e1e7765809d6edd17b678465b" type="item">7</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5239" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Snoopycat (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Snoopycat (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9c68241d81b892decffa2ccdeac24335" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marian Anderson at Constitution Hall, Washington, D.C. Farewell Recital RCA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_ad93252eebcefd19441b61817f5d70b6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_9957c0ab58554537a3835f7b1c2423e7" parent="aspace_ad93252eebcefd19441b61817f5d70b6" type="item">8</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5240" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Farewell Recital at Constitution Hall (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Farewell Recital at Constitution Hall (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_6de7b74c40dc6f84536414513f76e074"><head>General</head><p>33 1/3" LP
Tracks: The Spirit Song; My Mother Bids Me Bind My Hair; Suleika; Liebesbotschaft; Der Doppelganger; Der Erlkonig; Blow, Blow Thou Winter Wind; The Plough Boy; Lew Us Break Bread Together; Oh! What a Beautiful City; Ride On, King Jesus; Done Foun' My Los' Sheep; Lord, I Can't Stay Away; He's Got the Whole World in His Hands; Ungeduld</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_cbc5fdb22634adfbb8cbe25dd5eb6fe2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Schubert and Brahms Lieder RCA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container altrender="Bound volume" id="aspace_74cabb99b7c1d8c2dfe6170fee58f522" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS 1</container><container id="aspace_eef97acab717ea49eb071b72654594bc" parent="aspace_74cabb99b7c1d8c2dfe6170fee58f522" type="item">9</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/omeka/items/show/5241" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Schubert and Brahms Lieder (cover)" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Schubert and Brahms Lieder (cover)</p></daodesc></dao></did><odd id="aspace_f06d78ef2913fb304f35e2c621508817"><head>General</head><p>33 1/3" LP</p><p>Tracks:
Liebesbotschaft, Ungeduld, Der Tod und das Madchen, Die Forelle, An die Musik, Suleika I, Gretchen am Spinnrade, Wiegenlied, Erlkonig, Heidenroslein, Von ewiger Liebe, Botschaft, Vergebliches Standchen, Der Schmied, Dein blaues Auge</p></odd></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
