<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="wcsu_as.xsl"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-ctdabn" url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/studentNewspapers.xml">studentNewspapers</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Student Newspapers Collection
Student newspaper publications of the Danbury Normal School, Danbury Teachers College, Danbury State Teachers College, Western Connecticut State College and Western Connecticut State University <num>RG 5.15.1</num></titleproper><author>Meg Moughan and Mary Rieke</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from Student Newspapers.doc</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections</publisher><address><addressline>Haas Library</addressline><addressline>181 White St</addressline><addressline>Danbury 06810</addressline><addressline>stevensb@wcsu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-02-01 13:23:31 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Student Newspapers Collection.</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="lcnaf">Western Connecticut State University</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG 5.15.1</unitid>
    <unitid audience="internal" identifier="147" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE">147</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">26 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">17 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1931/2002" type="inclusive">1931-2002</unitdate>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_674ecc9b99ab5fa5dc4e1725acaa5fdb">Ruth A. Haas Library</physloc>
    <abstract id="aspace_021cdcc6f6b0fcb98a8703b37e922568">The collection includes newspapers published by student through the history of Western Connecticut State University and its institutional antecedents.</abstract>
  </did>
  <custodhist id="aspace_acc6495fd2e35408c6641b2330f99b7d">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Ongoing transfer to the University Archives.</p>  </custodhist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_168732839035d7bbbc897fd24af31320">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8e386670579cda3ff672adf26967e880">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the:<lb/>Ruth A. Haas Library<lb/> 
Archives and Special Collections<lb/>
181 White Street<lb/>
Danbury, CT 06810
<lb/>Phone: 203-837-8992<lb/>
E-mail: stevensb@wcsu.edu<lb/></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2026277d85fdc3e4e364a827dcb48d13">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form:<lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date (if known); The Student Newspapers Collection: student publications of the Danbury Normal School, Danbury Teachers College, Danbury State Teachers College, Western Connecticut State College and Western Connecticut State University.; RG 5.15.1; box number; folder number; <address><addressline>Western Connecticut State University Archives</addressline></address></p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_296bc6aad3e5f6899813aa336f9633e2">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>The Western Connecticut State University (WCSU) student newspaper went through several incarnations before it became <title render="italic">The Echo</title> in 1955. </p><p>The oldest surviving student "newspaper" dates from October 16, 1931. However, the masthead indicates that this was the first issue of the eighth volume of <title render="italic">Dee N Ess</title> (phonetic spelling for "DNS" -Danbury Normal School) and was a mimeographed publication more akin to a newsletter. It may be that the first issues were published in the early 1920s. The publication contained campus news, student writings (essays and poetry primarily), comics, and artwork. In 1936, the Danbury Normal School became the Danbury Teachers' College. The newspaper reflected the changes taking place at the school by changing its name in the fall of 1936. <title render="italic">Dee Tee Cee</title> continued <title render="italic">Dee N Ess</title>. In 1941, the name changed again to <title render="italic">Campus Crier.</title> The Archives does not have any copies of newspapers from 1942 through the spring of 1944. This may be due to the fact that student organizations curtailed their activities during the war years. In March of 1944, the student newspaper reemerged, this time under the name: <title render="italic">The Inkling</title>. <title render="italic">The Inkling</title> took on a more professional look, was typeset and contained photographs.</p><p>In 1948 when the college adopted a new constitution and emerged as the Danbury State Teachers' College, the student paper repositioned itself again as <title render="italic">The Courier</title>. This was another step toward becoming a more professional publication and, for a while, it even adopted the more traditional newspaper-style tabloid format. However, <title render="italic">The Courier</title> evolved into a more literary publication and in the spring of 1953 a group of students started publishing a second newspaper, <title render="italic">The Supplement </title>. It operated as a more informal but carried on with more student-newspaper-like content than <title render="italic">The Courier</title>.</p><p>In 1955 <title render="italic">The Supplement</title> took on a new and enduring moniker: <title render="italic">The Echo</title>. From November 23, 1955 to the present, this has been the primary student newspaper for the university.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b63dc0289599a27ed563ca3c53235d70">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>Of interest is the final May 1936 issue of <title render="italic">Dee N Ess</title> that contains a foreword written by the school's president, Ralph C. Jenkins, entitled "What's In a Name?" In the piece, President Jenkins discussed the meaning of the word "normal" in the school's title and its implications for the school's mission. It was at this time that the school's name changed to Danbury Teachers' College. The newspaper reflected the changes taking place at the school by changing its name in the fall of 1936.</p><p>Volume and issue numbering is inconsistent throughout the first twenty-year-run of the newspapers. Volume numbers stop and start at random and the number of a particular issue is sometimes duplicated or left off all together. </p><p>As of the first publication of <title render="italic">The Echo</title> in 1955, issue and volume numbering is normalized, and the Archives holds a complete set. Issues after 2002 have not been processed but the Archives holds copies.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_067a50e7710a715b24b24b0d7e8067e0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Folders are chronologically within each subject/author heading.</p><p>The files are grouped into 1 series.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>Inventory</item>
    </list>
  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Newspapers.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College students.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Teachers colleges.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Newsletters.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Publications.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Danbury (Conn.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges -- United States -- Newspapers -- History.</subject>
    <persname source="local">Jenkins, Ralph Carlton, 1891-</persname>
    <corpname source="local">Western Connecticut State University -- History.</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Western Connecticut State College -- History.</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Danbury State Tearchers College -- History.</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Danbury Normal School -- History.</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Danbury Teachers College -- History.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref13_iou" level="series"><did><unittitle>Inventory</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42054" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42054</unitid></did><c02 id="aspace_ref14_cqg" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Dee N Ess, </title>March 1926</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42094" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42094</unitid><unitdate normal="1926/1926" type="inclusive">1926</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_aaf9cb559fb8c8dfd4b2d8a04e883258" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_b197e0abc084c67822abe2be98340a36"><head>General</head><p>Formation of the Student Cooperation Plan; student events and trips.</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_00a01bb91a4aa06189f758c010263c9c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>First issue of Dee N Ess dated March 25, 1926, Vol. II, No. 27.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref15_ekz" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Dee N Ess, </title>October 1931 through May 1936</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42093" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42093</unitid><unitdate normal="1931/1936" type="inclusive">1931-1936</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_887869802e1b6150381948673a8ccfe9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_89aacba7019f569947d140a8b634a7e6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Missing Issues:</p><p>March 18, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 22 to April 30, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 27</p><p>May 27, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 31 to September 16, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 19</p><p>December 16, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 14</p><p>January 20, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 18</p><p>March 3, 1933 Vol. 9, No. 24 to March 17, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 26.</p><p>April 14, 1933, Vol 9, No. 30 to November 8, 1933, Vol. 10, No. 7</p><p>November 29, 1933, Vol. 10, No. 9</p><p>January 3, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 12</p><p>January 24, 1934, Vol 10, No. 15</p><p>February 21, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 19</p><p>February 28, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 20</p><p>March 13, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 21</p><p>April 10, 1935, Vol 11. No. 25 - May 1935, Vol. 11, No. ?</p><p>September 1935, Vol. 12, No. 1 - November 13, 1935, Vol. 12, No. 6</p><p>November 27, 1935, Vol. 12, No. 8</p><p>February 9, 1936, Vol 12, No. 16</p><p>February 16, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 17</p><p>March 11, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 18 - May 6, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 27</p><p>
Articles missing from the following issues:</p><p>November 4, 1932
November 18, 1932
December 9, 1932
January 8, 1936</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_2129c15dc656d50273d265407235fce0"><head>General</head><p>October 16, 1931, Vol 8, Number 1
Student activities; Club and Alumnae Notes; the Forum's first meeting of the year; and poetry by Florence Stoll.</p><p>October 23, 1931, Vol 8, Number 2
The DeeNeeS is published by a new senior division each month; "The Forum Asks" Personals; Alumnae, Faculty, and Club notes.</p><p>October 30, 1931, Vol 8, Number 3
International news; "The Forum Suggests;" Club and Alumnae Notes; Personals; student poetry.</p><p>November 11, 1918, Vol 8, Number 4
Cover illustration entitled "Le Wagon du Marechal Foch, The car in which the Armistice was signed November 11, 1918," by A.L.T: Club Notes; Personals; first mention of Student Council; "The Forum" Notes.</p><p>November 13, 1931, Vol 8, Number 5
Club and Alumnae Notes, The Forum Column, and Personals.  </p><p>November 20, 1931, Vol. 8, Number 6
Club activities, Assembly Notes; The Forum Column; Governor Cross visits Danbury for Armistice day; poetry, and Personals.</p><p>November 25, 1931, Vol. 8, Number 7
Club activities; Personals; students visit New York City.</p><p>December 4, 1931, Vol. 8, Number 8
Junior and senior volleyball; Club Notes; The Forum Column; and Personals.</p><p>December 11, 1931, Vol. 8, Number 9
Dr. Ambroso L. Suhric, head of the Teacher Training Department of NYU visits DNS; The Forum Column; students and faculty attend luncheon given by Connecticut Secondary Schools Society of Internation Cooperation at New Haven and hear Sir Wilfred Grenfell speak on foreign affairs; varsity-faculty volleyball; and poetry.</p><p>December 18, 1931, Vol. 8, Number 10
Training School Notes, Alumnae and Club Notes; The Forum Column; and, Personals.</p><p>December 23, 1931, Vol. 8, No. 11
Dramatic Club presents a Christmas play "When the Chimes Rang;" Club Notes, The Forum Column.</p><p>January 8, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 12
Annual conference of the Connecticut Normal School faculty members held in New Haven; International news; Faculty and Club Notes; and, student poetry.</p><p>January 13, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 13
Formal dance planned by the Social Committee; Dr. James E. Rogers speaks at special assembly; Club Notes; series of assemblies planned to observe the bicentennial; The Forum Column.</p><p>January 22, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 14
Cover illustration of Benjamin Franklin entitled "Beware of little expenses, a small leak will sink a great ship."  Assembly programs; Club and Hall Notes; The Forum Column; and, student poetry.</p><p>January 29, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 15
Assembly hosts Miss Kiely, Principal of the Bridgeport City Normal School; Hall Notes; sports; Club News; The Forum Column; student poetry.</p><p>February 5, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 16
Cover illustration of world entitled "Forum Dinner" by A.M.M.  Forum Radio Committee formed; Forum guest speaker Mr. C. Douglas Booth of the Royal Institute of International Affairs in England; The Forum column; Club and Faculty Notes; Hall and Locust Avenue Notes.</p><p>February 11, 1932, Vol. 8 No. 17
Cover illustration "LINCOLN, an Apostle of Freedom, and a lover of peace."  Forum speaker D.Douglas Booth; The Forum Column; Faculty, Hall, Balmforth Avenue Notes.</p><p>February 19, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 18
Dramatic Club will present "The Rector" by Rachel Cruthers, and "The Obstinate Family."  Club news, Faculty Notes; Locust Avenue and Balmforth Avenue notes; The Forum Column; poetry by Gladys Fishelberg.</p><p>February 26, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 19
Club notes; alumnae weekend; The Forum Column; poetry by Gladys Fishelberg.</p><p>March 4, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 20
Alumnae weekend; Faculty and Club Notes; Athletic Association news; The Forum Column.</p><p>March 11, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 21
Alumnae weekend; statesman Aristide Briand dies; Club and Hall Notes; The Forum Column.</p><p>May 6, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 28
New column introduced "The Inquisitive Reporter;" Assembly program; Faculty, Hall, and Club Notes; The Forum Column; poetry by Gladys Fishelberg.</p><p>May 13, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 29
Club, Faculty, Hall, and Assembly Notes; Dramatic Club presents "A Dish of China Tea" and "At Candlelight Time" for the benefit of the PTA of both rural schools; The Forum Column; The Inquisitive Reporter.</p><p>May 20, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 30
Club and Hall Notes; The Forum Column; Training Notes; and, poetry by Gladys E.Fishelberg.</p><p>May 27, 1932, Vol. 8, No. 31
George Washington pageant by the children of Balmforth Avenue School; Assembly, Clubs; Hall News and Notes; The Inquisitive Reporter.</p><p>September 16, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 1
Club News, The Forum Column; Faculty Notes; First Days at D.N.S.; Coming Events.</p><p>September 23, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 2
Club News and Notes; Assembly Notes; Faculty-Student Reception; Britian Condemns German Arms Plea.</p><p>September 30, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 3
Dr. Ernest Butterfield, Commissioner of Education to speak; "Great Britain Relents, Gandhi Ends His Fast;" Clubs, Assembly, and Faculty Notes; The Forum Column.</p><p>October 6, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 4
Clubs, Assembly, Social, Faculty Notes; and, The Forum Column.</p><p>October 14, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 5
Assembly, Faculty, and Club Notes; The Forum Column; and, Social Notes.</p><p>October 21, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 6
The Forum Column by Frances Hamm and Ann Cronin, Faculty, Assembly, and Club Notes. </p><p>October 27, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 7
Faculty, Social and Club Notes; and, The Forum Column by Frances Hamm and Ann Cronin.</p><p>November 4, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 8
The Forum at Wesleyan; Club News; volleyball; Personals; The Forum Column by Irene Coughlin, Catherine Magner, and Adelaide Starr; Dramatic Club presents "Part Time Job."</p><p>November 10, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 9
Faculty, Hall, and Assembly Notes, Club News; The Forum Column; and poetry by Fannie Teichholz.</p><p>November 18, 1932, Vol 9, No. 10
Faculty Notes; Club Notes; Personals; The Forum Column; poetry by Ruth Miller and Mary Wrenn.</p><p>November 23, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 11
Assembly Notes, Club news; The Forum Column; Personals; Faculty Notes; and, poetry by Fannie Teichholz and Mary Wrenn.</p><p>December 2, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 12
Club News and Notes; The Forum Column; Faculty Notes, Personals; and, student poetry.</p><p>December 9, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 13
December meeting of the Danbury League of Women Voters held at DNS; The Forum travels to Yale to hear Dr. Julius Curtuis on "Germany and Disarmament;" Poetry by Ellen Hunt.</p><p>December 21, 1932, Vol. 9, No. 15
Assembly and Faculty Notes; The Origins of Christmas; Forum Notes; Athletic Association gives a party.</p><p>January 6, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 16
Dramatic Club will present "Between Trains" and "Her Uncle's Boots."  The Forum Column; Clubs News and Notes; Personals; Alumnae News; Faculty Notes; poetry by Mary Wrenn.</p><p>January 13, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 17
Review of Dramatic Club's two one-act plays; Assembly, Faculty and Club Notes; The Forum Column; Philippine Independence discussed.</p><p>January 27, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 19
Mrs. Marietta Johnson of the Fairhope School in Fairhope, Alabama, speaks of the founding of the school; League of Nations questions Japan on Mandates; The Forum Column; Faculty and Assembly Notes.</p><p>February 3, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 20
Death of two authors: Sara Teasdale and John Galsworthy; Assembly, Club and Faculty Notes; Forum Reports; Personals</p><p>February 10, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 21
Lothrop Higgins addressed the first February meeting of The Forum; The Forum Column; Faculty and Assembly Notes; Personals.</p><p>February 17, 1933, Vol. 9. No. 22
The Forum Column, Club News and Notes; Faculty Notes; Sports; poetry by Fannie Teichholz.</p><p>February 24, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 23
Club News and Notes; The Forum Reports; Faculty and Hall Notes.</p><p>March 24, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 27
Assembly and Club Notes; new faculty at Balmforth Avenue School; thoughts on Education and Depression; Hall Notes; The Forum  Column.</p><p>March 31, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 28
"Will Danbury Normal School Close?"  Dramatic Club speaker Madame Ortmann, German opera star; Faculty, Assembly, Club, and Hall Notes; Forum Column.</p><p>April 7, 1933, Vol. 9, No. 29
Forum to hold dinner, Dr. James T. Shotwell, professor of history at Columbia University, to speak; Clubs News; Assembly and Hall Notes; Forum Column; poetryby Alice C. Wight and Gertrude Baughan.</p><p>November 15, 1933, Vol. 10, No. 7
Special Features on Art and Music by Edith Vogel, Assistant Editor;  Assembly and Forum notes; Personals.</p><p>November 22, 1933, Vol. 10, No. 8
Women's Basketball; Beacon Hill Symphonic Ensemble performed at Danbury High School Auditorium; Club news; Personals; poetry by Inez Whitworth; book reviews on "Mild Oats" by Florence Ryerson and Colin Clemonts, and "San Michele" by Axel Munthe.</p><p>December 6, 1933, Vol. 10, No. 10
DNS students attend "University in Exile" seminar at the New School for Social Research; Alumnae Association sponor camp project; Forum News.</p><p>December 13, 1933, Vol. 10, No. 11
Forum members attend League of Nations Dinner in New Haven; Divisions to sponsor teas; Alumnae and Club News; comments on Prof. Brandt's lecture on peasant life in Europe and Asia. </p><p>January 10, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 13
Club news; personals; concert news; Commercial Students wish everyone a successful year.</p><p>January 17, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 14
Assembly news; basketball, Forum and Club news; Faculty Notes.</p><p>January 31, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 16
Formal dance held at Fairfield Hall; Assembly Notes; Club, Forum, and Faculty News.</p><p>February 7, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 17
Mr. Higgins addresses Nature Club; Assembly Notes; Faculty and Weekend News.</p><p>February 14, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 18
Assembly to commemorate the anniversary of President Lincoln's birth; Club news; Faculty News, Over The Week-End (personals); Tributes to Lincoln.</p><p>March 7, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 21
Hitler Seeks Vienna Peace; Assembly News; Personals.</p><p>March 14, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 22
Assembly Notes; Personals; Faculty News; poetry by Ella Wheeler Wilcox.</p><p>March 21, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 23
Walter B. Spencer, principal of New Haven Commercial High School, addresses business students; Dramatic Club will present "St. Cecelina" and "Up in the Air."  Assembly and club notes; Faculty News; Forum students quiz Mr. Albert Walsh, first selectman of the Town of Danbury.</p><p>March 28, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 24
The history of Easter; Assembly Notes; Principal of Waterbury High School addresses DNS students; Club activities; Faculty News; Personals; Review of John Masefield's "Bird of Dawning."</p><p>April 11, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 25
Social Committee entertains with a Bridge-Tea; Assembly Notes; Faculty News; "Snoops-----or Scoops" column.</p><p>April 18, 1934, Vol 10, No. 26
Forum Banquet speakers Lothrop Higgins and Dr. Schuyler Wallace; Assembly Notes; Club activities; Personals; advice to freshmen.</p><p>April 23, 1934, Vol. 10, No. 27
Forum Banquet; Club Activities; Normal School Camp; Assembly Notes; News of the Training Schools (Locust Avenue and Balmforth Avenue).</p><p>October 3, 1934, Vol. 11, No. 1
Freshman welcomed at reception; Danbury Fair; Editorial on Christopher Columbus; Book Review on "The Testament Of Youth" by Vera Brittain; Alumnae and Assembly Notes; Faculty News; Club activities; NewsFlashes; Spices column.</p><p>October 10, 1934, Vol. 11, No. 2
Spanish Socialist Revolt; Nobel Peace Prize; Book Review on "As The Earth Turns" by Gladys Hasty Carrol; Assembly Notes; Editorial; Spices and Music Columns.</p><p>October 17, 1934, Vol 11, No. 3
Alumnae and Faculty Notes; Clubs News; Editorial Column; Book Review on "Stars Fell On Alabama" by Carl Carmer; Dramatic Club sponsors visit by Nancy Byrd Turner, poetess; Last Complimentary Issue of the DeeNesS.</p><p>October 24,1934, Vol. 11, No. 4
Annual Play Day of the four Normal Schools and Connecticut State College; Editorial "Keep Young;" Assembly and Club News; Book Review on "Twenty Years A Growing" by Maurice O'Sullivan; Faculty and Alumnae Notes.</p><p>October 31, 1934, Vol 11, No. 5
Senior C Division hold Bridge-Tea; Faculty Notes; Book review on "42 Years in the White House" by Irvin H. (Ike) Hoover; Personals; Library Committee Party; Coming Events.</p><p>November 7, 1934, Vol 11, No. 6
Forum sponsors lecturers on Russia, Augusta Sutton first speaker; Assembly, Faculty, and Alumnae Notes; Book Review on "The Sea Hawk" by Rafael Sabatini; Coming Attractions; "Through the Keyhole" Column.</p><p>November 15, 1934, Vol. 11, No. 7
International Peace Program, The Family of Nations, reviewed; Faculty, Alumnae, Assembly and Club Notes; Coming Attractions Column; Personals; Book review on "Wine From These Grapes" by Edna St. Vincent Millay.</p><p>November 21, 1934, Vol 11, No. 8
Forum sponsors lecturers on Russia, Augusta Sutton second speaker; Assembly, Alumnae, Faculty Notes; Book review on "The Book That Nobody Knows" by Bruce Barton; "Through the Keyhole" column; Coming Attractions Column; student poetry.</p><p>November 28, 1934, Vol 11, No. 9
Forum sponsors lecturers on Russia, Augusta Sutton third speaker; Club news; Book review on "Without My Cloak" by Kate O'Brien; Assembly and Faculty Notes; Personals; Social Committee Column.</p><p>December 5, 1934, Vol 11, No. 10
World News; Mr. and Mrs. Higgins attend student Thanksgiving celebration in Fairfield Hall; Book review on "The House in the Hills" by Simmone Ratel; Assembly News; Students visit Town Farm; Personals.</p><p>December 12, 1934, Vol 11, No. 11
World News; Annual Senior Kiddie Party; Locust Avenue School sponsors bazaar; Coming Events column; Assembly and Club news; Personals; Book review on "Lamb in His Bosom" by Caroline Miller.</p><p>December 18, 1934, Vol 11, No. 12
Labor news; August Sutton speaker at Connecticut branch of the League of Nations Association; Assembly News; Glee Club operetta; Miry Brook entertainment; Social Committe notes; books for vacation reading; student poetry.</p><p>January 9, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 13
International News entitled "An Anxious World Is Waiting;" Visits to Town Farm encouraged; January 3 Assembly speaker Mr. Higgins spoke on world affairs; Dramatic Club presented "The Cancelled Debt" on December 20, 1934; Faculty and Training School News; Club News; Personals.</p><p>January 16, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 14
International News entitled "New Friendships;" Assembly and Club News; Faculty News; Coming Events; Personals.</p><p>January 23, 1935, Vol 11, No. 15
Forum speaker Mr. E. Ward Ireland, Superintendent of Schools in Stratford, discusses "Education;" Assembly and Club Notes and Personals; article entitled "An International Issue in the New Deal;" Book review on "An Altar In The Fields" by Ludwig Lewisohn; Faculty News.</p><p>January 30, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 16
Editorial Staff listed; Forum speaker Leon C. Staples, Superintendent of Schools in Stamford, urges school leadership; Assembly Notes; Club and Faculty Notes, Personals; Book review on "Another Caesar" by Alfred Newman.</p><p>February 6, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 17
DNS Library supplemented by pay collection of recent outstanding books; Club and Assembly Notes; "The Story of the Schaghticokes;" Faculty Notes and Personals; Book review on "The Taking of the Gry" by John Masefield; student poetry.</p><p>February 13, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 18
Assembly and Club Notes; Highlights on Nearby Towns; Faculty Notes; Personals; Book review on "Road To Ages" by Robert Nathan.</p><p>February 20, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 19
Rural Club speaker James R. Case discusses some of the problems encountered in working with youth, particularly in the 4-H Clubs; Assembly and Club Notes; Coming Events; Faculty Notes; Personals; Book review on "Matador" by Marguerite Steen.</p><p>February 27, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 20
"Twelfth Night" presented by the Edgerow Theater Players of Rose Valley, PA; Forum to resume Sunday night speakers; Book review on "The Old Man Dies" by Elizabeth Spriggs; Personals; Faculty News.</p><p>March 20, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 22
Progressive Education Convention and Scholastic Press Convention attended by DNS students; Memoriam for Lothrop D. Higgins; Assembly Notes on European nations; Club Notes; Coming Events; Personals; Faculty News.</p><p>March 27, 1935, Vol. 11, No. 23
Dramatic Club presents "The Obstinate Family" and "Will-O' the Wisp;" Faculty, Assembly and Club Notes; Personals; Book reviews on "Of Time and the River" by Thomas Wolfe and "What Price Mallorca;" student poetry.</p><p>April 3, 1935, Vol 11, No. 24
Anthony "Eden's Week of Travels;" Assembly Notes; Club News; The Forum Column; Coming Events; Faculty News; "A Story With Names" by Evelyn Luciano.</p><p>November 20, 19325, Vol. 12, No. 7
Editorial Staff listed; Forum speaker Dr. Goodwin Watson of Columbia University discusses "Building a New America;" Coming Events; Club News; Personals.</p><p>December 4, 1935, Vol 12, No. 9
Editorial Staff listed; Coming Events; Personals; Assembly news; Book review on "Manners for Millions" by Sophie C. Hadida.</p><p>December 11, 1935, Vol. 12, No. 10
Forum delegates attend Foreign Policy Association meeting in New York, and the League of Nations Association annual meeting in Hartford; DNS attends New England English Teachers' Convention; Coming Events; Editorial on Emily Dickinson; Assembly and Club Notes, Personals.</p><p>December 18, 1935, Vol. 12, No. 11
Inter-Club Bazaar; Assembly News; Editorial on Christmas; Coming Events; Who's Who Column; Christmas in the training schools.</p><p>January 8, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 12
Editorial Board listed; First student-teacher groups discuss DNS curriculum; President Roosevelt's war speech; Editorial on Rudyard Kipling; Book review on "Mary Poppins" by P. L.  Travers; Personals; Assembly news; Personals; Who's Who; Alumnae Notes; Coming Events.</p><p>January 15, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 13
Public Forum Leadership course at Columbia University; Coming Events; Club Notes; Assembly News; Book review on "Valiant is the Word for Carrie" by Barry Benefield.</p><p>January 22, 1936, Vol. 12. No. 14
Death of England's King George V; Alumnae Notes, Personals, Who's Who, Editorial on American schools; Assembly Notes.  </p><p>January 26, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 15
Italy and WW II; Assembly Notes; Popularity of Pay Collection Books; Personals, Alumnae Notes, Who's Who; Book review on "If I have Four Apples" by Josephine Lawrence.</p><p>February 23, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 18
Club News; Augusta Sutton lectures on the Constitution; DNS students Doris Baxter and Margaret Stone were guest speakers at the New Haven Normal School; DNS faculty member, Grant E. Finch, speaks to Universalist Men's Club on the true story of John Wilkes Booth; poem "Washington" by Nancy Byrd Turner; "Rules of Civility" from George Washington's Copybook; profile of Miss Tobias and Mr. Brill; Club and Assembly Notes and Personals.</p><p>March 4, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 19
Editorial Board listed; DNS girls visit Camp Fechner on 2/18/1936; Coming Events; Editorial on crime prevention; Book review on "Silas Crockett" by Mary Ellen Chase; Club Notes; Poetry by alumnae Margaret M. Worthy and Ruth Miller; Personals; Alumnae Notes; Assembly Notes for 2/20 and 3/2.</p><p>April (Undated)
Thirty students from DNS attend Eastern States Conference in New York City by May Sherwood; Augusta Sutton attends Conference on Better Personnel in Education held at the Edgewood School in Greenwich; Club and Assembly Notes; Personals; "Normal School vs. College" by Eleanor Kingman.</p><p>April (Undated)
Club and Assembly Notes; Alumnae Notes; profile of Rachel Field, author of children's books and plays.</p><p>April (Undated)
Delegates attend Country Life Conference; Mrs. deVillafranca addressed the Ridgefield PTA on "The Value of Music in the Public Schools;" Toscanini farewell concert in Carnegie Hall; Personals; Alumnae, Assembly and Club Notes; Profile of Robert Frost.</p><p>May 13, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 28
Alumnae Notes; Personals and Club Notes; Dramatic Club production of "Ladies in Waiting" by Cyril Campion; profile of Will Cather.</p><p>May 13, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 28 (Final issue with year's activities)
Editors for the years 1935-1936 and their assistants listed; Foreword by Ralph C. Jenkins; Science Club marks nature trail at Squantz Pond; Coming Events; poetry by Ella Quitt '39; Summary of events by the Athletic Association, Craft Guild,  Dramatic Club, The Forum, the Glee Club, Philomathean Club, Rural Club, and Science Club; Assembly events; book review on "Silas Crockett" by Mary Ellen Chase; Social Committee; Welfare Committee; "Who's Been Who;" and, the Junior's Last Will and Testament dated June 20, 1936.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref16_0te" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Dee Tee Cee </title>, September 1936 through October 1937</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42092" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42092</unitid><unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_89801138b090e06e9a4a3865a2c6063b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_38b484fdcde6e3c6a94693361be949db"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Missing Issues:</p><p>Numbering Incorrect
December 2, Vol 11, No. 11 - December 9, Vol. 11, No. 13</p><p>Numbering Incorrect
January, February, March, April, May Issues numbered incorrectly</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_502299179ad38cf3d418ae2870808957"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>September 1936, Vol. 13, No. 2
Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; members of Athletic Association hike to Wildman's Landing at Lake Candlewood; Freshman receiption; Club Notes; Alumnae Notes; The Forum column by K. A. Sutton; faculty notes.</p><p>September 1936, Vol. 13, No. 3
Ninety members of the Athletic Association enjoy hike to Wildman's Landing; Dramatic Club holds open meeting; Personals; The Poetry Corner: Poems by Adele Flanagan and Edward Thomas; Faculty Hobbies; Literary Notes on "Gone With The Wind" by Margaret Mitchell.</p><p>October 1936, Vol. 13, No. 4
Rural Club visits schools and Marion Newton's farm; Danbury Fair begins; Club Notes; Letter to the Editor regarding time constraints on students; Poetry Corner: Poems by Theodore J. Shannon and Orrick Johns; Sophomores Inspect Wilton School; Personals; Faculty Hobbies.</p><p>October 1936, Vol. 13, No. 5 
Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; Athletic Association members hike to McKay's farm in Cedar Heights; Newly organized Men's Forum to present varied social program; Lord Marley, Vice Chairman of the House of Lords in the British Parliament will be guest speaker on December 11 at the Green Hotel; Tennis Tournament begins; Editorial on the expiration of Article xix of the Washington treaty of 1922 by Helen Pauloski; Literary Notes: "Around The World In Eleven Years" by the children of Mr. Abbe, a newspaper photographer and Mrs. Abbe, a former follies girl; Reviews of the newest plays on Broadway; Personals by Jessie Levino; Club News.</p><p>October 28, 1936, Vol. 14, No. 6
Dee Tee Cee staff listed; Men's and Women's Forum news; Sports News; Class News; Alumnae News; Editorial on the religious education; Club news; Dramatic Club rehearsing for "Rector" and "Wedding Spells;" Personals; Poem "Reverie" and "To A Brook" by Martha Warner; New plays on Broadway.</p><p>November 4, 1936, Vol. 15, No. 7
Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; The Forum Dinner; Dramatic Club's three act play "Wedding Spells" to be given on November 24th; Club activities and sports news; Personals; Poetry of New England; The Book Nook.</p><p>November 11, 1936, Vol. 11, No. 8
Editorial Staff listed; Augusta Sutton addressed the Armistice Day meetings of the League of Women Voters; Book news and Reviews; poetry by Jane Reardon and Ralphine Patton; Club News and Personals. </p><p>November 18, 1936, Vol. 11, No. 9
Club Notes, Personals; poetry by Harriet Lawlor, C. O., and M. P.; Cinema Briefs.</p><p>November 25, 1936, Vol. 11, No. 10
Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; Club News; Opera News; Annual Visit to Town Farm; "On Broadway;" Personals, student poetry; and, Inquiring Photographer.</p><p>December 2, Vol. 11, No. 11
Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; Men's baseketball; DNS faculty and students to air 15 minute musical program on WICC radio; International News; plays and pictures review; Children's Theater; Personals; student poetry.</p><p>December 9, Vol. 11, No. 13
Assemby Notes; local events; Drama and Music Notes; poetry; Club News; December's Air Waves; local news.</p><p>December 16, Vol 11, No. 14
The Forum Banquet; Assembly News; Personals; Club News.</p><p>December 22, 1936, Vol 11, No. 15
Christmas program; Melody Singers visit DTC; Club News; Opera news; Poetry Corner; and, Humor Column.</p><p>January 6, 1937, Vol 13, No. 15
Editorial Staff listed; Club News; Personals; "1936 In Review;" student poetry.</p><p>January 13, 1937, Vol. 16, No. ?
Music Centre to present The Mikado; Club News; Mr. Jenkins to speak in Assembly; "As We Begin 1937;" student poetry; Training School Notes, Personals; Faculty Hobbies.</p><p>January 20, 1937, Vol. 13, No. 18
News story "Industry and Labor Again At Odds;" Opera news; Letter to the Editor regarding plan of study by A Progressive Junio; student poetry; men's basketball, Faculty Hobbies, and song hits of DTC.</p><p>January 27, 1937, Vol. 14, No. 14
President Roosevelt's inauguration; Men's Forum to discuss Social Security Act; Men's basketball; Faculy replies to Progressive Junior's Letter to the Editor; short story and student poetry; Personals, Club News; Best Sellers; and Faculty Hobbies.</p><p>February 1937, Vol 12, No. 19
Editorial Staff listed; Assembly and Club Notes; Winter formal; Personals; Locust Avenue Training School Notes; student poetry; book reviews.</p><p>February 1937, Vol 12, No. 20
Club Notes; Musical Projects; student poetry on Abraham Lincoln; "The Shadow" column; Men's basketball; Inquiring Reporter; letters to St. Valentine.</p><p>February 1937, Vol. 12, No. 21
A. A. Tea Dance; Assembly Notes; Club News; "The Shadow" column.</p><p>March 3, 1937, Vol. 12, No. 22
Editorial Staff listed; the Nation and School News; Assembly and Club News; Carl Sandburg profiled; Personals and Etiquette columns; student poetry; book reviews on The Man Who Didn't Exist, Of Mice and Men, and "Paradise."</p><p>[March 10, 1937], Vol. 12, No. 23
Editorial Staff listed; Metropolitan Opera news; "The Value of Alexander Bell's Invention;" Alumnae, Club and Assembly News, Personals; "Guess Who" column; student poetry by Nancy B. Turner, Henry Van Dyke; Hilda L. Frost; Modern Etiquette column; and "Where Is Our School Emblem?"</p><p>[March 17, 1937], Vol. 12, No. 24
Prospective students; Mrs. deVillaFranca opinion on teaching music in school; publicity for progressive education; spelling bee; student poetry; book review "We Are Not Alone" by James Hilton; sports and club news; Personals; Phantom Three sees Sophmore B's in 1943.</p><p>[March 24, 1937], Vol. 12, No. 25
Discussion on Danbury News-Times editorial comment on teacher training; Town Farm trip planned; Assembly News; student poetry and book reports on "Young Robert" by George Allen, and "A Lamp On The Plans" by Paul Horgan; Sports and Club News; Personals; and April events.</p><p>No Date [March 31, 1937]
Juniors conclude trial seminar plan; Progressive Education Association Meets; Club News; Welfare Committee presented musical progam at the Town Farm; student poetry; Easter Program; "Do You Remember When" column; and, Personals.</p><p>No Date [April 15, 1937] Vol. 16, No. 28
Retaining Normal Schools or Teachers Colleges topic of discussion with lawmakers; Club News; "Madrigal" discussed; new Text Book Room; student poetry.</p><p>No Date [April 22, 1937, Vol. 16, No. 29]
Editorial Staff listed; Forum Column; Library Staff planning "Juvenile Collection;" Assembly News; "The New Finland;" Club News and Professional Scholarship; book review on "Cards On The Table" by Agatha Christie; Campus Chatter and Personals.</p><p>No Date [April 28, 1937], Vol. 13, No. 20
Eastern States Conference; Assembly Notes; Club News; Of Mice and Men by John Steinback reviewed; Student poetry; Personals; Song Hits at DTC.</p><p>No Date [May 5, 1937], Vol. 13, No. 21
Juniors to present "The Mystery of the Masked Girl;" Miss Emily Barnard, daughter of Dr. Henry Barnard to speak at DTC on May 10, 1937; Training School clases enterain in Assembly; Local News; Club Notes; Student Poetry.</p><p>October 1937, Volume 1, Number 1
Danbury Normal becomes Danbury State Teachers College and Dr. Ralph C. Jenkins installed as President on September 29, 1937; Club and Alumnae News; Personals; Sports already organized at DTC; Forum Club Officers listed; first appearance of ads for local businesses.</p><p>November 1937, Volume 1, Number 2
Augusta Sutton speaks at Armistice Day Service on November 7, 1937; Senior Class trips; The Pied Piper Puppeters from Cos Cob present "Little Red Horse;" Who's Who column; Club Notes; Literary Corner; Department News; Descriptive Ditties column; Campus Chatter; and, Alumnae News. </p><p>December 1937, Volume 1, Number 3
History of Connecticut Club travels; Eighth Annual Forum Banquet, Dr. No Yong Park and Dr. Yutaka Minakuchi debate "The Far Eastern Crisis;" Assembly and Alumnae News; Sports; Training School Notes; and, Personals.
  </p></bioghist></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref17_tne" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Dee Tee Cee </title>, January 1938 through June 1938</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42091" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42091</unitid><unitdate normal="1938/1938" type="inclusive">1938</unitdate><container altrender="Medium flat (15 x 12 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_fd7102290326f72fca9bf21525e8258c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a62133058153cd83307c6a914f3432d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>No Subnote Content</p></scopecontent><odd id="aspace_350f88b8c5e729aee839715048842834"><head>General</head><p>January 1938, Volume I, Number 4
DTC Men's basketball team photograph; Winter formal at DTC; Senior A's take trip to New York City; DTC wins opening basketball game; Titles conferred upon eight teachers; What do you think? column on international affairs; Club news; Assembly news; poetry by A. Coladarci, R. S. McDonald, Wilbur R. Turner, and Shelley; Alumnae News; DTC Personals, Training School Notes; Song hits of DTC.</p><p>February 1938, Volume I, Number 5
Dr. Jenkins gives education views; College Night; State Progressive Education Association meeting to be held at Danbury High School; Freshmen Valentine party successful; Dr. Ralph C. Jenkins made member of National Education Association Committee on Supply, Preparation, and Certification of Teachers; Training School Notes; Sports and Clubs News; Alumni Notes; poetry by Ruth McDonald and A. Coladarci; Original poetry from Fifth Grade--Locust Avenue School; Popular Song Hits.</p><p>March 1938, Volume I, Number 6
Sophomore Party has record attendance; Assemblies feature varied programs; Music Department to give annual concert; Basketball season closes for season; DTC Student 'Y' organizes for '38; Athletics at DTC article; Sport activities at DTC; What men and women will be wearing this spring; Club news; Poet's Corner; Training School Notes.</p><p>April 1938, Volume I, Number 7
Foreign Affairs expert, Dr. James G.l McDonald, associate editor of the New YOrk Times, will speak in the college Assembly Hall; "Frosh" plan formal; faculty member addresses Americanization classes; Teachers College represented at Eastern States; Annual concert successful; college men to attend Athletic Conference; Seniors sponsor Play Day; Club News; Poet's Corner; Assembly news.</p><p>June 1938, Volume I, Number 8
First Annual Commencement Exercises of Danbury Teachers College; Class of 1938 picture on front page; Commencement activities; seniors honored at formal by Juniors; Senior Poetry Corner; Senior Syllogisms; ClassWill; Henry Barnard Pageant celebrates Centennial; The Scholar's Dictionary; Class of 1938 History; Seniors Given Recognition.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref18_1m2" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Dee Tee Cee </title>, November 1938 through May 1941</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42090" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42090</unitid><unitdate normal="1938/1941" type="inclusive">1938-1941</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_ff86a1da64436d76337bb0bae3a05620" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_88ed4f75a41334966f5faadff17cc9ca"><head>General</head><p>November 1938, Volume II, Number 1 
Dr. Alonzo P. Grace, State Commissioner of Education spoke to students and faculty on "The Changing School;" Danbury Players of DTC sponsor "Arms And the Man" by George Bernard Shaw; News Of The Clubs column; Campus Chatter; Clubs name officials; "Dressing for Class, What to wear and how to wear it."</p><p>December 1938, Volume II, Number 2 
Sir George Paish, noted British economist, to speak at Forum's annual banquet; Dr. Ralph C. Jenkins appoionted 1939 chairman of the New England Teachers Preparation Association; Sport News; Poetry by Theresa Walsh, Helen O'Grady, and Emmet W. Bongar; Club News; Campus Chatter; Dressing For Formals column.</p><p>January 1939, Volume II, Number 3 
Senior Class to give "Stage Door" as its senior play;Sport News; Book Review on "This Proud Heart" by Pearl S. Buck; Campus Chatter; poetry by Harry Carey, Arthur Coladarci, Mariette Keane, Helen Joyce and T. Walsh; Dressing For Sports; Senior visit New York's art museum.</p><p>February 1939, Volume II, Number 4 
Music Department to present Deems Taylor's arrangement of "The Highwayman" by Alfred Noyes; Senir formal successful; Book review of "Oscar Wilde, The Man, The Artist, The Martyr" by Boris Brasol; Sports News; Training School Notes; Campus Chatter; poetry by Jeanne Robb, Emmet W. Bongar; and Paul Coladarci; Dressing for Class;</p><p>April 1939, Volume II, Number 5 
Freshmen to sponsor formal dance; Training Schools to present pageant dealing with the development of rhythms, songs and dance; Book Reviews on "Reaching for the Stars by Nora Waln, "My Son, My Son" by Howard Spring, and "The Summing Up" by W.Somerset Maugham; Club and Sports News; Seniors to present "Stage Door;" Campus Chatter; Poetry by Harry Carey, H.Starr Jackson, and Paul Coladarci; Dressing for Class; and, Faculty News.</p><p>May 1939, Volulme II, Number 6 
Activities scheduled for senior week; Junios sponsor formal for seniors; Student elections; Forum guest speaker Mrs. Miriam Beard Vaghts gives historical background for Hitler's rise to power; Campus Chatter; Club and Sports News; Book reviews on "My Sister Eileen" by Ruth McKenny, "With Malice Toward Some" by Margaret Halsey, and "Listen! The Wind" by Anne Morrow Lindbergh; Governor R. E. Baldwin to speak at commencement; Poetry by A.Coladarci, Emmet W. Bongar and H. Starr Jackson.</p><p>June 1939, Volume II, Number 7 
Junior Prom successful; Commencement to be held June 16, 1939; Training Schools pageant successful; Faculty Facts, poetry by Arthur Coladarci, Emmet W. Bongar, and Hariett Jackson; Campus Chatter; DTC BestSellers, "What's On Your Mind" column.</p><p>October 1939, Volume III, Number 1
Faculty attend annal Convocation held at New Britain; Freshman reception; sophomore formal; Book Review on "All This and Heaven Too" by Rachel Field; Clubs organize at DTC; Campus Chatter; Faculty News.</p><p>November 1939, Volume III, Number 2
Senior Class select "You Can't Take It With You" as their senior play; Danbury Players sponor play festival; Forum Luncheon successful; Fire Drill Committee organized; Sport News; Faculty Facts; Campus Chatter; Assemby Notes; poetry by Emmet Bonegar, Harriett Jackson, Kathryn Barrett, and Thomas Daly.</p><p>December 1939, Volume III, Number III
Senior Yearbook staff selected; Dr. Lengyel to be Forum Speaker; Senior Class Play column; Dr. Jenkins speaks on Henry Barnard; Book Review on "The Memoirs of Julian Hawthorne" by Edith Garrigues Hawthorne; Faculty Facts; Campus Chatter; Club and Dorm News; and, poetry by Arthur Coladarci.</p><p>April 1940, Volume III, Number 7 
Casting completed for Iolanthe; Freshman to sponsor formal; Club News; Sport News; Book Review on "A Novel of the Life of Galileo" by Zsolt de Harsanyi; Campus Chatter; Dorm News; Student poetry by Arthur Coladarci and Jeanne Robb.</p><p>May 1940, Volume III Number 8
Junior Class signs Enoch Light and his orchestra for the Junior-Senior promenade in honor of the graduating class; Alumni hold reunion; Club News; Two students discuss war, Section 1; Assembly Notes; Campus Chatter; Dorm News; student poetry by Jeanne Robb and Arthur Coladaric; Alumnae News.</p><p>June 1940, Volume III, Number 9
Light's Orchestra plays at Junior-Senior Prom; Seniors In Final Week, activities planned; Last words of the seniors; A. A. Activities; The Seniors in Poetry; Campus Chatter; Dorm Doings; Assembly News.</p><p>Introductory Issue 1940, Vol. IV, No. 1
Freshman reception; Flying courses offered to college students with two years of college training; Sports Panorama Day successful; Enrollment increases; DSTC entering 37th academic year; Sports News; Club News; Asembly Notes; Campus Chatter; Dorm Doings.</p><p>October 1940, Volume IV, Number 2
Senior B. World Literature Class visited the productions of "The Cricket on the Hearth' and "Twelfth Night" at the Chekhov Theatre in Ridgebury; First Aid Course Offered; Class of '44 holds first picnic; Flying courses underway; Campus Chatter; Dorm News; DSTC gives extension courses; Book reviews on "Portrait of Jennie" by Robert Nathan and "The Boy and Girl Tramps of America" by Thomas Minehan; Meteorite specialist spoke to Junion B division geology class; Club Activities; Sport News Column.</p><p>November 1940, Volume IV, No. 3
Senior play "Death Takes a Holiday;" Forum dinner party speaker Dr. Frederick L. Schuman, Prof. of Political Science at Williams College; Red Cross First Aid Course; Sport News and Club News Columns; Book Review on "Mrs. Miniver" by Jan Struther; Forum Column; Student poetry by Sarah E. Smith, C. L. Cleaveland; and, Oliver Goldsmith; Campus Chatter and Dorm News; "Slanguage" versus American language heard on campus.</p><p>December 1940, Vol. IV, No. 4
DSTC will present the Chekhov Theatre Company in "The Cricket On the Hearth;" Assembly Notes; Club and Sport News columns; student poetry by Emmet W. Bongar, William Young, Sarah E. Smith, Sarah Reed; and H. Starr Jackson; Campus Chatter; Club News; Forum News gives history and offspring of The Forum which was founded by Dr. Augusta Sutton.</p><p>January 1941, Vol. IV, No. 5
"The Cricket On the Hearth" review; Publications Association formed; D.T.C. Basketball Squad, 1940-1941, labeled photograph; Athletic Association news; Assembly notes; Book Review on "You Can't Go Home Again" by Thomas Wolfe; Dorm and Club News; Campus Chatter; Forum News.</p><p>February 1941, Vol. VI, No. 6
President Jenkins attends the Natiional Conference of Defense Committees of Colleges and Universities; Remedial courses organized; Editorial on need to organize an Athletic Association; Assembly Notes; Sports Column; Campus Chatter and Dorm Doings; student poetry by Alabert E. Bedat, Sarah Smith, Mary E. Walsh, Emmet W. Bongar, and Eugene McGowan; Students interest in driving course.</p><p>March 1941, Vol. VI, No. 7
DTC to attend Eastern States Association for Teachers Convention; Alum Daniel Skandera, class of 1940, to get wings; DSTC will sponsor second annual Drama Day; Editorial on Student Council; Assembly and Faculty Notes; Club News focus on The Forum and its activities; Campus Chatter; New column "Advice to Lovelorn" debuts; student poetry; sport activities.</p><p>April 1941, Vol. IV, No. 8
Miss Anna E. Scollin to be honored at a dinner party; Annual Forum Spring Lecture/Dinner to hear Mr. Joseph Barnes, foreign editor of the New York Post who will give analysis of current war; Club and Assembly News; Sport News; Campus Chatter and Dorm News; student poetry by Evelyne Rotunda, Mary E. Walsh and others; Faculty News.</p><p>Senior Issue 1941, Vol. IV, No. 9
Graduation day program published; Yale Collegians to play at the annual Junior-Senior Prom; Senior activity week; June 4, 1941 Senior Class day Exercises; Reminiscing; Assembly Reviews; Faculty News; Campus Chatter; Athletic Association news.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref19_wci" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Campus Crier, </title>October 1941 through November 1942</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42089" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42089</unitid><unitdate normal="1941/1942" type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_9e10e73b3ac69ee8e76376c108d0f92d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_66e6d11bba49eb85d7160718f45dde62"><head>General</head><p>October 22, 1941, Volume I, No. 2 
Club and Dorm News; Men's Mixer; Short biography of notable undergraduates quiz; Freshman news and elections; Faculty News; Athletic Association News; Clubs News; Indian Summer Formal October 24th.</p><p>November 17, 1941, Volume I, Number 3 
Forum members attends New England International Relations Conference at Smith College; Students attend New England Conference; Sophomore training; Student Council news; Men's basketball; touch football tournament; Faculty News; Forum members visit Federal Correctional Institute to participate in newly installed "Prison Forum."</p><p>December 18, 1941, Volume. I, Number 4 
No deferments for college students; Freshmen news; Assembly news; Senior activities; DTC Seniors present "What A Life" in the Danbury High School Auditorium; Sports news.</p><p>November 1942, Volume I, Number 2 
Dr. Grant E. Finch honored at convocation of the Connecticut State Board of Education; Seniors to present "The Man Who Came to Dinner" by Hart and Kaufman; field trips; Victor Hasler, Sophomore Class President, drafted; Editorial addressed to faculty on "cuts;" Student officers and committee members listed; "Men in Service--More About The Boys In Camp;" Club News and activities.</p></odd><scopecontent id="aspace_b0a926352792f2d8ab43a6bb37d8d312"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Missing Issues:  </p><p>October 8, 1941, Volume I, No. 1</p><p>Spring Semester 1942</p><p>October 1942, Volume I, Number 1</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref78_ph9" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Inkling, March 1944 through June 1947</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="56489" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">56489</unitid><unitdate normal="1944/1947" type="inclusive">1944-1947</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_c78051282e7d1e63f11bef4e43610925" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4d11772aa4d58710a8de075a7b262deb" parent="aspace_c78051282e7d1e63f11bef4e43610925" type="folder">7A - 14</container></did><odd id="aspace_8a52cb8fe77f7cbbfa83eb085dcc6842"><head>General</head><p>March 1944, Volume 1, Number 1 </p><p>Editorial: The Neonate; DTC sponors Danbury Citizens' Forum; A Word From: The Freshmen, The Juniors, The Seniors, and Council; Club News; Forum News.</p><p>April 1944, Volume 1, Number 2 
Youth Confernece in May; Editorial "Pros and Cons;" Student Council News; Press Committee news; "cut system" a debatable subject.</p><p>May 1944, Volume 1, Number 3 
Pageant "Our Latin American Neighbors" to be held in June; Editorial "Girl Wanted" discussing pros and cons of working versus education; Notes From column; Yearbook near completion.</p><p>June 1944, Volume 1, Number 4 
Wartime Changes In College Program, Acceleration-Deceleration Cycle; Senior Class picture; Summer activities, Kappa Delta Pi news, "Much Ado About the Pageant" column; School Calendar; poem The Day Shall Come" by Ruth F. Carlson; Senior Scoops column.</p><p>November 1944, Volume II, Number 1 
Dr. Leslie Pinckney Hill, of the Cheney Teachers Training School, visits campus; Evolution and Revolution--The Inside Story of Council [The Council of the Cooperative Government Association]; Who's Who [clubs officials]; Dr. Grant E. Finch Retires; New Faculty; Forum attends New Britain Conference.</p><p>December 1944, Number II, No. 2 
Class of '45 Graduates, Shakespearian Play "Comedy of Errors" presented by Junior Class; Editorial on Educational Opportunities; Letters to the Editor; Kappa Delta Pi solumn; Our Post-War Plans column; Junior Commentaries; Assembly Bulletin; Eastern States Conference.</p><p>January 1945, Volume II, No. 3 
Music Center Presents Martha Graham; Dr. Jenkins aaddresses college; Cast photograph of "Comedy of Errors;" 
Editorial on "Evening Library Hours;" What's New on the Shelves [Library]' 1946 yearbook staff; Poetry by Lieut. Arthur Coladarci (Somewhere in the Pacific); Inkling joins Columbia Scholastic Press Association;" College Activity Fund Established.</p><p>February 1945, Volume II, No. 4 
Dr. Finch presents one aspect of world peace; War Time Measure--Eastern StatesCancelled; Review of the constitution of the Cooperative Goernment Association; Dr. K.Augusta Sutton lectures on Russia; Letter from Lt. Robert Thompson, Class '43; Inter-mural basketball tournament.</p><p>March 1945, Volume II, No. 1
Cheney State Teachers College choir presents concert; Forum presents Dr. Phillips Bradley, Professor of Political Science at Queen college, Flushing, NY; Assembly speaker, Mrs. Charles House of the American Farm School in Salonica, Greece, addressed faculty, students, and guests at a special assembly; Clubs and Committee News; Assembly Cut Committee news; DTC forms a college choir.</p><p>April 1945, Volume II, No. 2
Roosevelt's Death; students travel to New York City to see "The Tempest"; Assembly Bulletin; Science department to be expanded; DTC opens national clothing drive in town; Dr. Yu Gwan Chen lectures on China.</p><p>May 1945, Volume II, No. 3
CGA elect Claire Kelley, Floriene Judell, and Marie Golder; Editorial "Thoughts on V-E Day;" CGA suggested constitutional revisions; Dates and Events column; Assembly Bulletin.</p><p>June 1945, Volume II, No. 4
Students to graduate in December; Senior Memorial Day outing at Squantz Pond; Seniors given banquet; Entire school attends Danbury High School band concert; The Seniors Speak column; Danbury Players close season with plays, music and vocal selections; Class Day Exercises; Women's Athletic Association selects leaders for 1945-46; Kappa Delta Pi Initiates; Sport Finale; State grants fifty additional student scholarships; War Loan dance; Calendar for 1945-46; Outdoor fireplace is gift from senior class.</p><p>October 1945, Volume II, No. 5
Reception for new members of the faculty and new students; Inkling apprentices chosen; new faculty member Miss Mary Swokla; Miss Alice S. Tucker, Fairfield Hall dietitian; Archery Tournament at the University of Connecticutto "Meet Our Executives" (list of students to head student government and clubs).</p><p>November 1945, Volume II, No. 6
Dr. Finis E. Engleman to speaks during Assembly for National Education Week; Faculty considers plan for curriculum improvement; Musical Commentary; Assembly News; Dr. Grant E. Finch shows two-reel movie of a trip he took to South America; Junior Play "Harriet."</p><p>December 1945, Volume II, No. 7
Senior-Faculty Dinner Final Social Event; Christmas Graduation, Class of '46; "Inkspots" column; The War is Over article; Campus Casuals column.</p><p>January 1946, Volume II, No. 8
"New Era Stimulates Far-Reaching Plans" on education; "Welcome" editorial directed to men and women from the armed forces; The Dramtic Club petitioned Council for a charter; "We Asked The Questions" article; DTC basketball season begins.</p><p>April 1946, Volume III, No. 2
Mr. Burton Cooks joins faculty; "Yesterday and Today" fashion show; "How to meet men" article; Inkspots colume; Cooperative Government Elections Second Week in May;" "The Power and the Glory," excerpts from Freshman and Sophomore term papers on What Makes America Great; Gertrude Braun will teach as a memberof the History Department.</p><p>May 1946, Volume III, No. 3
The Conference of Elementary School Principals in Western Connecticut held at DTC; CGA Elections; DTC's Annual Spring Drama Festival; "We Were Listening" column; new World Student Service Club; DTC to have blazers made up in school colors.</p><p>June 1946, Vol. III, No. 4
Dr. Mary Langmuir discusses marriage at Assembly;DTC's first peacetime dance; radio commercial article; poetry and creative writing; "What  Do You Think" article on returning male students; Freshman elections, Athletic Association election; freshman class picnic.</p><p>October 1946, Volume III, No. 5
Dr. Ralph Jenkins dies; "We Will Remember" editorial; DTC officers; men's basketball; "Hurrah for Postcards" article on sending short notes on postcards versus letters; summer activities by students; new faculty member Mr. John J. Murphy.</p><p>November 1946, Volume III, No. 6
Dean Haas elected President; Junior play to be "Claudia;" first major celebration held by seniors will be reunion dance at the Hotel Green; Literary Section; Miss Cora Jane Russell honored; Assembly hears Mr. Otto Borch speak on the World Student Service Fund; Freshman class officers.</p><p>December 1946, Volume III, No. 7
Miss Claire G. Trisch becomes new Dean; Dr. Sutton, former professorof History at DSTC honored at formal dinner; Literary Secion; Kappa Delta Pi activities; Sale of school banners by the sophomore class; Freshman chemistry class visits Margerie Water Reservoir.</p><p>January 1947, Vol. III, No. 8
DSTC may see building plans approved; Editorial concerning CGA and its activities; Literary Section; campus news; debate on "Equal Pay for Equal Work for Women;" Drama Club news.</p><p>February 1947, Vol. III, No. 9
Sweetheart Ball successful; Mr. Joseph Abrahams crowned Queen; Dr. Lewis Paul Todd article; Literary Section; Music Department expanding.</p><p>April 1947, Vol. III, No. 11 [Election Special Edition]
Candidates for President, Vice President, Recording Secretary, Treasurer, and Publicity Secretary, and excerpts from the Constitution of the Cooperative Government Association. </p><p>May 1947, Vol. III, No. 11
Photograph of cast members of Junior Class play "Claudia;" Athletic Association Banquet;  Literary Section; Classroom Chatter; Assembly News; Comments on "The Greek Situation;" CGA officers for 1947-48; post season basketball.</p><p>June 1947, Vol. III, No. 12
Senior class photograph; Seniors Receives Degrees; Editorial "To The Seniors;" Sports Parade, Literary Section, Odds and Ends column; Class election results; Senior-Faculty Banquet.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref21_i4b" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic"> What's My Name</title> "I'm your paper; name me," November 1947</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42087" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42087</unitid><unitdate normal="1947/1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_788fb07255840c951ca1b6e50e092449" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_69eda39c7396f18d6d1cdf66b0c10525"><head>General</head><p>November 1947, Vol. I, No. 1
"What's My Name? edition; Editorial Board seeks name for paper from student boy; DTC CGA adopts new constitution; Eruma Society [Mature rearranged spelling by male students]; Editorial Board of School Publication photograph (identified); Mr.Carl A. Pettersch new history teacher; phonograph with six head phones to be installed in the library; Mr. Stanley Glowacki joins music department; AA program accelerates under new leaders;  Cheer leaders selected in October; basketball news; Dr. Alic Donnelly new gym teacher; Student Forum elects officers.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref22_94f" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Courier, </title>February 1948 through June 1954</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42086" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42086</unitid><unitdate normal="1948/1954" type="inclusive">1948-1954</unitdate><container altrender="Medium flat (15 x 12 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_989403769ab3fffedccd60cc5a802bf7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_6f53bff4c62994c528db1c08a4aef657"><head>General</head><p>February 1948, Vol. I, No. 3 
DTC to attend Eastern States Conference for Professional Teachers Colleges; Forum members Helen Platt and Carl Paight, along with other Connecticut colleges, attend meeting to plan Mock Legislature; Courier staff changes; Erutma to give play; Do-Day Editorial; Literary Section; Sports Scope by Cosbeck; Men's Intramurals.</p><p>April 1948, Vol. I, No. 5 
Juniors initiate means for curriculum study; First "Do-Day" ushered in; Kappa Delta Pi initiation; News Briefs; Literary contest; Gossip column "Aunt Gertrude;" Sports Scope" column; Music Department News; Fairfield Hall to have written set of rules; Sophomore class announce carnival.</p><p>May 1948, Vol. I, No. 6 
Junior play "Berkeley Square" a hit; senior class activities; Three Cheers Column choice is Prof. John Murphy; CGA election returns; Editorial on months events; Literary Contest: Delegates to Mock Legislature named; News Briefs column; "Aunt Gertrude" column; Junior Travelogue; Sports Scope column; "Do Day Was Big Day" column; "Our War Baby" column gives background of child DTC is sponsoring though the Foster Parents Plan for Orphaned War Children.</p><p>November 1948, Vol. II, No. 1 
Forum gives timely discussion on "The Political Parties and the Coming Elections; AA starts first year under new plan; Danbury Choral Society prepares for coming season; Three Cheers Column goes to Joe Allo, includes picture of Joe Alllo and his son; Editorial on Tom Curley's death; Sports Scope; new part-time psychology instructor Mr. Edmond J. Cain; new departmental plan defines students as "Elementary and General Education, Music Education, and Junior Engineering and Lab. Tech." rather than by Freshman and Sophomore classes; News Briefs column.</p><p>February 1949, Vol. II, No. 2 
DTC receives letters from foster child; "The Night of January 16th" annual school play; New Courier editors; Erutma new officers chosen; Sports Scope column; Senior Scoops, DTC orchestra to present concert; News Briefs; Science Department news; Junior Class officers.</p><p>March 1949, Vol. II, No. 3 
Thomas F. Curley honored at Dedication of Hut, Recreation Hut now call Curley Hall; Neil Wagner profile; Curriculum Committee has difficult task and requires student cooperation; Dramatic Club News; Editorial on CGA's closure of Curley Hall; Music Department students and faculty travel to Baltimore and Washington, DC; Do-Day article; creative writing "A Sad Study In Black or The Life of Mort Tician;" Cast and stage crew of "The Night of January 16" photograph and review of play; Senior Scoops.</p><p>June 1949, Vol. II, No. 4 
Last dance for class of '49; Tony Mercadante elected president of CGA; Do-Day Deans Tony Sagnella and Nill Koulbanis; Science Department news; Sports Scope; Happy Hearts column; poetry corner; Music Education Department news; Senior Scoops.</p><p>October 1949, Vol. III, No. 2 
New staff leaders for Courier; Literary contest; Kappa Delta Pi news; Editorial on Curley Hall; Roving Reporter column; poems by students; Sports column; Curriculum Committee news; Erutma News; Music and Science News.</p><p>March 1950, Vol. III, No. 3
Miss Yonush, the "mother" of the dorm girls profiled; Olga Zukowsky, President of the General and Elementary Educaion Department and treasurer of Form profile; Dramatic Workshop to present "You Can't Take It With You;" Moc Legislature to be held next week at the state capitol; Who's Who? column; Roving Reporter; Do-Day Communique; CGA sponsoring a Vigilante Committee to help regulate conditions in Curley Hall; Creative writing "The Clock" by Harold Walker, and "Retaliation" by John Coyle; poetry by D. Kurt Singer and Bruce Haeger; "Dream Street" mustical comedy written; Junior class trip to Washington, D. C.' Erutma News; Kappa Delta Pi, Senior News; and Public Relations Committee News.</p><p>April 6, 1950, Vol. III, No. 4
DTC proposes Laws in Mock Legislature; Personalities focus on Bud Sisterhemn and Bob Case; Roving Reporter; Platter Chatter by Don Dempsey; Sport Scope; Letter to the Editor: Present departmental organization headed for chaos; Mardi Gras sponsored by the General and Elementary Education Department; new Science Building; Library news.</p><p>April 21, 1950, Vol. III, No. 5
Do-Day Dean Candidates and photographs; Mardi Gras a success; The Voice of '51; Sports Scope, Who's Who? column; Senior May Day; Music Deparment's trip to St. Louis Conference; Parent-Teachers enjoy tour of DTC; Roving Reporter; G.E.E Assembly.</p><p>May 23, 1950, Vol. III, No.6
Do-Day Deans, Florence Hossan and Harry Forsberg, take over day's activities; College to present "You Can't Take It With You;" Junior News; May Day Program; Sports Scope; Who's Who? articles; poetry by Jerry Musson and D. Kurt Singer; "May 10, 1950!! or The day after Do-Day" cartoon "Do we gotta go to Class?"  Around the clock at DTC; Senior Post Training Notes; "At Last" news about seniors.</p><p>June 16, 1950, Vol. III, No. 7
Barbara Austin and Paul Gillotti first music majors to graduate from DTC; Commencement; "You Can't Take It With You" a hit; G.E.E.D. Department news; A.A. News; Senior News; Who's Who? Class Will; Platter Chatter; Dorm Officers; Music Department picnic; Science Department News; Junior Prom, and Roving Reporter.</p><p>October 11, 1950
Third annual CGA banquet; Mr. Otav Sundet, advisor to the Ministry of Education at Oslow, Norway, visits college; Yearbook u nder way; Junior News, Kapp Delta Phi and Library Committee news; Interim interviews begin; Senior news; Dots and Dashes column on campus news; "The Question of Academic Freedom" by Joe Leheney; "A Plea for Understaing" [differences between Americans and Europeans] by Lyman S. Burbank; Sports Scope; AA sponsoring Halloween Dance; "A Better Athletic Program" article.</p><p>November 2, 1950
Courier to begin school-wide poll today and tomorrow to determine how well informed students and teachers are; Wayne Engle, freshman assistant editor; Reverend Craw speaks at Forum; Irene Fenick elected queen of the Danbury Hat Parade; Fred Canfield becomes President of the CGA; Erutma membership drive ends soon; President's Corner; Women's AA in Intramurals; news briefs; "Sophisticated Lady" prom.</p><p>December 4, 1950
Student Study Curriculum and Committee's proposals presented to school; Drama Workshop; Juniors hold carnival; Mock Legislature; Basketball season opens; AA news; "The Twenty-Fifth Hour; from Fables to Facts" by J. Leheny.</p><p>December 15, 1950
Annual Christmas concert presented by the Danbury Choral Society was shared by the Dramatic Club of the college; Bills sent to mock legislature; Mr. Petteresch at United Nations; Forum speaker Dr. Lyman Burbank on "Contemporary Europe;" Who's Who? column; Sports News; The Sweeper column; "The Clock" by Harold Walker.</p><p>March 19, 1951
DTC students recognize problem of Curley Hall; names accepted for Who's Who; Thirty students attend Hartford session; Irish square dance; Delegates elected to Eastern States; State Department of Educaion's new rules for teacher certification; Propspects for male enrollment; sophomore ideas on curriculum; "Moroccan Situation" by Al. Hajj; "Accelerated College" by J. Leheny; The Sweeper column; Do-Day planning underway; Faculty news; The Chorus will present "Iolanthe" for its spring concert; Sports news; Photograph of Varsity Basketball Team.</p><p>April 11, 1951
Forty DTC delegates attend Eastern States Conference; The Drama Workshop presented "Doll's House;"  Editorial to clarify the purpose and policy of the Courier; Draft deferment tests; Senior News; Photograph of students making a wish by the well in the "Spring Garden;" Tentative four year curriculum structure has been drawn up by the Curriculum Committee; Who's Who? by M. J. Mulrooney; "Impressions of Mexico" by George LaCava; Juniors elect Do-Day Deans; Forum News.</p><p>May 1, 1951
DTC to present "Lolanthe", Production to benefit college yearbook for 1952; Curriculum plan in final stages; seniors sign for positions after graduation; Conference presents outlines for peace by Pauline Randall; C.E.A. Council news; WAA intramurals in final stages; "Just Ramblin'" by Dot Shaw; Culture and Scholarship at DTC by Jerry Musson; origin of Do-Day; Words and Music by Williard S. Starbard; Duford and Tahan Do-Day Deans; The Sweeper column by Mitzi.</p><p>June 12, 1951
Rabbi Malino speaker at Baccalaureate service; Vincent Cibarelli to head CGA; Senior-Faculty graduation banquet; Dr. Alpenfels, Associate Professor of Education at NYU, to address graduates; Five faculty members to retire; Iran Oil Situation by Alfred Hajj; Sophomores elect new officers; "Incident in Calcutta" by Herb Coleman; "Nature At Its Best" by Wayne Engle; The Sweeper column by Mitzi; Music Department officers; Sports news; AA banquet at Lakeview.</p><p>September 24, 1951
The Courier welcomes DTC Freshmen; Eight New Faculty; Miss Claire Trisch visits Europe; The Interim Program; President's Corner; The Library column; The Sweeper by Myrt and Olga; CGA information; Business column by Lyman B. Burbank; Washington Sidelights by Dot Hogan; Voice of the Frosh; A Junio and Soph Suggests;  AA first social event.</p><p>November 19, 1951
German Professor, Dr. Walter Kamm, Studies DTC System; Muriel Pronovost chosen yearbook editor; Miss Peggy Scanlon joins library staff; DTC observes education week; Curley Hall is changing; The Koren Story by Alfred Hajj; Jazz on Parade by Marie and Joe; Students attend NY Herald Tribune Forum; Faculty news; Forum begins; campus events; winners of the AA Masquerade; Playday at DTC; Clean-up Campaign in Curley Hall; Sports.</p><p>December 12, 1951
Chorus and Orchestra in Christmas Concert; Dr. Kamm honored; Seniors to give ball; Seniors separate again; The Sweeper column; Music Department will present its annual band and orchestrat concert; WAA Intramurals; Photograph of basketball team (identified); AA skating party; Varsity basketball; America, My Homeland by Elsie M. Smith.</p><p>April 8, 1952
Headline: Dwight D. Eisenhower Our Choice"; Co-Ed Capers a great success; Mary Gillotti chosen yearbook editor; Kappa Delta Phi Initiates; Music educators meet in Philadelphia; Training School news; Asia--The Giant by Alfred Hajj; Men's sports; Eastern States Conference; WAA News; Students attend International Relations Forum.</p><p>May 20, 1952
Cibbarelli and George elected officers of the CGA; Work begins on two new buildings; Groundbreaking for new building; </p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref23_j0z" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Supplement, </title>April 1953 through November 1955</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42085" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42085</unitid><unitdate normal="1953/1955" type="inclusive">1953-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_ad4f034ac7caac899e3379adf7578f0f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref24_kva" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo, </title>November 1955 through June 1959</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42084" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42084</unitid><unitdate normal="1955/1959" type="inclusive">1955-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_b9800cc2b718ae0fb99b2aef941e026c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref25_5jf" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, October 1959 through November 1963</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42083" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42083</unitid><unitdate normal="1959/1963" type="inclusive">1959-1963</unitdate><container altrender="Half Document Box, Letter Size" id="aspace_26fa5f98deae109fee361d3004a88d73" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref26_oko" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1964 through December 1965</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42082" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42082</unitid><unitdate normal="1964/1965" type="inclusive">1964-1965</unitdate><container altrender="Medium flat (15 x 12 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_cc725fe813b8e41777d27760a4bec058" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref27_71h" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1966 through December 1968</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42081" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42081</unitid><unitdate normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_04eeb88b9ed23b4df4b9b687750b76a3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref28_2fc" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1969 through December 1972</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42080" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42080</unitid><unitdate normal="1969/1972" type="inclusive">1969-1972</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_3684a061cecba06af08ce5910c3affc4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref29_o4i" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1973 through December 1975</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42079" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42079</unitid><unitdate normal="1973/1975" type="inclusive">1973-1975</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_276ca58161afed891eca82663d70c64f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref30_7w4" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1976 through December 1978</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42078" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42078</unitid><unitdate normal="1979/1979" type="inclusive">1976-1978</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_3d8bfc43f735e39ba237880e56933c9f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref31_5ai" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, February 1979 through December 1981</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42077" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42077</unitid><unitdate normal="1979/1981" type="inclusive">1979-1981</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_10c1d56826714481edeb1c6dfdc3164d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref32_p1y" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1982 through December 1984</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42076" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42076</unitid><unitdate normal="1982/1984" type="inclusive">1982-1984</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_91c5bae8a9ff4b0b6531359b5185e1e5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref33_uyt" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, February 1985 through December 1987</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42075" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42075</unitid><unitdate normal="1985/1987" type="inclusive">1985-1987</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_eea9b64a1483e98495979dea4596f8d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref34_ea6" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1988 through December 1989</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42074" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42074</unitid><unitdate normal="1988/1989" type="inclusive">1988-1989</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_72faa11a1cf5558834c877022dbd2d4a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref35_wf9" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1990 through December 1992</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42073" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42073</unitid><unitdate normal="1990/1992" type="inclusive">1990-1992</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_d2edbff0f6efedce4fafb45ba5495bec" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref36_ba4" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1993 through December 1994</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42072" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42072</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_ead32b4ca6e6cedd345c6234c720c823" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref37_fpt" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1995 through December 1996</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42071" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42071</unitid><unitdate normal="1995/1996" type="inclusive">1995-1996</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_50e7737802dc6c23ee2500be0ea3d196" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref38_8i8" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1997 through December 1998</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42070" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42070</unitid><unitdate normal="1997/1998" type="inclusive">1997-1998</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_d65abffca450c8e8e9e60fd56d60e6e3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref39_zcp" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 1999 through December 2000</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42069" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42069</unitid><unitdate normal="1999/2000" type="inclusive">1999-2000</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (28 x 22 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_e1e590c27b12cece1e758c3ee0b937fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref40_i2q" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 2001 through December 2002</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42068" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42068</unitid><unitdate normal="2001/2002" type="inclusive">2001-2002</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (28 x 22 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_ce4dd900cad577b4bfc503a5c895b5cb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref41_97t" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, January 2003 through December 2004</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42067" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42067</unitid><unitdate normal="2003/2004" type="inclusive">2003-2004</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (28 x 22 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_9dc01454f804a1097815f2e437daa387" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref42_le8" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, February 2005 through December 2005</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42066" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42066</unitid><unitdate normal="2005/2005" type="inclusive">2005</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_b826021697019cc8f7792ccc4ab6688f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">21</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref43_644" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, February 2006 through December 2006</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42065" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42065</unitid><unitdate normal="2006/2006" type="inclusive">2006</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_e60816a0fdfc3f5fe3ca11af15d9de37" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref44_f89" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, February 2007 through December 2008</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42064" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42064</unitid><unitdate normal="2007/2008" type="inclusive">2007-2008</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_452aaa93c23bb74af4da969c50d04d57" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref45_7po" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Echo</title>, February 2009 through December 2010</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42063" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42063</unitid><unitdate normal="2009/2010" type="inclusive">2009-2010</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (28 x 22 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_e049e0cad927e2083763621f4f0bc142" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref82_mod" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Echo, February 2011through December 2015</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="57788" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">57788</unitid><unitdate>2011-2015</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (31.25 x 23 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_4c5c26e1d45e4cb2dfb686492f022407" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">25</container></did><odd id="aspace_094499da9cce4842f0fd79af862aaddc"><head>General</head><p>Currently missing volume LVII of 2011
Currently missing volume LVII of 2012 &amp; LVIII of 2012 Issue #5 &amp; LVIII of 2012 Issue #8
Currently missing volume LVIIII of 2013 Issue #2</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref46_c2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional copies of: <title render="italic">The Echo</title></unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42062" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42062</unitid><unitdate normal="1936/1955" type="inclusive">1936-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_b7131e5ab2b37a11851e053eaad18baa" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">Dup 1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref47_lhr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional copies of: <title render="italic">The Echo</title></unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42061" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42061</unitid><unitdate normal="1955/1963" type="inclusive">1955-1963</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Size Document Box" id="aspace_6182351cb4594b2dcba06c14574b3855" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">Dup 2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref48_s8y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional copies of: <title render="italic">The Echo</title></unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42060" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42060</unitid><unitdate normal="1937/1989" type="inclusive">1937-1989</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (18.5 x 14.5 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_27d0539bda7f7fdadb1a223ef2640a47" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">Dup 3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref49_s2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional copies of: <title render="italic">The Echo</title></unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42059" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42059</unitid><unitdate normal="1990/1999" type="inclusive">1990-1999</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (21 x 17 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_a24c77fdb02e06867ebcae370536f7cb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">Dup 4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref50_gar" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional copies of: <title render="italic">The Echo</title></unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42058" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42058</unitid><unitdate normal="2000/2000" type="inclusive">2000</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (21 x 17 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_fb7ca272842da711671343975b5e3ab8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">Dup 5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref51_mt9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional copies of: <title render="italic">The Echo</title></unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42057" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42057</unitid><unitdate normal="2001/2004" type="inclusive">2001-2004</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (31.25 x 23 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_b46225abf1caa4a2717b3ccd162985fe" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">Dup 6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref52_n21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional copies of: <title render="italic">The Echo</title></unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42056" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42056</unitid><unitdate normal="2005/2007" type="inclusive">2005-2007</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_30b81615c1ddefc8c5b4bdd5c28a6dc1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">Dup 7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref53_ss4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional copies of: <title render="italic">The Echo</title></unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="42055" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">42055</unitid><unitdate normal="2008/2009" type="inclusive">2008-2009</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize (25 x 19 x 3&amp;quot;)" id="aspace_8f494ff4c7bc7966c71066eb3e5e6bd4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">Dup 8</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
