<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctavfpl/ctavfpl_default_ead.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="ctavfpl" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctavfpl/clintonhadsellcollection.xml">clintonhadsellcollection</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Clinton B. Hadsell Collection</titleproper>
<author>Collection processed by Tina Panik, Patrice Celli.</author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>Avon Free Public Library</publisher>
<address><addressline>281 Country Club Road</addressline>
<addressline>Avon</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06001</addressline>
<addressline>email: tpanik@avonctlibrary.info</addressline>
<addressline>URL: https://avonctlibrary.info</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: 860-673-9712</addressline></address>

<date>Feb 06, 2018</date>
<p>https://avonctlibrary.info</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: </num>
<publisher>Avon Free Public Library
<lb/>281 Country Club Road
<lb/> Avon, CT  06001</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection processed by:</label>
<item>Tina Panik, Patrice Celli</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2018 Avon Free Public Library. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname source="DA:CS">Hadsell, Clinton B. (1871-1947)</persname>
</origination>
<unittitle>Clinton B. Hadsell Collection</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1899-1919</unitdate>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>28 linear feet</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Avon Free Public Library</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> 281 Country Club Road</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">The C.B Hadsell Collection contains 269 glass plate negatives and photographs created by Avon resident Clinton B. Hadsell from 1899 to 1919. Each glass plate negative is titled and dated. Detailed historical content for 60 of the Hadsell photos was researched by Avon Town Historian Nora O. Howard for the 2017 Hadsell Brothers exhibit at the Avon Public Library. The collection also includes several boxes of his original camera equipment, including a large Bellows camera, a Cycle Poco No. 1 camera, an ICA Camera, tripod, and wooden mounting frames. Also includes personal items such as scrapbooks, journals, various books, family mementos, postcards. A wooden bench from his family home on East Main Street in Avon, CT is part of the collection. A biography of the Hadsell Family, written by Nora O. Howard in 2017, accompanies the collection. </abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.
</langmaterial>
<physloc label="Physical Location">This collection is available digitally at the CT Digital Archives (http://collections.ctdigitalarchive.org/islandora/object/150002%3A2974) and physically at the Marian Hunter History Room Archives, Avon Free Public Library, 281 Country Club Road, Avon, CT 06001</physloc>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open and available for research. Please contact the reference department at the Avon Free Public Library before visiting to ensure that staff is available and materials are ready. https://avonctlibrary.info/services/history-room/</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>For copyright status, please contact the Avon Free Public Library.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], , [Box no]., Avon Free Public Library</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo>
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The materials in this collection were donated by Doris Miller, Seth Stewart and the Family of Marian Hunter.</p>
</acqinfo>
<bioghist>
<head>Biography</head>
<p>Clinton Bradley Hadsell was born on Nov. 12, 1871 in Avon, CT. He married Lavinia Chloe Miller on June 4, 1901; they had no children. His parents were Jane Marcy Hadsell (1838-1926) and Samuel Hadsell (1833-1900). C.B. Hadsell had two brothers and three sisters:</p>
<p>- Frank Marcy Hadsell (March 31, 1858-February 6, 1949) married Mary Bowen. No children.</p>
<p>- Ida Josephine Hadsell (November 25, 1861- July 21, 1908) married Sidney Redpath in 1883. They lived in Los Angeles. </p>
<p>- Eva Jane Hadsell (January 18, 1865-December 12, 1925) married William Woods in 1898. No children.</p>
<p>- Hattie Isabell Hadsell (January 15, 1868- 1947) married John Carrier (died 1918) of Avon in 1905. They lived on Nod Road. She sold the Nod Road farm to John W. Alsop in 1919. Second marriage to Edgar Fish in 1921 and lived in Hartford. </p>
<p>-Willys (Will) Herbert Hadsell (March 18, 1875-December 9, 1953) lived in Avon. Married Minnie Thurston June 8, 1904. No children. </p>
<p>Hadsell was an amateur photographer and worked at Climax Fuse Company (Avon, CT) for most of his life. Using the dry plate photography method, he portrayed the daily life of Avon and surrounding towns. He captured notable events, local landmarks, and the simple pleasures of living in a small New England village. Clinton's photographs often recorded the exact date, locations and subjects of his photography, thereby creating a legacy of Avon's history at the turn of the century. </p>
<p>He spent his career at the Climax Fuse Company (later called Ensign-Bickford) as a foreman and inspector. In 1926, Hadsell was severely injured when he was hit by a car on Route 44, Avon, CT in front of his house. He retired from Ensign-Bickford in 1929. </p>
<p>Clinton Hadsell died November 13, 1947 at age 76. His funeral was held at the Avon Congregational Church two days later. His wife, Lavinia Hadsell died in 1968 at age 85. </p>
<p>For a detailed family history please see (https://collections.ctdigitalarchive.org/islandora/object/150002%3A3624)</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
<p>This collection includes glass negatives, photographs, photo albums, cameras and camera equipment, a tripod, journal, books, post cards, music scores, a scrapbook and miscellaneous items from C.B. Hadsell's personal life.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement>
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>These items are boxed and arranged by subject under the "Hadsell, Clinton" heading in the archive room.</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<corpname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Avon (Conn.) -- History-- 19th century</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Avon (Conn.) -- History -- 20th century</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Avon (Conn. : Town) -- Pictorial works</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Black and white photographs </corpname>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial>
<head>Related Collections</head>
<p>Photographs and diaries by Frank Hadsell, Clinton's brother, are also available in the Marian Hunter History Room.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<separatedmaterial>
<head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Some of C.B. Hadsell's photographs are framed and on display throughout the Avon Free Public Library.</p>
</separatedmaterial>


<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>