<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctwspwhs/ctwspwhs_default_ead.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="ctwspwhs" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctwspwhs/wllocalhistory.xml">wllocalhistory</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>The Westport Library Local History Files</titleproper>
<author>Collection guide written by The Westport Library and Westport Historical Society. </author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>Westport Historical Society</publisher>
<address><addressline>25 Avery Place</addressline>
<addressline>Westport</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06880</addressline>
<addressline>email: cheryl.bliss@gmail.com</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://www.westporthistory.org</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: 203-222-1424</addressline></address>

<date>Apr 30, 2018</date>
<p>http://www.westporthistory.org</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: WL 001</num>
<publisher>Westport Historical Society
<lb/>25 Avery Place
<lb/> Westport, CT  06880</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection guide written by:</label>
<item>The Westport Library and Westport Historical Society</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2018 Westport Historical Society. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname source="DA:CS">The Westport Library </persname>
</origination>
<unittitle>The Westport Library Local History Files</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1900s-early 2000s</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="ctwspwhs" countrycode="us">WL 001</unitid>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>30 lft. </extent>
<extent>5 file cabinets (20 drawers)</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Westport Historical Society</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> 25 Avery Place</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">The Westport Library's extensive Local History Files are a unique, rich resource that contains newspaper and magazine articles, brochures, reports, manuscripts and ephemera on topics about Westport's past and of local, regional and national interest. These items were selectively chosen by reference librarians over many decades and  some were contributed by researchers and residents. </abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language> .
</langmaterial>
<physloc label="Physical Location">Filing cabinets, labeled A to E, in the Westport Historical Society Archives. Rare and fragile items are stored in the Westport Historical Society vault.</physloc>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for public access and remains available for research use by The Westport Library and Westport Historical Society staffs, patrons, community members, students, and other interested parties and scholars. Westport Library and Westport Historical Society restrictions apply. </p>
<p>For access to the collection, please consult the Library website: </p>
<p>https://westportlibrary.libguides.com/localinformation/HistoryFiles</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>For copyright status, please contact the Westport Historical Society.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], , [Box no]., Westport Historical Society</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo>
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>This collection of unique records that provide an unparalleled look back into Westport's history was created in the early 1900s by The Westport Library Reference Department. In 2017, The Westport Library announced a collaboration with the Westport Historical Society to transfer, by long term loan, to preserve the Library's historical files, and to give reasonable and continued public access to these files by Library and Westport Historical Society patrons, communality members, students, Library staff and other interested parties.</p>
</acqinfo>
<bioghist>
<head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Since 1886, The Westport Library has been devoted to enriching the intellectual and creative lives of the community. The Westport Library started The Local History Collection as a clippings file in the mid 20th century.  The goal was to collect, archive, and make available to the public special items, articles and ephemera that pertained to the town of Westport, greater Fairfield County, and important people who lived therein. Items were added to the collection to until the early 21st century.</p>
<p>To prepare for the relocation to the Westport Historical Society, the Library asked local historians and archival experts to review the contents, identify documents that are unique and historically significant, and create a thematic organization of the subject folders. </p>
<p>In 2017 The Westport Library loaned its Local History Files to the Westport Historical Society, a nonprofit 501c3 educational institution established in 1899 to collect and preserve the regional history of Westport. The Library considerers its research resource a natural adjunct to the Westport Historical Society Archives, which houses primary documents chronicling Westport's past, and seeks to deepen the appreciation of Westport's heritage among town residents and to increase awareness of the importance of preserving the town's heritage and its historic buildings and landmarks. </p>
<p>For more information and access to the Local History Files visit:</p>
<p>https://westportlibrary.libguides.com/localinformation/HistoryFiles</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
<p>This research resource contains clippings, brochures, reports, articles, photographs and ephemera related to government, schools, businesses, organizations, houses, buildings, sites, events and world famous and locally significant residents in the Westport, CT area.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement>
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>These materials were arranged alphabetically by subject heading until August 2017. When the Local History Files collection moved to the Westport Historical Society, the folders were re-grouped from an alphabetical organization system to a thematic one. Under each thematic category, folders are now organized by subject, arranged alphabetically. (There is a list of materials filed under each subject.)</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" role="subject">Westport (Conn.) - History</geogname>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" role="subject">Westport (Conn.) - Biography</geogname>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Local government - Connecticut -Westport </subject>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Brochures</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Printed ephemera </genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">newspapers</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Programs</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports and Studies</genreform>
</controlaccess>
<separatedmaterial>
<head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Rare and fragile items were extracted from the collection and are stored in the Westport Historical Society's vault. For a list of these items, contact the Westport Historical Society's Archives department for more information.</p>
</separatedmaterial>


<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>
