<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctsobm/ctsobm_default_ead.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="ctsobm" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctsobm/barnesfamilypapers.xml">barnesfamilypapers</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Bradley Barnes Family Papers</titleproper>
<author>Collection guide written by Marie Secondo and Bonnie Plourde. </author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>Barnes Museum</publisher>
<address><addressline>85 North Main St.</addressline>
<addressline>Southington</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06489</addressline>
<addressline>email: secondom@southington.org</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://thebarnesmuseum.weebly.com</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: 860-628-5426</addressline></address>

<date>Jul 16, 2018</date>
<p>http://thebarnesmuseum.weebly.com</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: BBFP</num>
<publisher>Barnes Museum
<lb/>85 North Main St.
<lb/> Southington, CT  06489</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection guide written by:</label>
<item>Marie Secondo and Bonnie Plourde</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2018 Barnes Museum. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname source="DA:CS">Barnes, Bradley </persname>
</origination>
<unittitle>Bradley Barnes Family Papers</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive">1749-present</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="ctsobm" countrycode="us">BBFP</unitid>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>Over 100 containers plus exhibits</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Barnes Museum</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> 85 North Main St.</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">This collection consists of all archived material from the Bradley Barnes family housed at the Barnes Museum in Southington Connecticut. </abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language> .
</langmaterial>
<physloc label="Physical Location">Throughout the Barnes Museum homestead located at 85 N. Main Street, Southington, Connecticut.</physloc>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection open for research.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>Copyright 2018 Barnes Museum ALL RIGHTS RESERVED, certain artifacts subject to individual copyright.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], , [Box no]., Barnes Museum</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo>
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Bequethed to the Town of Southington and Southington Public Library by Bradley H. Barnes, 1973.</p>
</acqinfo>
<bioghist>
<head>Biography</head>
<p>Beginning as a six room Greek Revival style homestead, the Barnes Museum was built in 1836 for Amon and Sylvia Bradley and was lived in by the Bradley/Barnes family for 137 years.  Amon was a Southington entrepreneur and he and Sylvia raised their three children, Franklin, Alice and Emma in the old homestead.  After Amon's death in 1906, Bradley Barnes, Amon's grandson, inherited the homestead and lived in the house till his death in 1973.  The entrepreneurial ventures started by Bradley Barnes' grandfather and father, as well as his own investments, gave Bradley the title of "richest man in Southington".  Upon his death in 1973, Bradley willed his entire fortune away to friends and employees, as well as local schools, libraries and hospitals.  He then bequeathed his family homestead, along with all of its contents, to the Town of Southington to be run under the direction of the Board of Directors and Southington Public Library as a museum.</p>
<p>Today, the Barnes Museum is a 3000+ square foot homestead on an acre lot in downtown Southington, Connecticut.  All archived material and artifacts are housed in the main building, two story barn (~2000 square feet) and connected garages.  </p>
<p>Amon Bradley (born February 20, 1812 in Southington, Connecticut - died August 19, 1906) Son of Ichabod and Abigail (Moore) Bradley he was the youngest of eight children.  He spent his early years on the family farm and was educated in district schools.  At the age of 19, his schooling finished, Amon took the first step in his long and successful business career, traveling in the South as a "Yankee Peddler," selling various dry goods and notions.  Two years later, in 1833, he returned to Southington and opened a dry goods and general merchandise store known as Amon Bradley and Company.  After the acquisition of a partner, Merit N. Woodruff, a former store clerk, the business was renamed Bradley and Woodruff.  It continued as such until the partnership was dissolved in 1865, and the store was once again known as Amon Bradley and Company.</p>
<p>In 1836, Amon married Sylvia Barnes of Southington, the daughter of Truman and Lowly (Barret) Barnes.  The couple moved into the house which Amon had built at 85 North Main Street and began to raise a family.  Their three children were Franklin B. Bradley (1857-1917), Alice (Bradley) Barnes (1849-1897), and Emma (Bradley) Yeomans Newell (1857-1917).</p>
<p>Throughout his long life, Amon Bradley was active in civic, business, and political affairs.  He was a member of the first Southington Fire Department organized in 1834.  During the 1840s, he served a term as sheriff.  When Lewis Academy was erected, 1846-1848, he was a member of the building committee.  He was instrumental in securing a charter for the Southington Savings Bank, serving on that institution's first board of directors.  When the Southington Cutlery Company was incorporated in 1867, Amon was named its first president.  He was the town postmaster from 1851-1863 and a Democratic representative to the state legislature in 1863, 1864, and 1866.  For a number of years, Amon was the town's oldest Freemason, having joined Friendship Lodge, No. 31, A.F. and A.M., in about 1850.</p>
<p>In 1886, Amon, long since retired from his Sheriff's post, he retired from his mercantile business and devoted most of his time to real estate and other investments; which he had been involved with for some time.  The amount of property he acquired in town may be gauged by Francis Atwater's observation in his "History of Southington" that Amon was "so thoroughly in possession of much real estate that one might almost say he had a mortgage on it all."  In addition to his investments, Amon also continued his work as an agent for the Aetna Insurance Company which he had joined in the 1870s.</p>
<p>When Amon Bradley died in 1906 at the age of 94, he had long been recognized as the wealthiest and most influential citizen in Southington.  </p>
<p>Sylvia Barnes Bradley (born October 28, 1818 in Southington, Connecticut - died December 11, 1903) Daughter of Truman and Lowly (Barrett) Barnes, she married Amon Bradley October 9, 1836.  She spent her entire life in Southington. </p>
<p>An editorial published in the Southington News, on the occasion of her husband's death in 1906, spoke of his happy married life with Sylvia and was a fitting tribute to her.  It said in part, "...Sylvia Barnes by disposition was lovable.  Early in life she was known as "Aunt Sylvia" by the young people of the town.  They went to her with all their sorrows and joys.  She possessed all of the attainment that a woman of her early day should have and in addition she exercised a judgment commonly called tact.  It was a great help to her husband...Her going left a husband who longed to follow her.  Without her there was no charm in life for him."</p>
<p>The diaries kept by Sylvia and her children, Franklin, Alice, and Emma do however shed some light on Sylvia's life.  Not surprisingly, washing, ironing, gardening, and tending to her children's needs were her priorities as it was for most women of that era.   </p>
<p>Franklin B. Bradley (born in Southington, Connecticut February 20, 1843 - died March 4, 1907 at the age of 64) was the son of Amon and Sylvia (Barnes) Bradley.  He was educated in Southington schools and at Lewis Academy before going on to Yale College where he was a member of the class of 1864. </p>
<p>In 1869, Franklin married Julia Arnold of New Britain.  The couple had one son, Amon Edward Bradley, born in 1870.</p>
<p>After several years spent working in his father's mercantile business in Southington, Franklin, along with another local man, Averisto Lewis purchased the carriage bolt machinery from Captain Julius B. Savage of Southington.  They moved the machinery to Cleveland, Ohio, in the summer of 1869 and established The Cleveland Norway Bolt Company.  In 1872, Franklin sold his interest in the firm and moved back to Southington.  He then held a position in a firm that manufactured eyelets and hardware, until it was sold to the Southington Cutlery Company in the late 1870s.  Franklin was subsequently associated with the Bridgeport Power Company and a brokerage business with offices in Hartford.  After his father's death, he was also occupied as executor of his estate.</p>
<p>Politically, Franklin Bradley was a Democrat; the one office he ever held was a registrar of voters.  Like his father, he was a Mason and a member of Friendship Lodge A.F. and A.M.</p>
<p>An editorial published at the time of his death described Franklin as "Generous and 'A Gentleman'...democratic in his bearing and esteemed for his ability and good Fellowship."</p>
<p>Upon her death in 1919, Franklin's wife, Julia (Arnold) Bradley, bequeathed to the Town of Southington money to establish Bradley Memorial Hospital.</p>
<p>Julia Arnold Bradley (born October 21, 1843 in New Britain, Connecticut - died February 17, 1919 at the age of 75 in Southington, CT). She married Franklin Bradley on June 16, 1869 and had one child, Amon Edward Bradley (born April 5, 1870 - died September 4, 1916 at the age of 46 of chronic alcoholism).</p>
<p>It was because of Julia Bradley that Southington has a hospital today.  Julia bequeathed $250,000, from what was practically her entire estate, for the establishment of a hospital to be built for the people of Southington.  She stipulated that her endowment be invested and reinvested until there was sufficient funding within twenty-one years of her death.</p>
<p>Organization of the Hospital Corporation of Southington was established shortly after her death. The Bradley Trust Fund began to grow until 1922, where upon officers and trustees were elected from some of Southington's prominent sons in business and banking.  The Bradley Memorial Hospital was dedicated on July 9, 1938 at a cost of $225,000, which included the building, sidewalks, landscaping, equipment, electrical and plumbing.</p>
<p>The Southington Hannah Woodruff Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution (DAR) was led by Julia and met at her home for the first time on June 25, 1897.  The chapter was formed with Julia Bradley as organizing regent.</p>
<p>Alice (Bradley) Barnes (born October 22, 1849 in Southington, Connecticut - died June 30, 1897 at the age of 47) the daughter of Amon and Sylvia (Barnes) Bradley.  Alice was educated in local Southington schools, including Lewis Academy, and at Professor Hubbard's School in New Haven.</p>
<p>She married Norman Adelbert Barnes on October 9, 1873.  Norman was a clerk at her father's company.  She had two siblings, Franklin, her senior, and Emma, the youngest Bradley child. Alice had one son, Bradley Henry Barnes in 1883 who was the last family member to live in her beloved childhood family homestead on North Main Street until 1973. She and her husband were members of the Southington First Baptist Church. Her long agonizing and courageous death prevented her from spending time with her parents at their home, which she normally visited daily.  Alice was kept confined to her chambers for six months. She and her son Bradley recited an evening prayer every night until her last breath.  </p>
<p>*Note - Alice's grandfather, Truman Barnes, and her husband Norman's grandfather, Joel Barnes, were brothers.  Their mutual great-grandfather was Jonathan Barnes.</p>
<p>Norman Adelbert Barnes (born August 18, 1843 in the Marion section of Southington, Connecticut - died March 8, 1911) son of Joel and Anna (Clark) Barnes. He married Alice Bradley on October 9, 1873 and had one child, Bradley Henry Barnes born on January 27, 1883. Norman was educated at local schools and Lewis Academy, where he taught school for a time.  Norman was a clerk at Amon Bradley and Company until that firm was disbanded.  At that time, he went into the mercantile business with Merit N. Woodruff, Amon Bradley's former partner.  He was later employed briefly as secretary and treasurer of the Aetna Nut Company.  In 1873, Norman joined the wholesale mercantile firm of W.M. Reed and Company in New Haven and was with them until 1878 when he became an employee of the Atwater Manufacturing Company in Southington.  He subsequently became secretary and treasurer of that company.</p>
<p>In terms of local affairs, Norman Barnes was a member of the First Baptist Church, served as president of the Southington Board of Education, and was a member of the Mason's Friendship Lodge # 33.</p>
<p>Bradley Henry Barnes (born January 27, 1883 in Southington, Connecticut - died February 23, 1973 at the age of 90) Son of Norman Adelbert Barnes (1843-1911) and Alice (Bradley) Barnes (1849-1897). His ancestry, on both paternal and maternal sides, date back to the late 17th century; his earliest known ancestor was Stephen Barnes who settled in Branford, Connecticut.</p>
<p>He married Leila Holcomb Upson (10/31/1884-10/10/1952) on October 5, 1910 in a quiet ceremony. They moved into the Bradley homestead on North Main Street, which was built by Bradley's grandfather, Amon Bradley, in 1836.  Bradley had recently remodeled the homestead. The 17-room home, furnished with family heirlooms, antique furniture, and rare Oriental rugs, was surrounded by beautifully landscaped grounds.  The 'Old Homestead' was featured in the "Country Homes" magazine, November-December, 1922 issue. Five years later, in 1927, Bradley and Leila purchased a summer home at Indian Cove, Guilford, Connecticut, which they named "Rockedge" where they spent their summer months.   </p>
<p>The couple was devoted to one another, and Leila was Bradley's constant companion and helpmate until her untimely death in October 1952, at the age of 67.  On the day she died, Bradley wrote the last entry in her diary, "End of world for me...My all gone forever."   He directed that her bedroom in the Southington house be locked.  Bradley kept the rest of the house and grounds essentially the same as they were when Leila had last seen them.  And so the house remained until Bradley's death in 1973; he lived another 20 years and was 90 years old upon his death.  </p>
<p>Being there were no direct family members left to hand the old homestead down to, he decided to bequeath it to the Town of Southington to be used specifically as a historic library and museum.  Realizing the historic significance of the collection he and his family had accumulated, he appointed the Southington Library Board of Directors to oversee the museum; given their ability and knowledge of the curatorial skills needed to put the collection in order.</p>
<p>Today, the homestead on North Main Street in Southington, Connecticut remains as the Barnes Museum.  Each year visitors come from every state in the United States and approximately 49 countries worldwide.  </p>
<p>Leila Holcomb (Upson) Barnes (born October 31, 1884 in Southington Connecticut - died October 10, 1952 at the age of 67).  Leila was the daughter of Frank Root Upson (10/12/1855-1/23/1917), who was the owner of the Upson &amp; Brothers Grocery Store located on the corner of Center and North Main in Southington, Connecticut in the old Oxley Building (as it was named during the turn of the 20th century).  Her mother was Hattie (Holcomb) Upson (9/25/1858-6/27/1913).  Her Grandfather, Andrew Upson (1825-1865) served as Captain in the 20th Connecticut Volunteer Infantry during the Civil War. She married Bradley H. Barnes on October 9, 1910.  They had no children.  They resided in what is known today as the Barnes Museum at 85 North Main Street in Southington, Connecticut.  Their homestead was built in 1836 for Amon &amp; Sylvia Bradley, Bradley Barnes' grandparents.</p>
<p>Leila was an avid horticulturalist and spent many hours with her husband taking care of the grounds of their home in Southington and their summer home (Rockedge) in Guilford on the Connecticut shore line.  Their gardens were so magnificently groomed they were featured in the November/December 1922 Issue of Country Home Magazine.</p>
<p>Leila was an accomplished artist and of the 136 paintings in the Barnes Museum, 61 are hers. She also had a fascination with Asian art and collected numerous oriental artifacts; however, she never traveled outside the boundaries of New England.  There are original containers and receipts for the purchases she made at antique shops, as well as estate and auction sales, that were meticulously recorded in her diaries. </p>
<p>Emma Bradley (born August 19, 1857 in Southington, Connecticut - died November 21, 1917) was the youngest daughter of Amon and Sylvia (Barnes) Bradley.  She attended local schools and Lewis Academy, where she graduated from as class salutatorian in 1876. She inherited considerable wealth from her father's estate. </p>
<p>In 1888, Emma married Edward S. Yeomans, owner of a local livery stable, who came to Southington from his native Litchfield, Connecticut.  In 1896, he sold his interest in the stable to W.A. Taylor and established a brokerage business in New Haven with W.T. Dill, known as Yeomans and Dill.  Mr. Yeomans died December 20, 1905 at the age of 51.  An editorial published at the time of his death described him as "...a lover of horseflesh and...a horseman (with)...a reputation that was more than local.  Possessed of a cheery disposition, he made many friends; and he retained them."</p>
<p>Emma remarried Henry H. Newell in 1909, a retired sales agent for a local bolt company.  The couple lived in the Whittlesey-Neal residence, now the Southington Elks Lodge.</p>
<p>According to Francis Atwater's "History of Southington," Emma "was very fond of nature and the last years of her life were spent among her flowers which she loved passionately.  A disease of the ear made it very hard for her to hear as well as difficult to converse with her friends and, therefore, her flowers were a great comfort to her."</p>
<p>Emma died November 21, 1917 at the age of 60; just hours before her husband Mr. Newell&#x00E2;۪s death the following day at the age of 66.  Both passed from complications of spinal meningitis.</p>
<p>In her will, among other bequests, Emma provided funds for a public drinking fountain to be erected in memory of her father on the Southington town green and for two fountains for animals to be erected in memory of her first husband, Edward Yeomans.  One monument stands in downtown Southington and one in the Plantsville section of Southington. She also provided funds for an annex to the old Public Library building (now home to the Southington Historical Society) in memory of her mother and known today as the Sylvia Bradley Memorial Room.</p>
<p>Jesse Olney M.A. LL.D (born October 12, 1798 in Union, Tolland County, Connecticut - died July 31, 1872 in Stratford, Connecticut) lived in Southington from 1833 to 1854 and resided on 16 acres on the west side of North Main Street. He represented the town 10 times in the state legislature and for two years as comptroller of the state.  He was devoted to the improvement of local public schools and was a member of the Baptist Society until 1841 where he was a founding member of the Unitarian Society. He was a member of the Southington Friendship Lodge #33 A.F &amp; A.M.</p>
<p>He married Elizabeth, daughter of Eli Barnes of New Haven. They had nine children, of which only six lived to adult age.   Bradley Barnes called them Aunt and Uncle as Elizabeth was a direct descendant of his father's family.</p>
<p>Author of highly acclaimed elementary school textbooks, Jesse published his first edition of a geography &amp; atlas textbook in 1828.  The 100th edition was published in 1860 and there were 98 editions printed with millions sold. It was used for over 30 years in almost every public and private school in the United States. No American book at that time had such high sales, second only to Webster's American Spelling book.   He traveled extensively throughout Europe perfecting his textbook facts.  After these books he wrote a series of Arithmetic, History and Reading books.  His History of the United States and Family Book of History gained popular recognition as well.   </p>
<p>Andrew Upson (born May 18, 1825 in Southington, Connecticut - died February 19, 1864 at Tracy City, Tennessee).  Son of Levi and Lovisa Todd Upson.  Andrew married Elizabeth L. Gridley (April 1, 1827-March 17, 1910) on April 18, 1850.  The couple settled on a farm in Southington in 1852.  They had four children- Ida, Frank, Willi, and Mary.  Frank Upson was the father of Leila Upson Barnes who would grow up to marry Bradley H. Barnes and live in the homestead now known as the Barnes Museum in Southington, Connecticut.  Andrew was a school teacher at Salem, N.J., Wellsboro, Pa and Corning N.Y., after graduating from Yale College in 1849. He represented the Town of Southington in the state Legislature in 1854.  Andrew enlisted as 1st Lieutenant in Company E, of the 20th Connecticut Volunteers of the Union Army in August 1862.  He was the local recruiting officer along with Captain Samuel S. Woodruff.  Andrew was captured at Chancellorsville and held prisoner at Libby Prison for two weeks, then released to rejoin his company.  He was then promoted to Captain of Company K.  Company K was ambushed by rebel guerrilla forces at Tracy City, Tennessee where upon he was shot three times and later died of his wounds.   He was honored as a "God-fearing, God-trusting soldier" fighting for a cause he so fervently believed in. Andrew Upson is buried in Quinnipiac cemetery off Marian Avenue in the Plantsville section of Southington.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
<p>This collection consists of AAA paperwork, automobile archives, building records, blueprints, books (including bibles, diaries and schoolbooks), Bradley Memorial Hospital records, calendars, cemetery records, civil war diaries, civil war letters, magazines, newspapers, currency, deeds, documents, indentures, poetry, wills, financial reports, receipts (including bank receipts), newsletters, genealogy, greeting cards, yearbooks, letters, maps, atlases, marriage certificates, matchbook covers, military documents, music rolls, National Carriage Builders Association documents, posters, postcards, reports (including Town of Southington annual reports), diplomas, decrees, commencement exercises, report cards, scrapbooks, stamps, sheet music, telephone directories and theater programs.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement>
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>These materials are arranged by type and are boxed and/or filed within the Barnes Museum Homestead.
AAA- American Automobile Association
Automobile- 272 Automobile Models, Makes &amp; accessories catalogs circus 1903-1949
Bibles (31)
Building records and blueprints
Books (500)
Bradley Memorial Hospital, 1922
Calendars 1883-1953 (95)
Cemetery records
Civil War Diaries, Private Hail S. Grannis 1864-1865
Civil War Letters, Captain Andrew Upson 1863-1864
Connecticut Quarterly Magazine, 10 volumes 1895-1906
Currency
Deeds
Documents (Indentures, Family Diaries (52) 1853-1952, Original Family Poetry, Family Wills, Financial reports and bank receipts, Newsletters, etc.)
Genealogy study guides and books, ancestral family tree, scrolls and charts
Greeting cards- Christmas, New Year, Valentine's Day, Birthday, Easter, Thank you, Wedding (circa 1855-1950s)
High School Yearbooks (Southington) 1931, 1935, 1939, 1979
Letters- social and business
Magazines (9169) 225 titles, 24 categories, circa 1894-1973
Maps and Atlases
Marriage certificates
Matchbook covers (2395)
Military ephemeral- WWI, early military orders, includes a complete collection of all paperwork and artifacts given to Lt. Allan Upson
Music rolls (271)
National Carriage Builders Association
Newspapers (1822) 64 titles
Photographs 1850-1973- prints, etchings, engravings, lithographs, tin types, daguerreotypes (see Barnes Museum Photograph Collection for more information)
Posters
Postcards
Receipts- original business letterheads
Reports- annual Town of Southington
School books
School diplomas
Degrees
Commencement exercises and report cards
Scrapbooks, family handmade circa 1885
Sheet Music (228)
Stamps
Telephone directories, 1950
Theater programs, 1910-1947, 836 from 87 theaters
Flags</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<famname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Barnes family</famname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Bradley family</persname>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial>
<head>Related Collections</head>
<p>See also Upson Family Papers Collection and Barnes Museum Photograph Collection.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<separatedmaterial>
<head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Due to the nature of the Barnes Museum, some items in this collection are on permanent display around the homestead, while others are stored and brought out periodically.  Certain items are never placed on display and can be viewed by request and for research purposes only.  All parts of this collection are housed at the Barnes Museum located at 85 N. Main Street in Southington, Connecticut.</p>
</separatedmaterial>


<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>

