<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctsobm/ctsobm_default_ead.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="ctsobm" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctsobm/upsonfamilypapers.xml">upsonfamilypapers</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Upson Family Papers</titleproper>
<author>Collection guide written by Marie Secondo and Bonnie Plourde. </author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>Barnes Museum</publisher>
<address><addressline>85 North Main St.</addressline>
<addressline>Southington</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06489</addressline>
<addressline>email: secondom@southington.org</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://thebarnesmuseum.weebly.com</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: 860-628-5426</addressline></address>

<date>Jul 16, 2018</date>
<p>http://thebarnesmuseum.weebly.com</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: UFP</num>
<publisher>Barnes Museum
<lb/>85 North Main St.
<lb/> Southington, CT  06489</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection guide written by:</label>
<item>Marie Secondo and Bonnie Plourde</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2018 Barnes Museum. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname source="DA:CS">Barnes, Bradley and Barnes, Leila Holcomb Upson Bradely</persname>
</origination>
<unittitle>Upson Family Papers</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive">1749-1952</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="ctsobm" countrycode="us">UFP</unitid>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>20 plus boxes</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Barnes Museum</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> 85 North Main St.</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">This collection consists of all archived material from the Leila Holcomb Upson Barnes family housed at the Barnes Museum in Southington Connecticut.</abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
.
</langmaterial>
<physloc label="Physical Location">Throughout the Barnes Museum homestead located at 85 N. Main Street, Southington, Connecticut.</physloc>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection open for research.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>&#x00C2;&#x00A9; 2018 Barnes Museum ALL RIGHTS RESERVED, certain artifacts subject to individual copyright.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], , [Box no]., Barnes Museum</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo>
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Bequeathed to the Town of Southington and Southington Public Library by Bradley H. Barnes, 1973.</p>
</acqinfo>
<bioghist>
<head>Biography</head>
<p>Beginning as a six room Greek Revival style homestead, the Barnes Museum was built in 1836 for Amon and Sylvia Bradley and was lived in by the Bradley/Barnes family for 137 years.  Amon was a Southington entrepreneur and he and Sylvia raised their three children, Franklin, Alice and Emma in the old homestead.  After Amon's death in 1906, Bradley Barnes, Amon's grandson, inherited the homestead.  Bradley Barnes married Leila Holcomb Upson in 1910, and together they lived in the house till her death in 1952.  Bradley remained in the homestead until his death in 1973. The entrepreneurial ventures started by Bradley Barnes' grandfather and father, as well as his own investments, gave Bradley the title of "richest man in Southington".  Upon his death in 1973, Bradley willed his entire fortune away to friends and employees, as well as local schools, libraries and hospitals.  He then bequeathed his family homestead, along with all of its contents, to the Town of Southington to be run under the direction of the Board of Directors and Southington Public Library as a museum.</p>
<p>Today, the Barnes Museum is a 3000+ square foot homestead on an acre lot in downtown Southington, Connecticut.  All archived material and artifacts are housed in the main building, two story barn (approx. 2000 square feet) and connected garages.</p>
<p>Bradley Henry Barnes (born January 27, 1883 in Southington, Connecticut - died February 23, 1973 at the age of 90) Son of Norman Adelbert Barnes (1843-1911) and Alice (Bradley) Barnes (1849-1897) His ancestry, on both paternal and maternal sides, date back to the late 17th century; his earliest known ancestor was Stephen Barnes who settled in Branford, Connecticut.</p>
<p>He married Leila Holcomb Upson (10/31/1884 - 10/10/1952) on October 5, 1910 in a quiet ceremony. They moved into the Bradley homestead on North Main Street, which was built by Bradley's grandfather, Amon Bradley, in 1836.  Bradley had recently remodeled the homestead.  The 17 room home, furnished with family heirlooms, antique furniture, and rare Oriental rugs, was surrounded by beautifully landscaped grounds.  The 'Old Homestead' was featured in the "Country Homes" magazine, November-December, 1922 issue. Five years later, in 1927, Bradley and Leila purchased a summer home at Indian Cove, Guilford, Connecticut, which they named "Rockedge" where they spent their summer months.</p>
<p>The couple was devoted to one another, and Leila was Bradley's constant companion and helpmate until her untimely death in October 1952, at the age of 67.  On the day she died, Bradley wrote the last entry in her diary, "End of world for me...My all gone forever." He directed that her bedroom in the Southington house be locked.  Bradley kept the rest of the house and grounds essentially the same as they were when Leila had last seen them. And so the house remained until Bradley's death in 1973; he lived another 20 years and was 90 years old upon his death.</p>
<p>Being there were no direct family members left to hand the old homestead down to, he decided to bequeath it to the Town of Southington to be used specifically as a historic library and museum.  Realizing the historic significance of the collection he and his family had accumulated, he appointed the Southington Library Board of Directors to oversee the museum; given their ability and knowledge of the curatorial skills needed to put the collection in order.</p>
<p>Today, the homestead on North Main Street in Southington, Connecticut remains as the Barnes Museum.  Each year visitors come from every state in the United States and approximately 49 countries worldwide.</p>
<p>Leila Holcomb (Upson) Barnes (born October 31, 1884 in Southington Connecticut - died October 10, 1952 at the age of 67).  Leila was the daughter of Frank Root Upson (10/12/1855-1/23/1917), who was the owner of the Upson &amp; Brothers Grocery Store located on the corner of Center and North Main in Southington, Connecticut in the old Oxley Building (as it was named during the turn of the 20th century).  Her mother was Hattie (Holcomb) Upson (9/25/1858 - 6/27/1913).  Her Grandfather, Andrew Upson (1825-1865) served as Captain in the 20th Connecticut Volunteer Infantry during the Civil War. She married Bradley H. Barnes on October 9, 1910.  They had no children.  They resided in what is known today as the Barnes Museum at 85 North Main Street in Southington, Connecticut.  Their homestead was built in 1836 for Amon &amp; Sylvia Bradley, Bradley Barnes' grandparents.</p>
<p>Leila was an avid horticulturalist and spent many hours with her husband taking care of the grounds of their home in Southington and their summer home (Rockedge) in Guilford on the Connecticut shore line.  Their gardens were so magnificently groomed they were featured in the November/December 1922 Issue of Country Home Magazine.</p>
<p>Leila was an accomplished artist and of the 136 paintings in the Barnes Museum, 61 are hers. She also had a fascination with Asian art and collected numerous oriental artifacts;  however, she never traveled outside the boundaries of New England.  There are original containers and receipts for the purchases she made at antique shops, as well as estate and auction sales, that were meticulously recorded in her diaries. </p>
<p>Andrew Upson (born May 18, 1825 in Southington, Connecticut - died February 19, 1864 at Tracy City, Tennessee).  Son of Levi and Lovisa Todd Upson.  Andrew married Elizabeth L. Gridley (April 1, 1827 - March 17, 1910) on April 18, 1850.  The couple settled on a farm in Southington in 1852.  They had four children - Ida, Frank, Willi, and Mary.  Frank Upson was the father of Leila Upson Barnes who would grow up to marry Bradley H. Barnes and live in the homestead now known as the Barnes Museum in Southington, Connecticut.  Andrew was a school teacher at Salem, N.J., Wellsboro, Pa and Corning N.Y., after graduating from Yale College in 1849. He represented the Town of Southington in the state Legislature in 1854.  Andrew enlisted as 1st Lieutenant in Company E, of the 20th Connecticut Volunteers of the Union Army in August 1862.  He was the local recruiting officer along with Captain Samuel S. Woodruff.  Andrew was captured at Chancellorsville and held prisoner at Libby Prison for two weeks, then released to rejoin his company.  He was then promoted to Captain of Company K.  Company K was ambushed by rebel guerrilla forces at Tracy City, Tennessee where upon he was shot three times and later died of his wounds.   He was honored as a "God-fearing, God-trusting soldier" fighting for a cause he so fervently believed in. Andrew Upson is buried in Quinnipiac cemetery off Marian Avenue in the Plantsville section of Southington. </p>
<p>Allan Gridley Upson (1887-1952) born in Southington, Connecticut was the grandson of Captain Andrew S. Upson and Elizabeth Gridley Upson.  Allan was the son of Frank and Hattie Holcomb Upson and brother of Leila Holcomb Upson Barnes who was married to Bradley H. Barnes and would later live in the homestead now known as the Barnes Museum in Southington, Connecticut.  Allan married Rosaline Taylor while serving in the military.  He served in WWI as 2nd Lieutenant in the 301 Machine Gun Btln Co. D. in St. Aignam, France.  He enlisted in August 1912 at Camp Fort Dix, N.J. for basic training.  He then served at Fort Adams, RI and Fort Devens, Massachusetts.  Allan reenlisted several times and was discharged in 1919, however, he served in the reserves until 1929.  Allan Upson was the secretary of Atwater Manufacturing Company in Southington, Connecticut after his military career ended.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
<p>This collection consists of archived material including diaries, diplomas, school degrees, photographs, family business records, Civil War letters, Civil War muster rolls, United States pension certificates, WWI memorabilia, Civil War memorabilia, deeds, land records, land titles, books, Upson Association of America documentation, records and receipts signed by Governor and Attorney Marcus Holcomb, and history of the twentieth Connecticut Volunteer Infantry.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement>
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>These materials are arranged by type and are boxed and/or filed within the Barnes Museum Homestead.</p>
<p>Leila Upson Barnes Diaries- 1935-1952
Leila Upson Barnes High School Diploma-1899 
Early family photographs
Family grocery store information and photos 
Andrew Upson Diary-1848
Degree from Yale College class of 1849- Andrew Upson
Civil War Letters written by Captain Andrew Upson- 1862-1864
Civil War Muster Roll 1862
United States Pension Certificate for Elizabeth Upson and children- 1875
Sergeant Allan Upson (brother of Leila Upson Barnes) WWI memorabilia
WWI military photographs
Deeds &amp; Land Titles 1749-1804
Books: 
Upson Family in America
Directory of the Upson Association of America 1940
History of the Twentieth Connecticut Volunteers (Captain Andrew Upson personal incident entry)
Governor and Attorney Marcus Holcomb records pertaining to the Upson Barnes family</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Barnes, Bradley H., 1883-1873</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Barnes, Leila Holcomb Upson, 1884-1952</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Upson, Andrew, 1825-1864</persname>
<corpname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Upson, Hattie Holcomb, 1858-1913</corpname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Upson, Frank Root, 1855-1917</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Upson, Elizabeth Gridley, 1827-1910</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Holcomb, Marcus H. 1844-1932</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Upson, Allan, 1887-1952</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Grannis, Hial S.</persname>
<subject encodinganalog="650">American Civil War</subject>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Family Photographs</genreform>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial>
<head>Related Collections</head>
<p>See also Barnes Museum Photograph Collection and Bradley Barnes Family Papers</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<separatedmaterial>
<head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Due to the nature of the Barnes Museum, some items in this collection are on permanent display around the homestead, while others are stored and brought out periodically.  Certain items are never placed on display and can be viewed by request and for research purposes only.  All parts of this collection are housed at the Barnes Museum located at 85 N. Main Street in Southington, Connecticut.</p>
</separatedmaterial>


<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>

