<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY-P"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/ypm.izar.000940">ypm.izar.000940</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Addison Emery Verrill Archives </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Verrill (Addison Emery) Archives</titleproper>
            <author>Daniel Jonathan Drew</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>170 Whitney Avenue</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06511</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">peabody.permissions@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://peabody.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:title="http://peabody.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2014</date>
            <num>IZAR.000940</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Tuesday April 30, 2019 at 06:30</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>translation missing: en.enumerations.resource_finding_aid_description_rules.Finding aid created in accordance with Manuscripts and Archives Processing Manual</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Addison Emery Verrill Archives</unittitle>
         <unitid>IZAR.000940</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
            </corpname>
         </repository>
    
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">10</extent>
         </physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1864/1926">1864-1926</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_0aeb830d1def1256971081191ae1a761">The archives of Addison Emery Verrill, accumulated over his lifetime, notably including Yale teaching and research materials.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_ce14a9f23d25bc8ed74ad740e4241b75">
            <language>In English.</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local_peabody">
               Verrill, Addison Emery
            </persname>
         </origination>
      </did>
      <prefercite id="ref1">
         <head>Cite As</head>
         <p>Addison Emery Verrill Archives, Invertebrate Zoology, Yale Peabody Museum</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist id="ref2">
         <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
         <p>Addison Emery Verrill (b. 1839, d. 1926) was born in Greenwood, Maine. Early accounts chronicle his ability as a naturalist while he was growing up in Norway, Maine, where his family moved in the early 1850s. Following his training under Louis Agassiz at Harvard University, Verrill, only 25 years old, accepted a position as Yale University's first Professor of Zoology. Thus began a career spanning more than 40 years teaching at Yale and serving as a curator at the Yale Peabody Museum. His lifelong devotion to taxonomic research resulted in the initial development of extensive collections at Yale in a wide variety of taxa.</p>
         <p>Remarkably, Verrill published more than 350 papers and monographs in his long career, and is credited with having described more than 1,000 species of animals in virtually every major taxon. A quick review of literally every major field guide to the invertebrates of the Atlantic coast, Bermuda, the Caribbean and the tropical eastern Pacific coast will reveal a wealth of Verrill's species, which remain valid even after years of taxonomic revisions by subsequent researchers. A search of early Verrill publications documents his breadth of interests, which included parasitology, mineralogy and botany.</p>
         <p>By any account, Verrill was considered an indefatigable worker; various biographies of him portray his incredible devotion to work, fueled by an almost inexhaustible stamina. He continued to publish large monographs well after his retirement in 1907 until his death in Santa Barbara, California, in 1926.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="ref4">
         <head>Description of the Material</head>
         <p>These papers include correspondence, manuscript related material, field notes, and biographical material.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79074102"
                   source="lcsh">
            Connecticut
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="local">
            Maine
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="local">
            USA
         </geogname>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
            Correspondence 
         </genreform>
         <genreform source="local">
            Field notebooks
         </genreform>
         <genreform source="local">
            Manuscript materials
         </genreform>
         <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">
            Yale Peabody Museum
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043367"
                   source="naf">
            Yale University
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref6" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_d942cf19c194949309aae8188b39adcd">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>These include correspondence with numerous researchers from around the world, touching on topics of evolution, systematics and zoology. Also included are correspondence from his day to day work as Curator.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>A. Howard Clarke Correspondence. Correspondence from A.H. Clarke to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001113</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1879-1880</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref8" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A. Howard Clarke Correspondence. A letter from A.H. Clarke to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending specimens (presumed to Gloucester Fisheries). He asks some questions about various lots. There are identifications in Verrill's hand on back of the letter.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001687</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Nov 1879</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref9" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A. Howard Clarke Correspondence. 2 letters from A.H. Clarke to A.E. Verrill on USFC letterhead out of Gloucester, MA. One giving a list of Octocorallia from various Gloucester Fish Lots. The other discussing an odd fish.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001114</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">23 Oct 1879 - 30 Sep 1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Albert G. Wetherby Correspondence. Correspondence from A.G. Wetherby to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001368</unitid>
               </did>
               <c id="ref11" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Albert G. Wetherby Correspondence. A letter from A.G. Wetherby containing a list of shells sent to the Museum, most appear to be freshwater. He also asks Verrill about future exchanges of West Coast shells. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001369</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alexander Emmanuel Rodolphe Agassiz Correspondence. Correspondence from A.E. Agassiz to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001093</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1886</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref13" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alexander Emmanuel Rodolphe Agassiz Correspondence. Letter from A.E. Agassiz to A.E. Verrill discussing Echinus, Periaster and other Blake Expedition specimens.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001094</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">09 Nov 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref14" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alexander Emmanuel Rodolphe Agassiz Correspondence. Letter from A.E. Agassiz to S.F. Baird asking the whereabouts of specimens packed and sent by A.E. Verrill. The letter must have been forwarded to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001095</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">25 Nov 1886</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alexander Goodman More Correspondence. Correspondence from A.G. More to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001133</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1876</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref16" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alexander Goodman More Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from A.G. More to A.E. Verrill thanking Verrill for 4 paperes he sent on the "Giant Cuttle-fishes" and also discussing the identity of a Cephalopoda stranded in Kerry [Ireland?]. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001156</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">26 Jul 1876</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alfred Merle Norman Correspondence. Correspondence from A.M. Norman to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001135</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1870</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref18" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alfred Merle Norman Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from A.M. Morman to A.E. Verrill thanking him for a box of specimens he received and telling him he is readying specimens for exchange. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001158</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">25 Apr 1870 - 26 Apr 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref19" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alfred Merle Norman Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from A.M. Morman to A.E. Verrill telling him that instead of sending 2 boxes of specimens through the Smihtsonian, he is sending them direct to Yale. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001161</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">30 Sep 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alpheus Hyatt Correspondence. Correspondence from A. Hyatt to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001226</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1893</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref21" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alpheus Hyatt Correspondence. A letter from A. Hyatt to A.E. Verrill informing Verrill he should not send the sponges that Verrill asked him to identify. Hyatt tells him it has been a long time since he worked on sponges and does not think himself capable of doing the work in a timely manny. He also asks Verrill if their are any sponges from Yale College still in his posession. If so, he asks that Verrill send hima list so he could return them.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001227</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">21 Dec 1893</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alpheus Spring Packard Correspondence. Correspondence from A.S. Packard to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001136</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref23" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alpheus Spring Packard Correspondence. A letter from A.S. Packard to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending the enclosed specimens. See Invoice Ledger. the letter appears to be related to the list of specimens in proximity to the letter in the Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001462</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Dec 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref24" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alpheus Spring Packard Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from A.S. Packard to A.E. Verrill. Brief note about "Lutken's remarks on A. Mex." Note: D.V. Rhodes did not know who "ASP" was. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001159</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Archibald Pride Correspondence. Correspondence from A. Pride to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001304</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1871</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref26" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Archibald Pride Correspondence. A letter from A. Pride inquiring if the museum would be interested in purchasing a male and female skeleton of Megaceros hibernicus (Irish Elk).</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001305</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">03 Nov 1871</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>August Assmann Correspondence. Correspondence from A. Assmann to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001418</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1867</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref28" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>August Assmann Correspondence. A letter from A. Assmann to A.E. Verrill apparently discussing Lepidoptera and Coleoptera. The letter is in German. See YPM Zoology Acc. No. 248. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001419</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">03 Jan 1867</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Berlin H. Wright Correspondence. Correspondence from B.H. Wright to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001280</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1885</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref30" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Berlin H. Wright Correspondence. A letter from B.H. Wright informing Verrill he has found crustaceans in a cistern and asking him how he can send them for identification.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001281</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">27 Mar 1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Byron D. Verrill Correspondence. Correspondence from B.D. Verrill to his brother, A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001166</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1871-1885</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref32" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Byron D. Verrill Correspondence. 6 letters from B.D. Verrill to his brother, A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001167</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">26 Jul 1871 - 14 Jun 1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>C. Ritter Correspondence. Correspondence from C. Ritter to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001243</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref34" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>C. Ritter Correspondence. A letter from a Dr. C. Ritter to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending a segment tape worm removed from a patient, questionably calling it Ligula, asking for a more definite identification. A Verrll note on the letter reads "supposed human parasite (not one)".</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001244</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">16 Nov 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Carl F. Gissler Correspondence. Correspondence from C.F. Gissler to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001245</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1888</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref36" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Carl F. Gissler Correspondence. A letter from C.F. Gissler to A.E. Verrill vouching for the authenticity of the parasite sent to Verrill from Dr. C. Ritter. Apparently, Verrill had expressed doubt it was a human parasite, Gissler, however was present when it was removed from the patient. He goes on to say he thought it either a Taenia medioeannelata or a Ligula.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001246</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">22 Sep 1888</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Chalres Earle Correspondence. Correspondence from C. Earle to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001264</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1886</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref38" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Chalres Earle Correspondence. A letter from C. Earle informing A.E. Verrill he is sending him a coral he collected from Bermuda.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001265</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">08 Dec 1886</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref39" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Chalres Lincoln Edwards Correspondence. Correspondence from C.L. Edwards to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001685</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1900</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref40" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Chalres Lincoln Edwards Correspondence. A letter from C.L. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a can of animals from the Florida Keys in thanks for Verrill giving him some Synaptas the previous December. Verrill note on envelope reads "Edwards Gorgonians sent."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001686</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">23 Apr 1900</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref41" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Charles A. Houghton Correspondence. Correspondence from C.A. Houghton to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001284</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877 - 1881</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref42" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Charles A. Houghton Correspondence. 4 letters from C.A. Houghton discussing taxidermy services rendered for numerous specimens of birds, mammals and reptiles.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001285</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">10 Apr 1877 - 18 Jun 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref43" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Charles A. Houghton Correspondence. A letter from C.A. Houghton informing Verrill he is sending him the bird and mammal mounts. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001370</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">19 Nov 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref44" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Charles Cleveland Nutting Correspondence. Correspondence from C.C. Nutting to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001099</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref45" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Charles Cleveland Nutting Correspondence. Letter from C.C. Nutting requesting the aid of A.E. Verrill in identifying a Gorgonacea coral from the British Virgin Islands.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001100</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">22 Aug 1889</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref46" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Charles Frederic Hartt Correspondence. Correspondence from C.F. Hartt to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001138</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1868</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref47" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Charles Frederic Hartt Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from C.F. Hartt to A.E. Verrill discussing Brazil and West Indian Anthozoa. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001162</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">02 Mar 1868</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref48" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Charles G. Am Ende Correspondence. Correspondence from C.G. Am Ende to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001251</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref49" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Charles G. Am Ende Correspondence. A letter from C.G. Am Ende to S.F. Baird, forwarded to A.E. Verrill. The letter discusses solutions of alcohol and salt created by Am Ende that can be used for the preservation of specimens.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001252</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">06 Aug 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref50" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Charles Hervey Townshend Correspondence. Correspondence from C.H. Townshend to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001272</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1893</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref51" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Charles Hervey Townshend Correspondence. A letter from C.H. Townshend informing Verrill he is sending oysters colleced from Strattford Light in Sep 1892.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001273</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">17 Jun 1893</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref52" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Christian Frederik Lutken Correspondence. Correspondence from C.F. Lutken to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>000942</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1866-1873</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref53" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Christian Frederik Lutken Correspondence. 15 letters from C.F. Lutken to A.E. Verrill discussing exhanges between the YPM and the Zoological Museum, Univerity of Copenhagen. They also discuss Octocorallia, Hexacorallia and Echinodermata research.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001009</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">06 Feb 1866 - 24 Apr 1873</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref54" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Christian Frederik Lutken Correspondence. A letter from C.F. Lutken discussing an exchange. He includes a list of Radiata he is sending. He also says he would send some Crustacea in the future. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001420</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">16 Mar 1867</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clinton Hart Merriam Correspondence. Correspondence from C.H. Merriam to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001517</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1883</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref56" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Clinton Hart Merriam Correspondence. A letter from C.H. Merriam asking Verrill for help in identifying a shell he thinks is Angulus tenellus collected from Long Island, N.Y, on 24 Sep 1883.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001518</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Oct 1883</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref57" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>D. W. Ferguson. Correspondence from D.W. Ferguson to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001257</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1873-1887</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref58" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>D. W. Ferguson. A letter from D.W. Ferguson to A.E. Verrill enclosing Natica heros, Astarte and Tellina. He tells Verrill he may keep them, and also says he does not have the shells in his collection that Verrill had apparently requested in a letter.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001258</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">06 Dec 1873</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref59" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>D. W. Ferguson. A letter from D.W. Ferguson to A.E. Verrill discussing the an echinoderm, Meoma which Verrill was interested in. Ferguson informs him he has sold all but a few of the "light spined variety" and offers one in exchange for other echinodermata not in his collection.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001259</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">09 Feb 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>D.B. Delavan Correspondence. Correspondence from D.B. Delevan to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001371</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref61" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>D.B. Delavan Correspondence. A letter from D.B. Delavan informing Verrill he may keep the Dendrophyllia nigriscens. See YPMZ Acc. No. 781. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001372</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">19 Nov 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref62" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Daniel Addison Heald Correspondence. Correspondence from D.A. Heald to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001278</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1881</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref63" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Daniel Addison Heald Correspondence. A letter from D.A. Heald suggesting a Mr. John Bell to do the taxidermy of the birds for the memorial collection. He informs Verrill that if this is acceptable he will have the taxidermy done on his own expense and have the birds shipped to the College by May 1st.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001316</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">05 Mar 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref64" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Daniel Addison Heald Correspondence. A letter from D.A. Heald informing Verrill the New Guinea Birds have been packed and will be sent. He also says in the future he will send specimens as he can acquire them, all in memory of his son. Also with the letter is a list of birds, presumably from New Guinea in which there is a Verrill note taht reads "Pres. G.M. Heald for Heald mem. Coll" The list has been kept with the letter.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001293</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">06 Apr 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref65" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Daniel Addison Heald Correspondence. A letter from D.A. Heald informing Verrill he would like to send a collection of birds from New Zealand on condition that they be kept together in memory of his son, and be on display in time for graduation so his son's classmates could see them.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001314</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">23 Feb 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref66" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Daniel Addison Heald Correspondence. A letter from D.A. Heald informing Verrill that he was mistaken in his previous letter as the birds are from New Guinea, not New Zealand.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001315</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">24 Feb 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref67" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Daniel Addison Heald Correspondence. A letter from D.A. Heald thanking Verrill for his condolences on the death of his son. He informs Verrill he will donate his son's insect collection in the future.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001279</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">26 Jun 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref68" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Daniel Cady Eaton Correspondence. Correspondence from D.C. Eaton to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001195</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1871</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref69" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Daniel Cady Eaton Correspondence. A letter from D.C. Eaton to A.E. Verrill forwarding a request for exchanges from a Maj. R.B. Beddome of India. The request for exchanges is dated 22 Dec 1869.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001196</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">25 Apr 1871</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref70" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>David Starr Jordan Correspondence. Corresppondence from D.S. Jordan to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001289</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1882 - 1883</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref71" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>David Starr Jordan Correspondence. 3 letters from D.S. Jordan to A.E. Verrill. in regards to the identification of fish.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001290</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 Dec 1882 - 07 Feb 1883</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref72" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dorflinger Glass Company Correspondence. Correspondence from the Dorflinger Glass Company to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001334</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref73" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Dorflinger Glass Company Correspondence. A specimen jar price list sent to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001335</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">08 Mar 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref74" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>E.E. Osgood Correspondence. Correspondence from E.E. Osgood to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001312</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1903</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref75" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>E.E. Osgood Correspondence. A letter from E.E. Osgood to A.W. Phillips forwarded to Verrill by Prof. Phillips. The letter discusses the pending arrival of a collection of Himalayan Butterflies sent by Mr. Osgood.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001313</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">03 Jun 1903</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref76" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Edith J. Blakeslee Correspondence. Correspondence from E.J. Blakeslee to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001302</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1888</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref77" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edith J. Blakeslee Correspondence. A letter from E.J. Blakeslee informing Verrill she is sending him a hummingbird's nest she found in a tree.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001303</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1888</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref78" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Edward Drinker Cope Correspondence. Correspondence from E.D. Cope to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001121</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1891</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref79" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Drinker Cope Correspondence. A letter from E.D. Cope to A.E. Verrill containing the identifications of Reptilia collected by A.H. Verrill and G.E. Verrill. In the letter Cope refers to the island as being Martinique. However they went to Dominica.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001123</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">09 Mar 1891</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref80" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Drinker Cope Correspondence. A letter from E.D. Cope to A.E. Verrill containing a list of lizard species that can be found in the North Bahama Islands, as well as a herpetology reference.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001178</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">20 Nov 1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref81" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Drinker Cope Correspondence. A letter from E.D. Cope to A.E. Verrill discussing a paper on reptiles of the West Indies for reference and informing Verrill he is finishing his work onthe North American Reptilia.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001122</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">23 Feb 1891</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref82" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Edward Norton Correspondence. Correspondence from E. Norton to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001413</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1867</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref83" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Norton Correspondence. A letter from E. Norton informing Verrill he is sending a vairty of insects and encloses a list of named specimens for Yale College. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001414</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">02 Dec 1867</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref84" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Edward Palmer Correspondence. Correspondence from E. Palmer to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001253</unitid>
               </did>
               <c id="ref85" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Palmer Correspondence. A letter from E. Palmer to A.E. Verrill informing him he has sent a box of specimens via Prof. Marsh that contain specimens from the San Diego area. See Invoice Ledger</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001387</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">10 Oct 1876</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref86" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Palmer Correspondence. A letter from E. Palmer to A.E. Verrill informing him he has sent a box of bottles for his identification. The specimens are from Panama, collected by J.M. Dow.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001254</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">14 Dec</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref87" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Edward Perceval Wright Correspondence. Correspondence from E.P. Wright to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001132</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1870</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref88" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Perceval Wright Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from E.P. Wright to A.E. Verrill requesting a copy of Verrill's Notes on Radiata in order to help him in his preparation of the Zoological Record for 1869. He also asks for the reference for a new sponge described by Leidy. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001155</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">18 May 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref89" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Perceval Wright Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from E.P. Wright thanking Verrill for his letter and enclosed photograph and asks for a set of Verrill's Gorgonidae types. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001151</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">23 Aug 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref90" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Edward Perceval Wright Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from E.P. Wright to A.E. Verrill requesting a copy of Verrill's Part IV. Actiniaria of the North Pacific Expedition, and help tracking down a a Joseph Leidy reference. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001154</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">27 Oct 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref91" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ernest F. Coe Correspondence. Correspondence from E.F. Coe to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001675</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1899</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref92" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Ernest F. Coe Correspondence. A letter from E.F. Coe informing Verrill he is sending him a gallinule that he found in New Haven. Verrill note on letter says "1 fresh Florida Gallinule fresh to be mounted"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001676</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">12 Jun 1899</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref93" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Fielding Bradford Meek Correspondence. Correspondence from F.B. Meek to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001268</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1870</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref94" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Fielding Bradford Meek Correspondence. A letter from F.B. Meek asking Verrill for aid in identifying a fossil coral he has sent. He informs Verrill he may keep the specimen.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001269</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">08 May 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref95" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Florence K. Howland Correspondence. Correspondence from F.K. Howland to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001300</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref96" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Florence K. Howland Correspondence. A letter from F.K. Howland to O.C. Marsh, apparently forwarded to Verrill. In it she asks if the museum would accept a collection of bird eggs left by her son. She asks that they be maintained as a unit collection, called the "Howland Collection." An accompanying letter in Verrill's hand, apparently a rough draft, says they would be willing to accept the collection provided that the museum not be required to display all the eggs as a unit in the public rooms for lack of space and out of concern for the condition of the specimens.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001301</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref97" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. Correspondence from F.H. Bradley to A.E. Verrill. All sent from his expedition to Central America.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001433</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1866-1867</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref98" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley from Callao discussing some of the specimens he has sent. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001441</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">01 Aug 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref99" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley discussing his collecting at the Pearl Islands. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001447</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">01 Dec 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref100" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley discussing some of the corals he has collected. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001444</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">01 Oct 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref101" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley discussing his collecting and telling Verrill he is leaving for Callao. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001439</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">09 Jul 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref102" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley informing Verrill he is sailing for Paita and then on to the Galapagos. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001450</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">10 Jan 1867</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref103" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley answering a letter of Verrill's. He discusses plans for more collecting and sending specimens. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001437</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 Jun 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref104" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley informing Verrill he has not sent the Central American specimens yet. He also says he will be going to the Pearl Islands and possibly Callao and Valparaiso before he returns home. He also discusses the origins of some of the Sternbergh collection he has sent. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001436</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">12 May 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref105" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley discussing the barrels of specimens he is sending. Includes localities. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001448</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Dec 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref106" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley informing Verrill he is sending the wet specimens from Central America and discusses his collecting. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001438</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">14 Jun 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref107" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley discussing his collecting in Callao and answering Verrill's letters of July and August. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001442</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">14 Sep 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref108" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley to A.E. Verrill answering a letter from Verrill and discussing his collecting. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001434</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">21 Apr 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref109" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley discussing specimens and his collecting. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001440</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">21 Jul 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref110" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley informing Verrill he intends to go to the Galapagos Islands via Paita instead of direct from Panama. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001449</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">22 Dec 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref111" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley answering Verrill's letter of Sep 8th, and expressing his displeasure with the tone of the letter. Must read!!. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001443</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">22 Sep 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref112" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley discussing his collecting and his returning to the Pearl Islands. He requests $100 from Verrill for alcohol purchase. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001445</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">23 Oct 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref113" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley informing Verrill he is sending the Pearl Islands specimens. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001446</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">27 Nov 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref114" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frank Howe Bradley Correspondence. A letter from F.H. Bradley informing Verrill he will remain for another 2 months and he has sent a barrel of specimens. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001435</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">30 Apr 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref115" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Franz Hermann Troschel Correspondence. Correspondence from F.H. Troschel to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001012</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1869</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref116" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Franz Hermann Troschel Correspondence. Letter from F.H. Troschel to A.E. Verrill. Letter is in german. There appears to be some request regarding Echinodermata.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001013</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">26 Jan 1869</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref117" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Fred Mather Correspondence. Correspondence from F. Mather to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001247</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1885</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref118" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Fred Mather Correspondence. A letter from F. Mather to S.F. Baird, forwarded to A.E. Verrill. In the letter on Forest &amp; Stream letter head, Mather talks about a drainage pipe clogged with some sort of Tunicates. Also in the pipe were Mya, tube worms, Nereis, Mytilus, oysters, jingle shells and small anenomes. A Verrill not on the letter reads "Cynthia partita?"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001248</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">08 Aug 1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref119" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Frederick Habershaw Correspondence. Correspondence from F. Habershaw to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001270</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1878</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref120" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frederick Habershaw Correspondence. A letter from F. Habershaw informing Verrill of a colleague, John H. Mortimer who will be returning to New York soon and has a collection of Scyphozoa he wishes for Verrill to see.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001271</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">26 Jan 1878</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref121" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Frederick J.V. Skiff Correspondence. Correspondence from F.J.V. Skiff to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001597</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1907</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref122" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frederick J.V. Skiff Correspondence. A letter from F.J.V. Skiff to A.E. Verrill informing him he is enclosing a list of material that will be sent.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001598</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">20 Aug 1907</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref123" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Frederick William True Correspondence. Correspondence from F.W. True to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001688</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1899</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref124" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Frederick William True Correspondence. A letter from F.W. True to A.E. Verrill informing Verrill that at the request of J.E. Benedict he is sending the last 2 Yale specimens of Sesarma back to Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001689</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">17 Nov 1899</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref125" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>George Brown Goode Correspondence. Correspondence from G.B. Goode to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001228</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref126" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>George Brown Goode Correspondence. A letter from G.B. Goode to A.E. Verrill informing him he will be sending corals and Ophiuroidea and discusses a proposal for a series of memoirs on the Natural History of Bermuda. He encloses a list of 14 proposed memoirs and suggested authors.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001229</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">17 Jun 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref127" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>George Brown Goode Correspondence. A letter from G.B. Goode to A.E. Verrill informing him he has sent 5 parcels of specimens from Bermuda, including Siderastraea, Eunice, Plexaura, Octopoda, Strombus, Astrangia and Crustacea.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001230</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">19 Jun 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref128" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>George Frederick Matthew Correspondence. Correspondence from G.F. Matthew to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001415</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1868</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref129" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>George Frederick Matthew Correspondence. A letter from G.F. Matthew informing Verrill he is sending his Cuba collection, mostly fossil. See YPM Acc. No. 21. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001416</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">07 Jan 1868</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref130" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>George Henry Horn Correspondence. Correspondence from G.H. Horn to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001426</unitid>
               </did>
               <c id="ref131" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>George Henry Horn Correspondence. A letter from G.H. Horn with a list of identified Coleoptera apparently sent to him by Verrill. A note in Verrill's hand on the letter reads "Salt water &amp; shore beetles." See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001427</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref132" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>George M. Totten Correspondence. Correspondence from G.M. Totten to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001298</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1881</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref133" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>George M. Totten Correspondence. A letter from G.M. Totten informing Verrill he has sent the box of birds collected by Guillermo Nanne from Guatemala.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001299</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">30 Dec 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref134" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>George Perkins Merrill Correspondence. Correspondence from G.P. Perkins to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001682</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1900</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref135" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>George Perkins Merrill Correspondence. A letter from G.P Perkins, informing Verrill that at the request of R. Rathbun, he is sending 3 duplicate invoices of the loans returned by Verrill to the USNM. He regrest the delay to the absence of W.H. Dall.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001683</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">29 Mar 1900</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref136" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Gustaf Lindstrom Correspondence. Correspondence from G. Lindstrom to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001128</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1872</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref137" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Gustaf Lindstrom Correspondence. Transcribed copy of a letter from G. Lindstrom to A.E. Verrill inforimg him he is sending him papers on fossil Corals and requesting copies of Verrill's papers on Radiata. Also discussing coral classification. See Related Object in Assocations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001140</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">30 Oct 1872</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref138" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>H. Wheeler Correspondence. Correspondence from H. Wheeler to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001255</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1865</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref139" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>H. Wheeler Correspondence. A letter from H. Wheeler of Davenport, Iowa to J.D. Dana, forwarded to A.E. Verrill. He informs Dana he is sending a package of minerals and a fossil coral. The minerals are from various localities listed, and the coral from Panama. A Verrill note on the letter reads "Fossil Coral Panama."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001256</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">17 May 1865</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref140" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>H.S. Hoyt Correspondence. Correspondence from H.S. Hoyt to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001677</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1899</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref141" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>H.S. Hoyt Correspondence. A letter from H.S. Hoyt to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending a female antelope head from Colorado.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001678</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">07 Jul 1899</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref142" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>H.T. Woodman Correspondence. Correspondence from H.T. Woodman to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001221</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1886-1887</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref143" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>H.T. Woodman Correspondence. A letter from H.T. Woodman to A.E. Verrill thanking him for his help and telling him of some East Indian corals he has that he thinks Verrill would be interested in.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001232</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">08 Aug 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref144" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>H.T. Woodman Correspondence. A letter from H.T. Woodman to A.E. Verrill asking him for help in identifying corals. He offers to send them, and future interesting specimens, asking only for the freight to be paid and to be given the appropriate credit if they should turn out to be new.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001231</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">08 Jun 1886</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref145" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>H.T. Woodman Correspondence. A letter from H.T. Woodman to A.E. Verrill informing him he has sent a few shells collected some 15 years prior from Tampa Bay, Florida. He describeds the habits of the snails and asks Verrill to identify them.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001222</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Jun 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref146" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>H.W. Beckwith Correspondence. Correspondence from H.W. Beckwith to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001282</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1891</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref147" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>H.W. Beckwith Correspondence. A letter from H.W. Beckwith informing Verrill he is sending humming bird eggs collected from near his house in Eat Lyme, Connecticut.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001283</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">30 Mar 1891</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref148" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry Augustus Pilsbry Correspondence. Correspondence from H.A. Pilsbry to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001182</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1900</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref149" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Henry Augustus Pilsbry Correspondence. A letter and list form H.A. Pilsbry to A.E. Verrill . The letter is telling Verrill he is returning the Bermuda terrestrial snails with the identifications on an enclosed list and discussing a paper on the subject that he is writing.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001183</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">01 Nov 1900</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref150" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry Augustus Ward Correspondence. Correspondence from H.A. Ward to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001176</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887-1892</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref151" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Henry Augustus Ward Correspondence. Letters from H.A. Ward to A.E. Verrill in regards to sales and exchanges of specimens. Also includes lists of various specimens. Letters and lists are bundled together.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001177</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">20 Sep 1887 - 10 Feb 1892</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref152" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry Hemphill Correspondence. Correspondence from H. Hemphill to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001146</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1875</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref153" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Henry Hemphill Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from H. Hemphill to A.E. Verrill telling him he has on hand several species of Echinodermata, Porifera, Anthozoa, etc. he wishes to have named. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001147</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">19 May 1875</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref154" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry Kessler Correspondence. Correspondence from H. Kessler to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001294</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref155" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Henry Kessler Correspondence. A letter from H. Kessler to O.C. Marsh apparently forwarded to Verrill. Kessler asks for an indentification of an animal he had never seen before in the area of Wyoming he was in. A Verrill note on the letter says "Big Cricket."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001295</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">27 Aug 1889</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref156" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry Weatherbee Henshaw Correspondence. Correspondence from H.W. Henshaw to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001373</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref157" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Henry Weatherbee Henshaw Correspondence. A letter from H.W. Henshaw informing Verrill he is sending "leeches" taken from the gut of a Podiceps auritus californicus from Lake Tahoe. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001374</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">24 Mar 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref158" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Herbert C. Reed Correspondence. Correspondence from H.C. Reed to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001690</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1900</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref159" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Herbert C. Reed Correspondence. A letter from H.C Reed to Verrill informing him he is sending a worm specimen found in log of wood from Argentina that he had imprted for his company.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001691</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">25 Jan 1900</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref160" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Horace Francis Carpenter Correspondence. Correspondence from H.F. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001218</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1872</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref161" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Horace Francis Carpenter Correspondence. A letter from H.F. Carpenter to J.D. Dana, and forwarded to A.E. Verrill. The letter says 2 specimens of a new species of shell from Rhode Island have been sent. He states the shells were described in a series of papers on the Conchology of Rhode Island, printed in the Central Falls, RI Weekly Visitor, a copy of which containing the description he has sent.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001219</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Apr 1872</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref162" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Horace Francis Carpenter Correspondence. A letter from H.F. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill informing him J.D. Dana suggested he contact Verrill. He assures Verrill the shells previously sent are a new species and lists a few conchologists he sent the shells to. Some of which disagreed with him. He encloses more of the shells and gives the specific locality.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001220</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">16 Aug 1872</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref163" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Identification Requests. Correspondence with requests for specimen identification.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001117</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref164" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Identification Requests. 2 letters from the Department of Docks, Pier "A," Foot of Battery Place, N.R. to A.E. Verrill. The first letter, informing him a worm eaten specimen of wharf pile is being sent to him. The second letter contains information is regards to specific locallity, depth and tide conditions of the pile. On the second letter Verrill wrote at the top "Teredo bored wood (piles)"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001118</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">17 Jan 1894</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref165" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Identification Requests. A transcribed copy of a letter from O.M. Baker, Webster's International Dictionary to A.E. Verrill asking him to review Funk &amp; Wangall's Standard Dictionary and comment on a page of birds that O.M. Bakers believes are colored wrong. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001149</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref166" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>J. Matthew Jones Correspondence. Correspondence from J.M. Jones to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001260</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref167" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>J. Matthew Jones Correspondence. A post card from J.M. Jones to A.E. Verrill. It is mostly illegible as it has been written over, possibly discussing an exchange.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001261</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">09 Nov 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref168" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>J.H. Sternbergh Correspondence. Correspondence from J.H. Sternbergh to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001395</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1867</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref169" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>J.H. Sternbergh Correspondence. A letter from J.H. Sternbergh acknowledging Verrill's receipt of the tapir (See YPMZ Acc. No. 257) as well as describing some bees he had sent through F.H. Bradley. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001396</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">31 May 1867</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref170" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>James Everhard Benedict Correspondence. Correspondence from J.E. Benedict to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001106</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1895</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref171" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>James Everhard Benedict Correspondence. A letter from J.E. benedict to A.E. Verrill that discusses a loan of Asteroidea to Verril. Specifically Mediaster aequalis, Porania grandis, and Solaster. Also discussed is the cataloging of Porifera.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001107</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">07 Feb 1895</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref172" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>James M. Whiton Correspondence. Correspondence from J.M. Whiton to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001310</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1868</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref173" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>James M. Whiton Correspondence. A letter from J.M. Whiton to G.J. Brush, apparently forwarded to Verrill. The letter discusses the possible donation of an entomology collection by a friend of his, a Mr. Harvey J, Rich. He also talks about Mr. Rich being a possible donor to the Sheffield Scientific School.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001311</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">16 Nov 1868</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref174" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>James Orton Correspondence. Correspondence from J. Orton to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001131</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1868-1870</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref175" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>James Orton Correspondence. A letter from J. Orton to A.E. Verrill informing him he has shipped a can of alcoholic specimens from the West Coast of South America. Included are Crustacea and fishes.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001225</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">07 Oct 1868</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref176" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>James Orton Correspondence. A letter from J. Orton that encloses a list of Reptilia specimens identified by E.D. Cope from the Upper Amazon. He asks Verrill if ther are of interest to him, he would be happy to send the specimens.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001288</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 Mar 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref177" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>James Orton Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from J. Orton to A.E. Verrill telling Verrill the Upper Amazon Reptiles he sent were a present, not and exchange. But requests shells and corals if available. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001150</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">19 Mar 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref178" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Joel Asaph Allen Correspondence. Correspondence from J.A. Allen to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001286</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1891 - 1892</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref179" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joel Asaph Allen Correspondence. 3 letters from J.A. Allen discussing the identification of birds sent to him from Verrill and Verrill's sons. Some of the birds are from Dominica.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001287</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">19 Jun 1891 - 13 May 1892</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref180" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John G. Anthony Correspondence. Correspondence from J.G. Anthony to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001193</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1868-1869</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref181" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>John G. Anthony Correspondence. A letter from J.G. Anthony thanking A.E. Verrill for the Modiolaria Verrill had sent. He laos asks Verrill what he would like in return.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001194</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">03 Nov 1869</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref182" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>John G. Anthony Correspondence. A letter from J.G. Anthony informing Verrill he is sending the shells from Brazil. He encloses a list of the specimens. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001401</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 Dec 1868</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref183" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>John G. Anthony Correspondence. A letter from J.G. Anthony giving the identification of some shells Verrill had sent him. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001403</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 Jun 1869</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref184" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>John G. Anthony Correspondence. A list of specimens (mollusca) returned to Yale College. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001402</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref185" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Green Brady Correspondence. Correspondence from J.G. Brady to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001241</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1880</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref186" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>John Green Brady Correspondence. A letter from J.G. Brady to O.C. Marsh, forwarded to A.E. Verrill. It informs he is sending a specimen from Sitka, Alaska, collected at 45 fathoms by a halibut fishing vessel,. A Verrill note on the letter reads Verrilliana Blakei.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001242</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Sep 1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref187" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John P. Terry Correspondence. Corresppondence from J.P. Terry to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001291</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887 - 1892</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref188" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>John P. Terry Correspondence. 3 letters from J.P. Terry. In each letter he is sending a specimen (arachnid) for Verrill's identification. On the second letter there is a Verrill note that reads "Salfuga (figd)".</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001292</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 Oct 1887 - 13 Apr 1892</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref189" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Strong Newberry Correspondence. Correspondence from J.S. Newberry to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001595</unitid>
               </did>
               <c id="ref190" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>John Strong Newberry Correspondence. A letter from J.S. Newberry asking Verrill to identify a sponge if possible.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001596</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref191" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Winters Jones Correspondence. Correspondence from J.W. Jones to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001541</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1870</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref192" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>John Winters Jones Correspondence. A letter from J.W. Jones informing Verrill he is sending the "Catalogue of Lithophytes" in behalf of the British Museum.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001542</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">18 Oct 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref193" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Joseph Albert Lintner Correspondence. Correspondence from J.A. Lintner to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001266</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1879</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref194" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Albert Lintner Correspondence. A letter from J.A. Lintner asking Verrill to identify a parasite that was removed from the "lower stomach" of a lamb.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001267</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">27 Oct 1879</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref195" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. Correspondence from J.F. Whiteaves to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001233</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1880 - 1897</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref196" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves thanking Verrill for his notes on the Queen Charlotte Island Echinodermata, Anthozoa, etc. He says he will send Verrill a proof of his paper and asks for any alterations and additions.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001236</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">01 Mar 1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref197" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves asking Verrill to describe the Archaster and the 2 species of Solaster he had previously sent. He informs Verrill to please hold off sending collections until they have had time to settle into the new museum in Ottawa. He also includes a list of desired west coast shells.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001237</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">04 Mar 1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref198" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves asking A.E. Verrill if had time to look at the Queen Charlotte Asteroidea he had sent him the prior summer. Whiteaves is finishing up a report and is anxious to get it off his hands. He also asks Verrill if has finished with the Gulf of Saint Lawrence shells he had sent, as Jeffreys has written requesting to see them.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001234</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">09 Feb 1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref199" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves thanking Verrill for the information he had sent, apparently for a report by Dr. R. Bell. He says he would like to send him a series of Bela from the Gulf of Saint Lawrence sometime in the future and aks for a few specimens of Conella from the west coast. He also is sorry to hear of the death of Dr. Jeffreys.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001238</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">26 Feb 1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref200" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves discussing Bela shells with Verrill and askign for the reutnr of previously loaned specimens.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001679</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">27 Dec 1897</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref201" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves informing Verrill he is sending specimens of Echinodermata from the Queen Charlotte Islands and asking for help in identifications, some of which Verrill may keep. He asks for west coast shells and corals in return. He sent 2 examples of a small Echinus, two specimens of Solaster and a 5 rayed starfish. He says the Echinus may be kept.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001235</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">27 Feb 1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref202" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Joseph Willcox Correspondence. Correspondence from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001168</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref203" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Willcox Correspondence. A letter from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill thanking him for the box of shells Verrill sent in exchange.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001171</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">03 Aug 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref204" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Willcox Correspondence. A letter from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill informing him he has a shipment of Pliocene shells ready to be shipped in exchange for West Coast shells and other specimens. He enclosed a list of the Pliocene shells to be sent.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001169</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">20 Jul 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref205" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Willcox Correspondence. A letter from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill informing him he will ship Pliocene shells to the Peabody Museum, and giving Verrill instructions on where to ship the shells in exhange. .</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001170</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">27 Jul 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref206" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Joseph Willcox Correspondence. A postcard from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill telling him where he can find a duplicate list of the specimens he had sent. Willcox says that when he sent the fossils he did not keep a list himself, but he had sent duplicates to Prof. Whitfield in New York. He tells Verrill if he needs to, he could get a duplicate from him.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001306</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">28 Nov 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref207" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Loomis J. Campbell Correspondence. Correspondence from L.J. Campbell to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001262</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref208" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Loomis J. Campbell Correspondence. A ltter from L.J. Campbell to A.E. Verrill discussing the editing of the dictionary Verrill was helping prepare.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001263</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">02 Jun 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref209" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mary Jane Rathbun Correspondence. Correspondence from M.J. Rathbun to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001680</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1897</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref210" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mary Jane Rathbun Correspondence. A letter from M.J. Rathbun informing Verrill she is sending back the collection of Sesarma she had borrwed. She is also sending Brazilian crabs for S.I. Smith collected by Hartt 1870 and duplicates from R. Rathbun 1875-1877. An Invoice of the Sesarma was enclosed, cataloged separately. See IZAR No. 1684</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001681</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">29 Mar 1897</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref211" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous Correspondence. Miscellaneous correspondence. Letters from unknown people, etc.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001152</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref212" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from "C. Kouser" [Spelling questionable] requestion Gorgonacea from Verrill for research purposes. As well as Asteroidea, Echinoidea and Holothuroidea. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001153</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">17 Dec 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref213" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Moses Harvey Correspondence. Correspondence from M. Harvey to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001172</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1876</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref214" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Moses Harvey Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from M. Harvey to A.E. Verrill discussing a tape worm from a salmon in Newfoundland.. It also discusses the identity of a whale. Verrill wrote on envelope "Harvey, Tapeworm, etc., basking shark". See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001143</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 Oct 1876</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref215" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mrs. R.W. Summers Correspondence. Correspondence from Mrs. R.W. Summers to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001274</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1885</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref216" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mrs. R.W. Summers Correspondence. A letter from Mrs. R.W. Summer informing Verrill she had sent him some specimens from San Luis Obispo, CA for indetification. She also encloses a list of duplicate specimens in her collection for possible exchange.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001275</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">02 Sep 1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref217" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal Correspondence. Personal correspondence to A.E. Verrill. Not related to his research.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001144</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref218" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Personal Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from C. Semper to A.E. Verrill inquiring when he could find Verrill at home in the Last week of November or first week of December. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001145</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">16 Nov 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref219" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Philip Herbert Carpenter Correspondence. Correspondence from P.H. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001129</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1882</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref220" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Philip Herbert Carpenter Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from P.H. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill discussing Crinoidea. He thanks Verrill for copies of his papers on the USFC dredging work. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001142</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Aug 1882</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref221" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Philip Pearsall Carpenter Correspondence. Correspondence from P.P. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001389</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1870</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref222" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Philip Pearsall Carpenter Correspondence. A letter believed to be from P.P. Caprenter forwarding notes on shells from Dr. Dawson and the staff at the British Museum to A.E. Verrill. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001390</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">05 Aug 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref223" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>R. Ellsworth Call Correspondence. Correspondence from R.E. Call to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001179</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1885</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref224" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>R. Ellsworth Call Correspondence. A letter from R.E. Call to A.E. Verrill telling him he is sending Verrill's share of the specimens collected during the "Tennessee shell trip" and thanking him for his contribution.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001181</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">05 Oct 1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref225" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>R. Ellsworth Call Correspondence. A letter from R.E. Call to A.E. Verrill where he is sending Verrill a paper on the Unionids of the Mississippi Valey and box of specimens. He also asks Verrill to contribute expenses for an upcoming collection trip, for which he would send Verrill specimens from.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001180</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">24 Jun 1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref226" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Rev. Lewis Grout Correspondence. Correspondence from L. Grout to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001214</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref227" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Rev. Lewis Grout Correspondence. A letter from L. Grout inforimg A.E. Verrill he is sending him land shells from Natal and Zululand, South Africa for identification and as a donation if desired.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001215</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">04 Jul 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref228" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Richard Rathbun Correspondence. Correspondence from R. Rathbun to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001109</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1880-1884</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref229" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Richard Rathbun Correspondence. 3 letters from R. Rathbun to A.E. Verrill discussing USFC collections.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001110</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">23 Nov 1880 - 27 Oct 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref230" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Robert George Bell Correspondence. Correspondence from R.G. Bell to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001189</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1883</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref231" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Robert George Bell Correspondence. 4 letters from R.G. Bell to A.E. Verrill requestion papers on American shells and inquiriing about exchanges.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001190</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">16 Apr 1883 - 03 Oct 1883</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref232" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Robert Hungerford Correspondence. Correspondence from R. Hungerford to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001249</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref233" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Robert Hungerford Correspondence. A letter from Dr. R. Hungerford to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending a "sort of worm or grub" which had been pulled from a 12 year old boy after it had "gnawed" its way to the surface of the skin near the boys groin. A note by Verrill on the letter reads " Parasitic larva? human".</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001250</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">24 Feb 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref234" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Robert Tracy Jackson Correspondence. Correspondence from R.T. Jackson to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001216</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref235" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Robert Tracy Jackson Correspondence. A letter from R.T. Jackson to A.E. Verrill thanking him for the material and paper Verrill Had sent him. He also inquires of the availability of Pelycopoda specimens for his studies, offering to send material in exchange.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001217</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">06 May 1889</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref236" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Rudolf Leuckart Correspondence. Correspondence from R. Leuckart to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001173</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref237" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Rudolf Leuckart Correspondence. A letter from R. Leuckart to A.E. Verrill. The letter is in german.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001174</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">15 Mar 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref238" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Rudolph Albert von Kolliker Correspondence. Correspondence from R.A. Kolliker to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001010</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1867-1870</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref239" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Rudolph Albert von Kolliker Correspondence. 8 letters from R.A. Kolliker to A.E. Verrill discussing Octocorallia and Hexacorallia research and exchanges.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001011</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">24 Nov 1867 - 05 Jun 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref240" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Samuel Fessenden Clarke Correspondence. Correspondence from S.F. Clarke to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001239</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1881</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref241" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Samuel Fessenden Clarke Correspondence. A letter from S.F. Clarke to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending specimens of American Amphioxus.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001240</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 Jan 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref242" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Samuel Henshaw Correspondence. Correspondence from S. Henshaw to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001276</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1886</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref243" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Samuel Henshaw Correspondence. A letter from H. Henshaw inquiring about the presence of A.S. Packard type specimens in the collection. He encloses a list of the species he is interested in.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001277</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">20 Nov 1886</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref244" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Sanderson Smith Correspondence. Correspondence from S. Smith to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001130</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1887-1892</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref245" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sanderson Smith Correspondence. A letter from S. Smith to A.E. Verrill telling him he has identified some of the shells from Verrill's sons trip to Dominica but is unable to do the rest. He suggests W.G. Binney or H.A. Pilsbry could do more.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001188</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">03 Mar 1892</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref246" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sanderson Smith Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from S. Smith to A.E. Verrill discussing revisions to a manuscript. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001148</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">26 Sep 1887</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref247" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Spencer Fullerton Baird Correspondence. Correspondence from S.F. Baird to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001104</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1880</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref248" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Spencer Fullerton Baird Correspondence. A letter from S.F. Baird to A.E. Verrill inquiring on Anthozoa sent to Verrill for identification from off Georgetown County, South Carolina.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001105</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">28 Jun 1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref249" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Stephen Alfred Forbes Correspondence. Correspondence from S.A. Forbes to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001134</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1879</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref250" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Stephen Alfred Forbes Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from S.A. Forbes to A.E. Verrill discussing Hirudinea, and requesting to see Verrill's Semiscolex grandis. Note on envelope by Verrill, says "Forbes answered leech." See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001157</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">22 Aug 1879</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref251" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>T.A. Verkruzen Correspondence. Correspondence from T.A. Verkruzen A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001184</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877-1882</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref252" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>T.A. Verkruzen Correspondence. A letter from T.A. Verkruzen. The letter is addressed to "the American Naturalists about to visit these seas". This refers to the arrival of the USFC Stmr. Speedwell to Halifax, Nova Scotia, of which Verrill was on board. He discusses his recent dredging work, and gives a list of specimens he left behind for them.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001185</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">06 Aug 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref253" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>T.A. Verkruzen Correspondence. A letter from T.A. Verkruzen to A.E. Verrill thanking him for Verrill's paper of the Mollusca dredged by the USFC. He also discusses the Mollusca fauna of Newfoundland.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001187</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">15 Sep 1882</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref254" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>T.A. Verkruzen Correspondence. A letter from T.A. Verkruzen to A.E. Verrill discussing the Mollusca fauna of Newfoundland and the Grand Banks. He inquires about the dredging work done by the USFC the summer before.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001186</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">29 Mar 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref255" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Theodore Lyman Correspondence. Correspondence from Theodore Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing mostly Echinodermata, particularly Ophiuroidea.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>000943</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1871-1882</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref256" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Theodore Lyman Correspondence. A letter from T. Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing Ophiuroidea. Particularly Hemieuryale, Ophioplocus, Ophiochandrus, Trichaster, Astrogomphus, and Asteroschema.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001006</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">07 Jan 1871</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref257" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Theodore Lyman Correspondence. A letter from T. Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing nomenclature and also mentioning Hemipholis gracilis.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001007</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">11 May 1872</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref258" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Theodore Lyman Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from T. Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing Ophiuroidea collected by USCS Stmr Blake. Particularly Asteronyx liveni and Ophioscolex. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001141</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">13 Oct 1882</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref259" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Theodore Lyman Correspondence. A letter from T. Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing rules of nomenclature and asking Verrill for his works on Corals to aid in the identification of specimens in the Museum Godeffroy, Hamburg Germany.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001008</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">22 Jul 1872</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref260" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Theofore Lyman Correspondence. A letter from T. Lyman informing Verrill he has identified the Ophiuroidea that was sent and would like to keep one of the Hemieuryale in exchange. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001367</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">19 Feb 1875</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref261" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ulysses S. Treat Correspondence. Correspondence from U.S. Treat to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001307</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1863</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref262" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Ulysses S. Treat Correspondence. A letter from U.S. Treat discussing alewifes and menhaden.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001309</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">16 Dec 1863</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref263" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Ulysses S. Treat Correspondence. A letter from U.S. Treat discussing his observations of "English Herrings" and Alewifes. He tells Verrill if it is of interest he may publish his observations if so desried.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001308</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">29 Nov 1863</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref264" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. Correspondence from V.N. Edwards to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001111</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1873-1881</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref265" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens. He lists localities and dates. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001375</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">01 Mar 1878</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref266" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards to A.E. Verrill inforimg him that he is sending a squid for identification.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001112</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">01 Nov 1881</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref267" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens, icluding fish and jellyfish. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001385</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">02 Apr 1873</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref268" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending 2 jars of specimens. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001376</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">03 Apr 1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref269" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of sponges from Nantucket Island. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001380</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">06 Dec</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref270" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001384</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">06 Oct 1873</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref271" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens, inlcuding a gravid lobster, sponges and "sea fleas" (Amphipoda). See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001381</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">12 Jan</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref272" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens with a list of loaclities, inlcuding ascidians. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001382</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">15 Dec 1875</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref273" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens and requests that Verrill identify them. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001383</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">18 Mar 1874</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref274" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimenwith a list of localities. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001379</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">21 Jan 1876</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref275" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens with a list of localities as well as a strange sea urchin with red spines. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001377</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">26 Apr 1876</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref276" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens as well as something collected at Noman's Island.. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001378</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">31 Mar 1876</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref277" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>W.A. Goodyear Correspondence. Correspondence from W.A. Goodyear to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001296</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1885</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref278" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>W.A. Goodyear Correspondence. A letter from W.A. Goodyear inquiring about luminescence in insects.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001297</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">12 Feb 1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref279" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>William Carmichael M'Intosh Correspondence. Correspondence from W.C. M'Intosh to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001137</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1874</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref280" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>William Carmichael M'Intosh Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from W.C. M'Intosh to A.E. Verrill thanking him for the papers Verrill sent. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001160</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">02 Jun 1874</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref281" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>William Healey Dall Correspondence. Correspondence from W.H. Dall to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001191</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1882-1901</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref282" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>William Healey Dall Correspondence. A letter from W.H. Dall to A.E. Verrill discussing the difference between Ringicula leptocheila and Ringicula nitida.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001192</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">01 Dec 1882</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref283" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>William Healey Dall Correspondence. A letter from W.H. Dall to A.E. Verrill thanking him for his Bermuda papers and discussing Mollusca from Bermuda.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001593</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">17 Nov 1900</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref284" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>William Healey Dall Correspondence. A letter from W.H. Dall to A.E. Verrill thanking him for his Bermuda papers and discussing Cardium and other species of Bermuda specimens.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001594</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">23 Jan 1901</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref285" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>William Stimpson Correspondence. Correspondence from W. Stimpson to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001139</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1866</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref286" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>William Stimpson Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from W. Stimpson to A.E. Verrill telling Verrill he has forwarded the specimens requested with a Smithsonian Institute package and asking him to return the bottles from Cape St. Lucas with the other things he borrowed. See Related Object in Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001163</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">21 Dec 1866</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref287" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Teaching Materials</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ed88192ec6b5919b409456601b6994de">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Materials related to Verrill's professorship.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref288" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notebooks.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>002801</unitid>
               </did>
               <c id="ref289" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Notebook. Appears to be a class roster for Zoology and Geology courses. There are also notes about various species.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001077</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1907</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref290" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Manuscript Materials</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_800b6456432768443738be3c0b17daa9">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Rough drafts, figures, line drawings, etc. used in the writing of manuscripts and papers.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref291" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Annelida. Archives related to Verrill's Annelida manuscripts.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001521</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref292" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Annelida. Numerous notes and figures related to marine Annelida of Southern New England. Many used in his 1873 Report on marine invertebrates Vineyard Sound and Southern New England.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001522</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref293" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Annelida. Figures and notes of various Annelida. Mostly Southern New England. Labeled by Verrill as "used of incomplete."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001531</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref294" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Annelida. Numerous copies of Plate 34, Trans. Conn. Acad. Arts. Sci. V. 4. Verrill, New England Annelids.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001547</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref295" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Annelida. 7 "plates" of Annelida. Labeled by Verrill as "Annelida Drawings Used."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001569</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref296" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Annelida. Numerous pages of notes on scale worms (Polynoidae). Most in K.J. Bush handwritting, but many have annotations by Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001634</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref297" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Annelida. Notes on various species of annelida. Included are texts for plates and figures.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001789</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1877-1879</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref298" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Materials related to Verrill's unpublished manuscript on the Alcyonaria of the Blake Cruises.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001793</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref299" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Plates 115-140. Some have notes by Verrill on them. Found together.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001795</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref300" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Proofs of Plates 1-140. Numerous notes by A.E. Verrill on plates. Bound in 10 plate increments.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001794</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref301" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 115, Dasygorgia.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001796</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref302" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 116, Dasygorgia capitata, Riisea paniculata</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001797</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref303" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 117, Dasygorgia spiculosa, Calliacis agassizii, Evacis rugulosa.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001798</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref304" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 118, Dasygorgia.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001799</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref305" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 119, Acanthacis austera, Echinacus armata.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001800</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref306" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 120, Acanthacis austera.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001801</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref307" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 121, Acanthacis scabra.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001802</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref308" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 122.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001803</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref309" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 123, Leptacis rubra, Scleracis pumila.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001804</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref310" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 124, Muricea agassizii, Acromuricea multispina.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001805</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref311" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 125, Echinacis clavata, Muricella (Cyclomuricea) flexuosa, Hyogorgia tenuis.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001806</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref312" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 126, Scleracis, Scleracis petrosa, Thesacis verrucosa, Evacis rubra.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001807</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref313" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 127, Paramuricea spinulosa, Acrogorgia muricata..</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001808</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref314" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 128, Agrogorgia hirtella, Galaxacis microspina.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001809</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref315" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 129, Hyogorgia parviflora.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001810</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref316" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 130, Hyogorgia parviflora, Leptacis rubra.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001811</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref317" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 131, Heteracis rudis, Heteracis mirabilis.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001812</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref318" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 132, Evacis robusta, Evacis rugosa.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001813</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref319" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 133, Evacis hebes, Evacis nivea.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001814</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref320" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 134, Acanthogorgia exigua, Calicogorgia.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001815</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref321" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 135, Acanthogorgia muricata, Cactomuricea setosa.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001816</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref322" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 136, Aristogorgia, Aristogorgia ordinata.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001817</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref323" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 137, Verrucella obesa.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001818</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref324" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 138, Verrucella galaxea.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001819</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref325" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 139, Stenogorgia gemmulata.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001820</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref326" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 140, Nephthyoides nigra, Acronephthya subinermis, Acronephthya spinosa, Chironephthya caribaea.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001821</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref327" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. The plates were wrapped in a paper that has since disintegrated. They we labled "Blake Plates to be[?] stored attic O.K. by Dr. Van Name."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001822</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref328" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Figures, labeled by Verrill as "photo engravings."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001826</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref329" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Numerous figures, photographs and notes. Labeled by Verrill as "mostly photographs used for colored plates and Dupli."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001827</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref330" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Numerous figures, photographs and notes. Includes Muricidae and Chrysogorgia.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001828</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref331" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Photographs and notes. Labeled by Verrill "used Photos....Muricidae Chrysogorgidae etc."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001829</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref332" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Drawings and proofs. Labeled by Verrill "used Drawings and proofs Foreign and native... for Canadian Report, U.S.F. Comm., etc. Pennatulacea, Alcyonacea, Nephthygidae, etc."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001830</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref333" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Photgraphs, figures. Labeled by Verrill "Blake Photos used."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001831</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref334" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Photgraphs. Labeled by Verrill "Photos mostly duplicates, used. Plexauridae, Pennatulidae, Primnoidae, Isidae, etc.""</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001832</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref335" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Notes, figures, proofs, text, etc.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001833</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref336" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Notes, photographs and figures. Labeled by Verrill as "Chrysogorgidae, For Bulletin and text cuts. Radicipes type...."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001834</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref337" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Plate proofs. Numerous notes by Verrill on them.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001835</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref338" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Plate proofs. Numerous notes by Verrill on them.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001836</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref339" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bryozoa. Archives related to Verrill's manuscripts dealing with Bryozoa.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001565</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref340" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Bryozoa. Numerous photos, plates, figures and notes dealing with Bryozoa.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001566</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref341" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cnidaria. A.E. Verrill manuscript materials related to Cnidaria.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001501</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref342" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Stimpson notes for USNM 1571 (YPM No. 35762). From parent lot of IZAR No. 1638.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001759</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1853</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref343" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. 6 figures of Cnidaria, including Pennatula aculeata and Iridogorgia pourtalesii.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001502</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref344" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Figures and dictionary cutouts dealing with Hydroida.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001503</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref345" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. 15 figures, labeled by Verrill as "Radiates." Found in the same folder as IZAR No. 1531.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001532</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref346" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Numerous figures and notes on Hydroida.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001536</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref347" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Compilation of plates of Hydroida. They are bound together. Unknown what publication they were used in.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001556</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref348" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. List of Hydroida and Scyphozoa from Verrill's Report on Vineyard Sound.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001564</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref349" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes and sketches of Actiniaria, labeled by Verrill as "used in 1864."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001568</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref350" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes and sketches of various Cnidaria, such as Edwardsia, Pennatula, etc.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001635</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref351" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes and sketches of various Cnidaria of the North Pacific Exploring Expedition. The notes appear to be William Stimpson's. They contain a description and locality information with annotations by Verrill. Some include USNM numbers. Verrill used them in his papers on the Polyps of the North Pacific Exploring Expedition, published in the Proceedings of the Essex Institue, V. 5.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001638</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref352" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes and sketches of various Cnidaria from F.H. Bradley's Expedition to central America. Labeled by Verrill as "Bradley notes on Radiata used"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001639</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref353" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Edwardsia cretata Stimpson collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1617.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002785</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref354" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Edwardsia clavata Stimpson [=Phellia? Clavata V. Mss.] collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1616.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002786</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref355" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Urticina coccinea V. Mss. collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1583</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002787</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref356" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Dysactis minuta V. Mss collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1570.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002788</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref357" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Sagartia sp. V. collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1567</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002791</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref358" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Metridium fimbriatum collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1592</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002792</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref359" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Actinia multicolor Stimpson collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1613</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002793</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref360" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Actinia like Metridium collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1579</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002794</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref361" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Actinia nigropunctata Stimpson [=Sagartia nigropunctata mss] collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1611</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002795</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref362" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Discostoma fungiforme collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1564</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002796</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref363" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Notes on Dendrophyllia gracilis (YPM No. 8476)</unittitle>
                     <unitid>002799</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref364" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cnidaria. Verrill's handwritten description of Paragorgia pacifica. It is attached to a photograph of the specimen sent by J.F. Whiteaves. See YPM No. 5373A-C.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001524</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref365" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Crustacea of Connecticut. Archives realted to Verrill's unpublished manuscript titled "Report on the Higher Crustace of Connecticut and Adjacent Waters".</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001725</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref366" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Crustacea of Connecticut. Rough draft of the "Bibliography" section for the "Report on the Higher Crustace of Connecticut and Adjacent Waters." According to a note by Verrill, he made an addittion of Rathbun's "Spider Crabs of America" on 15 Oct 1926.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001728</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">15 Oct 1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref367" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Crustacea of Connecticut. A typed copy of Verrill's unpublished manuscript titled "Report on the Higher Crustace of Connecticut and Adjacent Waters." Appears to have been edited, numerous notes were made.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001726</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref368" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Crustacea of Connecticut. Rough draft of the "Explanations of Plates" section for the "Report on the Higher Crustace of Connecticut and Adjacent Waters."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001727</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref369" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Echinodermata. Verrill's manuscript materials related to Echinodermata.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>000947</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref370" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Echinodermata. Photos and plates of Ophiuroidea and Asteroidea.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001562</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref371" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Echinodermata. 3 figures of Echinodermata (Crinoidea, Ophiuroidea). Also a figure of a Foraminifera. Labeled by Verrill as "Echinoderms unfinished."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001563</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref372" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Echinodermata. 6 photos of Ophiuroidea.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001567</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref373" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous. A.E. Verrill manuscript material made up of multiple taxa.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001506</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref374" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Numerous figures, notes, etc. on numerous groups of organisms, inluding Mollusca, Cnidaria, Crustacea, Annelida, Echinodermata, etc. Many of which used in publications. Predominantly of Verrill, but includes material from Bush, Beecher, Clarke and Smith.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001546</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref375" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Notes, figures and descriptios of Cnidaria, Mollusca and Echinodermata. Found in same envelope.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001548</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref376" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Notes, figures and descriptions of Annelida, etc..</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001551</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref377" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Notes, locality data, specimen lists, etc. of various taxa. Labeled as "mostly used in first report."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001559</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref378" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Numerous figures of sequentially numbered Echinodermata, Cnidaria, Mollusca etc. Unknown for what publication.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001629</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref379" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Numerous figures of developmental series.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001631</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref380" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. A plate containing 3 figures of Tunicata and 2 figures of Gastropoda. A note by Verrill says "make same size."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001661</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref381" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Many figures of Cnidaira, Echinodermata, etc. Used in Verrill, 1873. See Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001662</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1873</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref382" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. A rough draft of plates for a publication on the fishes of Bermuda. Unknown if ever published. May have been done in conjunction with G.B. Goode. See Correspondence.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001664</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1900</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref383" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. A rough draft of "True Nature Stories for Boy Scouts." Was published posthumously in 1929. Includes duplicate chapters.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001672</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref384" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Figures of multiple taxa. Including Gastropoda, Octopoda, etc. Found in association with one another in same folder.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001507</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref385" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Figures of multiple taxa. Including mammals, birds, plants. Found in association with one another in same folder.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001508</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref386" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Numerous figures, Eubranchipus vernalis, gastropoda etc. Also included are notes, many dealing with Radiata of Panama, etc.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001523</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref387" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous. Numerous figures, notes and lists of Gastropoda, Annelida, Tunicata, etc. from the New England Coast.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001533</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref388" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mollusca. Verrill's manuscript materials related to Mollusca.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>000946</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref389" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Figures and notes, labeled as "Mollusca, unfinished and imperfect, Deepwater and northern", by A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001510</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref390" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Figures and notes on Montacuta, Corbula and Clione.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001511</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref391" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 15 figures of Bivalvia. Labeled by Verrill as "used."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001512</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref392" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 12 figures of Mollusca, mostly bivalves. Labeled by Verrill as "mostly used."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001513</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref393" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures and notes on the veliger of several species.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001514</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref394" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 4 figures of a gastropod. They were found in an envelope labeled by Verrill as "N. Eng Bryozoa notes and sketches and finished figs." These 4 figures were the only things found in envelope.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001515</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref395" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 7 figures of Limpets.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001516</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref396" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures and plates of bivalves and gastropods used in Verrill's publications in the Connecticut Academy of Arts and Science and the American Journal of Science.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001530</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref397" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures and plates of Mollusca.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001534</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref398" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Notes and figures of Gastropoda. Labeled by Verrill as "unfinished gastropods."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001535</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref399" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Several pages of notes. Appear to deal with Bermuda Mollusca. Probably relating to Verrill and Bush, 1900 paper on the mollusca of Bermuda.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001537</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref400" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 10 figures of Mollusca.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001553</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref401" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures and notes of Mollusca, mostly bivalves. Labeled by Verrill as "Bivalves shallow water."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001554</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref402" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures of Bivalvia and Gastropoda. Labeled by Verrill as "Drawings &amp; Prooffs Shells Bermuda."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001632</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref403" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Photographs of Bivalvia and Gastropoda. Found in same folder as IZAR No. 1632.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001633</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref404" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Handwritten description of Octopus megalops. Apparently Verrill never published the name. See YPM No. 18164.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001636</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref405" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Notes and sketches of Bivalvia (Tellina, Ostrea, ect.).</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001637</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref406" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures of various Mollusca. Labeled by Verrill as "Mollusca figs copied or engraved."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001645</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref407" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 7 figures of Gastropoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001648</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref408" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 28 figures of Gastropoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled by Verrill as "Gastropods deep water drawings used."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001649</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref409" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 11 figures of Gastropoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Cingula etc. 3/4"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001650</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref410" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 4 figures of Limpets. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Limpets 1/2"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001651</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref411" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 4 figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Sipho 2/3"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001652</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref412" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "shallow water Mollusks published Gastropods"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001653</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref413" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Mollusca published Gastropods 1/2"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001654</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref414" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 9 figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Cyclostremea etc. Choristes, Natica "</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001655</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref415" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Cingula etc. New Drawings"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001656</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref416" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled by Bush as "Cylichna etc. Drawings 1895"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001657</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref417" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. A figure of Cingula castanea. It is a frontal view. It is drawn on the same card as YPM No. 17632.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001658</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref418" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Mollusca figures.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001668</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref419" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Several figures of Dentalium. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001670</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref420" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Several figures of Mollusca. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001671</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref421" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Rough copy of some paper on Mollusca (Bela, Mangilia, Dendronotus, Cratena, etc). Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001779</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref422" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Figure of the beak/buccal mass of Architeuthis. It is from Prof. Worth's specimen.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001660</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1870-1880</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref423" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Mollusca figures used in Verrill, 1873. See Associations tab.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001663</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1873</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref424" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 3 figures used in Verrill, A.E. 1882. Trans. Conn. Acad. Arts Sci. 5: 447-588, pl 57, fig. 3-5.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001787</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1882</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref425" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. 2 plates of Bivalvia figures.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001504</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref426" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. A collection of Gastropoda figures, including Crepidula plana.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001505</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref427" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastropoda (Bela, etc.) most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush publication.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001788</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref428" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nemertea. Verrill's manuscript materials related to Nemertea.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>000994</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref429" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Nemertea. Rough copy of Verrill manuscripts related to Nemertea. Most are in A.E. Verrill handwriting, some appear transcribed by K.J. Bush. Some rough figures included. The papers were found bound by string.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>000995</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref430" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Nemertea. A figure of a ribbon worm from Hawaii. C.M. Cooke.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001509</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref431" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Platyhelminthes. Archives related to Verrill's manuscripts dealing with Platyhelminthes.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001549</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref432" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Platyhelminthes. Several notes and descriptions. Labeled by Verrill as "Turbellaria N. Haven. mostly used in 1st Report."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001550</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref433" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Tunicata. Archives related to Verrill's manuscripts dealing with Tunicata.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001643</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref434" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Tunicata. A plate containing 8 figures of Tunicata. One figure is of a Boltenia. Unknow if used in any publication.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001644</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref435" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Tunicata. Several figures of Ascidiacea (Cynthia, etc.)</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001666</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref436" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Tunicata. Notes and figures of various Tunicata (Cynthia, Molgula) labeled as "mostly used" by Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001786</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1871</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref437" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Webster's Dictionary. Archives related to A.E. Verrill's work on the Webster's Dictionary.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001519</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref438" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Webster's Dictionary. Numerous figures of grasses. Also included are 2 lists of grasses and several miscellaneous figures (bird, flowers, fish). Appear to be used in preparation of Verrill's contribution to the Webster's Dictionary.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001520</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref439" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Webster's Dictionary. Numerous figures of miscellaneous organisms (invertebrates, mammals, fish, reptiles, birds, etc.). Most likely used in research for Verrill's dictionary work.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001659</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref440" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Webster's Dictionary. Figures of fossil brids, mammals, dinosaurs, arachnids, etc.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001669</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1889</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref441" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Webster's Dictionary. Labeled as "Dictionary cuts etc. drawings in proof notes and caption." Possibly non-dictionary related material also, including lists of species, etc.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001560</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref442" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Webster's Dictionary. Numerous figures, labeled by Verrill as "Dictionary cuts"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001642</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref443" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Biographical Materials</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series IV</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_4ca613fc0ca4806782701fdc123ad683">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Material related to Verrill's life and achievements.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref444" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Awards. Awards, etc. given to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001014</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref445" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Awards. Diploma recognizing A.E. Verrill's admittance into the National Academy of Sciences.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001015</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">17 Apr 1872</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref446" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Biography. Papers related to A.E. Verrill biography.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001772</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref447" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Biography. 8 copies of Verrill's advertisement to sell the collections.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001777</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1885</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref448" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Biography. A brief biography about Verrill from 1904.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001773</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1904</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref449" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Genealogy. Papers related to Verrill family Genealogy.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001673</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref450" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Genealogy. Ancestors of George W. Verrill and Lucy Hilborn (2 copies). Ancestors in female lines of George W. Verrill (6 copies). Ancestors of Asa Barton, great grandfather of Flora Louise Smith (6 copies).</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001674</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref451" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs, Paintings, etc. Photographs of A.E. Verrill, family, etc.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001603</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref452" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Photographs, Paintings, etc. A painting of A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>005917</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref453" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Photographs. A photo negative of A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001604</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref454" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Postcards. Postcards sent to A.E. Verrill.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001982</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref455" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Postcards. A postcard from E.B. Verrill sent to her father, A.E. Verrill. Digitcal copy only.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001983</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref456" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Research Materials</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series V</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c id="ref457" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Figures. Miscellaneous figures used in A.E. Verrill's research.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001004</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref458" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Figures. On one side of the sheet are 4 figures of Ascidiacea identified by Verrill as "Perophora?". There are also 3 figures Sipuncula identified as "Sipunculid". One the opposing side are 2 figures, male and female of a the Nematoda, identified as "Pontonema maxima"</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001005</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref459" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Figures. A drawing and description of Leioptilum undulatum, from Gulf of Fonseca. See YPM No. 10467.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001540</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref460" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Figures. Miscellaneous figures of Cnidaria, Echinodermata, Mollusca, Anneldia, etc.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001665</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref461" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notebooks. Miscellaneous notebooks used in Verrill's research.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001080</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref462" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Notebooks. The notebook is a listing of species from USFC Stmr. Bache stations. It appears to be a comparison of hard and muddy bottoms, possible used by Verrill for publication.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001081</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-1875</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref463" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notes. Miscellaneous notes used in A.E. Verrill's research.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001623</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref464" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Notes. Found together and labeled by Verrill as notes on Cephalopoda.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001624</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref465" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Notes. Notes on Crustacea collected by F.H. Bradley. Labeled by Verrill as "Bradley's notes on Crustacea etc. Panama."</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001640</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref466" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference Material. Verrill reference material.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001336</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref467" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Reference Material. A list of refernces relating to Echinodermata of Chile and Peru.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001337</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref468" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Reference Material. List of Bermuda planaria published in the Transactions of the Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences. Most are Verrill species.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001340</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1901</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref469" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Reference Material. A list of Gorgonacea synonymies from Kent, 1870.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001539</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Feb 1870</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref470" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Reference Material. 2 reference lists for various species of Annelida, Mollusca, Echinodermata, Tunicata, etc.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001778</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref471" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Research Collections. Archives related to collections received by A.E. Verrill for the purpose of research. Some may have been returned and some retained in the YPM collections.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001096</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref472" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Research Collections. List of Corals received by Verrill for study. Specimens are from the Museum of Comparative Zoology and include speicmens from the U.S. Exploring Expedition, William Stimpson and the Northwest Boundry Survey.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001098</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref473" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Research Collections. List of Echinoidea received from the Museum of Comparative Zoology. The specimens were collected by A.E. Agassiz aboard the USCS Stmr. Blake.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001097</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1877-1879</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref474" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Specimen Lists.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001338</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref475" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. Numerours notes and lists ralated to Mollusca and Radiates. Includes a list from P.P. Carpenter.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001526</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref476" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. List of Corals and Echinoderms in Verril's hand. Also in Verrill's hane, the word "Copied" is written across both lists. Numbers may be catalog numbers.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001339</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref477" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. List of Crustacea from Bermuda.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001552</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref478" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. List of Echinodermata, Bryozoa, Hydroida, etc. Found bound together by string.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001555</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref479" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. List of specimens from various localities in the Bay of Fundy and off Nova Scotia.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001621</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref480" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. Numerous specimen lists. Most appear to be from Gloucester Fisheries Lots.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001622</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref481" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. A list titled "Notes on things from V.N. Edwards". In Verrill's hand. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001386</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1877</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref482" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. List of Crustacea sent to A.E. Verrill from Bermuda. The specimens were collected by T.H. Bean.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001667</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1906</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref483" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. List of Sesarma returned by the Smithsonian. See IZAR No. 1681</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001684</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1906</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref484" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. A list of Gorgoniidae from Panama. Species names are in Verrill's hand. See Invoice Ledger.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001432</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref485" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Specimen Lists. List of pleistocene fossils, mostly Mollusca, possibly collected by Verrill.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001460</unitid>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref486" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Bibliographic Materials</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series VI</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c id="ref487" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bibliographic Materials. Archives related to Verrill's bibliography.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001775</unitid>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref488" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Bibliographic Materials. 4 price lists for various Verrill papers.</unittitle>
                     <unitid>001776</unitid>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1926</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
