<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY-P"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/ypm.ipar.001239">ypm.ipar.001239</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Othniel Charles Marsh Archives </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Marsh (Othniel Charles) Archives</titleproper>
            <author>Samantha Murphy</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>170 Whitney Avenue</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06511</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">peabody.permissions@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://peabody.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:title="http://peabody.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2014</date>
            <num>IPAR.001239</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Tuesday April 30, 2019 at 06:30</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>translation missing: en.enumerations.resource_finding_aid_description_rules.Finding aid created in accordance with Manuscripts and Archives Processing Manual</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Othniel Charles Marsh Archives</unittitle>
         <unitid>IPAR.001239</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
            </corpname>
         </repository>
    
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">2</extent>
         </physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1831/1899">1831-1899</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_cb3878211f95569c3dbd0cfbf45a6827">These are O C. Marsh Archives associated with the Division of Invertebrate Paleontology. This is only a small sample of his archives associated with Yale University.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_8df5dad7aaf7d1da967a958bfbaee38b">
            <language>In English.</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79128954"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               Marsh, Othniel Charles, 1831-1899
            </persname>
         </origination>
      </did>
      <prefercite id="ref1">
         <head>Cite As</head>
         <p>Othniel Charles Marsh Archives, Invertebrate Paleontology, Yale Peabody Museum</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist id="ref2">
         <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
         <p>In 1866, Othniel Charles Marsh was appointed Professor of Paleontology at Yale, the first such position in North America. In 1867, he became curator of the Geological Cabinet at the new Peabody Museum, which was endowed by his uncle, the philanthropist George Peabody. Marsh brought with him 2.5 tons of books and specimens, the bulk of which were accumulated as a Yale College undergraduate and during a lengthy stay in Europe. This collection was the foundation of the vertebrate paleontology collection.</p>
         <p>During a lifetime at Yale, Marsh amassed an impressive collection of vertebrate fossils. Although he and the Peabody Museum would ultimately become famous for their collection of dinosaurs from the American West ? which included type specimens of many of the best known dinosaurs - Marsh?s earliest collections were from the Cretaceous of New Jersey. Under his leadership, the Yale College Scientific Expeditions of 1870?1873 obtained historically and scientifically important collections of fossil mammals, including some of the largest collections of uintatheres, titanotheres, fossil horses, and early primates in the United States. The expeditions also made important contributions to our knowledge of marine life from the Cretaceous, including mosasaurs, pterosaurs (most notably Pteranodon), and the toothed birds Ichthyornis and Hesperornis. In addition, they assembled a sizable collection of fossil fishes from Eocene lake deposits in Wyoming.</p>
         <p>After 1874, Marsh relied almost exclusively on ?professional? collectors, which included both local residents and collectors sent to the American West by Marsh. Marsh?s associates form a ?Who?s Who? of the history of vertebrate paleontology and geology: Erwin H. Barbour, David Baldwin, George Baur, Charles Emerson Beecher, Hugh Gibb, George Bird Grinnell, Oscar Harger, John Bell Hatcher, Arthur Lakes, Otto Meyer, Benjamin Mudge, O.A. Peterson, William Reed, George R. Wieland, and Samuel Wendell Williston.</p>
         <p>According to his biographers, Schuchert and LeVene (1940), Marsh named 344 new species and 161 new genera of fossil vertebrates. His genera include Brontosaurus, Apatosaurus, Stegosaurus, Triceratops and Eohippus. His work and collections were praised by Charles Darwin and Thomas Huxley as some of the most crucial evidence supporting the theory of evolution.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="ref4">
         <head>Description of the Material</head>
         <p>Includes drawings and lithographs of Solnhofen annelids, specimen lists for Keokuk Limestone slabs from Crawfordsville, IN, locality information about the Turners Falls area, a list of correspondence held at the Sterling Library at Yale, and locality information for a Placenticeras specimen sent to Marsh by General John Gibbon.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79074102"
                   source="lcsh">
            Connecticut
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="local">
            USA
         </geogname>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
            Correspondence 
         </genreform>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026387"
                    source="lcgft">
            Maps
         </genreform>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300" source="aat">
            Photographs
         </genreform>
         <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">
            Yale Peabody Museum
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043367"
                   source="naf">
            Yale University
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref6" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Specimen Information</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
            </did>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Illustrations. Drawings and Lithographs of specimens.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001242</unitid>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Specimen Lists.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001243</unitid>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref9" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_51b03d6d3d48bb5b9c695778ebb55e93">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Miscellaneous Archives from O C. Marsh in the collections of Invertabrate Paleontology including locality information and correspondence.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001245</unitid>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Locality Information.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>001244</unitid>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref12" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Locality Information</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e0c1cb03bb2e84328b07e23e25921988">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Locality information for specimens collected or received by O. C. Marsh</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Locality information.</unittitle>
                  <unitid>002430</unitid>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
