<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctwlgca/ctwlgca_default_ead.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="ctwlgca" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctwlgca/2018.17.xml">2018.17</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>World War II Collection</titleproper>
<author>Collection guide written by Julie Hughes. Collection processed by .</author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from the Institute of Museum and Library Services to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>G&amp;B Cultural Center</publisher>
<address><addressline>49 New Street</addressline>
<addressline>Wilton</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06897</addressline>
<addressline>email: juhughes.ibid@gmail.com</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://www.gandbculturalcenter.org</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: </addressline></address>

<date>Jul 02, 2019</date>
<p>http://www.gandbculturalcenter.org</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Collection guide encoded into EAD by . Machine-readable finding aid derived from .
<date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: 2018.17</num>
<publisher>G&amp;B Cultural Center
<lb/>49 New Street
<lb/> Wilton, CT  06897</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from the Institute of Museum and Library Services to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection guide written by:</label>
<item>Julie Hughes</item>
</defitem>

</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2019 G&amp;B Cultural Center. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Collector">
<corpname source="local">G&amp;B Cultural Center</corpname>
</origination>
<unittitle>World War II Collection</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1922-2010">1922-2010</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="ctwlgca" countrycode="us">2018.17</unitid>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>4 linear feet</extent>
<extent>2 Boxes</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>G&amp;B Cultural Center</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> 49 New Street</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">The World War II Collection contains information relating to the participation in and experiences of Georgetown residents during World War II.</abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.
</langmaterial>
<physloc label="Physical Location">49 New Street
Wilton, CT 06897</physloc>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection open for research.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>For copyright status, please contact the G&amp;B Cultural Center.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item Description, Date], World War II Collection, [Item no., Box no.], G&amp;B Cultural Center, Wilton, Conn.</p>
</prefercite>
<bioghist>
<head>History</head>
<p>The United States entered World War II following the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor on December 7, 1941. The conflict with Japan ended August 15, 1945. Germany surrendered on May 7, 1945. </p>
<p>In Georgetown, Conn., as elsewhere in the United States, the local community experienced the war through the draft and volunteering for service of young men and women; rationing of gasoline and other essentials; participation in the war effort through the Red Cross, growing "victory" gardens, and other activities.</p>
<p>According to the research of Marianne Fisher, these are the names of the 215 men and women from Georgetown who served in World War II:</p>
<p>Adams, Kenneth; Adams, Leon; Adams, Vernon; Agoes, Albert; Agoes, Edward; Agoes, Michael; Anderson, Ture; Barbour, Harold B.; Barrelle, Henry; Barker, Charles; Barker, James W., Jr.; Barrett, Clarence L.; Barrett, Charles R.; Barrett, David; Barrett, Homer J.; Barrett, Raymond; Barrett, Warren; Bennett, Richard; Bennett, Robert; Bergholm, Johan G.; Bonsignore, Ignazio,; Carlson, Axel; Carlson, John C.; Carlson, Victor; Carlson, Woodrow; Carroll, Edward; Cody, William; Colley, Everett W.; Colley, Harry L.; Connery, Michael J.; Cyr, Albert L.; Davidson, John G.; DiFranco, Russell, J.; DiOrio, James V.; Drab, Joseph; Driscoll, James C., Jr.; Driscoll, John R.; Dunham, Chester; Eckelberry, Dr. J. H.; Ekelund Eric; Engdahl, Bernard; Engdahl, Richard; Ericson, Eric F.; Ericson, Harry; Eyes, Raymond; Eyes, Robert; Fagerstrom, Hugo W.; Favreau, Lawrence; Favreau, Leslie; Ferguson. Frank; Floge, William C.; Fuller, John W.; Gabriel, Francis; Haajanen, Martin R.; Hanley, William B., Jr.; Hanson, Fred E.; Hanson, John; Hanauer, Boyd; Harco, Kazmer; Harco, Peter P.; Heibeck, George W., Jr.; Hermansdorfer, Ruth M.; Hill, Otto; Hochman, Isadore; Holmes, Henry T., Jr.; Holmes, MacAdams; Ingham, John S., Jr.; Jaderlund, Alfred; Jaderlund, Eiton; Jaderlund, Howard; Jensen, Fred; Jenstrom, Sven; Johnson, Arvid W.; Johnson, Clifford; Johnson, Clinton; Johnson, Donald I.; Johnson, Edwin; Johnson, Eric; Johnson, Frank, Jr.; Johnson, Gerald; Johnson, John C.; Johnson, Julius W., Jr.; Johnson, Karl A.; Johnson, Lawrence; Johnson, Raymond; Johnson, Warren B.; Keams, Herbert; Keeler, Seymour; Keeler, Wayne M.; Keeler, Wendall R.; Kyser, Nils; Legere, Arthur; Legere, Louis; Lent, Gordon C.; Lent, Everett; Lindblom, Russell; Lindblom, Victor; Lindstrom, Eric; Lindstrom, Leonard; Malone, John W.; Malone, Robert; Marchison, Andrew; Mattson, Gerald, G.; Mattson, Roland S.; McDonald Frank; McLoughlin, Donald; Mecozzi, Albert; Mecozzi, Dominick; Mecozzi, Thomas; Melanson, Louis; Miller, Bruce, Jr.; Mills, Clifford J., Jr.; Moeller, Sven; Moisio, Frank T.; Monroe, William; Moore, Andrew; Moore, Edward; Moore, Patrick; Morrissey, Charles; Morrissey, John P.; Morrissey, Peter; Morrissey, William; Natale, Albert; Natale, Fred; Natale, Joseph; Nimer, George W., Jr.; Nimer, James; Nimer, Samuel; Nixon, Susan; Oboza, George J.; Okarmus, Henry; Olsen, Eric; O'Neil, Frank, Jr.; Opas, William A.; Mills, Clifford J., Jr.; Moeller, Sven; Moisio, Frank T.; Monroe, William; Moore, Andrew; Moore, Edward; Moore, Patrick; Morrissey, Charles; Morrissey, John P.; Morrissey, Peter; Morrissey, William; Natale, Albert; Natale, Fred; Natale, Joseph; Nimer, George W., Jr.; Nimer, James; Nimer, Samuel; Nixon, Susan; Oboza, George J.; Okarmus, Henry; Olsen, Eric; O'Neil, Frank, Jr.; Opas, William A.; Palochick, John; Palochick, Joseph; Palochick, Steven; Paquin, Alexander; Paquin, Louis; Parks, David W.; Pasiuk, John, Jr.; Pasiuk, William; Pearson, Alden; Pearson, Harry; Pearson, Otto; Peck, Elizabeth A.; Perry, Walter H., Jr.; Pfahl, Charles A.; Pfahl, Richard; Pryor, Harry E.; Pryor, William J.; Raatikainen, Emil O.; Raatikainen, Turri H.; Robie, John; Rondos, James; Rondos, William; Ronnholm, Fred; Ronnholm, Leonard; Rosendahl, Carl Bertil; Salonen, Annus; Salonen, Henry A.; Salonen, Lawrence E.; Saleem, Albert; Saleem, Solomen; Samuelson, Einar; Samuleson, Eric; Samuelson, Gunnar; Samuelson, William; Sanford, John; Sansevieri, Fred; Santinella, Victor E.; Schimenz, Robert John; Sivo, Walter; Skoolund, Axel J.; Slaga, Stanley; Slawson, Alfred; Smith, William A.; Sodergren, Roy A.; Southworth, George, Jr.; Stietzel, Ernie; Sturges, John C.; Sturges, Philip S.; Svensson, Holger; Swenson, Karl; Tarrant, Albert E.; Terry, Roy M.; Therrien, Robert; Uhlan, Anthony; Walendziak, Edward; Weiskoph, Robert; Wessels, William; Williams, Frank.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
<p>The World War II Collection includes newspapers, newspaper clippings, and periodicals published domestically for the public and abroad for the troops. Books and pamphlets for general audiences and for servicemen, including War Department publications, are also in the collection. There is a large number of photographs, including many press proofs and prints from the U.S. Army Pictorial Service. Finally, the collection contains a number of maps, miscellaneous ephemera and realia, a few posters and banners, and signage from a 2010 exhibit held at the Gilbert &amp; Bennett School.</p>
</scopecontent>
<controlaccess>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Airplanes</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--France--Normandy</subject>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969</persname>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" role="subject">Georgetown (Conn.)</geogname>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Rationing</subject>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">United States. Army Pictorial Service</corpname>
<subject encodinganalog="650">World War, 1939-1945</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Address books</subject>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Stromburg, R. William</persname>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Books</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Clippings (books, newspapers, etc.)</subject>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Maps</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Newspapers</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Pamphlets</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Periodicals</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Posters</genreform>

</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial>
<head>Related Collections</head>
<p>The Wilton Historical Society holds World War II collections relating to the military service of Georgetown resident William Arthur Smith.</p>
</relatedmaterial>


<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>
