<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctgr/ctgr_default_ead.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="ctgr" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctgr/james_sttreeter.xml">james_sttreeter</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Collection of James L. Streeter, 1705-2018</titleproper>
<author>Collection guide written by Michael Spellmon. Collection processed by Kathy Foulke.</author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion..</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>Groton Public Library</publisher>
<address><addressline>52 Newtown Road</addressline>
<addressline>Groton</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06340</addressline>
<addressline>email: mspellmon@groton-ct.gov</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://www.grotonpl.org</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: 860-441-6750</addressline></address>

<date>Jan 18, 2018</date>
<p>http://www.grotonpl.org</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: 2018.01</num>
<publisher>Groton Public Library
<lb/>52 Newtown Road
<lb/> Groton, CT  06340</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection guide written by:</label>
<item>Michael Spellmon</item>
</defitem>
<defitem>
<label>Collection processed by:</label>
<item>Kathy Foulke</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2018 Groton Public Library. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname source="DA:CS">Streeter, James L.</persname>
</origination>
<unittitle>Collection of James L. Streeter, 1705-2018</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1705-2018">circa 1705-2018</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="ctgr" countrycode="us">2018.01</unitid>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>34.16 linear feet; </extent>
<extent>42 boxes</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Groton Public Library</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> 52 Newtown Road</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
    <abstract label="Abstract">Collection includes primary and secondary material collected by town historian Jim Streeter related to the history of Groton. Material documents families, structures, neighborhoods, businesses, industries and transport through public records, business and personal papers, photographs, maps and three-dimensional artifacts.</abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.
</langmaterial>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection open for research during library open hours.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>For copyright status, please contact the Groton Public Library.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
    <p>Collection of James L. Streeter, 1705-2018, Groton Public Library, Groton, CT</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo>
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Gift of James L. Streeter acquired through multiple donations from December 2015 and continuing through the present.</p>
</acqinfo>
<bioghist>
<head>Biography</head>
    <p>James L. (Jim) Streeter is a life-long resident of Groton. He attended local schools, and was a graduate of Fitch High School in 1963. He is a graduate of the University of New Haven, where he received undergraduate Science degrees in Criminal Justice, and a Master of Science Degree in Industrial Relations. Although he retired as a Forensic Science Evidence Examiner from the Connecticut State Police Forensic Laboratory in 2008, he still owns and operates a private forensic evidence examination business in Groton.
        
        He has been a member of the Groton Town Council and Served as the Mayor of the town from 2009-2011. He current serves on the Groton Representative Town Meeting. He is son the Board of Directors for the Fitch Alumni Association, the Bill Memorial Library, and the Avery-Copp Museum. He is very active in the saving and restoration of America’s lighthouses, serving as co-founder and co-chairman of the Avery Point Lighthouse Society, on the Board of Directors for the American Lighthouse Foundation, and on the Board of the New London Ledge Lighthouse Foundation. 
        
        Jim’s interest in documenting and collecting Groton history began in the late 1960’s, while he was employed as a police officer in the City of Groton. He authored weekly articles about Groton for the Groton Times newspaper from 2004-2009 and has recently begun writing articles for the paper. He authored Groton-Historical Bits and Pieces, Robert E. Fitch High School: A Historical Overview, Groton-Mystic Emergency Services, and Remembering Our Veterans: A Directory of Groton’s Veterans and War Memorials. He co-authored two volumes about Groton published by Arcadia Publishers.
        
        Jim currently serves as the Town Historian for the Town of Groton.
    </p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
    <p>Collection includes primary and secondary material related to the history of Groton collected by town historian Jim Streeter. Material documents families, structures, neighborhoods, businesses, industries and transport through public records, business and personal papers, photographs, maps and three-dimensional artifacts. </p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement>
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>As there was no original organization to the bulk of the material, arrangement is by format and then by subject as determined by the archivist.  Some material is in folders in boxes on open shelving, filed in cabinet drawers and stored in flat files. Booklets are foldered and boxed on open shelving. Three-dimensional objects are in artifact boxes stored in cabinets underneath the display cases.</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Daboll, Nathan, 1750-1818</persname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610">United States. Navy</corpname>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Almshouses</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Business enterprises</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Cemeteries</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Cities and towns</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Family histories</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Fire departments</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Municipal government</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Nonprofit organizations</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Schools</subject>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" role="subject">Groton (Conn.)</geogname>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Advertisements</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Almanacs</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Articles</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Artifacts (object genre)</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Burial records</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Calendars (documents by form)</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Family papers</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Fliers (printed material)</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Maps (documents)</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Municipal government records</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Reports</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655">Scrapbooks</genreform>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial>
<head>Related Collections</head>
<p>Related material may be found at other organizations within the Groton area, including the Avery-Copp House, Avery Memorial Association, Groton Historical Society, Indian and Colonial Research Center, Mashantucket Pequot Museum, Mystic River Historical Society, and Noank Historical Society.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<separatedmaterial>
<head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Newspapers documenting the Kennedy assassination are stored separately within the library for use in educational exhibits.</p>
</separatedmaterial>
    <odd>
        <head>Series</head>
        <p>Series I &#8211; Families &#8211; Hodgdon-Chapman Family Records  (1.25 linear feet) &#8211; Papers relating to the Hodgdon-Chapman family. Include ephemera, records related to vital events, records related to boats, and photographs.
            Family Papers (.417 linear feet) &#8211; Documents of the following families: Hempstead, Irene Erickson, Raymond Fogg, William Henderson, Theresa Crandell, Harry C. Brogan, Trolland Family, Starr Family and Hill Family.</p>
        <p>Series II &#8211; Photographs (.834 linear feet) &#8211; Various photographs related to Groton history.</p>
        <p>Series III &#8211; Almanacs (1.25 linear feet) &#8211; Daboll Almanacs &#8211; Series of The New England Almanac And Farmers' Friend, referred to Daboll almanacs published by Nathan Daboll. Daboll started the almanac in 1773. Collection run starts with 1840 and goes to 1910.</p>
        <p>Series IV &#8211; Calendars (1.667 linear feet)&#8211; Twelve month calendars promoting various Groton businesses. Businesses included are: Bridge Plaza Drug Store, A &amp; P Service Station, Collins T.V. &amp; Appliances, L.M. Cromwell IGA, Morgan &amp; White, Leonard J. Hutchins Milk, Groton Hardware, Bridge Plaza Filling Station, Branch Hardware Store, Spicer Ice &amp; Coal, V.E. Dewey Florist. Dates of calendars range from 1935-1977.</p>
        <p>Series V &#8211; Artifacts &#8211; (14.171 linear feet)&#8211; Jim Streeter actively collected items associated with famous sites in Groton. The collection includes Griswold Hotel items (plates, ashtrays, dinner ware, lamps, keys, soap, cigar boxes, matchbooks, napkins, pencils, silverware, door knobs); Fort Griswold and Groton Monument (medals, ribbons, plaques, plates, candy dishes, toothpick holders, candy dishes, cigar boxes); and general business related items (thermometers, ashtrays, thread, medicine bottles, bank deposit bags, coasters, rulers, candy trays).</p>
        <p>Series VI &#8211; Maps &#8211; (10.0 linear feet) &#8211; Collection includes plot maps depicting United Fuel Corporation, Salter Property, Groton Ferry Landing, Thames Street, railroad property, Vanadium Metals Company, Avery Point, A.L. Avery Farm, Groton Long Point Yacht Club, property on North Road and Grove Avenue subdivision. Additional maps include United States Geological Maps of Block Island Sound, Fishers Island Sound, New London Harbor and Submarine Base and the State of Connecticut. Towns and villages are represented by Beers maps of Groton, Stonington, Noank, Groton Bank, Mystic River and Mystic Bridge. </p>
        <p>Series VII &#8211; City and Town Government &#8211; Groton Schools (.834 linear feet) Documents related to Groton schools, including plans for construction of elementary schools, teacher appointments and School Visitor Reports.
            City of Groton Fire Department (1.5 linear feet) &#8211; Four scrapbooks created by Limke commemorating the City of Groton Fire Department (1971-2002) and the Eastern Point Company #2 (predominately photographs of individuals associated with the department.) 
            Groton Town Departments (.417 linear feet) &#8211; Documents created by the Tax office, Elections Department, Town Treasurer, and Town Deposit Fund. 
        </p>
        <p>Series VIII &#8211; Cemeteries (1.25 linear feet)&#8211; Records of Groton cemeteries, predominately of the Colonel Ledyard Cemetery. Includes burial ledgers and gravestone inscriptions.</p>
        <p>Series IX &#8211; Organizations &#8211; (.200 linear feet) &#8211; Documents and ephemera related to the Boy Scouts of America, Elks, Odd Fellows, and Thames Valley Science Center.</p>
        <p>Series X &#8211; Businesses &#8211; (.834 linear feet) – Documents and ephemera related to the following businesses: John S. Morgan Provisions, Asa Perkins Insurance, Connecticut Power Company, New London Country Fire Insurance Company, C.R. Church Motors, Groton Shoppers Mart, Groton Utilities, North End Diner, Bacon Banjo Company, Weil Motors, Skippers Dock, Latham’s Store, Griswold Hotel, Pequot Medical Center, Pfizer, Packers Tar Soap, various banks, and the Chamber of Commerce of Eastern Connecticut. Advertisements and flyers promoting several local businesses including Advertisements and flyers promoting several local businesses including Groton Week and Shoppers Guide.</p>
        <p>Series XI &#8211; Navy &#8211; Submarines (1.00 linear feet) &#8211; Scrapbook of newspaper articles and Sub  Base New London news of the production, testing and launching of submarines. Dates of articles range from 1954 to 1958.</p>
        <p>Series XII &#8211; Research of Previous Groton Town Historians &#8211; (.417 linear feet) &#8211; Research notes of Carol Kimball on Native American and Groton history topics.</p>
   </odd>

<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>