<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/cthhbsc/cthhbsc_default_ead.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="cthhbsc" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/cthhbsc/BeecherFamily.xml">BeecherFamily</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Beecher Family Circular Letters</titleproper>
<author>Collection guide written by Harriet Beecher Stowe Center, Hartford, CT. Collection processed by Harriet Beecher Stowe Center, Hartford, CT.</author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>Harriet Beecher Stowe Center</publisher>
<address><addressline>77 Forest Street</addressline>
<addressline>Hartford</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06105</addressline>
<addressline>email: research@stowecenter.org</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://www.harrietbeecherstowe.org</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: 860.522.9258 ext. 313</addressline></address>

<date>Jan 17, 2018</date>
<p>http://www.harrietbeecherstowe.org</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: 81.172, 81.564, 2008.6</num>
<publisher>Harriet Beecher Stowe Center
<lb/>77 Forest Street
<lb/> Hartford, CT  06105</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection guide written by:</label>
<item>Harriet Beecher Stowe Center, Hartford, CT</item>
</defitem>
<defitem>
<label>Collection processed by:</label>
<item>Harriet Beecher Stowe Center, Hartford, CT</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2018 Harriet Beecher Stowe Center. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Collector">
<persname source="DA:CS">Beecher, Charles, 1815-1900</persname>
</origination>
<unittitle>Beecher Family Circular Letters</unittitle>
<unitdate type="bulk">1835-1844</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="cthhbsc" countrycode="us">81.172, 81.564, 2008.6</unitid>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>2 linear feet,</extent>
<extent>1 box and 1 portfolio</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Harriet Beecher Stowe Center</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> 77 Forest Street</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">These group letters were written by and circulated among the Beecher Family as a way to keep its far-flung members, spouses, relations, and friends abreast of family news and activities. The letters provide insight into family members' ideas and opinions on public issues of the day, including slavery, politics, and religion. They also give a picture of the Old Northwest (Ohio, Illinois, Indiana) and New England in the early 19th century.</abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.
</langmaterial>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>Copies of letters in this collection are open and available for research use. Copyright restrictions apply.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>For copyright status, please contact the Harriet Beecher Stowe Center.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], , [Box no]., Harriet Beecher Stowe Center</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo>
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>18 letters were purchased from a Beecher descendant in 1981. Charles Beecher (1815-1900) compiled these letters after his father Lyman Beecher's death in 1863. They were published in Charles' 1865 book, The Autobiography of Lyman Beecher. Two letters were gifts from Beecher descendants in 1981 and 2008.</p>
</acqinfo>
<bioghist>
<head>Biography</head>
<p>The Beecher Family were descended from John Beecher (1594-1637), a follower of John Davenport and with him, one of the original settlers of New Haven colony. The family patriarch, Lyman Beecher (1775-1863), was a prominent clergyman, famous for his temperance activities, his pronouncement against dueling, his anti-Catholic tract, and his nationally-known pulpit oratory. Beecher was president of Lane Theological Seminary in Cincinnati, OH from 1832 to 1850. He married three times and fathered 13 children, 11 of whom survived to adulthood. It was said, only half in jest, that he was the father of more brains than any man in America.</p>
<p>All the Beecher daughters contributed to the circular letters in this collection. They were (1) Harriet Beecher Stowe (1811-1896), antislavery author of Uncle Tom's Cabin and other well-known novels; (2) Catharine E. Beecher (1800-1878), pioneer female educator and writer on "domestic economy": (3) Isabella Beecher Hooker (1822-1907), a prominent women's suffragist and rights author; and (4) Mary Beecher Perkins (1805-1900), who led a private life as a wife, mother, and constant support for the whole Beecher family.</p>
<p>The Beecher sons who contributed to these circular letters were all ministers. Henry Ward Beecher (1813-1887), the most famous preacher, orator, and popular spokesman of his day. Edward Beecher (1803-1895) was president of Illinois College, antislavery leader, and editor of The Congregationalist. Charles Beecher (1815-1900) was also involved in the antislavery movement and delivered sermons against both the Nebraska and the Fugitive Slave Acts. Thomas Kinnicut Beecher (1824-1900) was an unconventional minister, whose church in Elmira, NY became one of the first so-called "institutional" churches in the country, supplying a wide range of social services. The other two sons represented in the collection were George Beecher (1809-1843), a minister in Rochester, NY and Chillicothe, OH who died young, probably a suicide; and William H. Beecher (1802-1889) a minister of many parishes in Connecticut, Ohio, New York and Massachusetts.</p>
<p>The other family contributors to the circular letters were (1) Mary Porter Coffin (1782-1866), the mother of Sarah Coffin Beecher, Charles Beecher's wife; (2) Harriet Coffin Smyth, Sarah's sister; and (3) Mary Coffin Blood, another relative. Two family friends who contributed were George Hastings and Mary Dutton.</p>
<p>Source: For additional information on the Beecher Family and Henry Ward Beecher, see Guide to the Beecher Family Papers MS 71, Yale University Library. http://drs.library.yale.edu/</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
<p>This collection consists of 20 "circular letters" written to and by members of the Beecher family. Authors contributing to the letters include Lyman Beecher, his third wife Lydia Beals Jackson Beecher, his half-sister Esther Beecher, his adult children and their spouses, three Coffin relatives, and two family friends. For each letter a contributor wrote or added a few lines and sent the letter on to the next contributor, who repeated the process resulting a a chain or round-robin letter that kept them all posted on births, deaths, marriages, travel, work, writing, and church and seminary news. The letters also contain discussions of religion, slavery, abolition, politics, freedom of speech, and other public issues.</p>
<p>The authors wrote from Cincinnati, Chillicothe, Batavia, and Putnam, OH; Hartford, CT; Jacksonville, IL; New Orleans, LA; Batavia, NY; Indianapolis, IN; and Andover, Cambridgeport, and Boston, MA. The letters served to transmit family members' thoughts on topics of the day between New England and the Old Northwest. </p>
<p>The following Beecher family members and friends contributed to one or more of the circular letters in the collection:
Beecher, Catharine Esther, 1800-1878.
Beecher, Charles, 1815-1900.
Beecher, Edward, 1803-1895.
Beecher, Esther Mary, 1779-1855.
Beecher, Eunice Bullard, Mrs. Henry Ward, 1812-1897.
Beecher, George, 1809-1843.
Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887.
Beecher, Isabella Jones, Mrs. Edward, 1807-1895.
Beecher, Katharine Edes, Mrs. William H., ?-1870.
Beecher, Lydia Jackson, Mrs. Lyman, 1789-1869.
Beecher, Lyman, 1775-1863.
Beecher, Sarah Buckingham, Mrs. George, 1817-1902.
Beecher, Sarah Coffin, Mrs. Charles, 1815-1897.
Beecher, Thomas Kinnicut, 1824-1900.
Beecher, William H., 1802-1889.
Blood, Mary B. Coffin, 1815-1900.
Coffin, Mary Porter, 1782-1866.
Dutton, Mary, 1809-?.
Hastings, George W., 1827-1916.
Hooker, Isabella Beecher, 1822-1907.
Perkins, Mary Beecher, 1805-1900.
Smyth, Harriet Coffin, 1807-1865.
Stowe, Calvin E., 1802-1886.
Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1811-1896.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement>
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Beecher Family Circular Letters are filed chronologically.</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Abolitionist.</subject>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Catharine Esther, 1800-1878.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Charles, 1815-1900.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Edward, 1803-1895.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Esther Mary, 1779-1855.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Eunice Bullard, 1812-1897.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, George, 1809-1843.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Isabella Jones, 1807-1895.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Katharine Edes, ?-1870.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Lyman, 1775-1863.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Sarah Buckingham, 1817-1902.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Sarah Coffin, 1815-1897.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, Thomas Kinnicut, 1824-1900.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Beecher, William Henry, 1802-1889.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Blood, Mary B. Coffin, 1815-1900.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Clarke, Lewis, 1815-1897.</persname>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Clergy.</subject>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Coffin, Mary Porter, 1782-1866.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Dutton, Mary, 1809-?.</persname>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial>
<head>Related Collections</head>
<p>Additional Beecher Family correspondence is found throughout the Stowe Center Collection.</p>
</relatedmaterial>


<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>
