<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon/packages/collections/lib/ead.dtd">
<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
	<eadid mainagencycode="CtLHi" countrycode="us" url="http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&amp;id=11">1970-35-1</eadid>

	<filedesc>
    <titlestmt>
		<titleproper>Adams family papers</titleproper>
		<subtitle>An Inventory of Holdings at the Litchfield Historical Society</subtitle>
		<author encodinganalog="245$c">Collection Description/Finding Aid prepared by Leith Johnson and Stephen Powell.</author>
	</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
    <p>&#x00A9; Copyright 2009 Litchfield Historical Society.  All rights reserved.</p>
	<publisher>Litchfield Historical Society</publisher>
	<date type="publication" normal="20090928">09/28/2009</date>
	<address>
		<addressline>7 South Street, P.O. Box 385</addressline>
		<addressline>Litchfield, CT, 6759</addressline>
		<addressline>URL: http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon</addressline>
		<addressline>Email: archivist@litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org</addressline>
		<addressline>Phone: 860-567-4501</addressline>
		<addressline>Fax: 860-567-3565</addressline>
	</address>

</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>

<profiledesc>
<creation>This finding aid was encoding in EAD by Archon 2.22 from an SQL database source on <date type="encoded" normal="05192010">May 19th, 2010</date>.</creation>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
	<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
	<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
		<corpname>Litchfield Historical Society</corpname>
	<address>
		<addressline>7 South Street, P.O. Box 385</addressline>
		<addressline>Litchfield, CT, 6759</addressline>
		<addressline>URL: http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon</addressline>
		<addressline>Email: archivist@litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org</addressline>
		<addressline>Phone: 860-567-4501</addressline>
		<addressline>Fax: 860-567-3565</addressline>
	</address>

	</repository>

	<origination label="Creator:">

		<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Adams, Charles, 1805-1883</persname>
		<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Adams, Charles, Jr., 1845-1864</persname>
		<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Adams, Joseph, 1764-1856</persname>
		<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Wessells, Julia Adams How, 1842-1904</persname>
		<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1838-1895</persname>
	</origination>
	<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Adams family papers</unittitle>
	<unitdate label="Dates:" encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">1798-1928</unitdate>
	<unitdate label="Dates:" encodinganalog="245$g" type="bulk">1798-1877</unitdate>
	<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a"><extent unit="Boxes">2.00</extent></physdesc>

	<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">The personal papers of the Adams Family, including Joseph Adams (1767-1856); his son, Charles Adams (1805-1883); children of Charles Adams, including Julia Adams How Wessells (1842-1904), Mary Adams Wheelock (1838-1895), and Charles Adams Jr. (1845-1864); other family members; and friends and business associates. The collection consists primarily of correspondence.</abstract>

	<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" repositorycode="CtLHi">1970-35-1</unitid>

	<langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language of Materials">
	  The papers are in:
<language langcode="eng">English</language>
	</langmaterial>
</did>


<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->
<bioghist altrender="Biographical Note" encodinganalog="545"><head>Biographical Note</head>
  <p>Charles Adams (1805-1883) was a son of Litchfield residents Joseph Adams (1764-1856) and Deborah Marsh Adams (1773-1857). In the early 1820s, Charles Adams moved to New Haven and apprenticed with the printer Thomas Collier, formerly of Litchfield, and worked in the office of Sherman Converse. Adams established a printing business in 1825 and published The New Haven Chronicle in 1827 and then founded the New Haven Palladium in 1829. In the early 1830s, he moved to Bath, N.Y., where he published The Constitutionalist beginning in 1834. He also published the Corning and Blossburg Advocate. When his brother Henry died unexpectedly in 1842, Adams moved back to Litchfield and continued publication of The Litchfield Enquirer until 1845, when it was sold to Payne Kilbourne. Twice Adams assumed the editorship of the paper until it was sold to James Humphrey in 1859. After 1845, Adams was elected judge of probate court, a position he held for fourteen of the next twenty years. He was a deacon of the Congregational Church; a director of the Litchfield Savings Bank, the Litchfield Female Academy, and the Litchfield County Historical and Antiquarian Society, and a member of the Board of Visitors of the Elm Park Collegiate Institute. He married Jane Hinman of New Haven in 1827. She died in 1828. He married Julia Hinman of New Haven in 1830 and they had ten children.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
	<head>Scope and Contents</head>
	<p>The personal papers of the Adams Family, including Joseph Adams (1767-1856); his son, Charles Adams (1805-1883); children of Charles Adams, including Julia Adams How Wessells (1842-1904), Mary Adams Wheelock (1838-1895), and Charles Adams Jr. (1845-1864); other family members; and friends and business associates. The collection consists primarily of correspondence.</p>
	<p>Family members were descendants of Henry Adams of Braintree and distant cousins of the famous Adams family of Massachusetts. Joseph Adams was a fourth cousin of President John Quincy Adams. Living contemporaneously in Litchfield was the family of Judge Andrew Adams (1736-1797), which descended from Samuel Adams of Stratford, Conn., and not related to the family of Joseph Adams.</p>
	<p>Joseph Adams moved to Litchfield from Roxbury, Mass., in 1790 and established himself as a cabinet maker. With advertisements in issues of the Litchfield Monitor for June 1790 he introduced himself to Litchfield residents as a cabinet maker from Boston and solicited their business. He advertised frequently in the 1790s for apprentices, but sold his shop in 1802. He was Litchfield borough clerk, 1818-1823 and 1824-1838 and borough president 1839-1842. He also served as constable for six years, lister or rate-maker (functioning as assessor) for twelve years, grand juror for six years, a director of the Litchfield Savings Bank, and a surveyor. He married Deborah Marsh in 1792 and they had eight children. </p>
	<p>Two of the children, Henry Adams (1794-1842) and Charles Adams (1805-1883), established themselves in the newspaper business. The early interest of Joseph in journalism is evidenced in a letter he received from his nephew, Charles Chauncey Adams (1788-1814)  in 1807, in which he acknowledges information regarding the status of newspapers published in Litchfield. After working in Huntsville, Ala., in the 1820s, where he was associated with newspapers there, Henry Adams purchased the Litchfield County Post in 1829, changing the title to The Litchfield Enquirer with his first issue, January 29, 1829. He continued to publish the newspaper until his death by accidental drowning in 1842.</p>
	<p>In the early 1820s, Charles Adams moved to New Haven and apprenticed with the printer Thomas Collier, formerly of Litchfield, and worked in the office of Sherman Converse. Adams established a printing business in 1825 and published The New Haven Chronicle in 1827 and then founded the New Haven Palladium in 1829. In the early 1830s, he moved to Bath, N.Y., where he published The Constitutionalist beginning in 1834. He also published the Corning and Blossburg Advocate. When his brother Henry died unexpectedly in 1842, Adams returned to Litchfield and continued publication of The Litchfield Enquirer until 1845, when it was sold to Payne Kilbourne. Twice Adams assumed editorship of the paper until it was sold to James Humphrey in 1859. After 1845, Adams was elected judge of probate court, a position he held for fourteen of the next twenty years. He was a deacon of the Congregational Church; a director of the Litchfield Savings Bank, the Litchfield Female Academy, and the Litchfield County Historical and Antiquarian Society, and a member of the Board of Visitors of the Elm Park Collegiate Institute.</p>
	<p>With the exceptions of Henry Adams and Charles Adams (who returned from Bath, N.Y.), all of the children of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams left Litchfield: Sarah Adams Peck (1792-1877) to Bristol, Conn.; Betsey Adams May (1796-1877) to Bath, N.Y.; Amos Adams (1798-1859) to Baton Rouge, La.; John Marsh Adams (1801-1853) to Augusta, Ga.; Kezia Adams Rogers (1811-1899) to Buffalo; and Thomas William (1814-1848), to Augusta, Ga.</p>
	<p>The collection consists primarily of correspondence received by Joseph Adams from family members and members of the Litchfield community with legal or other matters involving him and correspondence among the immediate members of the family of Charles Adams, in particular, two daughters of Charles Adams, Mary Adams Wheelock and Julia Adams How Wessells. The correspondence is mostly personal in nature, relating to family news and concerned with matters of health, births, deaths, and visits. This was a traveling family, all generations, so there is an occasional glimpse glimpse of the trials of stage and canal travel. There is a pervasive religious awareness in the letters, perhaps most expressed by Charles to his father in the 1820s. Unfortunately, there is nothing in the collection related to the early career of Joseph Adams as a cabinet maker nor of publishing activities of Henry Adams and Charles Adams in Litchfield.</p>
	<p>Although domestic topics predominate in the letters, correspondents sometimes address local or national topics of interest. Joseph&#039;s correspondence includes letters from or news about two men who were at one time or another leading business figures in Boston: Amos Lawrence (1786-1852), who was married to Joseph&#039;s niece, and Giles Richards (1754-1829), who was Joseph&#039;s brother-in-law. For example, Lawrence&#039;s 1845 Feb 1 letter offers a personal philosophical expression of a wealthy and successful merchant. Letters from members of the family who moved to the South, particularly from Amos Adams (who owned a plantation and slaves), have a few references to business conditions. A nephew of Joseph Adams, Henry Adams Bullard, wrote twice (1832-1833) to Joseph from Washington when he was a Congressman. Benjamin Tallmadge (1754-1835), another Congressman, wrote Joseph five letters (1814-1826) from Washington, where he was acting for Joseph in financial matters. Four of the letters written while Tallmadge was serving in the House of Representatives.</p>
	<p>Some of the papers relate to the Civil War. Charles Adams (1845-1864), the son of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams, enlisted in the 19th Regiment Connecticut Volunteers in 1862 following the outbreak of the Civil War. On June 11, 1864, he died of wounds received on June 1 during the Battle of Cold Harbor. During the war, Adams regularly wrote letters to his parents and sisters. He recorded his thoughts about Generals McClellan, Burnside, and Grant, and President Lincoln; life in camp (maintaining and outfitting tents, sleeping arrangements, food, prayer meetings, entertainments and lectures, snowball battles); support for the Emancipation Proclamation; his belief in the cause; postings, guard duty, inspections, and drills; encouraging enlistment; speculation about duration of war and upcoming military activities; his cousin, Charles Hinman Graves, and other relatives he sees; the 40th N.Y. and Bull Run; African-American dock and government stores workers; guarding “contrabands” (freed or former slaves) from Virginia and Maryland; news of other Litchfield residents; politics in Connecticut; and the weather. The collection contains letters written relative to his death by Representative John H. Hubbard and Marie Barton Greene, who served with the Sanitary Commission. Charles Adams Jr. is not the only Adams family member serving in the Civil War to be documented in the collection; correspondence from Anna Adams (1814-1906) relates to the death of her brother Joseph Henry Adams (1843-1861) during battle on Santa Rosa Island, Fla.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351$b">
	<head>Arrangement of Materials</head>
	<p>The collection is arranged in four series:</p>
	<p>1. Correspondence</p>
	<p>2. Other papers</p>
	<p>3. Photographs</p>
	<p>4. Albums</p>
</arrangement>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
	<head>Related Materials</head>
	<p>Adams family collection (2010-119-0)</p>
	<p>Photographs of some Adams family are in Photographs, Portraits: Adams and Baldwin files.</p>
	<p>Louisiana State University Libraries, Special Collections. Freemasons St. James Lodge No. 47 (Baton Rouge, La.) records (Mss 2860).</p>
	<p>Massachusetts Historical Society</p>
	<p>Amos Lawrence Papers.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
	<head>Separated Materials</head>
	<p>Four silhouettes cut from paper (two portraits on one sheet and two on two separate sheets) have been removed from the Adams Family Collection and added to the museum collections.</p>
</separatedmaterial>

<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->

<!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: These are all repeatable  THESE SHOULD BE PUT INTO APPROPRIATE TAGS AS PER BELOW AND MARC INSTRUCTONS -->

<controlaccess>
<head>Index Terms</head>

<p>This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.</p>
	<controlaccess>
		<head>Family Name:</head>
			<famname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Adams family</famname>
	</controlaccess>
	<controlaccess>
		<head>Genre/Form of Material:</head>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Autograph albums</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Business records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
	</controlaccess>
	<controlaccess>
		<head>Geographic Name:</head>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Litchfield (Conn.) -- History</geogname>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States--Politics and government--1783-1865</geogname>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States--Social life and customs--1783-1865</geogname>
	</controlaccess>
	<controlaccess>
		<head>Topical Term:</head>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</subject>
	</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>


<!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->

<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->

<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
	<head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
	<p>The collection is open for research.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
	<head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
	<p>Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator(s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of copyright holders. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright holders. Responsibility for any use rests with the user.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="510">
	<head>Preferred Citation</head>
	<p>Adams family papers (1970-35-1), Litchfield Historical Society, Helga J. Ingraham Memorial Library, P.O. Box 385, 7 South Street, Litchfield, Connecticut, 06759.</p>
</prefercite>
<altformavail encodinganalog="530">
	<head>Alternate Formats Available</head>
	<p>Transcriptions are available for some documents.</p>
	<p>Additional information is avaliable at http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org</p>
</altformavail>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
	<head>Acquisition Information</head>
	<p>The materials were acquired by Litchfield Historical Society from Margaret and Dorothy Baldwin on 06/01/1970.</p>
</acqinfo>
<odd encodinganalog="500">
	<head>Other Information</head>
	<p>This collection was processed with support from the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR).</p>
</odd>
<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->

<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
<dsc type="combined">
<head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>
<c01 level="series" id="id2306">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by creator, except for correspondence sent to an Adams family member by a person outside the Adams family, which has been placed in the sub-series for that family member. Item descriptions note major topics of discussion.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2323">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Abbot, J. B.</unittitle>
    </did>
<c03 level="file" id="id2308">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Abbott, J. B.</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Letter to J. H. Hubbard reporting that Charles Adams (1845-1864) has been wounded during the Civil War in battle and is &quot;in a dying condition.&quot;</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2325">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos (1798-1859)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos Adams was born in Litchfield and settled in Baton Rouge, La. He was the son of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2310">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1821-1822</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written in Bath, N.Y., to his parents.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2311">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1821 Aug 12</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos reports from Bath, N.Y., on the health of family members and friends and his business affairs.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2312">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1822 Jan 19</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos reports from Bath, N.Y., on family news, birth of his daughter, his father&#039;s business dealings, and New York elections.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2313">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1834-1849</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three letters to his wife and parents.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="file" id="id2314">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos to Adams, Clara Bailey</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1834 Aug 9</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos writes that he is eager to receive word from his wife, he misses her and his children, and that he &quot;has not assumed my place in the church.&quot;</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2315">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1843 Apr 13</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos reports from Baton Rouge on the birth of his son, additional family news, his business of planting cotton, Miller&#039;s preaching in the north, and politics.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2316">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1849 July 28</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos writes in Baton Rouge that although he might like to, his family and he can not move to Litchfield because his wife and children are natives of Louisiana. He also writes of family news.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2317">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1858-1859</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written in Baton Rouge to his brother Charles.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2318">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1858 May 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos writes about the condition of the river, family visits and news, Charles&#039;s election as probate judge, the Kansas question and slavery, death of his sister-in-law on the packet boat, Sultan.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2319">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Amos to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 Jun 6</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos writes about family news and health, that he would like to make Litchfield his summer home, and old age.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2326">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Anna (1814-1906)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Anna (Annie) Adams (1814-1906) was the daughter of John Marsh and Sarah (MacMurphy) Adams and was the granddaghter of Joseph and Deborah (Marsh) Adams. She lived in Georgia.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2320">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Anna to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1861 Oct 16</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Five items sent to her uncle related to the death of Anna&#039;s brother Joseph Henry Adams (1843-1861), killed during the Civil War in battle on Santa Rosa Island, Fla.: her letter, &quot;To the memory of Joseph H. Adams by one of his playmates,&quot; &quot;In memoriam,&quot; a newspaper obituary, and the poem &quot;Pensacola.&quot;</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2327">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles (1805-1883)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles Adams (1805-1883) was born in Litchfield and eventually settled there. He was the son of Joseph and Deborah (Marsh) Adams. For additional information, see his entry in Creators.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2321">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1810s</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written in Sharon, Conn., to his parents. He writes  about his visit to Poughkeepsie with Mr. and Mrs. Pierce and that he does not like Mr. Pierce.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2322">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1822-1826</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters written in New Haven, Conn.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2328">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1822 Nov 22</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes about his decision to join the Church of Christ and mentions Mr. Converse and the office staff as being members of that church. He asks that two religious books be sent to him.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2329">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Kezia</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1825 Aug 29</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes to his sister in detail about the death of a little girl &quot;whom you formerly knew&quot; and &quot;much esteemed,&quot; Ann Eliza Starr, who found comfort in her religion at the time of her illness and death.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2330">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1825 Sep 13</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes about his affection for his parents, his health, his religious feelings and convictions, a speech by Mr. Gould and comments on his alcoholism, and a poem delivered by Dr. Percival.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2331">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1826 Oct 10</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles inquires about family members. His business is well, but he needs cash, and discusses loans. He believes he is well situated in New Haven and feels attached to the city.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2332">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1838-1863</unitdate>
    </did>
<c04 level="item" id="id2333">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1838 Jan 29</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes about the birth of his daughter, Mary Fairchild, family health and news, and the death of Julius Deming.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2334">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to unnamed daughter and May, Betsey Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1853 May 15</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes to a daughter in Bath, N.Y. that he hopes her new school will be pleasant, implores her to study and remember the Bible and its teachings and recalls his fondness for Steuben County. He also writes a note his sister Betsey about improvements made to Joseph Adams&#039;s carpets.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2335">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Sarah and unnamed sister(s)</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1858 Nov 20</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes to his daughters in New Haven asking them to return by train to Litchfield.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2336">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 Jun 1</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes to his wife their son, Frankie (Francis) has contracted scarlet fever and advises her to return home from Buffalo.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2337">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 June 16</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes from Washington, D.C. that he will be visiting with their son, Charlie. He reports on going to the Capitol and visiting with friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2338">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864-1870</unitdate>
    </did>
<c04 level="item" id="id2339">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to unnamed daughter</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 7</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes that son Charlie has been badly wounded in the Civil War Battle of Cold Harbor. He lists the dead and wounded men from Litchfield.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2340">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Julia Hinman and Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Dec 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes to his wife that he is glad she had a good journey, describes how he misses the family members who usually sit around the dinner table, reports on family health and weather.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2341">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1869 Apr 28</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes to his wife from Brooklyn, N.Y., that they are packing daughter Julia&#039;s effects and will return in several days. He reports on Julia and other visitors.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2342">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles to How, Julia Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870 Nov 15</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles writes to his daughter Julia from Brooklyn, N.Y., about the journey there with other daughters from Bath and plans for his return.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2343">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Kilbourn, Myron to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jul 23</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Kilbourn&#039;s letter accompanied the return of Charles Adams Jr.&#039;s watch.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2344">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Lawrence, William R. to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1868 Feb. 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Lawrence, son of Amos Lawrence, writes about their common ancestor, Rev. Amos Adams (1728-1775). Enclosed is a letter to Lawrence from C. H. Dillaway, 1868 Feb 7.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2345">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">7</container>
        <unittitle>[McMather?], D. to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1877 Mar 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>[McMather?], a longtime friend of Adams, writes about people and places they knew in Bath, N.Y.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2414">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">8</container>
        <unittitle>Peck, Tracy to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 May 14</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Peck, who is married to Adams&#039;s aunt Sally Adams, acknowledges receipt for rent and is concerned that it is more than he can afford to pay. Peck would be glad to see Adams and his family and hopes to ride to Litchfield. Peck expects Litchfield will have much business before the legislature this session because South Farms is asking to be made into a town.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2346">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">9</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, Henry W. to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859-1869</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters from Henry W. Rogers, husband of Charles Adams&#039;s sister Kezia Adams. He writes of Charles&#039;s daughters in Buffalo and family and business matters.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2347">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">10</container>
        <unittitle>Valentine to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1855</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Poem written by &quot;Valentine&quot; about Adams&#039;s poetry-writing ability.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2348">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">11</container>
        <unittitle>Weare, Mary Rogers to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 Mar 13</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Weare writes about her present situation in Cedar Rapids and family news.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2349">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">12</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Leverett W. to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Alexandria, Va., to his friend Adams about details of his encampment during the Civil War. The health of the soldiers, including Adams&#039;s son Charles, is good, their behavior is excellent, and he is eager to go to battle. He asks Adams to look into the matter of courts taxing is attendance at courts.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2350">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">13</container>
        <unittitle>[?], Ellena</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1876</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written by Ellena to her guardian, Adams. She explains why she is in New York and asks for money with which to purchase a new winter outfit. She thanks him for the draft and describes her activities including attending a concert and news from friends and relatives.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2351">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles (1845-1864)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles Adams (1845-1864) was the son of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams and grandson of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams. He was born in Litchfield. When the Civil War broke out, he enlisted in the 19th Regiment Connecticut Volunteers in 1862. On June 11, 1864, he died of wounds received on June 1 during the Battle of Cold Harbor. During the war, Adams regularly wrote letters to his parents and sisters. He recorded his thoughts about Generals McClellan, Burnside, and Grant, and President Lincoln; life in camp (maintaining and outfitting tents, sleeping arrangements, food, prayer meetings, entertainments and lectures, snowball battles); support for the Emancipation Proclamation; his belief in the cause; postings, guard duty, inspections, and drills; encouraging enlistment; speculation about duration of war and upcoming military activities; his cousin, Charles Hinman Graves, and other relatives he sees; the 40th N.Y. and Bull Run; African-American dock and government stores workers; guarding “contrabands” (freed or former slaves) from Virginia and Maryland; news of other Litchfield residents; politics in Connecticut; and the weather.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2352">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters to Adams&#039;s father, mother, and sisters Mary and Sarah describing going to school, church, and other childhood activities and interests.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2353">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1861</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two draft letters, one to Adams&#039;s mother and one to his cousin in Latin, in which he discuss the weather and going to church.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2354">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 Aug-Sep</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four Civil War letters written in Alexandria, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2355">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 Oct</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Five Civil War letters written in camp near Alexandria, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2356">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 Nov</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four Civil War letters written in camp near Alexandria, Va. and Alexandria.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2357">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 Dec</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four Civil War letters written in Alexandria, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2358">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">7</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Jan</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four Civil War letters written in camp near Alexandria, Va. and Head Quarters near Fort Worth, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2359">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">8</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Feb</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two Civil War letters written in Head Quarters near Fort Worth, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2360">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">9</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Mar</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three Civil War letters written at Head Quarters of General Tyler.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2361">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">10</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Apr</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two Civil War letters written at Head Quarters of General Tyler.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2362">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">11</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 May</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three Civil War letters written in Arlington House, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2363">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">12</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Jun</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two Civil War letters written in Arlington House, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2364">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">13</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Nov</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three Civil War letters written at Knight General Hospital, New Haven.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2365">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">14</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Dec</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three Civil War letters written at Bedloe&#039;s Island, New York, and Fort Worth, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2366">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">15</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jan</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three Civil War letters written at Fort Worth, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2367">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">16</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Feb</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four Civil War letters written at Fort Worth, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2368">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">17</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Mar</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three Civil War letters written at Fort Worth, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2369">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">18</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Apr</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Five Civil War letters written at Fort Worth, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2370">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">19</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 May</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two Civil War letters, one written at Fort Worth, Va., the other at Fort Craig, Va.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2371">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">20</container>
        <unittitle>Gilbert, S. B. to relatives of Charles Adams Jr.</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 15</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Solicitation card from S. B. Gilbert, notary public, general claim agent, &quot;collects pensions, bounties, and back pay, due families or relatives of deceased officers or soldiers.&quot;</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2372">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">21</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, Henry to relatives of Charles Adams Jr.</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1864 Jun 15</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Solicitation card from Attorney Henry Rogers, &quot;pensions, bounty pay procured for discharged soldiers and relatives of deceased officers and soldiers.&quot;</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2373">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles Chauncey (1788-1814)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Charles Chauncey Adams (1788-1814) was the son of Dr. Henry Adams and Sarah Pelton Adams and the nephew of Joseph Adams and Deborah Marsh Adams. He was a printer and newspaper publisher in Poughkeepsie, N.Y.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2374">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Charles Chauncey to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1807 Nov 23</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams expresses sympathy for the death of his uncle Joseph&#039;s brother and well wishes for the good health of Joseph&#039;s children. Adams regretfully turns down his uncle&#039;s  offer to come to Litchfield to publish a neutral newspaper, citing the remaining two years on his apprenticeship and perhaps two more after that. Adams indicates he is opposed to newspapers which are affiliated with political parties.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2375">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Dinah Wiley (1764?-1811)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Dinah Wiley Adams (1764?-1811) was married to Rev. Thomas Adams (1764-1797) and was the sister-in-law of Joseph Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2376">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Dinah Wiley to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811 Jun 12</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Dinah has traveled to Rehoboth, Mass., &quot;in search of health&quot; and inquires where she might find relatives in New England. She misses her son.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2377">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Henry (1794-1842)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Henry Adams (1794-1842) was the son of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams. He was born in Litchfield. For a time in the 1820s, he was a newspaper publisher in Huntsville, Ala. In 1829, he purchased The Litchfield County Post and renamed it The Litchfield Enquirer. He published the paper until his death by accidental drowning in 1842.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2378">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Henry</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1826</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written to his father.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2379">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Henry to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1826 Feb 12</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Henry writes from Huntsville, Ala., about his health. He also reports Mr. Alden has left Huntsville and Henry is owed $2,000 and will go to court in an attempt to collect it. He expresses his disappointment in his business affairs since arriving in Huntsville six years ago. He inquires about family members and wonders about his future business prospects.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2380">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Henry to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1826 May 31</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Henry writes from Owego, N.Y., that in the course of his travel from Alabama he has lost or been robbed of about $530. He asks for a loan of $200 and says he will repay it after bringing his business in Huntsville to a final close. Since coming of age, he has never been in so unpleasant a situation as regards money. He also offers news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2381">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Henry (1835-1889)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Henry Adams (1835-1889) was the son of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2382">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Henry to Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1854</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes to sister about family and friends and his attendance at a church service.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2383">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Joseph (1767-1856)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Joseph Adams (1767-1856) was the son of Rev. Amos and Elizabeth Prentice Adams. For additional information, see his entry in Creators.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2384">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Joseph to Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1825 Aug 17</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Joseph writes to his wife in Geneva, N.Y., about his travel so far. He was taken very sick in Albany, which continued as he traveled by stage through New York. He is extremely pleased with the country and would leave Litchfield were he a young man. He reports on the health of Mr. Chapman.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2385">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Barber, Timothy  to Adams, Jospeh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1843 Dec 16</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Barber writes from Madison, Ind. with news of his family and its whereabouts.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2386">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Bates, Buell L. to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1825 Jun 1</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bates writes regarding putting Henry (his son?) out to &quot;some place.&quot; His father thinks it best, but he does not agree. He requests that Adams do nothing about &quot;getting a place.&quot;</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2387">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Breck, Joseph to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1837 Jan 30</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Breck, who is married to Sarah Bullard, a niece of Joseph, writes to inform Adams that his sister Elizabeth has died.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2388">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Buell, David to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1816 Feb 21</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Buell writes from Troy, N.Y., regarding payment of William Baldwin&#039;s note, a tombstone to be placed in Troy, and poor business conditions.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2389">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, John to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1813 Jan 15</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard, who was married to Joseph Adams&#039;s sister Elizabeth, writes from Pepperell, Mass. regarding Adams&#039;s feeling that Lancaster is a pleasant town, but has high taxes. Still, it would be very agreeable if Adams settled there. Bullard discusses present down business conditions and the ongoing war, the health of his family, activities of his sons Henry and Royal.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2390">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">7</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, John to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1813 Apr 13</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard writes from Pepperell, Mass., that he is glad to hear of the good health of Adams&#039;s family, nephew William Adams has died in South Carolina and the estate will need an agent, would Adams be willing to come to Boston, the health of his family, and a legal matter involving Douglas Blanding.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2391">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">8</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, John to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1817 Aug 9</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard writes from Pepperell, Mass., expressing his concerns with Adams&#039;s demand for payment. Bullard mentions Amos Lawrence, Giles Richards, and Adams&#039;s sister Sally Adams Richards as possible agents for him.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2392">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">9</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, John to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1818 Jul 21</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard writes from Pepperell, Mass., that his son Charles has written to his son Royal to communicate Adams&#039;s wishes. Bullard will be happy to visit Adams but not earlier than September. Political affairs in Connecticut have given a shock to many men. Bullard reports on the health of his family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2393">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">10</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, Royal to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1809-1813</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Royal Bullard (1789-1846) was the nephew of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2394">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">10</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, Royal to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1809 Mar 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard writes from Yale about his plans to return to Pepperell, whether his father can attend commencement, and bringing family members to New Haven. He leaves it to Adams to best judge his plan.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2395">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">10</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, Royal to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811 May 10</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard writes from Boston on his and his Aunt Richards&#039;s behalf. Adams son Henry is well. Bullard remembers Joseph well for his money favors while in Connecticut. He reports news about his family and describes his present situations. He hopes to pass the bar and that money he had of Mrs. H. will be called for. It would be extremely difficult for his father to assist him.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2396">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">10</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, Royal to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1813 Jun 25</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard writes from Camden, S.C. regarding Mr. Lang&#039;s claim of about $10,000, in which Adams and Mr. Blanding is involved.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2397">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">11</container>
        <unittitle>Chamberlain, Oliver E. to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1843 Feb 10</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Chamberlain writes from Amenia Union, N.Y. to inform Adams that he should not be charged for advertising a stage company he no longer owns.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2398">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">12</container>
        <unittitle>Church, Rollin to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1820 Oct 7</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Church requests that he enter the name of Mrs. Rollin Church upon Adams&#039;s list for domestic manufacturing a pair of worsted stockings for the exhibition.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2483">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">13</container>
        <unittitle>Hartford Fire Insurance Company to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1819 Feb 5</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Letter from Walter Mitchell, secretary, appointing Adams surveyor for the company for Litchfield and the neighborhood.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2399">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">14</container>
        <unittitle>Holt, Ebenezer to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811 Feb 4</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Holt, a relative of Adams sister Kezia Adams Holt, requests Adams&#039;s assistance in collecting notes. If it can be done in a timely fashion, he will be able to pay a note at a considerable discount.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2400">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">15</container>
        <unittitle>Holt, Philemon to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811-1812</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Holt appears to be a relative of Joseph Adams&#039;s sister Kezia Adams Holt.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2401">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">15</container>
        <unittitle>Holt, Philemon to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811 Mar 7</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Holt writes from Willington, Conn., that he has purchased a farm for his son and wishes Adams to assist with collecting notes with which Holt can pay the man from whom he purchased the farm.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2402">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">15</container>
        <unittitle>Holt, Philemon to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811 Apr 4</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Holt writes from Willington, Conn., that he has purchased a farm and wishes Adams to assist with collecting notes. The man from whom he purchased the farm is in want of money.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2403">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">15</container>
        <unittitle>Holt, Philemon to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1812 Aug 10</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Holt writes from Willington, Conn., seeking Adams&#039;s advice regarding the validity of a deed for land that is subject to an action Capt. Hitchcock is about to commence.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2404">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">16</container>
        <unittitle>Hurlbut, Samuel to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1842 Dec 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Hurlbut, writing from Baltimore, encloses a draft for Adams&#039;s bill.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2405">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">17</container>
        <unittitle>Lawrence, Amos to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1823 Jul 26</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos Lawrence (1786-1852) married Sarah Richards, the daughter of Sarah Adams Richards and niece of Joseph Adams. He writes from Boston that Adams&#039;s sister&#039;s condition is very comfortable. He gives news about his family&#039;s activities and health.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2406">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">18</container>
        <unittitle>Lawrence, Amos to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1845 Feb 1</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Lawrence, writing from Boston, gives a thorough accounting of family members alive and dead. He states his philosophy of philanthropy and discusses feelings towards his wealth and children.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2407">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">19</container>
        <unittitle>Lawrence, Amos to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1851 Apr 27</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Lawrence, writing from Boston, declines to give introductions in all cases, but Mr. Bulkley may say that Mrs. Bulkley is a relative of his children. He reports on his and his family&#039;s health and that he is afflicted because of the death of a favorite nephew, Robert Appleton.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2408">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">20</container>
        <unittitle>Lovell, Joseph and Elizabeth Partridge Lovell to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1818 May 9</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Lovell, who was married to Joseph&#039;s aunt Jemima (Adams) Lovell before she died, reports from Medway, Mass., on the health of the family.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2409">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">21</container>
        <unittitle>May, James to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1820 Apr 14</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>May, husband of Joseph Adams&#039;s daughter Betsey, reports from Catherine, N.Y., that conditions are favorable and Amos will do better there than in Litchfield.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2410">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">22</container>
        <unittitle>Peck, Tracy to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1818-1844</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three letters from Tracy Peck, who married Joseph Adams&#039;s sister Sally Adams, writing from Bristol, Conn.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2411">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">22</container>
        <unittitle>Peck, Tracy and Peck, Sally Adams to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1818 Oct 2</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Peck reports the birth of a daughter.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2412">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">22</container>
        <unittitle>Peck, Tracy to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1822 Dec. 3</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Peck reports all are well, except for Joseph, who is quite sick. He discusses the claim of Sarah [Null?].</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2413">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">22</container>
        <unittitle>Peck, Tracy to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1844 Mar 5</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Peck would like Adams&#039;s opinion as to the value of his daughter Sally&#039;s share of the property of the late Henry Adams. Mary Adams is anxious to buy out the share of the same.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2415">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">23</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Giles to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1798 Feb 25</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards, who is married to Joseph&#039;s sister Sally Adams, writes from Boston regarding claims of the Joseph&#039;s late brother Thomas Adams. Richards provides an accounting. He also relates family news.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2416">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">24</container>
        <unittitle>Spencer, Truman to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1842 May 1</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Spencer writes from Camden, N.Y., regarding his subscription to The Litchfield Enqurier.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2417">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">25</container>
        <unittitle>Starr, William to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1820 Dec 18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Starr, writing from Goshen, Conn., relates that Adams had a complaint lodged against Starr and Guy Wadhams for playing cards the day before Thanksgiving. He would like to resolve the matter and asks what the fine is, wishing that Adams would be as reasonable in their fines as he consistently can.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2418">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">26</container>
        <unittitle>Tallmadge, Benjamin to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1814</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written in Washington, D.C., while Tallmadge was serving in the U.S. House of Representatives.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2419">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">26</container>
        <unittitle>Tallmadge, Benjamin to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1814 Feb 16</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Tallmadge writes that he finds that no further aid is needed from him to obtain Adams&#039;s money in South Carolina, but if he needs it, he shall &quot;very cheerfully afford it.&quot; If the weather permits, he shall be glad if Adams would survey several of his properties.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2420">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">26</container>
        <unittitle>Tallmadge, Benjamin to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1814 Mar 5</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Tallmadge has written to Mr. Huntington on the subject. If he needs any further aid from Adams &quot;to make a statement for the assessor, please to afford it.&quot; Tallmadge reports on appropriations made in the House.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2421">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">27</container>
        <unittitle>Tallmadge, Benjamin to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1816</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written in Washington, D.C., while Tallmadge was serving in the U.S. House of Representatives.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2422">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">27</container>
        <unittitle>Tallmadge, Benjamin to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1816 Feb 7</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Tallmadge discusses a transaction he will conduct on behalf of Adams relative to the value of &quot;D&#039;ft on Charleston&quot; and the sale of Adams&#039;s &quot;D&#039;ft&quot; to a gentleman in Georgetown. He relates percentages and specifies which banks are to be used to make payment.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2423">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">27</container>
        <unittitle>Tallmadge, Benjamin to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1816 Mar 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Tallmadge reports on the sale of Adams&#039;s &quot;D&#039;ft.&quot; He has received payment and purchased a bill on New York at 10 percent premium.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2424">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">28</container>
        <unittitle>Tallmadge, Benjamin to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1823 May 3</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Tallmadge, writing from Litchfield to Adams in Brooklyn, relates details of Tallmadge&#039;s trip to Litchfield via New Haven. He delivered Adams&#039;s letter to his wife. Adams&#039;s family is all well and since Mrs. Adams will write soon, he will not go into further reporting &quot;domestic matters.&quot; He reports on several recent deaths which have occurred in Litchfield.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2425">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">29</container>
        <unittitle>Wolcott, Oliver (1823-1856)</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1845 Mar 31</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wolcott sends an invitation to Adams on behalf of the Whigs of Litchfield to attend the polls and then enjoy &quot;suitable refreshments&quot; at the Mansion House.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2426">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Joseph (1838-1870)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Joseph Adams (1838-1870) was the son of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2427">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Joseph to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 May 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Terryville, Conn., to thank his mother for $3 with which to buy Charlie a hat. He describes how Charlie will not keep a hat on. He recalls the recent sad deaths of Sarah and Frankie in Terryville and reports on the health of the family. He is away on business half the time. He reports on his garden. Willie is off to school and supposes Ella will comfort him if he is homesick.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2428">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman (1810-1869)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Julia Hinman Adams was the second wife of Charles Adams. They married in 1830. He was previously married to Jane Hinman Adams (Julia&#039;s sister), who died in 1827.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2430">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1851-1852</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters, one to her father and one to her daughter.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2429">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman to Hinman, Scovil</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1851</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Litchfield to her father about sickness in and news of her family, that she is tired and dispirited, and about news of friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2431">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman to Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1853 Aug 22</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes to her daughter saying that it would be nice if she and Julia were back home. She reports on family news and visits by relatives.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2432">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862-1867</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters to family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2433">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman to Adams, Mary</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 May 22</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Buffalo to her daughter about family and friends she sees, her tour of Buffalo, and her husband&#039;s and her sadness over the recent death of daughter Sarah.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2434">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman to unnamed son</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 May 28</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Buffalo about her impressions of the city, encountering several Sisters of Charity, and news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2435">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Nov 17</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Terryville, Conn., to her husband about the health of Joseph, the weather and thinking of him, her health, and family news. Also on the sheet is a letter from her daughter Ella Adams to Ella&#039;s sister Mary.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2436">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1867 Jun 18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Brooklyn, N.Y., to her husband about visiting with Joseph in Plymouth, meeting up with Mr. McKee en route to Brooklyn, stops along the way, family news, the children are well, and what she is eating.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2675">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>[?] to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1860s</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Empty envelope.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2437">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Curtiss, Hannah E. to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860 Jan 26</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Curtiss writes from Hartford about the health of friends, the weather, her sore hand, and indelible pencils and obtaining a highly recommended ink. She received &quot;that letter&quot; from her mother, who thinks she should go to Ravenna as soon as the canal opens and keep house. She thinks she should rather stay in this part of the world.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2491">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>How, James (1840-1869) to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Mar 13</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>How writes to his mother-in-law from Brooklyn that it has been ten months since they were married and they are more happy each day. He writes about his activities, including his work for charitable institution, City Dispensary, and news from family, including from Charlie in camp.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2438">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah MacMurphy (1806-1901)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Sarah MacMurphy Adams married John Marsh Adams, son of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2439">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah McMurphy to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1842 Jun 17-18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Augusta, Ga., about her health and that of her family, gladness that Charles is going to settle in Litchfield, and the transfer of her and her husband&#039;s interest in the real estate of Henry Adams to his sister Mary. On the same sheet is notarized and signed statement by John Marsh Adams and Sarah Adams transferring their interest as referenced in the letter.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2440">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah (1840-1862)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Sarah Adams (1840-1862) was the daughter of Charles and Julia (Hinman) Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2441">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1855-1859</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three letters to her parents.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2442">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1855 Dec 10</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Hart Seminary in Plymouth about school life, activities, what she is reading, and news of some of the other girls.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2443">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 Jun 7</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Bath, N.Y., that she arrived three hours late because an engine conveying a freight train exploded outside of Port Jervis. She offers her account of the explosion and its aftermath. A man who introduced himself as Mr. Sanford said her father intended to return to Litchfield. She reports family news.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2444">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 Oct 22</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Terryville, Conn., that sister Emma asked to her to write and ask her mother to send a slop pail and foot tub for a bath tub for baby. Adams did not sleep well and is beginning to lose her faith in the blisters. She has made a visit long enough.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2445">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Letters from friends to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1856-1859</unitdate>
    </did>
<c04 level="item" id="id2446">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, D. to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 Nov 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Rogers writes from New Haven about a letter written but not sent, the value of reading, her headache and a walk, an upcoming visit by Clara and how she loves her friends, and wonders about the conditions of Adams&#039;s eyes.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2447">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, D. to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1859 Nov</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Letter fragment in which Rogers writes about Clara leaving and the house feeling different, her homesickness for Litchfield, her headache today, and her having wasted the day.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2448">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Stoddard, F. E. to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1856 Jun 1</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Stoddard writes from Seymour that he was in New Haven at the same time as Mary but did not see her. Stoddard would like to see Mary and Sarah sometime this summer. Stoddard has started taking music lessons in New Haven. Stoddard&#039;s family&#039;s black girl has run away and they are without help.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2449">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>[?], Maria to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1856 Feb 17</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Maria writes from Plymouth about letters she has received, her schooling, and fellow students.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2450">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, Henry W. to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 Aug 5</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Adams writes from Buffalo to his niece about Sarah&#039;s nice words about Julia, family news, reading, and his activities.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2451">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Baldwin, Ella Adams (1852-?)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Ella Adams Baldwin was the daughter of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2452">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Baldwin, Ella Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870 Feb 20</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Baldwin writes from Brooklyn about listening to public speakers, letters she&#039;s received, attending church, visiting Harriet De Puy, making many visits to New York, turning eighteen tomorrow, returning home, and Joel Hinman.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2453">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Bulkley, Mary Adams (1830-1900)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Mary Adams Bulkley was the daughter of John Marsh and Sarah MacMurphy Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2454">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Bulkey, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1839, 1868</unitdate>
    </did>
<c04 level="item" id="id2474">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Bulkley, Mary Adams to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1839 May 31</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bulkley writes to her grandparents about news of her sisters, the new baby&#039;s name, sending presents, and the scarlet fever that is in and about town.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2455">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Bulkley, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1868 Jun 30</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bulkley writes to her uncle about visiting next week with her family, provided he finds this an agreeable arrangement.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2456">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Bullard, Henry Adams (1788-1851)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Henry Adams Bullard (1788-1851) was the son of Rev. John and Elizabeth Adams Bullard. He was the nephew of Joseph Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2457">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, Henry Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1832-1833</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written from Washington, D.C. to his uncle Joseph Adams while serving in the U.S. House of Representatives from Louisiana.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2458">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, Henry Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1832 Apr 17</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard writes that he is grateful for his uncle&#039;s letter with interesting details of himself and his family. Since leaving New England, Bullard has had no opportunity to become acquainted with that branch of the family. He relates details about his family. The Jackson heresy has not tainted him and he hopes to see the day when the present misrule will be overturned. He hopes to be able to visit Litchfield in the fall.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2459">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Bullard, Henry Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1833 Feb 28</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Bullard writes that he visited with Charles, who travelled with his wife and son to Baltimore. Bullard is eager to return home after a long absence. Unfortunately, he was unable to visit Adams because one of his children was sick and later died. There was constant alarm about cholera. He has heard from Aunt Richards, who is feeble. He discusses the new tariff.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2460">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Coggswell, Elizabeth Rowland (1802-?)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Elizabeth Rowland Coggswell (1802-?) was the niece of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2461">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Coggswell, Elizabeth Rowland</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1828, 1830</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written in Cincinnati to Elizabeth&#039;s uncle Joseph Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2462">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Coggswell, Elizabeth Rowland to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1828 Nov 25</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Coggswell writes that she hopes to hear more often from Litchfield and misses her family and friends. They are living comfortably and rent from Mr. Woodward. She lost her son. There has been a great revival of religion. She tells of visits and hearing from family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2463">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Coggswell, Osmond and Coggswell, Elizabeth Rowland to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1830 Nov 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Osmond and Elizabeth Coggswell write that they sorry to have taken so long to write after visiting Litchfield. They describe the travel back to Cincinnati. They spent time with Mr. Collier and his family. Mr. Richards is building a large manufactory in Dayton and all in good health.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2464">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Dana, Rev. Malcolm McG.</unittitle>
    </did>
<c03 level="file" id="id2465">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Dana, Rev. Malcolm McG. to Hubbard, John H.</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 9</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters regarding the condition and transportation of Charles Adams (1839-1864), badly wounded in the Civil War Battle of Cold Harbor.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2466">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Deming, Frances Adams (1847-1901)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Frances Adams Deming (1847-1901) was the daughter of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2467">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Deming, Frances Adams to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1860 Jun</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Frances writes to her sister and hopes she will be very much better when she returns. Mary attended a wedding and a party at the Pinnacle. Frances mentions Julia, Susie Rogers, and Sophie. Frances likes school and would go all summer if father wanted her to.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2468">
    <did>
        <unittitle>De Puy, Harriet Adams (1822-1914)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Harriet Adams De Puy was the daughter of Amos and Eliza Dean Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2469">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>De Puy, Harriet Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1845, 1879</unitdate>
    </did>
<c04 level="item" id="id2475">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>De Puy, Harriet Adams to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1845 May 3</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>De Puy writes from Bath about the death of sister Ann Eliza. The health of her family is good and she enjoys their company. She hears that Joseph and Deborah Adams may visit Bath in the summer and nothing would please her more than seeing them.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2470">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>De Puy, Harriet Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1879 Sep 30</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>De Puy writes from New York City about her family history.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2471">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Doty, T.</unittitle>
    </did>
<c03 level="file" id="id2472">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Doty, T. to Terry, James</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870 May 17</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Telegram sent from Champaign, Ill., which informs Terry that J. H. Adams died there. Will put body in vault and wait fro instruction.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2473">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Graves, Mary Hinman (1812-1856)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Mary Hinman Graves (1812-1856) was the sister of Julia Hinman Adams, wife of Charles Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2476">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Graves, Mary Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1850-1853</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Five letters to her sister and father.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2477">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Graves, Mary Hinman to Hinman, Scovil</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1850 Aug 9</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Graves writes from Bristol, R.I. Her husband has become so debilitated by the heat that they have left Jamaica and moved to the home of father Graves. If Mr. Graves&#039;s health improves, they will return before the cold weather. Her husband endured the voyage from Kingston but is weak.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2478">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Graves, Mary Hinman to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1850 Oct 2</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Graves writes from Bristol, R.I. Mr. Graves is in very weak condition. It is not possible that he can live long in his present emaciated, feeble state. Julia Adams forwarded this letter to Scovil Hinman with an additional note to say that she is now safely in Litchfield after a recently traveling 800 miles to visit family.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2479">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Graves, Mary Hinman to Hinman, Scovil</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1851 Feb 27</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Graves writes from Bristol, R.I., that she has returned from Boston and is staying with father Graves. She is lonely and imagines how lonely her father is, and wishes she had a home into which she could take him and care for him, but her future plans are uncertain.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2480">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Graves, Mary Hinman to Hinman, Scovil</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1852 Feb</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Graves writes from Hartford. She is visiting, but she is actively engaged with her needle and her pen to assist in the support of her dear son and herself. She describes activities in Hartford and her&#039;s son religious inclinations.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2481">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Graves, Mary Hinman to Adams, Julia Himan</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1853 Feb 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Graves writes from Framingham, Mass. She has been in East Boston, where Charlie is attending school. She describes her activities in Boston. She wishes she could attend to her father, but is duty bound to provide for Charlie. The letter has a note from Mary Adams indicating it was sent on to Scovil Hinman.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2482">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Graves, Mary Hinman, empty envelope addressed to Hinman, Scovil</unittitle>
        <unitdate>[circa 1850s] Mar 26</unitdate>
    </did>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2484">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Hinman, Mary Coles</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Mary Coles Hinman was the second wife of Scovil Hinman, father-in-law of Charles Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2485">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hinman, Mary Coles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1858-circa 1864</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters to her step-grandchildren.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2486">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hinman, Mary Coles to unnamed stepchildren</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1858 Oct 18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Hinman writes from New Haven with news of her and her husband&#039;s activities and her desire to see the children.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2487">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hinman, Mary Coles to Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1861 Oct 7</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Hinman writes from Stonington, Conn., about her activties there, family and friends, and her desire to see her grandchildren.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2488">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hinman, Mary Coles to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1861 Oct 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Hinman writes from Stonington, Conn., about her family and friends and her activities.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2489">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hinman, Mary Coles to unnamed stepchildren</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1864 May 24</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Hinman writes from New Haven about her wish to visit Litchfield, her attire and that of her grandchildren, what she has been eating, and other activities.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2492">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Hubbard, John H. (John Henry) (1804-1872)</unittitle>
    </did>
<c03 level="file" id="id2493">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hubbard, John H.</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to the death of Charles Adams (1845-1864) from wounds received during the Civil War Battle of Cold Harbor.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2494">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hubbard, John H.</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Unaddressed telegraph message stating that Charlie Adams died this morning. &quot;I was with him.&quot; Offers a few additional details.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2495">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hubbard, John H. to his wife</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Writing from Washington, D.C., Hubbard describes the circumstances surrounding the death of Charles Adams (1845-1864) and the arrangements he is making for transfer of the body to Litchfield.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2496">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Hubbard, John H., ledger sheet</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains copies of his correspondence related to the death of Charles Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2497">
    <did>
        <unittitle>May, Betsey Adams (1796-1877)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Betsey Adams May was a daughter of Joseph Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2498">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Buel, C. [Charlotte?] to May, Betsey Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1815 Aug 28</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Buel writes from Troy, N.Y., with news of her and her family&#039;s health. Her mother begs Betsey&#039;s mother to accept the shawl for Betsey and the vest for Amos.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2499">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>May, Betsey Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1868-1869</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written from Bath, N.Y. to her brother.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2500">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>May, Betsey Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1868 Jan 31</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>May writes about comfort of Julia and Adams now small family, but that he is not far away from them should he need to visit. She reports on her family&#039;s health and activities. There have been many changes in Bath since he was there. She never receives letters from the Adams family.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2501">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>May, Betsey Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1869 Jan 8</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>May writes that because of her eyes, it is hard for her to write or read. She reports on her and her family&#039;s health and activities and is sorry to hear Julia is doing so poorly. She hopes they can visit this summer and recalls their visit last summer. Bath has been visited by another fire this winter.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2502">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Richards, Amos Adams (1794-1872)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos Adams Richards (1794-1872) was the son of Giles and Sally (Adams) Richards. Joseph Adams was his uncle.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2503">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Amos Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1813, 1866</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters, one to his uncle and one to his cousin.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2504">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Amos Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1813 Aug 1</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes from Boston about his and his family&#039;s health, his father&#039;s plan to give up his tools so he and Giles can establish themselves in Smithfield, R.I., how they plan to establish a business, American and British ships, and finding a place for Amos, but there has never been a worse time for business</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2505">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Amos Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1866 Dec 14</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes from Urbana, Ohio, and recalls visiting Litchfield in 1813 and other events in his life, reports on his family, recalls what he knows of Adams&#039;s family, and discusses his philosophy of life.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2506">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams (1769-1836)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Sarah Adams Richards was a sister of Joseph Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2507">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1798 Jun 12</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes from Charleston, S.C. about their late brother Thomas&#039;s affairs, a new baby has been added to the family, Mr. Richards traveling in New Hampshire and is much perplexed about his business matters, and family news.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2508">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1800</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters written in Cambridge, Mass., to her brother.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2511">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1800 Oct 1</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes that she has not heard from him in over twelve months. She would like to visit, but Mr. Giles business requires him to travel and if he heads for the vicinity of Litchfield, she will accompany him. She reports on her and her family&#039;s health.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2515">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1800 Nov 23</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes about her pleasure of hearing from Adams. Mr. Richards has been out of health lately provoked by his business affairs, but he has lately improved them to avoid embarrassment. He is at a loss as to what business to persue. She regrets being at a distance from her only brother. She reports on family health. She would be eager to read any news from the widow of their brother.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2523">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811-1813</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three letters to her brother Joseph Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2516">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811 Jun 29</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards reports on family news and health and the possibility of visiting Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2524">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1813 Apr 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes from Boston to report he death of their nephew William in Camden, S.C. and the status of his personal property and real estate and claims made against it. She would like Adams to render his opinion on the matter. She reports on the health of the family.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2525">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1813 Jul 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes from Boston thanking Adams for his kind attention to Amos. She offers her opinion concerning the Camden property and reports on health of family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2526">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1816-1819</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three letters written in Dedham, Mass., to her brother Joseph Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2527">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1816 Feb 1</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes that she has not heard from Adams in two years. She reports on her family and Mr. Richards&#039;s business affairs. They have purchased a house and property in Dedham and have no family there &quot;but George and Mary and a colour&#039;d girl of which I have had two years which I am to keep till she is 18.&quot; She encourages Adams to move to Dedham.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2529">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1818 Jun 21</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes about the health and news of her family and friends. They have made improvements to her house. Mr. Richards is better and is resuming his business.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2528">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1819 Aug</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes about loss of her dear Sarah. Mr. Lawrence has broken up his house and sent his children to relatives. She reports additional family news. She feels older and more broken down than their sister and is not up to writing.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2530">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1827 Nov 26</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes from Dedham, Mass., commenting on Adams&#039;s letter in which he reports on his family. She reports on the health and news of her family. She is glad Adams is attached to a minister and describes the many churches and liberal preaching in her neighborhood.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2531">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1829-1834</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three letters to her brother Joseph Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2532">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1829 Mar 22</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes from Dedham, Mass., about the health of her family. She intended to ask Kezia to spend the winter, but Mr. Richards&#039;s health did not permit it. She relates news of her family.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2533">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1831 Sep 25</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>She writes from Dayton, Ohio, about her health. She believes it best to stay close to her children, describes their business activities and activities of other family members and friends. She discusses philosophical differences in churches.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2534">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1834 Jan 7</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Richards writes from Boston. She has been to Vermont where she hoped her health would improve. She relates news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2535">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">7</container>
        <unittitle>Lawrence, Amos (1786-1852) to Richards, Sarah Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1833 Jun 27</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Lawrence writes to his former mother-in-law from Boston. His son William will meet her in Litchfield to accompany her to Boston. He reports news of family health and activities. He does not attend to business much, but provides counsel to his partners. He discusses arrangements for her stay.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2536">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Rogers, Kezia Adams (1811-1899)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Kezia Adams Rogers was the daughter of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2537">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, Kezia Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1869-1870</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Three letters to her brother Charles Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2538">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, Kezia Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1869 May 30</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Rogers writes from Dresden, Germany, about James How&#039;s death. She express her sympathy for Julia and discusses her situation. They are enjoying Dresden very much and she describes it, the people, and their religion.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2539">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, Kezia Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1869 Oct 14</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Rogers writes from Buffalo that she was shocked to learn that Julia had died and expresses her sympathies. She discusses her husband&#039;s illness. She writes about visitors and the difficulty in taking up housekeeping after traveling.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2540">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Rogers, Kezia Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870 Dec 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Rogers writes from Buffalo about her relocation and the long, tedious process of packing the books and storing the belongings. She is not going to worry any more about the future. She enjoyed his and the girls&#039; visit. She reports news of family and reflects on her long life.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2541">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How (1842-?)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Julia Adams How Wessells (1842-?) was the daughter of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2542">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters written from Buffalo to family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2544">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 Jan 30</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes about teaching her scholars. She is surprised to read in The Litchfield Enquirer her marriage notice and relates news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2543">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Baldwin, Ella Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1859</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Letter to her little sister.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2545">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 Feb 6</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes responding to her mother&#039;s recent letter which described lively winter activities in Litchfield. She writes about skating, her studies, news of friends and family, and attending entertainments.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2554">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1859 Apr 17</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes about her activities, including attending a magic lantern exhibition and a concert, her enjoyment of music, the condition of Adams&#039;s eyes, and news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2555">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters to family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2556">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860 Feb 19</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Buffalo about news of family and friends, school, and social activities.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2557">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Peck, Sarah Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860 Jul 24</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes to her aunt about family news and her social activities.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2558">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860 Aug 16</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes to her mother about her arrival back in Litchfield, people who have called on her or she has called on, and a joke in a telegram.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2559">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860 Sep 20</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes to her mother from Buffalo about new of family and friends, her schooling, and social calls she and others have made.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2560">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1861-1862</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters to family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2561">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1861 Mar 17</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Buffalo to her sister about surprise at receiving a letter from her given her condition, news of family and friends, entertainments she has attended, her schooling, and the national political climate and President Lincoln.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2562">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1861 Apr 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessell writes to her sister from Buffalo about Adams&#039;s illness, news of family and friends, the news from the South and civil war, singing a song at a school concert, and attending musical events.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2563">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 Mar 2</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Buffalo to her sister to wish her a happy birthday, news of family and friends, making a catalogue of uncle&#039;s library, her singing, and social activities.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2564">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 May 18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes to her mother that they are getting along well with sewing and housekeeping, this is father&#039;s fifty-seventh birthday, they have visited Sarah&#039;s grave, she supposes her mother will be in Buffalo soon and recommends friends to visit.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2565">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863-1865</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Six letters to family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2566">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles and Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Mar 29</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes about her mother&#039;s health, her constant thoughts about Frankie and Sarah, and Mary&#039;s health.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2567">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Jun 12</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Brooklyn about travels of family members, their residence, her daily routine, news of family and friends, her happy marriage and good husband, and Jim obtaining a piano.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2568">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Jul 22</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Brooklyn about getting Adams a dress, her health, recent visitors, news of family and friends, being alone and what she is reading.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2569">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Mar 28</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Brooklyn about her and her husband&#039;s health, the New York Fair and Sanitary Commission, dining at Willow St., and news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2570">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 May 18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Brooklyn about Adams&#039;s fifty-ninth birthday, well wishes from friends, recent visitors, and socializing.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2571">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1865 May 18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Brooklyn about her fathers&#039;s sixtieth birthday, her loneliness without her husband, and family news.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2572">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1866-1869</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Five letters to family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2573">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1866 Jan 28</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Brooklyn to her sister about her sister&#039;s birthday, health of family members, upcoming visit to Litchfield, longing for a sleigh ride, news of friends, and social activities.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2574">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1866 Sep 16</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from West Hampton, N.Y., about their sudden trip there. She describes her impressions of the landscape and relates family news.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2575">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1868 May 23</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Brooklyn about Mary&#039;s miscarriage last night.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2576">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1869 May 2</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Brooklyn that she has no heart for writing, but feels that she ought to. She longs to see her mother, and her friends are very kind. She thanks God for her two children and prays for strength to take care of them.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2577">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Henry</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1869 Oct 26</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wessells writes from Terryville, Conn., to her brother about coming up from New Haven with Jimmy and grandmother. She will be glad to be home again. She hopes father is improving and Fannie keeps well.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>

</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="id2578">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams (1838-1895)</unittitle>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Mary Adams Wheelock (1838-1895) was the daughter of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c03 level="file" id="id2579">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1855-1860</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Four letters to family members.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2580">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1855 Oct 27</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes to her father about school and news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2581">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1858 Sep 10</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes about family health, her mother&#039;s travels, the presents recently received, visitors, and news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2582">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860 Jun 29</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes that they have arrived in Washington from Buffalo. Uncle escorted them about the city. They will leave for Litchfield on the early train on Monday. They called on the Hows yesterday and go to Greenwood today and Central Park tomorrow.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2583">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters to her mother.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2584">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 May 21</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes that she is glad her mother has arrived in Bath, N.Y. She writes about activities in their home, health and news of family and friends, wishing her a good visit, and Julia and her giving their father &quot;The Memorial Vol. of the American Board of Missions&quot; for his birthday.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2585">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams and Adams, Charles to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1862 May 25</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes that she is glad her mother is having a pleasant visit. She has reassigned bedrooms for the children and reports on activities in their home. She reports news of friends and family. Her mother must not think of returning for weeks because they are getting along splendidly. They have received many kind letters of sympathy. She received a letter from Charley; he was in the Battle of Williamsburg and says he cannot see how he escaped being killed or wounded. Charles Adams writes that they are getting along nicely and all are well.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2586">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Five letters to her parents.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2587">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams and Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Mar 18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes to thank her father for the his letter and the money. She is delighted mother has been to Dea. Catlins and had the neighbors in for tea. Wessells writes that she is delighted to hear about mother&#039;s health. They have received a call from Brigadier General Carlin, who has been in a great deal of hard fighting. She went to the art gallery and describes social activities. She received a beautiful philopoena from Mr. Worthington.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2588">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Mar 23</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes that she and Auntie went to Bath, N.Y. and reports on family there. She was glad to receive letters from her mother and father. She has thought much of Sarah and Frankie and is very sad. She reports on family news and asks wonders about family and why father resigned as deputy sheriff.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2589">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 May 4</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock is glad is mother is gaining strength. She is pleased that the 19th regiment did not join Hooker. She discusses dresses for her sisters, the upcoming visit, and other matters related to Julia&#039;s wedding.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2590">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Dec 16</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes that she has not been out, but had a number of callers. Yesterday, she attended a historical lecture. She describes other social activities.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2591">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to [?]</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1863</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Letter fragment. Wheelock discusses brides&#039; maids dresses, a possible trip to Jamestown, and an invitation to visit from Clara Beebe Darling.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2592">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864-65</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Two letters to her mother.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2593">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Nov 30</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes from home of family and domestic news.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2594">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>[United States. Dept of Agriculture] to Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1864</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Empty envelope.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2595">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles and Adams, Julia Hinman</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1865 Aug 4</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes from Buffalo about her journey there and whom she traveled with. She met a man who knew Charles fifteen years ago. She is very glad she made the journey by herself this time and had no trouble. She reports news of family and friends.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2596">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870-1872</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Six letters written in Brooklyn, N.Y. to her father.</p>
    	</scopecontent>
<c04 level="item" id="id2597">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870 Jan 31</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes about news of family and friends, including dining with Charley Graves last night.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2598">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870 Feb 6</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes about her concern for her father&#039;s health and news of family.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2599">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, John to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870 Feb 6</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>John Wheelock&#039;s letter was sent with Mary&#039;s 1870 Feb 6 letter. He discusses arrangements relating to Ella, Mary, and Fannie.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2600">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1870 May 27</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes about the funeral services for Joseph and that her thoughts are with her father very much.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2601">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1871 Mar 11</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes about her concern for Fannie and news of family and friends. It is very kind of him to invite her home for the summer, but she cannot leave her husband and duties here.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>
<c04 level="item" id="id2602">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1872 Apr 17</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Wheelock writes that she feels half sick and good for nothing. She wishes she could spirit herself to Litchfield during the day because the hours are long and she feels lonely until John comes home. She describes their journey to New York.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c04>

</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="id2603">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Greene, Marie Barton to Wheelock, Mary Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Marie Barton Greene worked with the Christian Commission and Sanitary Commission attending to wounded Civil War soldiers as they arrived in Washington, D.C. She sent two letters to a sister of Charles Adams (1845-1864), Mary Adams Wheelock, describing how she attended Adams during the last hours of his life on June 11, 1864. Adams had been been severely wounded in  the Civil War Battle of Cold Harbor. John H. Hubbard and several others were present. One letter includes a poem she wrote &quot;suggested by meeting and watching beside&quot; Charles &quot;in his last moments.&quot;</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c03>

</c02>

</c01>
<c01 level="series" id="id2324">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Other papers</unittitle>
    </did>
<c02 level="file" id="id2490">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Joseph (1767-1856) last will and testament</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1841</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2604">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">2</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Joseph (1767-1856) last will and testament</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1850</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2605">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">3</container>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman (1810-1869), &quot;What Aunt Julia said...&quot;</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1869</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Document recording the last words of Julia Hinman Adams.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2606">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">4</container>
        <unittitle>Baldwin, Daniel estate distribution</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1840</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2607">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">5</container>
        <unittitle>Brewer, Jehoida, &quot;Hiding Place&quot;</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa early 1800s</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten copy of Brewer&#039;s 1776 poem.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2608">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">6</container>
        <unittitle>Bulkley, David C., St. Paul&#039;s Lodge No. Eleven lease</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860 Jul 26</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2614">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">7</container>
        <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1886, 1928</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Amos Adams Lawrence obituary, 1886 Aug 22, and Charles Hinman Graves obituary, 1928 Oct.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2610">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">8</container>
        <unittitle>Head Quarters Military District, Washington, D.C., pass for Charles Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863 Aug 13</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2611">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">9</container>
        <unittitle>Herbert, Morris citizenship record</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1863</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2612">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">10</container>
        <unittitle>Holt, Kezia Adams (1747-1811) last will and testament</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1811</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2613">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">11</container>
        <unittitle>Knitting instructions</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1850s</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2615">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">12</container>
        <unittitle>Phoenix Bank receipts</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1814, 1822</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2616">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">13</container>
        <unittitle>Waugh, Lucy B., lines suggested on attending the funeral of the late Charles Adams</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 26</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2617">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">14</container>
        <unittitle>Wedding cards</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860s</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Clara C. Vaill, Mr. &amp; Mrs. Charles E. Robinson, Miss Amelia H. Buck, Dr. &amp; Mrs. Alfred North.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>
<c02 level="file" id="id2609">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">15</container>
        <unittitle>Wheelock, Mary Adams, transcription of David Gray&#039;s poem &quot;Outrivalled&quot;</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1860s</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="item" id="id2620">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Litchfield Enquirer, The</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1864 Jun 18</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Entire third and fourth page. Contains extensive coverage of the Civil War Battle of Cold Harbor, a list of killed and wounded, and obituaries of Luman Wadhams, Charles Adams (1845-1864), and Lyman Smith. Currently housed in 18B oversize box 17.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>
<c02 level="item" id="id2619">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Marsh, Solomon estate survey</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1857 Jun 29</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Currently housed in 18B oversize box 9.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>

</c01>
<c01 level="series" id="id2618">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
    </did>
<c02 level="file" id="id2621">
    <did>
		<container type="Folder">1</container>
        <unittitle>Unidentified male silhouette</unittitle>
        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>

</c02>
<c02 level="item" id="id2626">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Album</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1860s-1870s</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Album of 36 cartes de viste, most unidentified. Cover has &quot;Julia M. Adams Dec. 7th 1862.&quot; stamped on it. Currently housed in 3A Box 4.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>

</c01>
<c01 level="series" id="id2627">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Albums</unittitle>
    </did>
<c02 level="item" id="id2628">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Jane Hinman (1806-1828)</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1825-1827</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Album of poems inscribed to Jane C. Hinman. &quot;J. C. Hinman&quot; is stamped on the cover. Later annotated. Her husband, Charles Adams, recorded her death and a poem on July 30, 1828. Currently housed in 3A box 4.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>
<c02 level="item" id="id2629">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Julia Hinman (1810-1869)</unittitle>
        <unitdate>1827-1830, 1850</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Album of handwritten poems. &quot;Miss Julia M. Hinman&quot; written on endpaper. Later annotated. Currently housed in 3A box 4.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>
<c02 level="item" id="id2630">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Adams, Jane Hinman (1806-1828) and Adams, Julia Hinman (1810-1869)</unittitle>
        <unitdate>circa 1827, 1848-1853</unitdate>
    </did>
    	<scopecontent>
					<p>Album of poems probably copied by Jane C. Adams. &quot;J.M.H.&quot; written on front endpaper. Diary entries from 1848-1853 added by Julia Hinman Adams. Currently housed in 3A box 5.</p>
    	</scopecontent>

</c02>

</c01>

</dsc>

<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
</archdesc>
</ead>
