<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/CtB/CtB_default_ead.xsl"?><!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd"><ead><eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid mainagencycode="CtB" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/CtB/bhcmss002.xml">bhcmss002</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Jasper McLevy Collection</titleproper><author>Collection guide written by Meghan Rinn. Collection processed by Meghan Rinn.</author><sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library</publisher><address><addressline>925 Broad Street</addressline><addressline>Bridgeport</addressline><addressline>CT</addressline><addressline>06604</addressline><addressline>email: hclibrarian@bridgeportpubliclibrary.org</addressline><addressline>URL: http://bportlibrary.org</addressline><addressline>Phone: 203-576-7400, #7</addressline></address><date>Jan 08, 2018</date><p>http://bportlibrary.org</p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation><date>.</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language></langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><frontmatter><titlepage><num>Collection number: BHC-MSS 0002</num><publisher>Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library<lb/>925 Broad Street<lb/> Bridgeport, CT  06604</publisher><p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p><list type="deflist"><defitem><label>Collection guide written by:</label><item>Meghan Rinn</item></defitem><defitem><label>Collection processed by:</label><item>Meghan Rinn</item></defitem></list><p>&#x00A9; 2018 Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library. All rights reserved.</p></titlepage></frontmatter><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Collection Summary</head><origination label="Creator"><persname source="DA:CS">McLevy, Jasper</persname></origination><unittitle>Jasper McLevy Collection</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1900-1962</unitdate><unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="CtB" countrycode="us">BHC-MSS 0002</unitid><physdesc label="Extent"><extent>35 l ft.</extent><extent>12 manuscript boxes, 8 record cartons, 13 oversized boxes</extent></physdesc><repository label="Repository"><corpname>Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library</corpname><!-- <address><addressline> 925 Broad Street</addressline></address> --></repository><abstract label="Abstract">The Jasper McLevy Collection represents the professional and public life of Jasper McLevy, Bridgeport's socialist mayor from 1933-1957.  It holds records from his administration, documentation from the Socialist Party of Bridgeport including minute books and account books, and personal scrapbooks compiled by McLevy, as well as speeches and additional material.</abstract><langmaterial label="Languages Represented"><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><accessrestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Collection open for research.</p></accessrestrict><userestrict><head>Publication Rights</head><p>For copyright status, please contact the Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library.</p></userestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>[Identification of item], , [Box no]., Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library</p></prefercite><bioghist><head>Biography</head><p>Jasper McLevy (March 27, 1878-November 20, 1962) served as the mayor of Bridgeport, Connecticut from 1933 to 1957.  The city's first socialist mayor, he is best remembered for helping to resolve the city's bankruptcy, on the site inspections, and keeping a tight purse string, as well as weeding out the corruption of the earlier mayors of the city.  To many in the city, he was simply known by his first name, Jasper.</p><p>McLevy was the son of Scottish immigrants, and the oldest of nine children.  He began to work with his father in the roofing trade after a stint of factory jobs prior to his leaving the eighth grade.  His interest in Socialism came from reading the book Looking Backward by Edward Bellamy, and would soon see him make a large number of attempts at public office.  He ran for the Connecticut General Assembly as a socialist in 1902, and that was followed by twenty more unsuccessful campaigns for various public offices.  It took nine campaigns for him to be elected mayor of Bridgeport, and these campaigns frequently featured him on a soapbox.</p><p>Small successes prior to his election in 1933 did exist though.  In 1903 he helped to get a petition passed that funded free textbooks for elementary school children in the city.  He also did organization work for the Central Labor Union, and became the International President of the Slate and Tile Roofer's Union.</p><p>These activities helped elect him to the office of mayor in 1933, following the resignation of Mayor Buckingham and the ensuing contest between James L. Dunn, President of the Common Council, and McLevy.  The tally was in McLevy's favor with 22,445 votes, a lead of about 6,000 over Dunn.</p><p>McLevy inherited a city wide debt upon coming into office, a combination of the 1929 stock market crash and poor management by the city afterwards.  That the federal government assumed the city's debt about eight days after McLevy was elected helped significantly. His administration was noted for penny pinching during McLevy's time in office.   Frequently McLevy's work day involved his going into his office for an hour in the morning and in the afternoon, and spending the rest of the day elsewhere in Bridgeport with those he represented.</p><p>Under his tenure, McLevy became known for being out in the field, for his fiscal restraint, and generally focusing on the details of managing the city.  He helped to bring the civil service to Bridgeport, build miles of esplanades for the Park City, spent federal relief money carefully, maintained low taxes, and helped to overhaul Bridgeport's sewer system channeling waste to dedicated plants rather than out into the Long Island Sound.  Bridgeport saw four federal housing projects built under McLevy's administration, including the later infamous Father Panik Village which was built as part of a "slum clearance" project.</p><p>His approach to running the city was not without criticism.  The inaccurate, but often told story of McLevy declaring "God put the show there, let Him take it away" reflects the fact that his hold on the city purse strings was sometimes too tight.  Beyond snow removal, he objected to an extra $4,500 for a dedicated full-time school physician, and later in his career, was caught up in a fight with city firefighters who wanted better conditions and more pay - a surprise for a man who was international president of a trade union.  Critiques increased as McLevy's tenure grew longer.  One notable one came as the city expanded - new residents in newly developed areas were not receiving the same fire, police, and sewer service as older parts of the city.  Downtown began to show its age, and there was no spending dedicated to improve it.</p><p>Come 1955 the Bridgeport Democrats ran Samuel Tedesco against McLevy.  While McLevy remained mayor for two more years, Tedesco unseated him in 1957.  McLevy campaigned for reelection afterwards, and he only stopped his engagement when he suffered a stroke in 1960.</p><p>Beyond his impact as mayor of Bridgeport, McLevy was also a part of the Socialist Party both in Connecticut and nationally. He helped get three socialists into the state senate, and two representatives in Hartford come 1934.   Some critics viewed McLevy and others as being so-called Old Guard Socialists who only appeared to adhere to party principles but failed to act on them.  This tension came to a head at the Detroit Convention of the Socialist Party in 1934. The Declaration of Principles, which had a more radical bent, was adopted at this time.  Members that voted against the declaration formed the Social Democratic Federation, which McLevy then joined, creating friction with party loyalists.  In 1938 briefly, and then permanently in 1950, McLevy and the Connecticut Socialists left the National Party.  McLevy's socialism was decidedly low key, and his work primarily focused on reform.</p><p>Much of McLevy's life outside of politics remained private to the point of being mostly hidden from the public.   There is little known about his first wife, Mary Flynn.   He married his second wife, Vida Stearns, in 1929, but this information remained unknown for five years until The Herald found the records in the Office of Vital Statistics.  Stearns herself was an artist, and the two had a farm in Washington, Connecticut, which served as their shared home.  According to rumor, the real reason the two lived apart was because Stearn's father objected to a perceived abandonment of socialist principles by McLevy, but this information was never remarked upon by either.  In their later years, they had two collies, both named Lassie, who were photographed frequently with McLevy, along with a cat named Peter.</p><p>Jasper McLevy died on November 19, 1962.  His honesty in office was constantly remarked upon, as was the frugality of his tenure.</p></bioghist><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content of Collection</head><p>The Jasper McLevy collection primarily provides an overview of Jasper McLevy's professional and political life, with an emphasis on his time as the mayor of Bridgeport and his association with socialism.</p><p>Correspondence, mayoral files, and related material cover the personal papers of McLevy, starting in 1919 and ending in 1962.  The vast majority of the contents relate to his political and public life, but additional material towards the end of the series addresses his personal life and includes correspondence with his second wife Vida Stearns and information about their farm.</p><p>The Socialist Party of Bridgeport series primarily contains the minute books of the Socialist Party of Bridgeport, as well as several account books, offering insight into the functions and day to day events of the party at the time.  Other material focuses on their activity and campaigns they have been involved in, including platforms, a scrapbook of newspaper advertisements, and campaign literature.</p><p>The material in the speeches series features drafts and finalized press releases of various speeches given by McLevy over the years.   </p><p>Printed material documents the various functions that McLevy attended or else was invited to, showing the scope of his involvement with the city, as well as organizations at the state and national level.</p><p>Scrapbooks are curated by McLevy himself, and demonstrate how he viewed himself.  Their date range provides a broad overview of his career in the public eye. </p><p>Clippings are arranged by rough chronological order when possible.  However many folders are undated, due to the delicate nature of the clippings.  They may yet undergo preservation work.</p><p>3d items are primarily awards given to McLevy.</p><p>The two boxes at the end of unprocessed material contain items that need treatment, but are likely unable to be attended to in the near future.</p></scopecontent><arrangement><head>Arrangement</head><p>In 2010, an inventory and initial processing of the Jasper McLevy papers were begun by Robert G. Marshall, who mainly organized the correspondence, mayoral files, and related material files.  Processing was begun again in 2017 by Meghan Rinn who completed the project.</p><p>The Jasper McLevy Papers are arranged into six series, based primary on format.  They are correspondence, mayoral files, and related material; Socialist Party of Bridgeport; Speeches; Printed Material; Scrapbooks; Clippings; 3D items; and unprocessed material.</p><p>Note that the contents of boxes 19 through 21 were found near the end of processing.  A decision was made not to integrate them into the existing scrapbook boxes primarily because these scrapbooks are in poorer condition than the others, and it was safer to keep them apart.</p></arrangement><controlaccess><head>Indexing Terms</head><p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection inthe library's online public access catalog.</p><persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">McLevy, Jasper, 1878-1962 </persname><corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Socialist Party of the United States of America</corpname><subject encodinganalog="650">Connecticut - Bridgeport</subject><subject encodinganalog="650">Politicians - Connecticut - Bridgeport - Biography</subject><subject encodinganalog="650">Socialism - United States - History - 20th Century</subject></controlaccess><dsc><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Series I, Correspondence, mayoral files, and related material</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">1</container><container type="folder">1-9</container><unittitle>Correspondence, mayoral files, and related material</unittitle><unitdate normal="1919/1933" type="inclusive">1919-1933</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">2</container><container type="folder">1-9</container><unittitle>Correspondence, mayoral files, and related material</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">3</container><container type="folder">1-8</container><unittitle>Correspondence, mayoral files, and related material</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">4</container><container type="folder">1-15</container><unittitle>Correspondence, mayoral files, and related material</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1953" type="inclusive">1940-1953</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">5</container><container type="folder">1-11</container><unittitle>Correspondence, mayoral files, and related material</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1962" type="inclusive">1954-1962</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">6</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Charter amendments to the City of Bridgeport</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937" type="inclusive">1937</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">6</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Survey and Recommendations of the Hartford Police Department</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941" type="inclusive">1941</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">6</container><container type="folder">3</container><unittitle>Narrative, Wheeler property for prop. Civic Center</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1955" type="inclusive">1954-1955</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">6</container><container type="folder">4</container><unittitle>Wheeler Mansion</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">6</container><container type="folder">5</container><unittitle>Honorary degree from Wesleyan</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941" type="inclusive">1941</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">6</container><container type="folder">6</container><unittitle>Undated correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">6</container><container type="folder">7</container><unittitle>Vida Stearns, early correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">6</container><container type="folder">8</container><unittitle>Mrs. McLevy’s lectures</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Income tax</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1959" type="inclusive">1958-1959</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Correspondence re: secret marriage</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934" type="inclusive">1934</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">3</container><unittitle>McLevy farm documents</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">4</container><unittitle>Obituaries</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">5-8</container><unittitle>Greeting cards</unittitle><unitdate normal="1910/1930" type="inclusive">1920s-1960</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">10</container><unittitle>Political cartoons of McLevy,</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1957" type="inclusive">1947-1957</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">11</container><unittitle>National cyclopedia of American Biography portrait of McLevy, signed</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">12</container><unittitle>Photographs, McLevy and other officials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1970" type="inclusive">1941-1970s</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">13</container><unittitle>Portraits of McLevy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">14</container><unittitle>Photographs of McLevy from Unknown Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">15</container><unittitle>Photographs, Construction of Bridgeport Firehouse #16</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">16</container><unittitle>Photographs, Dorthoy Secor and Audubon J. Secor</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">17</container><unittitle>Other photographs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">7</container><container type="folder">18</container><unittitle>Negatives, McLevy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Series II, Speeches</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">8</container><container type="folder">1-21</container><unittitle>Speeches</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934" type="inclusive">1934</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">8</container><container type="folder">22</container><unittitle>Various short topic essays</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Series III, Socialist Party of Bridgeport</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">9</container><container type="folder">1-6</container><unittitle>Socialist Party of Bridgeport minutes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1920" type="inclusive">1900-1920</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">10</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Socialist Party of Bridgeport minutes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1932" type="inclusive">1932</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">10</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Socialist Party of America Financial Secretary’s Ledger, c.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1908" type="inclusive">1908</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">10</container><container type="folder">3-4</container><unittitle>Socialist Party of Bridgeport combination account book</unittitle><unitdate normal="1911/1930" type="inclusive">1911-1930</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Additional socialist party materials including ballots</unittitle><unitdate normal="1912/1936" type="inclusive">1912-1936</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Declaration of Principles</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934" type="inclusive">1934</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">3</container><unittitle>In Answer to Devere Allen's Alleged Truth about New York: by James ONeal, March, 1936; Rules, minutes of National Convention of Democratic Socialists, May 29-31, 1937;  List of bills sponsored by the Socialist Party of Connecticut, 1939p; Hartford's Tammany Hall and Invisible Government" by Bellani Trombley, undated</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">4</container><unittitle>Socialist Party newspaper advertising scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944" type="inclusive">1944</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">5</container><unittitle>Socialist party publications and advertising</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1959" type="inclusive">1930-1959</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">6</container><unittitle>Socialist Party platforms</unittitle><unitdate normal="1938/1946" type="inclusive">1938-1946</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">7</container><unittitle>Socialist Party banquet programs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">8-10</container><unittitle>McLevy Mayoral Campaign literature</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1945" type="inclusive">1939-1945</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">11</container><unittitle>History of the Socialist Party in Connecticut Integrated with the National Socialist Party by Victory E. Muniec</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953" type="inclusive">1953</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">12</container><unittitle>Socialism and women: the Bridgeport Experience, by Henry H. Barnard</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976" type="inclusive">1976</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">11</container><container type="folder">13</container><unittitle>Photographs, socialists</unittitle><unitdate normal="1920/1969" type="inclusive">1920-1969</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Series IV, Printed material</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">12</container><container type="folder">1-5</container><unittitle>Programs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1960" type="inclusive">1934-1960</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Series V, Scrapbooks</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">13</container><container type="folder">1-3</container><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">14</container><container type="folder">1-3</container><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">15</container><container type="folder">1-3</container><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1937" type="inclusive">1935-1937</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">16</container><container type="folder">1-3</container><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1960" type="inclusive">1937-1960</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">17</container><container type="folder">1-3</container><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1970" type="inclusive">1959-1970s</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">18</container><container type="folder">1-3</container><unittitle>Socialist party scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1941" type="inclusive">1934-1941</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">19</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Scrapbook, Socialist party</unittitle><unitdate normal="1905/1910" type="inclusive">1905-1910</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">19</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1929/1932" type="inclusive">1929-1932</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">20</container><container type="folder">1-3</container><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1955" type="inclusive">1937-1955</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">21</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">21</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Scrapbook, Awards to Mc Levy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1959" type="inclusive">1950-1959</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">21</container><container type="folder">3</container><unittitle>Scrapbook, group photos and testimonials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1959" type="inclusive">1950-1959</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">21</container><container type="folder">4</container><unittitle>Scrapbook, personal and untitled</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Series VI, Clippings</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">22</container><container type="folder">1-11</container><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934" type="inclusive">1934</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">23</container><container type="folder">1-14</container><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1938" type="inclusive">1935-1938</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">24</container><container type="folder">1-10</container><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">25</container><container type="folder">1-8</container><unittitle>Clipping</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1949" type="inclusive">1940-1949</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">26</container><container type="folder">1-10</container><unittitle>Clippings,</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1954" type="inclusive">1950-1954</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">26</container><container type="folder">11</container><unittitle>Clippings, Barnum Festival</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953/1954" type="inclusive">1953-1954</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">27</container><container type="folder">1-3</container><unittitle>Clippings, Barnum Festival</unittitle><unitdate normal="1955/1957" type="inclusive">1955-1957</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">27</container><container type="folder">4-14</container><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">28</container><container type="folder">1-12</container><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">29</container><container type="folder">1-9</container><unittitle>Newspapers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1960" type="inclusive">1937-1960</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Series VII, 3-d items and oversized material</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">30</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Cap, gown, and honorary degree from Wesleyan University</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941" type="inclusive">1941</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">31</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Bridgeport Municipal Airport sign</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">31</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Recognition award from YMCA Industrial Recreation council,</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960" type="inclusive">1960</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">31</container><container type="folder">3</container><unittitle>Legion of Valor recognition award</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935" type="inclusive">1935</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Series VII, Unprocessed material</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">32</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Two wooden boxes for documents bearing McLevy’s name on the spine. Due to acidic nature, these spines will be sawed off and put in safe housing, and the boxes themselves discarded</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">33</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>A scroll and additional photographs that are curled up and in need of treatment</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Accrual, March 2018</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">34</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Page 1 biography, revised to April 7, 1962,</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">34</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Campaigns</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">34</container><container type="folder">3</container><unittitle>Administration</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">34</container><container type="folder">4</container><unittitle>Socialist splits</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">34</container><container type="folder">5</container><unittitle>Soapbox, 8 takes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">34</container><container type="folder">6</container><unittitle>Inspected city jobs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">34</container><container type="folder">7</container><unittitle>Housing plan</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><langmaterial><language langcode="eng"/></langmaterial><unittitle>Accrual, August 2018</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">35</container><container type="folder">1</container><unittitle>Award from Bridgeport Brass Company Quarter Central Club to McLevy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><container type="box">35</container><container type="folder">2</container><unittitle>Emancipation award to McLevy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate></did></c02></c01></dsc></archdesc></ead> 