<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./styles/wesstyletop.xsl" ?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "./dtds/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY weseal PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//NONSGML (weseal)//EN" "./seals/weseal.gif" NDATA gif>
<!ENTITY hdrsca PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (hdrsca)//EN" "./addresses/hdrsca.xml">
]>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtW" publicid="-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (US::CtW::1000-198::Cuvierian Society Records)//EN" url="http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/cu1000-198.html">cu1000-198</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Inventory of the Cuvierian Society Records, <lb/><date normal="1836/1846">1836 - 1846</date>
                </titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Margorie A. Biafore (class of 1979); machine-readable finding
                    aid created by: Valerie Gillispie</author>
<!-- OPTIONAL: Sponsor Statement
                    <sponsor></sponsor>
                -->
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>&hdrsca;<p><date normal="2010" encodinganalog="date">©
                        2010</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights Reserved.</p></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Machine-readable finding aid derived from XML authoring program.<lb/>
                <date>Date of source: July 2010</date>
            </creation>
      <langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid was prepared using <title>DACS</title></descrules>
    </profiledesc>
<!-- Location of <revisiondesc> if needed -->
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Inventory of the Cuvierian Society Records, <date type="span">1836 -
                    1846</date>
            </titleproper>
      <publisher><extptr show="embed" entityref="weseal"/> Special Collections &amp;
                Archives<lb/>Wesleyan University<lb/> Middletown, CT, USA </publisher>
<!-- Delete paragraph below and this comment line if your institution does not copyright its findingaids. -->
      <p><date normal="2010">© 2010</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights
                Reserved.</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <repository label="Repository">Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan
                University</repository>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname encodinganalog="110">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Cuvierian Society</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle label="Title" encodinganalog="245">Cuvierian Society Records, <unitdate normal="1836/1846" type="inclusive">1836 - 1846</unitdate></unittitle>
      <unitid countrycode="us" repositorycode="CtW" label="Call Number" encodinganalog="099">1000-198</unitid>
      <langmaterial label="Language of Material" encodinganalog="546">Material in <language langcode="eng"/>English</langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Linear Feet">
        <extent encodinganalog="300">0.1</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physdesc label="Volume">
        <extent>1</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Location">For current information on the location of these materials,
                please consult Special Collections &amp; Archives staff.</physloc>
      <abstract label="Abstract" encodinganalog="545">The Cuvierian Society was organized in
                April 1836 as the Natural History Society, a primarily undergraduate organization at
                Wesleyan University for the study of natural science. Along with some faculty
                members, alumni, and local community members, the organization gathered for monthly
                meetings, during which members read essays and heard addresses from invited guests.
                The group changed its name to the Cuvierian Society in 1837. It continued to meet
                regularly until May 1846. </abstract>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520">The Cuvierian Records consist of a single volume, which
                includes constitutions, by-laws, lists of members, and meeting minutes.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp type="admininfo">
      <head>Administrative Information</head>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
        <head>Access Restrictions</head>
        <p>No restrictions.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
        <head>Copyright Notice</head>
        <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Wesleyan University; all
                    other copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their
                    descendants, as stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Preferred Citation</head>
        <p>[Identification of item], Cuvierian Society Records, Collection #1000-198,
                    Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University, Middletown, CT,
                    USA.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
        <head>Acquisitions Information</head>
        <p>Acquired by the library in the 1930s.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo>
        <head>Processing Information</head>
        <p>Processed by Marjorie A. Biafore (class of 1979), spring 1977</p>
        <p>Encoded by Valerie Gillispie, July 2010</p>
      </processinfo>
    </descgrp>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the bioghist in separate p elements. -->
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The Natural History Society was organized 18 April 1836 as a predominantly
                undergraduate organization for <emph render="doublequote">the investigation and
                    promotion of various departments of natural science.</emph> The original
                constitution and by-laws were adopted in April 1836 and were revised 29 May 1841.
                The constitution provided for the election of officers at an annual meeting of the
                society: President, Vice President, Corresponding Secretary (always a faculty
                member), Recording Secretary, and Curator/Librarian. Members were designated as
                Resident (students of Wesleyan and residents of Middletown); Corresponding (students
                who had graduated); Honorary (elected if <emph render="doublequote">deemed worthy,
                    for their attainments in Natural Science</emph>); and Faculty (ex-officio
                resident members). It was voted at the second meeting of the society (26 April 1836)
                to include juniors in the ranks of members, and at the meeting of 18 August 1840,
                the society voted to amend the constitution to include freshmen and sophomores.</p>
      <p>In order to collect money for a treasury, it was decided at the meeting of 25 August
                1836 that <emph render="doublequote">A tax of 12 1/2 cents was levied on each of the
                    members to defray certain incidental expenses.</emph> Whenever extra money was
                needed, a similar <emph render="doublequote">tax</emph> was voted upon by the
                society.</p>
      <p>Although the society was originally known as the Natural History Society of the
                Wesleyan University, its name was changed (apparently not in a formal way, i.e., no
                evidence of a vote by members) to the Cuvierian Society, presumably after Baron
                Georges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert
                Cuvier (1769-1832), French zoologist and geologist, a founder of comparative anatomy
                and paleontology. The first evidence of a name change is seen in the minutes of the
                meeting of 30 September 1837: A regular meeting of the Natural History Society,
                alias Cuvierian Society was held this day. After this date it was always referred to
                as the Cuvierian Society in the meeting minutes. Both versions of the constitution
                refer to it as the Cuvierian Society.</p>
      <p>The last minutes in this record book are for the meeting of 30 May 1846. Essayists
                were appointed to speak at the next meeting, but it is not known if any further
                meetings were held.</p>
      <p>At each monthly meeting, essays on some aspect of science were expected to be read to
                the society by members who had been chosen at the previous meeting. Many, however,
                were not prepared with essays, prompting a resolution at the meeting of 14 November
                1838, that <emph render="doublequote">persons having essays to write and failing in
                    the duties devolving upon them shall be fined 25 cents each.</emph> Even this
                stern measure apparently did little to motivate the appointed essayists; recording
                secretary B. F. Mudge, in the minutes for 26 February 1842, editorialized somewhat
                on the situation: <emph render="doublequote">Essayists upon being called upon were
                    found deficient <emph render="underline">as usual</emph>.</emph> Some of the
                topics of the papers included <title render="doublequote">Phrenology</title>; <title render="doublequote">Grasshoppers and Locusts</title>; <title render="doublequote">The Bee</title>; <title render="doublequote">Salt</title>;
                    <title render="doublequote">Coal Formations</title>; <title render="doublequote">Eels</title>; and <title render="doublequote">The Hummingbird.</title> Local
                natural phenomena were also discussed at meetings: e.g., the Great Comet of 1843 (25
                March and 24 April 1843), a locust colony (27 May 1843), and a bald eagle lately
                taken in Meriden (27 July 1844).</p>
      <p>An address to the Society on the subject of natural science on 31 July 1838 by
                William H. Allen, professor of chemistry and experimental philosophy in Dickinson
                College, was printed in New York in 1838.</p>
      <p>The Cuvierian Society maintained a cabinet and, later, a room, to hold various
                specimens which the members had collected or which had been donated. The minutes of
                25 August 1836 read: <emph render="doublequote">A rattlesnake was received and a
                    vote of thanks returned to the donor H. W. Smith. Also a Shark's
                    Skeleton.</emph> It was noted on 19 May 1837 that the society was given the use
                of <emph render="doublequote">the room over the labratory [sic]</emph> for <emph render="doublequote">the preservation and exhibition of their collections and
                    specimens in Nat. His.,</emph> as long as none of the specimens were removed
                from the University. It was also understood that the collection would be donated to
                the University in the event that the Cuvierian Society should cease to exist; the
                collection eventually became part of the Museum in Judd Hall.</p>
      <p>Several non-students had a great influence on the Cuvierian Society. Professor John
                Johnston served as corresponding secretary for most of the society's existence, and
                was elected president at the meeting of 25 July 1845. Prof. Johnston was an active
                participant at nearly every meeting. Dr. Joseph Barratt of Middletown was elected an
                honorary member of the society 8 June 1836. The minutes of 19 September 1836 read,
                    <emph render="doublequote">It was . . . voted that the thanks of this society be
                    presented through the corresponding secretary to Dr. Barratt for the interest he
                    has taken in behalf of said society.</emph> Dr. Barratt was also an active
                member, delivering essays or papers and making <emph render="doublequote">remarks</emph> on various topics of natural science at many meetings. He was
                elected president 29 June 1844, and served until the election of Prof. Johnston.
                Augustus Smith, professor of mathematics and astronomy, 1831-1857, was also involved
                in the society during its last years.</p>
<!-- use "Chronlist Tags" here if there is a chronology -->
    </bioghist>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the scopecontent and arrangement in separate p elements. -->
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The Cuvierian Records consist of a single volume, which includes constitutions,
                by-laws, lists of members, and meeting minutes.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess><head>Online Catalog Headings</head><p>These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online
                catalogs.</p><!-- use "Item Level Tags" here for controlaccess terms --><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Cuvierian Society.</corpname><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.</corpname><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.</corpname> 
                    <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.</corpname>
            
            <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Natural history--Connecticut.</subject>
            
            <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Natural history--History--19th century.</subject>
            


        </controlaccess>
<!-- Use separated materials and related materials clips here to enter in information -->
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>
<!-- use component levels clips to enter in the description of subordinate components -->
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Cuvierian Society Volume, 1836-1846</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Leaf">1-4</container>
            <unittitle>Lists of members, arranged by class year</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Leaf">6-7</container>
            <unittitle>Constitution, adopted 29 May 1841</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Leaf">8</container>
            <unittitle>By-laws, adopted 25 September 1841</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Leaf">13-14</container>
            <unittitle>Constitution, undated (article 16 was amended 12 June
                            1839)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Leaf">15</container>
            <unittitle>By-laws, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Leaf">16-41</container>
            <unittitle>Minutes of meetings 18 April 1836-30 May 1846</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
