<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./styles/wesstyletop.xsl" ?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "./dtds/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY weseal PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//NONSGML (weseal)//EN" "./seals/weseal.gif" NDATA gif>
<!ENTITY hdrsca PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (hdrsca)//EN" "./addresses/hdrsca.xml">
]>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtW" publicid="-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (US::CtW::1000-43::James Oliver Longstreet Diary)//EN" url="http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/lo1000-25.html">lo1000-25</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the James Oliver Longstreet Diary, <lb/><date normal="1856">1856</date>
                </titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Drew Flanagan; machine-readable finding aid created by:
                    Valerie Gillispie</author>
<!-- OPTIONAL: Sponsor Statement
                    <sponsor></sponsor>
                -->
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>&hdrsca;<p><date normal="2010" encodinganalog="date">©
                        2010</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights Reserved.</p></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Machine-readable finding aid derived from XML authoring program.<lb/>
                <date>Date of source: February 2010</date>
            </creation>
      <langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid was prepared using <title>DACS</title></descrules>
    </profiledesc>
<!-- Location of <revisiondesc> if needed -->
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Guide to the James Oliver Longstreet Diary, <date type="single">1856</date>
            </titleproper>
      <publisher><extptr show="embed" entityref="weseal"/> Special Collections &amp;
                Archives<lb/>Wesleyan University<lb/> Middletown, CT, USA </publisher>
<!-- Delete paragraph below and this comment line if your institution does not copyright its findingaids. -->
      <p><date normal="2006">© 2010</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights
                Reserved.</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <corpname>Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University</corpname>
      </repository>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname encodinganalog="100">Longstreet, James Oliver, 1833-1861.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle label="Title" encodinganalog="245">James Oliver Longstreet Diary, <unitdate normal="1856/1856" type="inclusive">1856</unitdate></unittitle>
      <unitid countrycode="us" repositorycode="CtW" label="Call Number" encodinganalog="099">1000-25</unitid>
      <langmaterial label="Language of Material" encodinganalog="546">Material in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Linear Feet">
        <extent encodinganalog="300">0.1</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physdesc label="Volume">
        <extent>1</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Location">For current information on the location of these materials,
                please consult Special Collections &amp; Archives staff.</physloc>
      <abstract label="Abstract" encodinganalog="545">James Oliver Longstreet was born
                November 16, 1833. He received a bachelor's degree from Wesleyan in 1857. As a
                student at Wesleyan, he was a member of the Mystical Seven secret society and the
                Missionary Lyceum. After graduating from Wesleyan, Longstreet worked as both a
                teacher and a preacher until his death in 1861.</abstract>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520">James Oliver Longstreet's personal diary from the year
                1856 covers the second semester of his junior year at Wesleyan, as well as the first
                semester of his senior year. Many events are recorded in the diary, including the
                1856 presidential election and the founding of the Middletown chapter of the Alpha
                Delta Phi fraternity. Longstreet also discusses his work as a teacher in North
                Guilford, Connecticut and North Branford, Connecticut.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp type="admininfo">
      <head>Administrative Information</head>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
        <head>Access Restrictions</head>
        <p>No restrictions.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
        <head>Copyright Notice</head>
        <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Wesleyan University; all
                    other copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their
                    descendants, as stipulated by United States copyright law. </p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Preferred Citation</head>
        <p>[Identification of item], James Oliver Longstreet Diary, Special Collections
                    &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University, Middletown, CT, USA.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
        <head>Acquisitions Information</head>
        <p>Received prior to 1980.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo>
        <head>Processing Information</head>
        <p>Processed by Drew Flanagan, February 2010</p>
        <p>Encoded by Valerie Gillispie, February 2010</p>
      </processinfo>
    </descgrp>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the bioghist in separate p elements. -->
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>James Oliver Longstreet was born November 16, 1833, in Onondaga, New York. His
                parents owned and operated a farm in Onondaga. He received a BA from Wesleyan in
                1857. As a student at Wesleyan, he was a member of the Mystical Seven secret society
                and the Missionary Lyceum. Starting in 1856, he served as president of the
                Missionary Lyceum and as president of the senior class. Longstreet was politically
                active while at Wesleyan, campaigning for John C. Fremont during the 1856
                presidential campaign. He was a member of the Republican Party, and active in their
                group on campus. Longstreet was vocal about his abolitionist views, and expressed
                pleasure in reading the writings of Frederick Douglas. During the summers and
                winters he taught school in various locations, especially in North Guilford and
                North Branford (both in Connecticut). After graduating from Wesleyan, Longstreet
                taught in Croton Falls, NY, from 1857 to 1858. From 1858-1860, he attended the
                Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, NY, receiving the degree of
                Masters of Arts. He married Josephine Christopher of Croton Falls, NY, on July 7,
                1859. In 1860, he joined the Troy Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church. He
                was a preacher at Hyde Park, Vermont, from 1860 until his death in 1861.</p>
<!-- use "Chronlist Tags" here if there is a chronology -->
    </bioghist>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the scopecontent and arrangement in separate p elements. -->
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>This collection consists of James O. Longstreet's personal diary from the year 1856.
                The diary covers the second semester of his junior year at Wesleyan, as well as the
                first semester of his senior year. Many events are recorded in the diary, including
                the 1856 presidential election and the founding of the Middletown chapter of the
                Alpha Delta Phi fraternity. Other notable subjects discussed in the manuscript
                include the caning of Charles Sumner on the U.S. Senate floor, President Buchanan's
                interest in the annexation of Cuba, Methodist missionaries in Fiji, abolitionism,
                temperance, the Mystical Seven, Psi Upsilon, the Eclectic Society, and other
                Wesleyan activities and organizations.</p>
      <p>The diary begins in North Guilford, CT, where Longstreet was employed as a schoolteacher
                for the winter break. While serving as a teacher, he participated in the conversion
                to Methodism of several individuals, including Carrie and Evan Bartlett, Charles
                Fowler, Alden Fowler, Dwight Hall, Mary Ann Norton, Mary Chittenden and Cynthia
                Scranton. Longstreet's strong Methodist faith is in evidence throughout the diary.
                During the winter of 1856, he began leading prayer meetings in his schoolroom to the
                consternation of some local religious leaders, who appear to have viewed him as
                competition. On January 8, the diary records Longstreet's budding affection for one
                of his students, Miss Lois Dudley, whom he describes as <emph render="doublequote">so smart.</emph> Longstreet's school was kept in working order with the help of
                several friends from the neighborhood of North Guilford, including students of his
                and participants in his prayer meetings, notably Anson Fowler and Edwin Bartlett.
                The arrival in mid-January of Mr. Dutton, another Methodist preacher, seems to have
                disturbed Longstreet as Dutton would eventually take the meetings <emph render="doublequote">out of (his) hands</emph>, according Longstreet's December
                31 year-in-review entry. Dutton would move into the parsonage and take Longstreet's
                place as preacher.</p>
      <p>On January 18, Longstreet describes the conversion of Carrie Bartlett, a girl who he
                will counsel for much of the remainder of the year on matters of faith. On January
                31, he notes that <emph render="doublequote">Fowler hinted strange</emph> against
                his prayer meetings in the school building. The opposition voiced by Fowler made him
                feel <emph render="doublequote">a little bad.</emph> On February 3, <emph render="doublequote">Fowler again hinted at me for doing meetings in the
                    schoolhouse but he may hint on and it will do no good.</emph> In mid-February, a
                property dispute appears to have arisen between Longstreet and a man named Tobey. On
                February 13, he quips <emph render="doublequote">Oh! Tobey, what a liar!</emph> The
                debate is further explicated on February 16, when Longstreet notes that Tobey is
                currently in possession of goods formerly belonging to a Mr. Britton. Those goods
                appear to have been claimed by both Tobey and Longstreet, although Longstreet
                repeatedly calls Tobey a liar. Meanwhile, Longstreet's teaching job was nearing its
                end. He remained in North Guilford for two weeks after his engagement was over. On
                March 9, he heard a temperance lecture from a Mr. Cue which he described as <emph render="doublequote">in most respects the most absurd thing I ever heard.</emph>
                His issues with Mr. Dutton continued, and on March 12 <emph render="doublequote">the
                    girls</emph> were <emph render="doublequote">annoyed</emph> that Dutton gave
                Longstreet no chance to speak at the meeting. Anson Fowler, Edwin Bartlett, and
                Charles Fowler helped Longstreet to plan the exhibition for the end of school, which
                    <emph render="doublequote">went well except some of the singing</emph> on March
                19. On that date, he received the gift of <emph render="doublequote">a beautiful
                    gold pencil and pen</emph> from a student named Augusta. His school ended on March 20, and he
                departed for Middletown CT and college on March 22.</p>
      <p>Once at college, Longstreet attended the first of many 
                meetings of the Mystical Seven secret society. He took classes including Mineralogy
                and Mechanics. During this time and afterward, he would often spend evenings at the
                home of Brother Fox, apparently a popular hangout for students at the time. On March
                31, Longstreet went to Mr. Tobey's store to resolve their dispute over Mr. Britton's
                goods. Tobey agreed to <emph render="doublequote">divide Britton's yard</emph> or
                else sell his half to Longstreet for $80. After carefully examining the goods,
                including 75-100 <emph render="doublequote">good books,</emph> he determined that
                the goods would sell for 70-80 dollars and determined to offer Tobey 20 dollars for
                his half of the goods. On April 7, he concluded a deal to purchase the other half of
                the goods from Tobey at a price of $38. <emph render="doublequote">That way if they
                    sell well, I will get my pay.</emph> In May, classes continued including German
                and Logic. On May 29, Longstreet mentions the health situation of Charles Sumner,
                the recently caned Republican abolitionist Senator, stating that he <emph render="doublequote">is worse.</emph></p>
      <p>On June 6, Longstreet appears to have received marks. <emph render="doublequote">Made
                    5 in Logic and German and 4 in Geology,</emph> he wrote. Throughout his diary,
                Longstreet questions the strength of his faith, including on June 7 when he worries
                that he is <emph render="doublequote">too lifeless in (his) religion, tho still
                    trusting with trembling.</emph></p>
      <p>On June 21, he mentions attending a Republican meeting. <emph render="doublequote">I
                    am determined to get up a platform,</emph> he reports. On June 22, he notes that
                Carrie Bartlett is <emph render="doublequote">discouraged trying to be a
                    Christian,</emph> a situation she seems to find herself in repeatedly. On June
                25 he reports that the local Republican club has <emph render="doublequote">adopted
                    the constitution that we drew up.</emph> More political news follows, with a
                    <emph render="doublequote">grand Democratic splurge</emph> on July 17. <emph render="doublequote">Fremont men [including Longstreet] cheered after meeting
                    adjourned.</emph> He describes how <emph render="doublequote">some Democrats,
                    headed by Putnam, made [Brother] Fox run for his life. He hid in Mc.
                    Donough.</emph> On July 21, he commenced reading Frederick Douglass. <emph render="doublequote">I like it well.</emph></p>
      <p>The diary describes the founding of the Middletown chapter of the Alpha Delta Phi
                fraternity. On July 23, Longstreet's friend Powers (probably Orville Watson Powers,
                class of 1856) contacted him because his society, known as the Lebanians, wanted to
                    <emph render="doublequote">become a chapter of ΑΔΦ and he wants me to recommend
                    his society to Head.</emph> Also on that date <emph render="doublequote">fire
                    broke out in the college barn. Buddington's horse was burned.</emph> Longstreet
                wrote the recommendation letter for Powers on July 24. On August 1, Longstreet
                writes, <emph render="doublequote">This morn have learned that the Betrians and
                    [Powers' group] have united and come out ΑΔΦ!!!</emph></p>
      <p>On August 7 was commencement, and in possibly the first recorded instance of its kind
                at Wesleyan, <emph render="doublequote">Carr was rejected by ΑΔΦ and feels
                    dreadfully.</emph> After commencement, Longstreet visited family in New York. On
                September 4, he returned to school. September 9, Longstreet was elected president of
                the Missionary Lyceum. <emph render="doublequote">I don't like the responsibility of
                    the office,</emph> he wrote. Longstreet was involved actively in cultivating new
                members for the Mystical Seven during this period, including Wardell, Edson and
                Gould. Competition between the societies (Longstreet mentions Mystical Seven, Chi
                Psi, Eclectic, Alpha Delta Phi and Psi Upsilon) was sharp. October 7 he had tea with
                Professor Van Vleck. On October 9, he and Lois, Ella, Mary E.C., Katy D., Carrie, Mary
                B., Anson, Edwin, Harrison and Fayette went to the state fair in New Haven.</p>
      <p>On October 17, Longstreet reports that Buchanan had won the presidential election.
                According to Longstreet, <emph render="doublequote">. . . the country will go to the
                    Devil.</emph> He showed great interest and involvement in the Republican cause,
                even after John C. Fremont's electoral defeat. His diary records the widespread
                interest in the election. For example, when he went for dinner at his friend Mr.
                Blake's house on November 5, he reported that, <emph render="doublequote">They are
                    very much excited about the election. They think old Buck (Buchanan) will make
                    slaves of us all.</emph> On November 11, Longstreet was hired to teach school in
                North Branford, CT, for the winter. On a few occasions, most recently on December 30,
                1856, he reported that he was reading about Methodist missionary work amongst the
                Feejies (Fijians).</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Of Interest:</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Several Wesleyan faculty appear repeatedly in the diary, including Professor True,
                Professor Johnson, Prof. Huber in German, Professor Lindsay who <emph render="doublequote">preaches a good sermon,</emph> and Professor Van Vleck.</p>
      <p>Longstreet often worried about his health. February 14 he complained of back pains,
                while on March 2nd it was <emph render="doublequote">pain in the back and
                    shoulders.</emph> June 11, he was in bed all day with headache. June 13, he
                remained in bed but was feeling better. December 4, <emph render="doublequote">looseness of bowels</emph> sent him <emph render="doublequote">with haste to
                    the barnyard</emph> several times during the night. On December 20, he said
                    <emph render="doublequote">Don't feel well. Am conscious I am going <emph render="underline">down</emph>. Oh God if consistent give me good
                    health.</emph> He complained of headache and general sickness.</p>
      <p>On February 12, Longstreet recorded sending a letter to the <emph render="doublequote">Honorable J. Longstreet,</emph> possibly his father's name.
                His mother's name is not mentioned.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Longstreet's Year in Review</emph>
      </p>
      <p>James O. Longstreet's diary in unusual, in that it contains a sort of <emph render="doublequote">year in review</emph> section in which he reflects on his
                experiences in 1856. The following is a full transcription of this section. The
                underlines (and grammatical irregularities) are Longstreet's own. This section is
                followed, in the manuscript, by Longstreet's personal financial accounts.</p>
      <p>12/31/1856 (Wednesday)</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="italic">The school today has been <emph render="underline">very</emph>
                    noisy and <emph render="underline">most</emph> tired me out. Fine winter weather
                    tho just at night it was snowing some. Lydia, Mr. Chidsey's daughter has gone to
                    a party. Eve Fayette called at my room. This day closes up the year 1856. It is
                    with rather sober feelings that I look over the past year and into the new one
                    just at hand. When this year came in I was at North Guilford teaching the
                    pleasantest school I ever expect to have. Soon after the commencement of the
                    year, Lois R. Dudley, a young lady of about 16 came into my school. Of her more
                    anow. When 1856 came to us I was having good times in school and had begun to
                    hold religious meetings in school room and they were interesting. Anson Fowler
                    and I did most all the work but as the winter went on the interest increased. We
                    had after a time a prayer meeting and a class meeting every week. In the course
                    of the winter Edwin Bartlett, Charles Fowler, Alden Fowler, Dwight Hall, Carrie
                    Bartlett, Mary Ann Norton, Mary Chittenden and Cynthia Scranton gave good
                    evidence of conversion and Fayette, Augusta and Ada Rassiter, Myrta Heall,
                    George Hall, Mary Bartlett, Louise Norton and Ella Dudley were deeply interested
                    until Mr. Dutton came and took the meetings out of my hands, then all interest
                    died out. I was greatly opposed by both churches and when Mr. Dutton came I had
                    nothing to see to except the class meetings which I kept. Where all these are
                    tonight is more than I can tell. I fear only a very few are trying to be
                    Christians. Oh God save them going to perdition.</emph>
      </p>
      <p>
        <emph render="italic">My school closed March 20th. Eve before, had exhibition which
                    went off well. 28 of my scholars presented me a beautiful gold pen and pencil
                    which I now prize <emph render="underline">very highly</emph>. Parted with my
                    school in tears and on March 22nd went to Middletown. Worked hard 'til end of
                    term, passed examinations and spent one week of vacation visiting North
                    Guilford. Went back to college and in July came again for a few days. Passed
                    examinations at the end of the year and became a <emph render="underline">senior</emph>. Went home. Stayed 3 weeks. Bought for sisters a Melodian
                    (cost $90). Leave home with tears and come back to college. During fall made
                    several fruitless attempts to get a school for the winter and at last determined
                    to go home. Packed my trunk and got excused from college November 10th. Came
                    to North Guilford to make short visit and while there had offer of district
                    school in North Branford at $35 and found per month of 20 days each and I took
                    it. So here I am at the close of the year teaching within four miles of where I
                    was one year ago. This year which is just leaving has been in some respects the
                    best of my life and will be long remembered. Last winter was a bright page in my
                    history. But what is my present situation, prospects and c.? Not as good as I
                    could wish. My school is too large and by no means a pleasant one. My boarding
                    place is worse than the school. The board is the worst I have ever had in my
                    life and if I could move my quarters I would do it suddenly. My room is
                    comfortable and my bed good. I now expect to preach at North Madison every other
                    Sunday during the winter. I hope God will use me for accomplishing some little
                    good. My health is not good. I have had several poor days this winter,and feel
                    that I am going downhill. I work pretty hard and have poor fare and grow poor
                    under it. I hope and pray for health, for if that leaves me, I am gone for I
                    have nothing to live upon, much less to pay my debts with.</emph>
      </p>
      <p>
        <emph render="italic">I have been dreaming for some months about getting married.
                    Not that I wish a wife now, but I would like some Yankee girl in about two
                    years. I have been on the look out for some time but have seen none that quite
                    suit me. I want a good, pious girl, well educated and moderately handsome and a
                    good singer and a <emph render="underline">neat</emph> housekeeper. For quite a
                    while I have had Lois in my mind and I cannot get her out, though I know in all
                    reason she can never be my wife. She is smart enough and good enough and her
                    singing will do and I am sure that she is neat and she is pretty good looking
                    and has a <emph render="underline">good</emph> figure; but am some six years the
                    older, she has not yet sufficient education, though she might improve that
                    before I should want her, and she has red hair. These are some objections on my
                    part and no doubt on her part there are many more, so that if she was
                    alright it might do me no good. She is a blessed good girl and I shall not only
                    keep alive our acquaintance but push it further, but must do it cautiously. At
                    present I think more of her than all the other girls in the world but shall not
                    allow the back part of my head to run away with me. I have prayed and continue
                    to pray, <emph render="doublequote">Oh God, direct me in so important a matter
                        as the selection of a wife.</emph> Well here I am truly just on the brink of
                    the old year's grave. In looking over my life for the past year I can see some
                    things which I did and am now sorry for but my fault has been not so much in
                    positive evil acts as in living at too great a distance from God. I have not
                    been spiritual enough through this whole year. I think on the whole I have
                    improved in some respects. I think I have a more settled Christian character
                    than I had one year ago but am not more <emph render="underline">alive</emph>.
                    Will I do better for the future? I am almost afraid to promise, for I see no
                    reason to think I shall keep it any better than I have kept others. But Lord if
                    thou will assist me to keep my promise I will agree to live nearer thee.</emph>
      </p>
      <p>
        <emph render="italic">Another year has gone and I am one year nearer my grave. I
                    have one year less in which to do good. Oh, how swiftly does time move on. Soon
                    my work will be ended, or at least my time for work and I shall be in the
                    presence of my judge. Oh God, help me to live so that I can give up my account
                    with joy. Show me my duty oh Lord that I may do it. Will thou have me to preach
                    thy gospel? Prepare me for the great work and I will go forth. My trust in God
                    tonight it strong. I give my all into his hands and firmly believe that he will
                    direct my ways. Tonight I am comfortable and happy. Where will I be in one year
                    from this night? Perhaps in eternity. Oh Lord thou alone canst tell, prepare me
                    for what is before me. Old year I sigh to bid you adieu. 1857 may be as
                    pleasant, but thy face is familiar. Thy name I have learned to love, and what
                    the next day may bring no mortal knows. I am almost afraid to trust it, but thou
                    canst no long stay so good bye, old year, good bye. Thou hast been my friend,
                    and in thy new made grave I drop a tear. Well little book I have about done with
                    thee. Thy page will tell truthfully the most of my history for the past year.
                    Thou has been willing to receive my sorrows and trials as well as my joys, and
                    in after time I will love to hear the stories that thou will tell of my course
                    through the year 1856. Little book I am now to place you among my old friends.
                    Good bye.</emph>
      </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Online Catalog Headings</head>
      <p>These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online
                catalogs.</p>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Republican Party (Conn.)</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown,
                Conn.)--History--19th century.</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.).
                Missionary Lyceum.</corpname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600">Longstreet, James Oliver, 1833-1861.</persname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown,
                Conn.)--Students.</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Mystical Seven (Fraternity : Wesleyan
                University, Middletown, Conn.)</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Alpha Delta Phi. Wesleyan
                Chapter.</corpname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Presidents--United
                States--Election--1856.</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Diaries.</genreform>
      <geogname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="651">North Guilford (Guilford,
                Conn.)</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="651">North Branford (Conn. : Town)</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="651">Middletown (Conn.)</geogname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">College students--Political activity--Connecticut--Middletown.</subject>
    </controlaccess>
<!-- Use separated materials and related materials clips here to enter in information -->
    <relatedmaterial>
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>Young Men's Republican Club of Wesleyan, Constitution and Minutes, 1856, Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <unittitle/>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Volume">1</container>
            <unittitle>James Oliver Longstreet Diary, 1856</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
