<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./styles/wesstyletop.xsl" ?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "./dtds/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY weseal PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//NONSGML (weseal)//EN" "./seals/weseal.gif" NDATA gif>
<!ENTITY hdrsca PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (hdrsca)//EN" "./addresses/hdrsca.xml">
]>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtW" publicid="-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (US::CtW::1000-141::Military on Campus Collection)//EN" url="http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/mi1000-141.html">mi1000-141</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Military on Campus Collection,
		<lb/><date normal="1968/1975">1968 - 1975</date>
		</titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Stephen Padilla; machine-readable finding aid created by: Valerie Gillispie</author>
<!-- OPTIONAL: Sponsor Statement
<sponsor></sponsor>
-->
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>&hdrsca;<p><date normal="2007" encodinganalog="date">© 2007</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights Reserved.</p></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc><creation>Machine-readable finding aid derived from XML authoring program.<lb/>
		<date>Date of source: November 2007</date>
	</creation><langusage>Description is in
		<language langcode="eng">English</language>
	</langusage><descrules>Finding aid was prepared using <title>DACS</title></descrules>  

</profiledesc>
<!-- Location of <revisiondesc> if needed -->
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage><titleproper>Guide to the Military on Campus Collection, <date type="span">1968 - 1975</date>
</titleproper><publisher><extptr show="embed" entityref="weseal"/>
Special Collections &amp; Archives<lb/>Wesleyan University<lb/>
		Middletown, CT, USA		



		
</publisher><!-- Delete paragraph below and this comment line if your institution does not copyright its findingaids. --> 

<p><date normal="2007">© 2007</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights Reserved.</p></titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC">
    <did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><repository label="Repository">Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University</repository> 

<origination label="Creator"><corpname encodinganalog="110">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)</corpname></origination><unittitle label="Title" encodinganalog="245">Military on Campus Collection, <unitdate normal="1968/1975" type="inclusive">1968 - 1975</unitdate></unittitle><unitid countrycode="us" repositorycode="CtW" label="Call Number" encodinganalog="099">1000-141</unitid><langmaterial label="Language of Material" encodinganalog="546">Material in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><physdesc label="Linear Feet"><extent encodinganalog="300">0.25</extent></physdesc><physdesc label="Archival Boxes"><extent>1</extent></physdesc><physloc label="Location">For current information on the location of
these materials, please consult Special Collections &amp; Archives staff.</physloc> 

<abstract label="Abstract" encodinganalog="545">During the Vietnam War, especially in the late 1960s and early 1970s, some Wesleyan University students and faculty protested military recruiters visiting the school. In response to the controversy, Wesleyan developed a policy about military recruitment. This issue subsided with the end of the Vietnam War and the draft.</abstract><abstract encodinganalog="520">The Military on Campus Collection contains correspondence, memos, clippings, and other materials related to the controversy on military recruitment at Wesleyan University from 1968 to 1973. Major correspondents are Phillip Rockwell and Paul Reynolds.</abstract></did>
    <descgrp type="admininfo">
      <head>Administrative Information</head>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
        <head>Access Restrictions</head>
        <p>No restrictions.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
        <head>Copyright Notice</head>
        <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Wesleyan University; all other copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Preferred Citation</head>
        <p>[Identification of item], Military on Campus Collection, Collection #1000-141, Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University, Middletown, CT, USA.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
        <head>Acquisitions Information</head>
        <p>Acquired from university offices, 1975-1997.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo>
        <head>Processing Information</head>
        <p>Processed by Stephen Padilla, November 2007</p>
        <p>Encoded by Valerie Gillispie, November 2007</p>
      </processinfo>
    </descgrp>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the bioghist in separate p elements. -->
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>During the years 1968 and 1969, military recruitment on the Wesleyan University campus became a heated issue. In February of 1969, Navy recruiter Lieutenant Kehoe came to campus to conduct interviews with students in North College. Approximately 30 Wesleyan students and 3 faculty members crammed the room, making the proceedings impossible, while about 100 more students gathered outside to protest the military presence on campus. In order to deal with the crisis, the University, under the presidency of Edwin Etherington, created a referendum amongst the student body through the College Body Committee, which was followed by a faculty vote. By November 1969 they had arrived at a new policy. Etherington resigned shortly thereafter and was succeeded by Colin Campbell. The full-time position of an Advisor on Military Programs was created and Phillip Rockwell took the job. Meetings with military representatives would from then on take place based solely on student request and were to be organized by Phillip Rockwell. All interviews, examinations, and tests for military entrance would be done off campus at the appropriate location. </p>
      <p>In December 1970, Colonel Kerrigan of the US Marine Corps informed Wesleyan that, due to his interpretation of the University's policy, the Secretary of Defense was advised that Wesleyan was barring military personnel from campus because of the requirement for a student request for a Marine officer visit. The justification for this was, according to Kerrigan, the NASA Act and the Armed Forces Appropriation Act. The University, in its response, was able to clarify its policy and successfully dispute the accusation. Simultaneously, Professor of Philosophy Paul Reynolds was a member for the anti-war Union for Progressive Action, and actively protested recruitment on campus. In numerous documents, he objected to what he called the University sanctioning <emph render="doublequote">executive sessions of classified government personnel</emph> with members of the community. He maintained that a member of the government under <emph render="doublequote">security clearance</emph> has no claim to academic rights, and therefore executive sessions being held on campus threatened the academic climate of the University, and legally required a warrant to be held on public premises or at the University. He also objected to the Office of Career Planning helping to recruit students for espionage in the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), or National Security Agency (NSA). According to documents from the University administration, there were not any executive sessions or espionage recruitment. When the draft and the Vietnam War ended in 1973, much of the conflict on campus seems to have died down. </p>
<!-- use "Chronlist Tags" here if there is a chronology -->
    </bioghist>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the scopecontent and arrangement in separate p elements. -->
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>This collection is divided into five folders. The first and second folders are general correspondence between Wesleyan and the various branches of the military, during the years 1968-1971, and 1972-1975, respectively. This correspondence is mostly generic in nature: military requests to visit campus, University responses to these requests, University inquiries about military programs, and military mailings and brochures detailing their career options for students.</p>
      <p>The third folder is the Policy folder, and it contains the documents pertaining to the creation of the University's policy towards military presence on campus. Because of student and faculty protests about the military actively coming on campus and conducting interviews with students, the University created a new policy whereby there was an Advisor on Military Programs for students who scheduled meetings with the military based solely on student request. There was some controversy, as the Marines accused Wesleyan of barring the military from the campus, and due to a Public Law in the NASA Act (enclosed in the collection), the university could have been penalized by the Secretary of Defense by having funds denied to it. The information pertaining to this conflict is all enclosed in the third file.</p>
      <p>The fourth file is the Phillip Rockwell file. It includes several articles from the <title render="italic">Argus </title>and the <title render="italic">Middletown Press</title> from 1968 and 1969 about military protests by students, and the University's decision to create a new position for an <title render="doublequote">Advisor on Military Programs.</title> It is at this time that the University created a new policy toward the military on campus. This file contains information about the creation of this office, a handwritten essay by Rockwell entitled <title render="doublequote">My Stand on Position of Advisor on Military Programs,</title> correspondence, and his annual report of activities from 1969 to 1972.</p>
      <p>The last file in the collection is the Paul Reynolds file. Paul Reynolds was a professor at Wesleyan who vocally protested the Vietnam War and military presence on campus, for various reasons. This file mostly contains his writings, his letters to the administration, the Argus, and detailed written explanations about his beliefs and actions toward military and espionage recruiters on the Wesleyan campus as well as the administration's response to this accusations and inquiries. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Online Catalog Headings</head>
      <p>These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.</p>
      <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="600">Rockwell, Phillip.</persname>
      <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="600">Reynolds, Paul A.</persname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest movements--United States.</subject>
      <geogname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="651">United States --Armed Forces --Recruiting, enlistment, etc.</geogname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Administration.</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--History.</corpname>
<!-- use "Item Level Tags" here for controlaccess terms -->
    </controlaccess>
<!-- Use separated materials and related materials clips here to enter in information -->
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>
<!-- use component levels clips to enter in the description of subordinate components -->
      <c01>
        <did>
          <unittitle/>
        </did>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, 1968-1971</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>This folder contains correspondences between the military and the University (mostly Phillip Rockwell) about career options in the military for Wesleyan Students: this file contains many duplicates.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>3 letters from the Army</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>8 letters from the Navy</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>1 letter from the Coast Guard</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>1 letter from the National Guard</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>2 letters from the Air Force</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>9 letters from Rockwell to the Navy, mostly responding to requests for campus visits or information</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>3 letters from military requesting names of seniors and alums</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, 1972-1975</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>3 letters from Rockwell to the Army</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>4 letters from the Army</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>2 letters from the National Guard</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>1 letter to Rockwell from the Mayor of Middletown about National Guard ceremony</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>2 letters from the Air Force</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>2 Letters from the Coast Guard</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>1 summary of Rockwell's visit with the Army</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>2 documents about Army's cooperative education program, Project Ahead</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Policy File</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>This file is comprised of documents, arranged in chronological order pertaining to the Wesleyan's policy on military recruiting. It includes documents from Wesleyan and the military.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Letter by Richard Ohlmann, Chancellor, dated 1969</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Approximately 11 letters from the military to Wesleyan</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Two copies of the NASA Act and the Public Law 91-119 forwarded by the military to Wesleyan University </unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Letter dated 1970 in which the Marines inform Wesleyan that the Secretary of Defense was informed that Wesleyan bans military personnel from campus</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Rough draft and final copy of Wesleyan's response to the Marine's notification rejecting the accusation of breaking the NASA Act and explaining University policy</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Multiple correspondences between the Marines and Phillip Rockwell</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Copy of Armed Forces Appropriation Act</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Phillip Rockwell File</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="doublequote">Navy Draws Protesters at Wesleyan,</title><title render="italic">Middletown Press</title>, November 18, 1968</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="doublequote">Wes Officials Moving on Disciplinary Action,</title><title render="italic">Middletown Press</title>, February 7, 1969 </unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="doublequote">Wesleyan Recruiter Foiled,</title><title render="italic">Hartford Courant</title>, February 7, 1969 ""</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="doublequote">Recruiter is Halted by Protest,</title><title render="italic">Middletown Press,</title> February 6, 1969</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="doublequote">My stand on the position of advisor on military programs,</title> Phillip Rockwell</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Handwritten essay.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="italic">Argus</title> article about creation of advisor on military options, November 1969 </unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Memo from President Etherington, <title render="doublequote">Urgent decision on military recruiting</title></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="doublequote">Rockwell cancels military recruiting on campus,</title><title render="italic">Argus</title>, December 1969</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Sample of bulletin for military counseling</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Approximately 15-20 items of correspondence to and from Phillip Rockwell</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Letters to specific students about reserve unit vacancy, or other military options</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Annual Reports of Activities, 1969-1970, 1970-1971, and 1971-1972</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Paul Reynolds File</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Approximately 10 letters to Wesleyan staff, mostly the President, from Reynolds, about military on campus</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Approximately 5 letters to the editor of the Argus from Reynolds</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Approximately 3 correspondences between Reynolds and the ACLU</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>A document entitled <title render="doublequote">For the record</title> by Reynolds explaining his actions of protest</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>1970 copy of the Argus mentioning Paul Reynolds</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
