<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./styles/wesstyletop.xsl" ?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "./dtds/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY weseal PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//NONSGML (weseal)//EN" "./seals/weseal.gif" NDATA gif>
<!ENTITY hdrsca PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (hdrsca)//EN" "./addresses/hdrsca.xml">
]>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtW" publicid="-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (US::CtW::1000-116::Moses Clark White Collection)//EN" url="http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/wh1000-116.html">wh1000-116</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Moses Clark White Collection,
		<lb/><date normal="1845/1900">1845 - 1900</date>
		</titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Patricia Bodak Stark; machine-readable finding aid created by: Valerie Gillispie</author>
<!-- OPTIONAL: Sponsor Statement
<sponsor></sponsor>
-->
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>&hdrsca;<p><date normal="2006" encodinganalog="date">© 2006</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights Reserved.</p></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc><creation>Machine-readable finding aid derived from XML authoring program.<lb/>
		<date>Date of source: June 2006</date>
	</creation><langusage>Description is in
		<language langcode="eng">English</language>
	</langusage><descrules>Finding aid was prepared using <title>DACS</title></descrules>  

</profiledesc>
<!-- Location of <revisiondesc> if needed -->
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage><titleproper>Guide to the Moses Clark White Collection, <date type="span">1845 - 1900</date>
</titleproper><publisher><extptr show="embed" entityref="weseal"/>
Special Collections &amp; Archives<lb/>Wesleyan University<lb/>
		Middletown, CT, USA		



		
</publisher><!-- Delete paragraph below and this comment line if your institution does not copyright its findingaids. --> 

<p><date normal="2006">© 2006</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights Reserved.</p></titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC">
    <did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><repository label="Repository"> 
<corpname>Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University</corpname></repository> 

<origination label="Creator"><persname encodinganalog="100">White, Moses Clark, 1819-1900.</persname></origination><unittitle label="Title" encodinganalog="245">Moses Clark White Collection, <unitdate normal="1845/1900" type="inclusive">1845 - 1900</unitdate></unittitle><unitid countrycode="us" repositorycode="CtW" label="Call Number" encodinganalog="099">1000-116</unitid><langmaterial label="Language of Material" encodinganalog="546">Material in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><physdesc label="Linear Feet"><extent encodinganalog="300">0.4</extent></physdesc><physdesc label="Archival Boxes"><extent>2</extent></physdesc><physloc label="Location">For current information on the location of
these materials, please consult Special Collections &amp; Archives staff.</physloc> 

<abstract label="Abstract" encodinganalog="545">Moses Clark White (1819-1900) was a graduate of the Wesleyan University class of 1845. White worked as a preacher, a doctor and a missionary, and lived in Fuh Chau, China, from 1847-1853, returning to live in New Haven, Conn. and practice medicine.</abstract><abstract encodinganalog="520">The Moses Clark White Collection contains four items: Common Place book; a Bible by N. T. Matthew in Fuhchan colloquial; a bound volume of <title render="italic">Copy of Manuscripts by Moses C. White, M.D., Pioneer Missionary, Relating to the Founding of Methodist Missions in Foochow, China</title>; and unbound photocopy of the <title render="italic">Copy of Manuscripts</title>.</abstract></did>
    <descgrp type="admininfo">
      <head>Administrative Information</head>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
        <head>Access Restrictions</head>
        <p>No restrictions.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
        <head>Copyright Notice</head>
        <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Wesleyan University; all other copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Preferred Citation</head>
        <p>[Identification of item], Moses Clark White Collection, Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University, Middletown, CT, USA.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
        <head>Acquisitions Information</head>
        <p><title render="italic">Copy of Manuscripts by Moses C. White, M.D., Pioneer Missionary, Relating to the Founding of Methodist Missions in Foochow, China</title> was given to Wesleyan University Library by Cornelia C. White in 1930.</p>
        <p>No information on acquisition of  the Common Place Book although price markings on inside cover appear to indicate purchase.  There is a date stamped on an inside page as October 20, 1937, which is probably when the Wesleyan Library acquired the item.
</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo>
        <head>Processing Information</head>
        <p>Processed by Patricia Bodak Stark, 2005</p>
        <p>Encoded by Valerie Gillispie, June 2006</p>
      </processinfo>
    </descgrp>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the bioghist in separate p elements. -->
    <bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Moses Clark White was born in Paris, Oneida County, New York on July 24, 1819.  He was a graduate of the Wesleyan Class of 1845.  By the time of graduation, White had already decided that he would devote his life to missionary work in China.  He had been influenced by a sermon, <title render="doublequote">A Call to the Ministry</title> by the Rev. Stephen Olin, around 1835 and entered the Cazenovia Seminary in 1840.  In February 1842, he entered Wesleyan and graduated in 1845. Under Olin's guidance, he spent two years after graduation in New Haven studying medicine and theology at Yale.  He sometimes preached in the neighboring town of Milford.</p><p>He married Jane Isabel Atwater of Homer, Cortland County, New York on March 13, 1847.  Born on August 26, 1822, she entered the Oneida Conference Seminary at Cazenovia in 1839 and graduated in July 1842 with high honors.  At the seminary, she formed a close friendship with Mary Seely and it is here that she met Moses White who was preparing for college. From 1842 to February 1847, she was a teacher in the Sabbath School in Rochester, N.Y. </p><p>Jane also had a missionary calling and together they sailed on the <emph render="italic">Heber</emph> for Fuh Chau, China, on April 15, 1847.  They arrived there after a five month voyage on September 7, 1847.  Jane became sick shortly after arriving and died seven months later of consumption on May 25, 1848 at the age of 26. </p>   

<p>At Fuh Chau, White served as both doctor and missionary, and conducted a school for the secular and religious instruction of the Chinese of that city.  He studied and treated the toxic effects of opium, as well as translated the Gospel of Matthew.  It was the first Christian document ever published in the colloquial dialect of that region. </p> 

<p>Moses White was married a second time to Mary Seely in Foochow in 1851.  Mary Seely was from Onondaga, New York and went to China as a missionary with Dr. Isaac W. Wiley and his wife. It was by Mary that Moses had children. (Isaac Wiley received an honorary degree from Wesleyan in 1864.)</p><p>Mary Seely White returned to New Haven in 1852 because of poor health.  Due to his own bad health, Moses White also left China in 1853 for New Haven where he resumed medical studies at Yale and began a medical practice which he continued until the end end of his life.  He received an MD degree from Yale in 1854.  Mary White died in 1887.  Moses White died on October 24, 1900.</p><!-- use "Chronlist Tags" here if there is a chronology --></bioghist>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the scopecontent and arrangement in separate p elements. -->
    <scopecontent><head>Collection Overview</head><p>The collection consists of two bound volumes, and an unbound photocopy of one of the volumes.  The collection is housed in two half-letter size boxes.</p><p>Bound volume,  <title render="italic">Copy of Manuscripts by Moses C. White, M.D., Pioneer Missionary, Relating to the Founding of Methodist Missions in Foochow, China.  Presented to the Wesleyan University Library by his Niece, Cornelia C. White, 1930.</title>   (There is also an unbound photocopy of this volume.)  In addition to presenting a copy of this volume to Wesleyan,  Cornelia White also gave copies to Yale University and the New Haven Colony Historical Society. </p> 

<p>Cornelia White appears to have transcribed and copied both published and unpublished material in order to compile this volume.  Although pages are not numbered in consecutive order, some of the material in the order that it appears is as follows:</p>
  
<p>1.	Moses Clarke White, a biographical obituary sketch retyped from the original in the <title render="italic">Yale Medical Journal</title>, Dec. 1900, v.7, no.6.  </p><p>2.	Moses Clarke White, biographical obituary sketch retyped from original in the New York East Conference Minutes for 1901, in the General Minutes of the Spring Conferences for 1901, page 116.</p>  

<p>3.  Article by S.H. Gage which appeared in the <title render="italic">Journal of Applied Microscopy and Laboratory Methods</title>, vol. 4, no. 1, Jan. 1901. </p><p>4.	Founding and Early History of Our Chinese Mission, 1847-1853 by Moses C. White , being an address delivered at Boston, September, 1887.  Copied by C.C. White with permission of M.C.W.</p>  

<p>5.	Transcription of letters by Elijah Hedding, Rufus Anderson, J.H. Woolcott, Charles Pittman, etc.</p>
	
<p>6.	Cornelia C. White writes:  The following article I pasted, in 1896, in one of my Scrap-books, and from its appearance I judge it was taken from an issue of the Christian Advocate near that date (1848), probably one that my parents saved.  C.C.W.  (pages 1-5)</p><p>7.	Early History of the China Mission of the Methodist Episcopal Church By Rev. Moses C. White, M.D.  Contains typescript of a letter by Frederick Thomas Keeney, Resident Bishop, Methodist Episcopal Church, Foochow, China to Mrs. Mary E. King (grand niece of MCW), 1923 Dec 4. </p><p>8.	Toward the end of the volume there is material that is described in the following words: " Copied August 21, 1898, from data given by Rev.M.C. White, and from papers published by him in 1897".  Included here is a moving biographical sketch and tribute to Jane Isabel White, transcribed from <title render="italic">American Missionary Memorial, including biographical and historical sketches.</title> Ed. By H.W. Pierson.  (N.Y.:  Harper, 1853.) </p>  

<p>The second item is described in an old inventory as a Common Place Book, dated May 24, 1845.  Handwritten information on the inside cover of the volume: <emph render="doublequote">The Property of Moses C. White, Middletown, Ct., May 24, 1845.</emph>  There is a date stamped on an inside page of the volume as October 20, 1937 which is probably when the Wesleyan Library acquired the item.  The volume is a combination of diary, notes on lectures that he has attended, Bible references, and scrapbook.  Some pages are interleaved with loose correspondence, notes, and plant leaves. There is a page with Chinese characters.  A letter or page of Chinese is inserted into the front of the volume.  </p>
 
<p>The first entry in the volume is dated Wesleyan University, Saturday evening May 24, 1845, several days after the end White's last term at Wesleyan.  Several entries are dated as Wesleyan, but approximately one-third of the way through the volume is an entry titled, <emph render="doublequote">Fokien Examination Hall at Fukchan</emph> followed by another titled, <title render="doublequote">Sketches relating to Christianity in Java</title>  which begins <emph render="doublequote">On my return from China in Jan 1853 the ship in which I sailed met with an accident in the Java Sea.</emph>  It appears this volume was started at Wesleyan, taken to China, and back.</p><p>The third item in the collection is the Gospel of Matthew translated into the Fuhchan colloquial dialect.  It was prepared from the classical Chinese version in 1851 for the Missionary Lyceum of Wesleyan University.   </p></scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Online Catalog Headings</head>
      <p>These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.</p>
      <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="600">White, Moses Clark, 1819-1900. </persname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Alumni and alumnae. </corpname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Missions, American --China. </subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Clergy --Connecticut. </subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Physicians --Connecticut. </subject>
      <geogname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="651">Fuzhou Shi (Fujian Sheng, China) </geogname>
      <geogname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="651">New Haven (Conn.) </geogname>
    </controlaccess>
<!-- Use separated materials and related materials clips here to enter in information -->
    <relatedmaterial>
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>Vertical Files contain some pictures and biographical information.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <unittitle/>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
            <container type="Folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Bound volume, <title render="italic">Copy of Manuscripts by Moses C. White, M.D., Pioneer Missionary, Relating to the Founding of Methodist Missions in Foochow, China. </title> Presented to the Wesleyan University Library by his Niece, Cornelia C. White, 1930.  
</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Folder">2-3</container>
            <unittitle>Unbound photocopy of <title render="italic">Copy of Manuscripts by	Moses C. White, M.D., Pioneer Missionary, Relating to the Founding of Methodist Missions in Foochow, China. </title> 
</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
            <container type="Folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Common Place book, 1845</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="Folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Bible, N.T. Matthew, 1851</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>In Fuhchan colloquial.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
