<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./styles/wesstyletop.xsl" ?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "./dtds/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY weseal PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//NONSGML (weseal)//EN" "./seals/weseal.gif" NDATA gif>
<!ENTITY hdrsca PUBLIC "-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (hdrsca)//EN" "./addresses/hdrsca.xml">
]>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="CtW" publicid="-//Wesleyan University::Special Collections and Archives//TEXT (US::CtW::1000-190::Young Men's Republican Club of Wesleyan University Records)//EN" url="http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/yo1000-191.html">yo1000-191</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Young Men's Republican Club of Wesleyan University
					Records, <lb/><date normal="1856">1856</date>
				</titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Drew Flanagan; machine-readable finding aid created by:
					Valerie Gillispie</author>
<!-- OPTIONAL: Sponsor Statement
<sponsor></sponsor>
-->
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>&hdrsca;<p><date normal="2010" encodinganalog="date">©
						2010</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights Reserved.</p></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Machine-readable finding aid derived from XML authoring program.<lb/>
				<date>Date of source: March 2010</date>
			</creation>
      <langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid was prepared using <title>DACS</title></descrules>
    </profiledesc>
<!-- Location of <revisiondesc> if needed -->
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Young Men's Republican Club of Wesleyan University Records,
					<date type="single">1856</date>
			</titleproper>
      <publisher><extptr show="embed" entityref="weseal"/> Special Collections &amp;
				Archives<lb/>Wesleyan University<lb/> Middletown, CT, USA </publisher>
<!-- Delete paragraph below and this comment line if your institution does not copyright its findingaids. -->
      <p><date normal="2010">© 2010</date> Wesleyan University. All Rights
				Reserved.</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <repository label="Repository">Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan
				University</repository>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname encodinganalog="110">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Young Men's
					Republican Club.</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle label="Title" encodinganalog="245">Young Men's Republican Club of Wesleyan
				University Records, <unitdate normal="1856" type="inclusive">1856</unitdate></unittitle>
      <unitid countrycode="us" repositorycode="CtW" label="Call Number" encodinganalog="099">1000-191</unitid>
      <langmaterial label="Language of Material" encodinganalog="546">Material in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Linear Feet">
        <extent encodinganalog="300">0.1</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physdesc label="Volumes">
        <extent>1</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Location">For current information on the location of these materials,
				please consult Special Collections &amp; Archives staff.</physloc>
      <abstract label="Abstract" encodinganalog="545">The Young Men's Republican Club was Wesleyan's first Republican political
				organization. It was founded on June 21, 1856, with the goal of aiding in the
				election of John C. Fremont to the presidency of the United States. A
				significant number of Wesleyan students were vocal supporters of the Republican
				Party in the early years, and much of their rhetoric centered on their opposition to
				slavery in Kansas. </abstract>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520">The single volume of the Young Men's Republican Club of Wesleyan University Records
				consists of an account of the activities of the club in the first year of its
				existence, 1856. It includes the group's constitution and minutes of meetings.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp type="admininfo">
      <head>Administrative Information</head>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
        <head>Access Restrictions</head>
        <p>No restrictions.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
        <head>Copyright Notice</head>
        <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Wesleyan University; all
					other copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their
					descendants, as stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Preferred Citation</head>
        <p>[Identification of item], Young Men's Republican Club of Wesleyan University
					Records, Collection #1000-191, Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan
					University, Middletown, CT, USA.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
        <head>Acquisitions Information</head>
        <p>Donated to the library by the Young Men's Republican Club around 1856; transferred to the Archives before 1997.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo>
        <head>Processing Information</head>
        <p>Processed by Drew Flanagan, March 2010</p>
        <p>Encoded by Valerie Gillispie, March 2010</p>
      </processinfo>
    </descgrp>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the bioghist in separate p elements. -->
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The Young Men's Republican Club was Wesleyan's first Republican political
				organization. It was founded on June 21, 1856, with the goal of aiding in the
				election of John C. Fremont to the presidency (and William L. Dayton to the
				vice-presidency) of the United States. The election of 1856 was the first in U.S.
				history to be contested by the newly formed Republican Party. Fremont ran on a free
				soil platform, opposing the expansion of the institution of slavery to Kansas. Many
				of his most vocal supporters were abolitionists, and many northern Methodists were
				<emph render="doublequote">free soilers</emph> (who opposed the expansion of slavery) or abolitionists. A
				significant number of Wesleyan students were vocal supporters of the Republican
				Party in the early years, and much of their rhetoric centered on their opposition to
				slavery in Kansas. </p>
    </bioghist>
<!-- Enter each paragraph of the scopecontent and arrangement in separate p elements. -->
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The single volume of the Young Men's Republican Club of Wesleyan University Records
				consists of an account of the activities of the club in the first year of its
				existence, 1856. It begins with an account of the first meeting of the club. On June
				21, the group selected as its first chairman William J. Foss, class of 1856. The
				group also inaugurated its tradition of speechmaking at meetings, with Mallalieu,
				Upham, Elmer, Ela, Longstreet, Ginn, Johnson, Shepard, and Buddington listed as
				having given speeches. The first meeting also saw the selection of a committee,
				intended to draft a proposed constitution for the group. That committee was to
				consist of J.M. Pomeroy, A. Reynolds, Mallalieu, Longstreet, Ela and Pitkin. The
				club reconvened on June 25 and <emph render="doublequote">unanimously approved the report of the committee of
				six.</emph> The group's constitution follows.</p>
      <p>The preamble begins, <emph render="doublequote">Whereas, our country is now about to enter into a Presidential
				campaign involving issues which we believe to be the most momentous presented to the
				American people since the adoption of the constitution . . . .</emph> Two such issues were, <emph render="doublequote">The
				salvation of Kansas, and the restoration of the purity of the federal government,</emph>
				which, <emph render="doublequote">can be achieved only by the election of the nominees of the Republican
				Party.</emph> The remainder of the constitution consists of 21 articles.</p>
      <p>Article 1: Designates the official name of the group as <emph render="doublequote">the Young Men's Republican
				Club of Wesleyan.</emph></p>
      <p>Article 2: Sets up the terms of membership in the group. Members were required to
				sign <emph render="doublequote">these articles</emph> within one week of their adoption and <emph render="doublequote">afterward . . . [had to] be
					elected by a majority of the club.</emph> All members were required to <emph render="doublequote">testify their
				adhesion to the party platform of June 17, 1856.</emph> </p>
      <p>Article 3: States the purpose of the organization, being <emph render="doublequote">to aid in the diffusion and
				advocacy of the principles of the Republican Party . . . and the election of John C.
				Fremont and William L. Dayton as President and Vice President of the United
				States.</emph></p>
      <p>Article 4: Enumerates methods by which the group planned to fulfill its purpose,
				including <emph render="doublequote">an organized system of addresses on the politics of the day, to be
					delivered before the citizens of this county and vicinity</emph> and also <emph render="doublequote">the purchase
				and distribution of the Republican (campaign materials).</emph> It also allows for the
				employment of <emph render="doublequote">such other means as from time to time the club may deem proper.</emph> </p>
      <p>Article 5: Lays out the top officer positions in the club, including president, vice
				president, secretary and treasurer. </p>
      <p>Article 6: Provides for election of officers: president and VP from senior class,
				secretary from junior class, and treasurer from sophomore class. </p>
      <p>Article 7: Provides for the organization of an executive committee including the
				officers and four representatives (one from each class year) to be elected after the
				adoption of the constitution.</p>
      <p>Article 8: Describes the general responsibilities of the committee--to <emph render="doublequote">carry out all
				orders of the club.</emph> </p>
      <p>Article 9: Provides for the selection of a subcommittee of three to confer with the
				<emph render="doublequote">Fremont Club of Middletown</emph> and to <emph render="doublequote">assign the times, places, and speakers for all
				meetings held under the direction of the club throughout the county and vicinity,</emph>
				and also to plan and provide for said meetings. </p>
      <p>Article 10: Provides for the time and place of meetings of the executive committee,
				to be determined by the chairman. </p>
      <p>Article 11: Executive Committee must report its activities and expenses to the general
				meeting. </p>
      <p>Article 12: Provides for the removal of members of the Executive Committee.</p>
      <p>Article 13: Provides for filling of vacancies in the Executive Committee.</p>
      <p>Article 14: Assigns the time and day for general meetings.</p>
      <p>Article 15: Provides for calling of extra meetings.</p>
      <p>Article 16: No non-members may attend meetings.</p>
      <p>Article 17: Order of business for meetings.</p>
      <p>Article 18: Motions to adjourn or table <emph render="doublequote">shall not be debatable.</emph></p>
      <p>Article 19: Provides for collection of money for campaign documents by voluntary
				subscription.</p>
      <p>Article 20: Members may be expelled by majority vote.</p>
      <p>Article 21: Provides for amendment of the constitution by a 2/3 majority.</p>
      <p>The first signature on the document is that of John W. Hoyt ('58), followed by the
				term <emph render="doublequote">scripsit</emph> meaning that Hoyt recorded the document. His signature is followed
				by several pages of the signatures of the founding members of the club. Their names
				follow, along with the class years (in the 1800's) of all confirmed Wesleyan
				students.</p>
      <p>James M. Pomeroy ('56), John Duncan Taber, ('58), George H. Whitney ('58), William T.
				Elmer ('57), Edward (or Edwaro) Johnson ('56), Allen Reynolds ('56), John Peterson
				('57), Joseph W. Cushing ('57), Willard F. Mallalieu ('57), David Hough Ela ('57),
				Thomas R. Ercanbrack ('58), Melville Cox Smith ('59 but did not graduate), William Jay
				Foss ('56), John W. Hoyt ('58), Albert Vail ('57), William V. Snyder ('56),
				Hiram Pliny Shepard ('58), Samuel (or Salmuel) B. Paris ('58), Alverd E. Winchell
				('57), Frederick Walter Pitkin ('58), Wilbur Fisk Noyes ('58 but died in 1857),
				Gilbert S. Keys ('58), Anthony Woodward ('58), Wesley Curtis Ginn ('59), Spencer R. Fuller
				('59), Francis Asbury Smith ('59), Quincy
				Johnson Collin ('57), Charles H. Payne ('56), George Fisk Comfort ('57), George
				Crosby Smith ('56), Orville W. Powers ('56), James O. Longstreet ('57), Henry
				Crounce Abbott ('59), Edward W. Virgin ('57), Daniel Clark Knowles ('58), John W.
				Currier ('57), Edwin S. Snow ('58), Williams A. Reynolds ('58), Amherst W. Kellogg
				('58), George W. Mansfield ('58), Solomon Parsons ('58), Nathaniel Fellows, Benjamin
				H. White ('59, but did not graduate), James N. Garatt ('58 but did not graduate),
				Charles H. Gardner ('59 but did not graduate), William F. Hatfield ('59), Henry A.
				Collin ('58), Charles S. Rogers ('58), Andrew Roe ('57), Jonathan H. Dally ('59),
				George L. Roberts ('59), Silas E. Quimby Jr. ('59), Joseph W. Ellis ('58), Charles
				H. Stocking ('58), Asa P. Lyon ('59), J. L. Morse ('59), A. Boothby Jr. ('59), George
				H. Falley, Horace William Parmenter ('59), J. D. Reynolds ('59, did not graduate),
				Newell F. Nichols ('57), Charles W. Brooks ('57), G. H. Gracy, Nelson Stutson ('58),
				James Carr, Jr. ('59), William Henry Starr ('59), Burwell P. Goode ('56), Henry A.
				Budington ('57), Lorenzo D. Blanchard ('57), G.N. Stowers, E.R. Carey, George
				Judkins ('60), Herbert F. Fisk ('60), William T. Worth ('60), John B. Lapham ('60),
				Edward M. Anthony ('60), Edward Edson ('60), William E. Morgan ('60), Robert L.
				Mathison ('60), Edwin B. Harvey ('59), Solomon Chapin ('57), William L. Spalding
				('60), Ichabod Simmons ('60), Hiram C. Sexton ('60 but did not graduate), James M.
				Buckley ('60 but did not graduate), Andrew K. Crawford ('60), George C. Webber
				('60), William L. Bodwell, Benjamin K. Lovatt ('60 but did not graduate), James T. Edwards ('60),
				Henry Blaisdell ('60), Samuel A. Winsor ('60), Daniel Kimball Stetson ('60 but did
				not graduate), Robert Pagan Bucknam ('59), Alvin G. White ('60 but did not
				graduate), William H. Wardell ('60), Benjamin S. Sharpe ('60 but did not graduate),
				George Clarke ('60), Webster R. Walkley ('60), George W. Clement ('60 but did not
				graduate), Edson W. Burr ('60), Melvin D. Kinney ('60), W. F. Comfort, Albert Gould
				('60 but did not graduate), James Stuart Gordon ('60 but did not graduate), George
				S. Chadbourne ('58), Sanford B. Sweetser ('60).</p>
      <p>The section of the book that follows consists of accounts of several meetings of the
				club.</p>
      <p>At the first regular meeting on June 26, 1856, the executive committee and club
				officers were elected. H. P. Foss was elected as president, J. M. Pomeroy as vice
				president, E. A. Winchell as secretary and D. H. Ela as Treasurer. The remaining
				members of the executive committee were to be E. Johnson, W. F. Mallalieu, N. Fellows
				and W. C. Finn. The meeting also saw the selection of <emph render="doublequote">Smith, Pomeroy, and Powers</emph> to
				a subcommittee tasked with coordinating the efforts of the Wesleyan club with the
				Middletown Fremont Society. </p>
      <p>The second set of meetings on June 27, 1856, began with a meeting of the Executive
				Committee which saw the adoption of <emph render="doublequote">a tax of a few cents,</emph> that is dues, to be paid
				by the members of the club. Pomeroy and Foss were tasked with contacting the
				Middletown Fremont Society. The executive committee also provided for a list to
				collect the names of club members <emph render="doublequote">willing to speak on behalf of Fremont and
				freedom.</emph> At the evening meeting of the full club, Smith, Pomeroy, and Powers
				reported on the meeting with the Middletown Fremont Society and their report was
				<emph render="doublequote">accepted</emph> by the club. Also, <emph render="doublequote">motion was carried to send for two copies of the
				Campaign Tribune.</emph> </p>
      <p>The next meeting on July 5, 1856, included the acceptance of the first report of the
				executive committee and speechmaking. The report describes the selection and
				election of club officers and subcommittees that had occurred at the prior meetings,
				and reports on the progress of the group so far. The executive committee report also
				reveals that a <emph render="doublequote">ratification meeting</emph> was <emph render="doublequote">held in the city</emph> on June 25, and
				provides a list of the members that spoke at the event.</p>
      <p>At the meeting on July 26, 1856, the report of the Executive Committee was heard and
				accepted, and speeches were made. <emph render="doublequote">President being absent, VP presided.</emph> The report
				follows the relationship between the Wesleyan Young Men's Republican Club and the
				Middletown Fremont Society. It notes that the subcommittee had been enabled to
				contact the Middletown group, and that the Middletown organization had appointed a
				liaison, <emph render="doublequote">probably of a temporary nature,</emph> to attend the Wesleyan club's meetings.
				The Wesleyan club had by then been assured of the <emph render="doublequote">hearty cooperation</emph> of the
				Middletown club. The report itemizes campaign materials to be bought with club funds,
				including, <emph render="doublequote">1 copy of Upham's Life of Fremont, 1 copy of History and Principles of
				the Republican Party, 2 copies of Facts for the People [and] 2 copies each of the
				publication of the Washington Republican Association.</emph> The report reveals the
				concerns of the Executive Committee, noting that, <emph render="doublequote">great care</emph> must be taken to
				<emph render="doublequote">avoid offending anyone</emph> on the subject of the Vice Presidency, <emph render="doublequote">because pleas for
				either Dayton or Johnson could have an injurious effect on the vote for Fremont in
				this state.</emph> The club was instructed not to make <emph render="doublequote">any offensive remarks about Mr.
				Fillmore,</emph> and to confine their remarks as speakers to the official platform so as
				not to <emph render="doublequote">distract and divide.</emph></p>
      <p>The meeting of September 6, 1856 marked the beginning of a new school year. The
				minutes of the meeting describe the election of new members and a new Executive
				Committee. G. F. Comfort became chairman, and A. Eggleston, H. Shuster, G. Squire,
				Worth, and Anthony were elected as new members. New elections also included William
				J. Elmer as president, E. A. Winchell as vice president, J. R. Ercanbrack as
				secretary, and S. Fuller as treasurer, while the election of the remaining Executive
				Committee members-at-large was deferred until the following meeting. It was also
				resolved at this meeting to form a glee club <emph render="doublequote">in connexion [sic] with the Repub.
				Club.</emph></p>
      <p>September 10, 1856, the president of the Executive Committee and members of the
				subcommittee were selected. <emph render="doublequote">Were present Elmer, Winchell, Fellows, Mallalieu and
				Ercanbrack.</emph> Mallalieu was made president of the committee, and Fellows, Winchell,
				and Mallalieu were elected to the subcommittee. Provisions were also made for the
				posting of advertisements for speeches to be made by club members. </p>
      <p>September 13, 1856, the third report of the Executive Committee was <emph render="doublequote">listened to and
				accepted.</emph> The following new members were elected to the club: <emph render="doublequote">Mssrs. Mandell,
				Clement, Fisk, Simmons, Spalding, Mattison, Sharp, Stowers, Bulkley, M. P. Kinney,
				Cary, Sweetser, Danes, W. C. Morgan, Glaats, J. Hibbard, Sewell, J. E. Pawins, Nichols
				and C. Lorin.</emph> <emph render="doublequote">Ellis, Longstreet, Comfort, and Ercanbrack</emph> were <emph render="doublequote">invited to sing
					for the club.</emph> It was also <emph render="doublequote">voted that the Executive Committee make arrangements for
				going to the Meriden mass meeting on next Saturday.</emph> </p>
      <p>Evening of November 4, 1856, the group <emph render="doublequote">shouted uproariously</emph> but was brought to
				order by President Elmer. <emph render="doublequote">The glee club, Ellis, Longstreet, Gould, and Ercanbrack
					discoursed music from time to time according to the call of the society.</emph> <emph render="doublequote">Many
				enthusiastic speeches were made. Mallalieu was funny, Fellows was pathetic.
				Ercanbrack was impudent, Elmer was enthusiastic and all were in for free Kansas. The
				club adjourned, resolving to do their whole duty on the morrow.</emph> Signed: <emph render="doublequote">J.R.
				Ercanbrack, Secretary.</emph></p>
      <p>November 6, 1856. <emph render="doublequote">Republican club convened. Elmer presided. The club bewailed the
				probable result of the national election. Each and all joined to assert that they
				would remain firm advocates of Republican principles. Voted that these records be
				placed in the college library for the investigations of future classes who shall see
				fit to engage in politics. Club adjourned sine die.</emph> Signed: <emph render="doublequote">J.R. Ercanbrack, cur.
				Sec.</emph> </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess><head>Online Catalog Headings</head><p>These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online
				catalogs.</p><!-- use "Item Level Tags" here for controlaccess terms --><corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Young Men's
				Republican Club.</corpname><corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.</corpname><subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Presidents--United States--Election--1856.</subject><corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Republican Party (Conn.)</corpname><corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--History--19th century.</corpname>  
			<geogname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="651">Middletown (Conn.)--History.</geogname><corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">Republican Party (U.S. : 1854- )--History--19th century.</corpname>  
			<subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Antislavery movements.</subject>  

		</controlaccess>
<!-- Use separated materials and related materials clips here to enter in information -->
    <relatedmaterial>
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p><extref href="http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/lo1000-25.html">James Oliver Longstreet Diary</extref>, Special Collections &amp; Archives, Wesleyan University</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <dsc type="combined"><head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head><!-- use component levels clips to enter in the description of subordinate components --><c01><did><unittitle/></did><c02><did><container type="Volume">1</container><unittitle>Constitution and Minutes, 1856</unittitle></did></c02>
	
</c01>
			
			



		</dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
