<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ru.1106">mssa.ru.1106</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies at Yale Records
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies at Yale Records</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Daniel Hartwig</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>July 2009</date>
            <num>RU 1106</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Friday January 11, 2019 at 09:45</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies at Yale records</unittitle>
         <unitid>RU 1106</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">16</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(16 boxes)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1996/2009">1996-2009</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_2722fd6ab2eab5f245bc7918d3c3172d">The records consist of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies visiting lecturer application files.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">
               Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies at Yale
            </corpname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <odd id="aspace_4e8dfcc2ba96bf08e57d4632680a73c6">
         <head>General note</head>
         <p>Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.</p>  
      </odd>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_d2228ff4015f58a6fe4223cfee9b7e60">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The records were transferred from Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies, 2009.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_76af874616264c8bcd1b017ae00cfa26">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_2c2a96d8c21dbe6e191f303596a94fc0">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Copyright for materials authored or otherwise produced as official business of Yale University is retained by Yale University. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_8184c31c86ef8b9c4af22909a70f8094">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies at Yale University Records (RU 1106). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_450ddf7aaffd0b518e350888e868e537">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Yale University records are arranged and described at the accession level by the creating office. The University Archives creates collection level descriptive records, but typically does no further arrangement and description at the accession level.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_ad9004e1a9ba18b74e3f2e1334d0f054">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>In 1986, Yale medievalist John Boswell chaired a committee of faculty and students that established the Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale (LGSCY, or "Legacy"), one of the first such centers in the nation. LGSCY was renamed Lesbian and Gay Studies in 1999. In 2007 it became Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies (LGBTS) at Yale.</p>
         <p>LGBTS promotes innovative interdisciplinary scholarship and teaching on the historical and contemporary experience of lesbians, gay men, bisexuals, and transgendered people. It also fosters critical analysis of queer and normative sexualities, the formation of sexual and gender minorities, and the role of sexuality in culture and politics across the world. It has a national and international reputation for its faculty, lecturers, fellowships, prizes, and symposia.</p>
         <p>As an interdisciplinary committee, LGBTS organizes and co-sponsors scholarly lectures, conferences, film screenings, and other events; provides research grants to faculty, graduate students, and undergraduates; co-sponsors the Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies Graduate Colloquium; and works closely with Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies (WGSS) to coordinate LGBTS course offerings. From 2001-2006, a generous gift from a donor allowed LGBTS to establish and oversee the Larry Kramer Initiative, which hosted a wide array of public programs on LGBT issues and strengthened LGBTS at Yale. Today, LGBTS has a 14-member committee, a faculty chair, and a full-time program manager.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_fc0ac97c34f448b50d00a7facacaf7d6">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The records consist of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies visiting lecturer application files.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_f4cd1b9e444b8dd1810b02ebaf62ffb6">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The records are arranged chronologically.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85028378"
                  source="lcsh">
            College teachers
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh95001341"
                  source="lcsh">
            Gay and lesbian studies
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85075675"
                  source="lcsh">
            Lecturers
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85141120"
                  source="lcsh">
            Universities and colleges -- Faculty
         </subject>
         <subject source="local">
            LGBTQ resource
         </subject>
         <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">
            Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies at Yale
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043367"
                   source="naf">
            Yale University -- Faculty
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref12" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Studies visiting lecturer application files</unittitle>
               <unitid>Accession 2010-A-005</unitid>
               <physdesc>
                  <extent unit="Linear Feet">16</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2009</unitdate>
            </did>
            <accessrestrict id="aspace_3e176a31f217e05993ed96f272eecebb">
               <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
               <p>Restricted until Jan 1, 2045.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
