<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.1649">mssa.ms.1649</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Peter B. Cooper Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Cooper (Peter B) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>Preliminary inventory by Diane E. Kaplan</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>October 1993</date>
            <num>MS 1649</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Saturday December  8, 2018 at 10:55</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules/>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Peter B. Cooper papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 1649</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">32</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(32 boxes)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970/1979">1970-1979</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_f50f8dff932c47fb2e9e3350ea48d8a9">The papers consist of correspondence, notes, and background material which document Peter Cooper's legal work to preserve the quality of the environment in the New Haven area and on Long Island Sound. Cases involve issues of energy transmission, coastal area development, highway construction, pollution of public water supplies, air quality control, and nuclear power plant construction.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80087881"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               Cooper, Peter B.
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_2f17e83d971f4fb9837b017a807b9041">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_45ec7c84f275f60d08b1e0358edd3e61">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Peter B. Cooper Papers (MS 1649). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_3d0eaa2db003f58a8dbf9ac3d30bc868">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Cooper, Whitney, Cochran and François, 1993.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_47c61c692d8fef05b0a1668c7b48d88f">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The papers consist of correspondence, notes, and background material which document Peter Cooper's legal work to preserve the quality of the environment in the New Haven area and on Long Island Sound. Cases involve issues of energy transmission, coastal area development, highway construction, pollution of public water supplies, air quality control, and nuclear power plant construction.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_d3cc858737eda3fbbbafb4f5ae5f50ef">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Copyright has been transferred to Yale University for unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator(s) of this collection. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85002574"
                  source="lcsh">
            Air -- Pollution
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85027434"
                  source="lcsh">
            Coastal zone management
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85093030"
                  source="lcsh">
            Nuclear power plants
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85145600"
                  source="lcsh">
            Water quality
         </subject>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85078263"
                   source="lcsh">
            Long Island Sound (N.Y. and Conn.)
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79100828"
                   source="lcsh">
            New Haven (Conn.)
         </geogname>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85075351"
                  source="lcsh">
            Lawyers
         </subject>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80087881"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Cooper, Peter B.
         </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref8" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">Circa 1970s</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_58a8c3f70c740022f1eb3b2bfe2d0a68">32 linear feet (32 boxes)</physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_5e71b4b756870a0080067c5a0e132375">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Rceived from: Cooper, Whitney, Cochran and Françios, 1993 October 4</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>CLP/HELCO and U.I. cases, includes some AEC Shoreham findings (These are early rate cases demonstrating the utility company's practice of artificially increasing electricity consumption through the manner in which rates are set. The cases tried to highlight those types of advertising and other promotional activities which worked against the conservation of electricity. The AEC Shoreham findings refer to the range of water quality issues brought about through the releases of heated water into Long Island Sound.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d2e4">1–2</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">
                        BLECC vs. CL&amp;P
                     </title> (This was an attempt by the utility companies to set up a council of citizens to examine transmission line and pumped storage site issues in the Berkshire/Litchfield County area and to mediate competing interests.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d3e8">3–6</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>North Haven Mall (This case explored the regional economic impact of major mall proposal in the Quinnipiac River flood plain. It raised economic and sociological issues in the process of applying for the traditional environmental dredge and fill permit before the Army Corps of Engineers.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d4e6">6–8</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coastal Area Management/North Haven Mall (These files show early efforts to analyze the impact of development on Long Island Sound, in the context of Federal Legislation dealing with coastal area management.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d5e6">8–10</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Bridgeport Hydraulic vs. Council on Water Company Lands
                     </title> (This was a federal case at the District Court level, and then before the Second Circuit Court of Appeals, involving a challenge to the State's moratorium on the sale of Bridgeport Hydraulics land pending the establishment of a health and environmentally related classification of such lands. Technical information gathered analyzes the scope of non-point sources and the impact on the quality of drinking water.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d6e6">10–12</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Council on Water Company Lands: ISPS (The Council set up a land classification system following the defeat of Bridgeport Hydraulic's challenge to the moratorium that allowed the Council to do its work. The ISPS course at Yale covered the range of environmental, economic, and land use issues which surround this topic.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d7e6">12–14</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Farrington vs. PAC
                     </title>/Solvents Recovery (Farrington vs. PAC was an unsuccessful attempt to protect a land owner adjacent to proposed I-84 from adverse impact to the wetlands and ponds on her property. Solvent Recovery was a case brought by Connecticut Fund for the Environment to stop a company next to the Quinnipiac River from polluting public water supplies. Solvents Recovery went bankrupt, never having built a corrective control containment system.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d8e6">14–16</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Connecticut Air Implementation Plan (This is background information compiled by the firm on retainer from the State of Connecticut Department of Environmental Protection to draft regulations for the state subsequent to the passage of the Clean Air Act of 1970.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d9e4">16–17</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">
                        The City of New Haven vs. Chandler
                     </title> (A 1970 case challenging U.I.'s plan to build power lines across the New Haven harbor.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d10e4">18–19</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Millstone 3/Indirect source (These were application for construction and operating licenses before the AEC. Indirect source-Plainfield dog track involved a specific case under the Clean Air Act regulations dealing not with direct emitters of air pollutants but with an entity which effected air quality by drawing trucks, buses, and cars.</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d11e6">19–21</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>AEC Shoreham (This material relates to the proceedings before the AEC on the proposed construction of a nuclear power Plant at Shoreham, across Long Island Sound from the New Haven harbor. Issues include water quality, safety, and disposal problems.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d12e10">21–25</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coastal Area Management material (These records and documents deal with the feasibility of undergrounding for energy transmission.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d13e4">26–27</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Connecticut River Crossing (This material concerns an administrative and court battle over proposed transmission line crossings of the Connecticut River near a number of state parks. The settlement permitted less obtrusive overhead crossings in return for over one million dollars in funds to the Connecticut River Gateway Commission for the purchase of park and other natural area habitat.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d14e6">28–30</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coastal Area Management Planning/Coke Works/Combustion Equipment Associates (The Coastal Area Management material is similar to that described above. Coke Works relates to U.I.'s application for the power plant in New Haven harbor. Combustion Equipment Associates was an early, unsuccessful trash to energy proposal in Bridgeport.)</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d15e6">30–32</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
