<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.0141">mssa.ms.0141</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Cogswell Family Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Cogswell Family Papers</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Mary C. LaFogg</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>January 1978</date>
            <num>MS 141</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Saturday December  8, 2018 at 08:29</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules/>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Cogswell family papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 141</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">2</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(4 boxes, 1 folio)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1740/1924">1740-1924</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_d00bbefab09f922922f84fce773294cd">The papers of nine members of the Cogswell family and related branches, spanning nearly 200 years, are included in this collection. The principal elements are three sets of correspondence: the letters between the Reverend James Cogswell and his son, James, which deal with the son's experiences as a surgeon during the American Revolution; the correspondence of Harriet Broome Cogswell Mott and her husband, Robert Willis Mott, largely made up of courtship letters, 1817-1819, but also including a detailed letter on preparations for the winter of 1823; and the correspondence between Stella Mott Onderdonk and her husband, William Handy Onderdonk, also largely courtship letters, 1839-1843. Their correspondence of later years includes a description by William Onderdonk of a trip to Cuba in 1865. Miscellaneous family items are comprised of a will, school certificates, diaries, clippings, and other memorabilia.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh86001371"
                     source="lcsh">
               Cogswell family
            </famname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_520e4480335b5d16ad02016fd8be546f">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_4271499ad1183bae90b7955964b8a525">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Cogswell Family Papers (MS 141). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_83a454f8fceb6bcbc104fa638656b23d">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Mrs. Vernon Mann Simonds, 1941.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_903de19aeb7e434245f3b78edeaa21e0">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Cogswell Family Papers, 1740 to 1902, consist of family and business correspondence, documents, writings and other papers to, from and relating to the Cogswell family of Connecticut and the collateral and descendant families of Lloyd, Woolsey, Hillhouse, Fisher, Mott and Onderdonk. The central figures in this collection are:</p>
         <p>James Cogswell (1720-1807)</p>
         <p>James Cogswell (1746-1792)</p>
         <p>Samuel Cogswell (1754-1790)</p>
         <p>Mason Fitch Cogswell (1761-1830)</p>
         <p>Alice Cogswell Fisher (1777-1850)</p>
         <p>James Lloyd Cogswell (1784-1832)</p>
         <p>John Lloyd Cogswell (1789-1831)</p>
         <p>Harriet Broome Cogswell Mott (1790-1843)</p>
         <p>Harriet Stella Mott Onderdonk (1820-1902?)</p>
         <p>Arranged chronologically, the Cogswell family correspondence represented in these papers is composed of three principal exchanges: 1) correspondence of the Reverend James Cogswell and his son Dr. James Cogswell, 2) correspondence of Harriet Broome Cogswell Mott and her husband, Robert Willis Mott and 3) correspondence of Harriet Stella Mott Onderdonk and her husband, William Handy Onderdonk. Letters of five generations of Cogswells and related family members appear throughout the correspondence as well.</p>
         <p>The correspondence for the years 1740 to 1808 consists mainly of letters to and from Reverend James Cogswell (1720-1807) and his son, Dr. James Cogswell (1746-1792). Dr. James Cogswell was an army surgeon during the American Revolution, and the letters of that period deal with his experiences during the war. Other family members whose letters appear in the correspondence for 1740 to 1808 include Abigail Lloyd Cogswell, Samuel Cogswell and Mason Fitch Cogswell.</p>
         <p>The second segment of correspondence, covering the years 1809 to 1846, is largely that of Harriet Broome Cogswell Mott and her husband, Robert Willis Mott. Their courtship letters comprise the bulk of the correspondence for the years 1817 to 1819. The correspondence from 1809 to 1846 also contains business letters between Robert and his brother, William Mott. Among the family correspondents of this period are Abigail Lloyd Cogswell, Mason Fitch Cogswell, Sarah Lloyd Cogswell, Alice Cogswell and Charlotte Broome Cogswell. Throughout the years 1820 to 1843 there are letters exchanged by Harriet and Robert Mott. In one letter of particular interest (5 November 1823), Robert Mott wrote to his wife describing the preparations he wanted her to make at home for the coming winter months in his absence.</p>
         <p>In the final segment of correspondence, 1839 to 1902, the chief correspondents are Harriet Stella Mott Onderdonk and her husband, Willian Handy Onderdonk. Their letters throughout their four year engagement comprise the bulk of the correspondence between the years 1839 to 1843. The Onderdonks were often separated from each other because of family or business trips, and the correspondence after 1843 reflects this. Of special interest is William Onderdonk's description of a trip he took to Cuba in 1865. The correspondence after 1846 is somewhat sketchy, but includes letters of other family members, among them. Samuel F. Cogswell, Charlotte Broome Cogswell and Robert M. Onderdonk. The last section of papers, one manuscript box, includes writings, wills, documents and other papers relating to the family members.</p>
         <p>The Cogswell Family Papers were a gift of Mrs. Vernon Mann Simonds to the Yale University Library in 1941.</p>
         <p>Additional biographical information may be found in Ephraim A. Jameson's <title render="italic">
               The Cogswells in America
            </title> and in <title render="italic">
               Yale Biographies and Annals,
            </title> by Franklin B. Dexter. There are a number of other collections in Yale University, Manuscripts and Archives, which contain additional material on the Cogswell family. Please consult Orbis and the reference staff. The Mason Fitch Cogswell Papers are at the Beinecke Rare Book Library.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <bioghist id="aspace_c6ba47825ad4401b47cecf62e682aad5">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>JAMES COGSWELL, 1720-1807</p>
         <p>James Cogswell, the youngest son of Samuel and Ann Denison Cogswell, was born in Saybrook, Connecticut, January 6, 1720. His family moved to Lebanon, Connecticut, in 1724, and Cogswell spent his youth in that town. He graduated from Yale with the Class of 1742. After graduation, he studied theology with the Reverend Solomon Williams and on December 28, 1774, Cogswell became the pastor of the church at Canterbury, Connecticut. He remained at Canterbury for twenty-seven years.</p>
         <p>During those years he married and raised his family. On April 24, 1745, Cogswell married Alice Fitch (1725-1772). James and Alice Cogswell had five children: James (1746-1792), Alice (1749-1772), Samuel (1754-1790), Mason Fitch (1761-1830) and Septimus (1769-1773).</p>
         <p>Reverend Cogswell resigned his pastorate at Canterbury on November 5, 1771. The following February he accepted the office of pastor at Scotland Parish, in Windham, Connecticut. Two months later, Alice Fitch Cogswell died. A year later, Reverend Cogswell married Martha Lothrop Devotion (1715?-1795). She was the widow of Cogswell's predecessor in Windham, the Reverend Ebenezer Devotion. After twenty-two years of marriage, Martha died on December 6, 1795. On May 5, 1797, Cogswell married Irene Ripley Hebard [Hibbard?] (d. 1804).</p>
         <p>Upon Irene's death in 1804, Cogswell resigned his ministerial duties at Scotland and retired to his son Mason's home in Hartford, Connecticut. He died there on January 2, 1807.</p>
         <p>* * * * *</p>
         <p>JAMES COGSWELL, 1746-1792</p>
         <p>James Cogswell, the oldest son of James and Alice Fitch Cogswell, was born in Canterbury, Connecticut, on July 31, 1746. He studied medicine and began his practice in Preston, Connecticut. The American Revolution interrupted his career. Cogswell served as army surgeon at Cambridge, Massachusetts, during the battle of Bunker Hill.</p>
         <p>On August 8, 1776, he married Elizabeth Davenport (1756-1779). They settled in Stamford, Connecticut. James and Elizabeth Cogswell had one child, Alice (1777-1850). As the war progressed, Cogswell was again called upon to aid the patriot cause with his services. During the years 1776 and 1777, he was assigned as regimental surgeon to General Gold Selleck Silliman, who was on duty at New York with the Connecticut militia. While at New York, Cogswell's younger brother, Mason Fitch, served as his assistant.</p>
         <p>Elizabeth Cogswell died on November 15, 1779. When the war ended, Cogswell returned to Stamford. He married Abigail Lloyd (1751-1830) on May 18, 1783. The Cogswells subsequently moved to New York. They had four children: James Lloyd (1784-1831), Sarah Lloyd (b. 1786), John Lloyd (1789-1831) and Harriet Broome (1790-1843).</p>
         <p>Cogswell continued his medical practice at New York with Mason Fitch serving as his assistant. For a time they both maintained as apothecary business. James Cogswell contracted yellow fever while attending a stricken patient; he died on November 20, 1792.</p>
         <p>* * * * *</p>
         <p>SAMUEL COGSWELL, 1754-1790</p>
         <p>Samuel Cogswell, son of James and Alice Fitch Cogswell, was born in Canterbury, Connecticut, on May 23, 1754. His father prepared him for college, and he graduated from Yale in 1777.</p>
         <p>Cogswell joined the Continental Army and fought throughout the Revolution. He remained with his brigade until November, 1783. After the war ended, Cogswell began a mercantile business in Lansingburg, New York.</p>
         <p>In 1784, he married Mary Backus. Samuel and Mary Cogswell had three children: Mason Backus (1787-1790), James Fitch (1789-1862) and Maria (1790-1870). Cogswell's business was unsuccessful, and he had to give it up. He then decided to study medicine. Before he could embark upon a new career, he was killed in a hunting accident on August 20, 1790.</p>
         <p>* * * * *</p>
         <p>MASON FITCH COGSWELL, 1761-1830</p>
         <p>Mason Fitch Cogswell, son of James and Alice Fitch Cogswell, was born in Canterbury, Connecticut, on September 28, 1761. He graduated from Yale College in 1780. His chosen profession was medicine. Mason served as assistant to his brother James, both during the Revolutionary War and afterwards at New York.</p>
         <p>In 1789, Mason opened his own practice in Hartford, Connecticut, where he soon distinguished himself as a surgeon. He pioneered the technique of removing a cataract from the eye by extracting it whole, rather than breaking it, as had been done until that time.</p>
         <p>On April 13, 1800, he married Mary Austin Ledyard (1775-1849). Mason and Mary Cogswell had five children: Mary Austin (1801-1868), Elizabeth (1803-1856), Alice (1805-1830), Mason Fitch (1809-1865) and Catharine Ledyard (1811-1882).</p>
         <p>It was through an affliction which rendered his daughter Alice deaf and dumb, when she was six years old, that Dr. Cogswell made another significant contribution to medicine. Largely because of Cogswell's influence, Thomas Gallaudet visited Paris, where he learned as much as he could about the work taking place in France to educate children handicapped by deafness. Gallaudet returned to America in 1816, with an assistant, Laurent Clerc. Shortly afterwards, Gallaudet, Clerc and Cogswell established the Hartford Asylum for the Deaf and Dumb as the first institution of its kind in the United States.</p>
         <p>Cogswell remained active in the medical profession throughout his life. He served as president of the Connecticut Medical Society from 1812 to 1822. Cogswell died in Hartford on December 10, 1830.</p>
         <p>Please note that the bulk of the Mason Fitch Cogswell Papers are in the Beinecke Rare Book Library. The Laurent Clerc Papers are in Manuscripts and Archives. Consult Orbis and the reference staff for further information.</p>
         <p>* * * * *</p>
         <p>ALICE COGSWELL FISHER, 1777-1850</p>
         <p>Alice Cogswell Fisher, daughter of James and Elizabeth Davenport Cogswell, was born in Stamford, Connecticut, June 15, 1777. She married Samuel Fisher (1777-1856) on August 22, 1805. For the first five years of their marriage they resided in Wilton, Connecticut. In 1812, they moved to Morristown, New Jersey. Finally, in 1816, they settled in Paterson, New Jersey.</p>
         <p>Samuel and Alice Fisher had six children: Elizabeth D. (1806-1871), James Cogswell (1808-1880), Catherine Avery (b. 1810), Harriet Cogswell (1812-1831), Samuel Ware (1814-1874) and Mary D. (1817-1865). Alice Cogswell died in Orange, New Jersey, on May 9, 1850.</p>
         <p>* * * * *</p>
         <p>JAMES LLOYD COGSWELL, 1784-1832</p>
         <p>James Lloyd Cogswell, son of James and Abigail Lloyd Cogswell, was born in Stamford, Connecticut, on April 26, 1784. He married Sarah Burr Sherwood (1788-1830) on May 2, 1819. They resided at Lloyd's Neck, Long Island. James and Sarah Cogswell had three children: Sarah B. (1820-1875), James A. (1822-1837) and Mary Ledyard (1824-1841). James Lloyd Cogswell died on January 5, 1832.</p>
         <p>* * * * *</p>
         <p>JOHN LLOYD COGSWELL, 1789-1831</p>
         <p>John Lloyd Cogswell, son of James and Abigail Lloyd Cogswell, was born in New York City, in 1789. He served in the United States Army during the War of 1812. On October 31, 1821, he married Love B. Coffin (1792-1857). They resided at Lloyd's Neck, Long Island. John and Love Cogswell had five children: John T. (1823-1866), Charlotte Broome (b. 1825), Samuel F. (1827-1858), Alice Fisher (b. 1829) and Mason Fitch (1830-1832). John Lloyd Cogswell died on April 13, 1831.</p>
         <p>* * * * *</p>
         <p>HARRIET BROOME COGSWELL MOTT, 1790-1843</p>
         <p>Harriet Broome Cogswell Mott, daughter of James and Abigail Lloyd Cogswell, was born in New York City on March 6, 1790. She married Robert Willis Mott (d. 1846) on September 17, 1819. They resided at Great Neck, Long Island, and had one child; Harriet Stella (1820-1902?). Harriet Cogswell Mott died on September 6, 1843.</p>
         <p>* * * * *</p>
         <p>HARRIET STELLA MOTT ONDERDONK, 1820-1902?</p>
         <p>Harriet Stella Mott Onderdonk, daughter of Robert and Harriet Cogswell Mott, was born September 13, 1820. On June 7, 1843, she married William Handy Onderdonk (1820-1882), son of Bishop Benjamin T. Onderdonk of New York. The Onderdonks resided at Great Neck, Long Island.</p>
         <p>William H. Onderdonk, a prominent lawyer, was a member of the bar of Queens County, New York. William and Harriet Onderdonk had two children: Harriet Cogswell (1844-1881) and Robert Mott (1846-1857). William H. Onderdonk died December 11, 1882.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <userestrict id="aspace_2dcd1341bf6462340bcaee41142f629a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator(s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
  
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85033596"
                  source="lcsh">
            Courtship
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85047009"
                  source="lcsh">
            Families
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85061673"
                  source="lcsh">
            Home economics
         </subject>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85034551"
                   source="lcsh">
            Cuba -- Description and travel
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85074879"
                   source="lcsh">
            Latin America
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140131"
                   source="lcsh">
            United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140139"
                   source="lcsh">
            United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783
         </geogname>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027112" source="aat">
            Diaries
         </genreform>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85101610"
                  source="lcsh">
            Physicians
         </subject>
         <persname source="local">
            Cogswell, James Lloyd, 1784-1832
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85024054"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Cogswell, James, 1720-1807
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            Cogswell, James, 1746-1792
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            Cogswell, John Lloyd, 1789-1831
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2008160187"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Cogswell, Mason Fitch, 1761-1830
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            Cogswell, Samuel, 1754-1790
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            Fisher, Alice Cogswell, 1777-1850
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            Mott, Harriet Broome Cogswell, 1790-1843
         </persname>
         <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
            Onderdonk, Harriet Stella Mott, 1820-1902?
         </persname>
         <famname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh86001371"
                  source="lcsh">
            Cogswell family
         </famname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref10" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>CORRESPONDENCE AND OTHER PAPERS</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1740-1924</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e1de9b1010b6fd4a5b1449917afb0506">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The papers are arranged within one series: CORRESPONDENCE AND OTHER PAPERS. The correspondence, in three manuscript boxes, is arranged chronologically, 1740 to 1902. The final box of miscellaneous papers is arranged chronologically, 1765 to 1924.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1740 - 1818</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1740 - 1818</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200763)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_75238cd327e5b67e8b48b3750972a6bc"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a2cb001ceadac7b49f17ded3b73b0233"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_75238cd327e5b67e8b48b3750972a6bc">1-15</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1819-1838, 1839 January - Nov, 1840 February - Jun, 1840 September - December</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200771)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_97a1d5e42d06053bfc904bda7be1126f"
                             type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ecd5d69ad5c7b8ac36d1796e4d2f2bd8"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_97a1d5e42d06053bfc904bda7be1126f">16-33</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1841 - 1860, 1863-1886, 1896 - 1902</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200789)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_2bbb087ebc7f54207502f519250c02fd"
                             type="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3b470d85118222e729aac3345cf46c18"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_2bbb087ebc7f54207502f519250c02fd">34-45</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200789)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_66a10c8199b3329f2ac8412a420e9529"
                             type="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_59d52f726c9b91eeb0de1a0be5db23cf"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_66a10c8199b3329f2ac8412a420e9529">46-47</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>B.A. diploma awarded to Henry Lloyd</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1765 May 21</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_97c79cfdea1e240528279aaf112d5c36"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_bd2d488fca97fe80fb37fafeb754fa82"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_97c79cfdea1e240528279aaf112d5c36">48</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Will of Abigail Woolsey</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1770 April 4</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_0666a68d33b35c29fe3a199aaf04e7d3"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6d424fb696758a0201999f00e12620eb"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_0666a68d33b35c29fe3a199aaf04e7d3">49</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Epistle to Mr. Joseph Lancaster on the Royal British System of Education by S. Whitchurch</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1809 December</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_8e6d3144f2c0fc7d9750a40067c92437"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f3a9901e078059e716ac32ac42051ddf"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_8e6d3144f2c0fc7d9750a40067c92437">50</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Poetry, author unknown</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Circa 1809-1830</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_e9f69243ff375f38d1e08e5c7a4cbaa1"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0cafee3e1f52809bc39d4175c643d41a"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e9f69243ff375f38d1e08e5c7a4cbaa1">51</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Farm journal and agricultural observations, Robert W. Mott</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1823</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_7f186ee4f80c110331e94f0e0c23b681"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4b1118f97d86b7f5dc69e139e9480fbd"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_7f186ee4f80c110331e94f0e0c23b681">52</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Composition book, author unknown</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Circa 1830-1840</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_29052ffebd50f3fe933e08a450ff374d"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d6ec9296ed9143b0ec496fdd2d6946e1"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_29052ffebd50f3fe933e08a450ff374d">53</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous programs</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1837, 1838, undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_c01ea22bc321389ff5daf7cb3c1b59d2"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_08e204564f415e863fa3dbaf3ac47531"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c01ea22bc321389ff5daf7cb3c1b59d2">54</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Book of lithographs with pencil sketches, author and date unknown</unittitle>
               </did>
               <odd id="aspace_eec08c663c19cc8da7878deafad741db">
                  <head>General note</head>
                  <p>See: <ref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="replace" target="ref35">box 4, folder 63</ref>
                  </p>
               </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Certification of William H. Onderdonk as counsellor at law in the state of New York</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1846 May 15</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_1eb32a0a4578193d13d96dd6f3978efc"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_47644405dfb0bd458a5da4d79bc655c3"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_1eb32a0a4578193d13d96dd6f3978efc">55</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Certification of William H. Onderdonk as attorney in the state of New York</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1858 July 14</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_9b131949db1d1406aa801a6cf1f5e8da"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6b903c910c9124d7ea782514b8c133fc"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9b131949db1d1406aa801a6cf1f5e8da">56</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Thermometer record [H. S. Onderdonk?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1877-1882</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_ce32901671c3c960068dcffe30b9a377"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6f16077a959df580c6dd5b3306f307d5"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_ce32901671c3c960068dcffe30b9a377">57</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Journal, author unknown</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1904 April-November</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_ed8ab8d30e20ec8306b69a45c4fb0f3e"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_cfa40b766852809a6ab23873b33aa46d"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_ed8ab8d30e20ec8306b69a45c4fb0f3e">58</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Father and Daughter
                     </title>: A Collection of Cogswell Family Letters and Diaries, edited by Grace Cogswell Root</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1924 August</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_8d99797271fdfabdf6dea27ced95b3e8"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4d30ed38fce9924bc00913df01961a1a"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_8d99797271fdfabdf6dea27ced95b3e8">59</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"An Hieroglyphic Epistle in Answer to That Lately Reciev'd from Pandemonium" [Harriet (Mott) Onderdonk?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_547397cbcfdfbf065082cecad2714eb2"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_40fcf97de35322517ae3951548241849"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_547397cbcfdfbf065082cecad2714eb2">60</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Medical remedies, Henry Mott</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_f3d29044bb3e72ca395ab3c31f1fa490"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e014b5768b17ce4118b7a31e08a97915"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_f3d29044bb3e72ca395ab3c31f1fa490">61</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Certification of William H. Onderdonk as attorney in the Supreme Court of the state of New York. 1842 May 13</unittitle>
               </did>
               <odd id="aspace_d2af9303f3994e8239803dee53762451">
                  <head>General note</head>
                  <p>See: <ref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="replace" target="ref35">box 4, folder 63</ref>
                  </p>
               </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notebooks, reflections, author unknown</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_e2274174a9a545d7a4200aa3d7379951"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8b2a85bfe3f16f153d0b8c88a43053b8"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e2274174a9a545d7a4200aa3d7379951">62</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038200797)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_d1960688803c30b57bad04539333e5e5"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b67a9de8f06250de350b6531c7393ec6"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_d1960688803c30b57bad04539333e5e5">63</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oversize material</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042602517)"
                             id="aspace_8306dd367ff7d355a311217d9c65d482"
                             type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
