<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.0978">mssa.ms.0978</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Charles James Morse papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Morse (Charles James) papers</titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>July 2008</date>
            <num>MS 978</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Saturday December  8, 2018 at 10:16</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Charles James Morse papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 978</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">16</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(38 boxes)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1897/1911">1897-1911</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_3e6f7afa790318d6ea5bb6781df6e643">The largest part of these papers consist of 137 volumes of translations into English, mainly from Japanese, of published works on Japanese and other branches of Oriental art. Also in the papers are two bound volumes of letters from Japan written between 1897 and 1898 by Charles James Morse and his wife, Anne Perkins Woodbridge Morse.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
               Morse, Charles James, 1852-1911
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_9aadd488a287d6803656347a9e30331f">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Mrs. Jared K. Morse in 1952.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_04b0b3cf466db72f4fd12dfade21cf92">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_9e150ecd12f5d47957c4c6c7b4ecef3a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator(s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_ebe2a0acd106fc8d97416aeef38d0031">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Charles James Morse Papers (MS 978). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist id="aspace_a573b5613030940f91be282bd1ee553b">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>CHARLES JAMES MORSE, second son of Henry Kirtland Morse and Mary (Lynn) Morse, was born July 7, 1852, at Poland, O. His grandfather had settled in the Western Reserve, going there from Wallmgford, Conn He was a grand nephew of Dr Jared P Kirtland (M.D Yale 1815), in whose memory Kirtland Hall was named.</p>
         <p>He studied m Poland Union Semmaiy and worked two years with the city engineer of Youngstown, Ohio, then entered the Sheffield Scientific School m the winter of 1871, taking the course in Civil Engineering.</p>
         <p>Upon graduation he was Assistant in Surveying in the School for a year, and m 1877 received the degree of Civil Engineer from Yale University.</p>
         <p>Taking up construction work m the summer of 1875 he became assistant engineer for the Wrought Iron Bridge Co at Canton, O , and during 1876 and 1877 was engineer of the Massillon (Oh) Bridge Co With his brother, Henry G Morse (Troy Polytechnic Inst 1871), he founded the Morse Bridge Co of Youngstown, Ohio , in 1878 With this he was actively engaged for ten years when the works were destroyed by fire In 1889 he visited Europe with members of the American Society of Civil Engineers and other national societies. In 1890-91 he was manager of the Association of Bridge Builders, with an office in Chicago During the latter year he became the consulting engineer and western representative of the Edgemoor Bridge Works of Wilmington, Del, and removed to Evanston, Illinois. He had charge of the construction of the Manufactures Building at the Columbian Exposition at Chicago, the Columbia River Bridge for the Great Northern Railway, the replacement of the Roebhng Suspension Budge at Covmgton, Ky, without suspension of travel, and many other important bridges and other structures.</p>
         <p>In order to study oriental art, in which he had for a number of years been interested, he retired from professional work in 1897, and spent a year in Japan, visiting the great temples, museums, and private collections there. On returning home he continued his studies at Evanston, employing Japanese scholais to translate the ancient literature on the subject In 1905 he visited Europe, and Japan again in 1907. During his years of study he collected paintings, prints, pottery, and other objects of Chinese and Japanese art, and a library of eight thousand volumes relating to art and art history, for which he built a fireproof library and vault adjoining his home. He was a member of the Royal Asiatic Society and the Asiatic Society of Japan.</p>
         <p>Several years after his retirement he returned temporarily to engineering work, and with Julian Kennedy (Ph.B Yale 1875) and others, bought a large tract of coal land near Uniontown in Pennsylvania, where during the years 1902 to 1904 he constructed great coke works for the Orient Coal and Coke Co.</p>
         <p>After years of suffering Mr Morse died from myocarditis at his home in Evanston, December 6, 1911, at the age of 59 years.</p>
         <p>He married at Youngstown, Ohio, October 16, 1884, Annie Perkins Woodbndge, daughter of Dr. Timothy Woodbndge and Isabella (McCurdy) Woodbndge. Mrs Morse survived him with their eldest son, Jared Kirtland Morse (Ph B Yale 1908), twin sons having died. A brother, Edwin K Morse, graduated from the Sheffield Scientific School in 1881.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_31355245a5290efe065eb9f15ecb644c">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The largest part of these papers consist of 137 volumes of translations into English, mainly from Japanese, of published works on Japanese and other branches of Oriental art. Also in the papers are two bound volumes of letters from Japan written between 1897 and 1898 by Charles James Morse and his wife, Anne Perkins Woodbridge Morse.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2009114859"
                  source="lcsh">
            Americans -- Japan
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85007726"
                  source="lcsh">
            Art, Japanese
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85007549"
                  source="lcsh">
            Art, Asian
         </subject>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85069398"
                   source="lcsh">
            Japan -- Description and travel
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85008606"
                   source="lcsh">
            Asia
         </geogname>
         <persname source="local">
            Morse, Ann Perkins Woodbridge
         </persname>
         <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
            Morse, Charles James, 1852-1911
         </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref9" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Original accession</unittitle>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1897-1911?</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_23c1772b36c1a1b76a10f03af742b049">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>There is a list of titles of the translated works in the register file. Please consult reference staff.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>137 volumes of translations into English, mainly from Japanese, of published works on Japanese and other branches of Oriental art.</unittitle>
                  <container type="box" id="d2e77">1–37</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>2 volumes, "Letters from Japan, 1897-98 (typed copies with photographs and sketches) by Charles James Morse and Anne Perkins (Woodbridge) Morse</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042326091)"
                             altrender="archive letter"
                             id="aspace_5fbca2dc7f1bc0fd752679b137f49e0f"
                             type="box">38</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
