<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.1053">mssa.ms.1053</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Joseph Washburn Family Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Washburn (Joseph) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Janet Elaine Gertz</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>July 1983</date>
            <num>MS 1053</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Thursday January 10, 2019 at 10:38</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules/>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Joseph Washburn family papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 1053</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">0.25</extent>
         </physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1783/1829">1783-1829</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_092a137d8e9156dcdb47a585c3576c42">Chiefly the sermons of Joseph Washburn, together with a collection of the sayings of others, written down from memory. Also included are a sheet of maxims written out to display fine penmanship and a Yale College song book (1790). Five letters from his son, Elizur T. Washburn to various members of the family were written during 1829 to describe his trip from New York to London.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2009165249"
                      source="naf">
               Washburn, Joseph, 1766-1805
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_5ae9772eba9fd74fa52522419d81ed54">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Henry B. Keffer, 1939, and Carroll A. Means, 1940.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_ca661890d82621f9119c27e6863451f4">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_5479f69a9e2c170938f2faa312e61bb6">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Joseph Washburn Family Papers. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_70b965e34bd3b6cc3caddee7f9d140e6">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection contains papers of Joseph Washburn (1766-1805) and his son, Elizur Timothy Washburn (1805-1831). The papers of Joseph Washburn consist of a page of maxims done in ink and color with manuscript decorations, and intended to show proficiency in penmanship; a booklet, "Social Hilarity and Musical Entertainment," of songs, odes, and favorite Yale College pieces of music; a volume of "Sermonical observations taken from various preachers and written from memory," begun at the Leicester Academy and continued at Yale; and eleven small notebooks of sermons and one containing a register of sermon outlines.</p>
         <p>Five letters written to his mother and step-father, Mr. and Mrs. Elijah Porter of Farmington, Connecticut, and one to his brother Horace Washburn make up the papers of Elizur Washburn. The letters are a record of his journey from New York to England, undertaken in 1829 for the sake of his health, and document his impressions of Liverpool and London.</p>
         <p>The items in this collection were received as three separate acquisitions. The page of maxims and the song book were purchased in 1939, while the other papers of Joseph Washburn were donated in that year by Harry B. Keffer. The letters of Elizur Washburn were donated in 1940 by Carroll A. Means.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <bioghist id="aspace_13e0e71b606e6953e042f36061e35b6b">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Joseph Washburn, the son of Joseph and Ruth Washburn, of Middletown, Connecticut, was born in Middletown on May 13, 1766, and baptized five days later. His mother was the youngest daughter of Daniel and Dorothy (Hale) Wetmore, of Middletown.</p>
         <p>He did not enter College until May of the Freshman year, when he was 24 years old. His preparation was conducted by his pastor, the Rev. Enoch Huntington (Yale 1759). He had already taught school in the vicinity. He was admitted to the College Church on profession of faith at the close of the Junior year. At graduation he was the oldest member of the Class.</p>
         <p>He then studied for the ministry with Mr. Huntington, and was licensed to preach by the Hartford South Association of Ministers in June, 1794.</p>
         <p>Four months later he began to supply the vacant church in Farmington, Connecticut, and gave such satisfaction that on May 7, 1795, he was ordained and installed as pastor.</p>
         <p>He loved his work and was successful in it, great additions being made to the church during his ministry. But his course was suddenly arrested by pulmonary consumption, brought on, as was supposed, by his incessant labors.</p>
         <p>In October, 1805, he left home with his wife to spend the winter in a southern climate. While on their passage by water from Norfolk, Virginia, to Charleston, South Carolina, they encountered very tempestuous weather, which probably hastened his dissolution. He died serenely and peacefully on the morning of December 25, in his 40th year, and was buried at sea.</p>
         <p>He published in the Connecticut Evangelical Magazine, vol. I, 1901, pp. 378-86, 420-31:</p>
         <p>Letters on the Revival of Religion in Farmington; republished in the Rev. Dr. Bennet Tyler's <title render="italic">
               New England Revivals
            </title>, 1846, pp. 160-78.</p>
         <p>After his death a volume was published for the benefit of his destitute family, with the following title:</p>
         <p>Sermons on practical subjects.--To which is added, a Sermon of the Rev. Asahel Hooker, delivered in Farmington, on the occasion of Mr. Washburn's death. Hartford, 1807. 12°, pp. 376. <emph render="italic">Andover Theol. Sem. Harv. Y. C.</emph>
         </p>
         <p>Twenty-three of the author's sermons are included; and at the end is a very interesting list of subscribers, in which one suggestive feature is that over four hundred and fifty copies were taken in the city of Charleston, where large public sympathy had been aroused on account of Mrs. Washburn's afflicted condition. In Connecticut over nine hundred copies were taken.</p>
         <p>He married, on August 18, 1795, Sarah, youngest daughter of Deacon Timothy and Jemima (Johnson) Boardman, of Middletown, by whom he had two daughters and two sons. One daughter married the Rev. Dr. Horatio N. Brinsmade (Yale 1822).</p>
         <p>Mrs. Washburn next married, on August 23, 1812, Deacon Elijah Porter, of Farmington, who died in 1845; and she died in New York City on July 2, 1847, in her 78th year, at the home of her only surviving son by her first marriage.</p>
         <p>(<title render="italic">
               Biographical Sketches of Yale College
            </title>, by F.B. Dexter, pp. 92-93).</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <userestrict id="aspace_9712fa74048363b3ad39020dbb51c92f">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator(s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85047009"
                  source="lcsh">
            Families
         </subject>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85045631"
                   source="lcsh">
            Europe
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85056605"
                   source="lcsh">
            Great Britain
         </geogname>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026669" source="aat">
            Sermons
         </genreform>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026944"
                  source="lcsh">
            Clergy
         </subject>
         <persname source="local">
            Washburn, Elizur Timothy, 1805-1831
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2009165249"
                   source="naf">
            Washburn, Joseph, 1766-1805
         </persname>
         <famname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85145330"
                  source="lcsh">
            Washburn family
         </famname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043367"
                   source="naf">
            Yale University -- Songs and music
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043367"
                   source="naf">
            Yale University -- Students
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref11" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Joseph Washburn</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref13" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Maxims</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1783</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042326109)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_f35e2fea887c27d80d3b7b855ab5b4fa"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3890a85cb3d6093da0b362c04014f47b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f35e2fea887c27d80d3b7b855ab5b4fa">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref14" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Yale College song book</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1790</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042326109)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_70a392afdd4900bbf64b3fb87fbe93b7"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d73dd757ca4fa8d4dc0d37b051c780f7"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_70a392afdd4900bbf64b3fb87fbe93b7">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref15" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"Sermonical observations taken from various preachers and written from memory"</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1793</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042326109)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_0d421759ed9e154142e2b9723cf84411"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_df7d2059c092bafcaa7499131fc968e6"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0d421759ed9e154142e2b9723cf84411">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref16" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sermons and sermon outlines</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1796-1803</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042326109)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_fe8043c5360611800838bf85104c604a"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_49fac14d8463afa58b42626598309f1b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_fe8043c5360611800838bf85104c604a">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Elizur Timothy Washburn</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref18" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letters</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1829</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042326109)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_c92ac85fd1ced44d1710d86b2898e1f6"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_436e4e11c0376e160725959476ba4dfc"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c92ac85fd1ced44d1710d86b2898e1f6">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
