<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.0405">mssa.ms.0405</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Truman Smith Reports Collection
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Smith (Truman) Collection</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Janet Elaine Gertz</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>August 1981</date>
            <num>MS 405</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Thursday January 10, 2019 at 09:07</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules/>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Truman Smith papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 405</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">0.5</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(1 box, 2 v.)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1924/1956">1924-1956</unitdate>
         
         
            <unitdate type="bulk" normal="1954/1956">1954-1956</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_8c575f84ad108fa41bf982f68e62d1b9">Two reports by Truman Smith prepared during his army service. One on Hitler and the National Socialists in Munich in November 1922 and the other on "Air intelligence activities... with special reference to the services of Colonel Charles A. Lindbergh."</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2004063817"
                      source="naf">
               Smith, Truman, 1893-1970
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <altformavail id="aspace_e81edaa76b93c5f833ef1d71f414b925">
         <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
         <p>"Air Intelligence Activities" is available on microfilm (170 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM12.</p>  
      </altformavail>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_58a0a4ec2542c649a8d9c6973d99e176">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Truman Smith in 1957 and 1961.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_2ca00c91fafca98f79f1f52cb30ffccd">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>
         <p>Patrons must use HM 12 instead of the original "Air Intelligence Activities" report.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_9604d52415a89b93cad7076b71addf5f">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Truman Smith Papers. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_b691a0a01054323825a183788d18d8be">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>These volumes were given to Yale University by Truman Smith in 1957 and 1961.</p>
         <p>The Truman Smith Papers are located in the Hoover War Library, Stanford University.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <bioghist id="aspace_9ff05922397d9f988cc5fe15d1d5aeaf">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Truman Smith was born in West Point, New York, on August 25, 1893. He was the son of Captain E. D. Smith of Stamford, Connecticut, and grandson of Truman Smith of Connecticut, who represented the state in both the House of Representatives and the Senate from 1842-1852.</p>
         <p>Smith was brought up and attended school in Stamford, Connecticut, and graduated from Yale University in 1915. In 1917, he married Katherine Alling Hollister.</p>
         <p>Smith served on the Mexican border in 1916 as a lieutenant in the New York National Guard, and then was commissioned in 1916 as a 2nd lieutenant in the U.S. Army, from which he retired in 1946, having attained the rank of colonel. During World War I he served as company and battalion commander in the 4th Infantry of the 3rd Division, participating in the Marne Defense battles and the Meuse Argonne offensive. For the latter he received the Silver Star for gallantry in action and was promoted to major for the capture by his battalion of the Bois de Poret. Smith later took part in the occupation of Germany from December 1918 to June 20, acting as political officer in the office of civil government.</p>
         <p>From 1920 to 1924 Smith served as assistant military attache in Germany, and from 1935-1939 as military attache. Though retired in 1941 because of physical disability, Smith continued in active service from 1941-1946 as German specialist in the Intelligence Division of the General Staff. For his work in Germany and in the Intelligence Division he was awarded the Distinguished Service Medal in 1949.</p>
         <p>In 1946 and 1947, Smith served as a military advisor on the National Defense Committee (Eberstadt Committee) of the Hoover Commission, and afterwards as military aide to the governor of Connecticut. He translated, edited, and wrote the preface for <emph render="italic">Invasion, 1944: Rommel and the Normandy Campaign</emph>, by Lieutenant General Hans Speidel, Rommel's chief of staff.</p>
         <p>Smith died in Fairfield, Connecticut, on October 3, 1970.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <userestrict id="aspace_584189c76d2099e2e671875cfd7ad819">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Copyright status for collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85090131"
                  source="lcsh">
            National socialism
         </subject>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85045631"
                   source="lcsh">
            Europe
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85054589"
                   source="lcsh">
            Germany -- History -- 1918-1933
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85054594"
                   source="lcsh">
            Germany -- History -- 1933-1945
         </geogname>
         <occupation source="local">
            Soldiers
         </occupation>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79046200"
                   source="naf">
            Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79100565"
                   source="naf">
            Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2004063817"
                   source="naf">
            Smith, Truman, 1893-1970
         </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref12" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Hitler and the National Socialists: Notebook and Report of Captain Truman Smith, Infantry, U.S. Army, Assistant Military Attaché, Berlin, Germany, Describing a Visit to Munich from November 15 to November 22, 1922" (notebook and typed transcript)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Post 1924</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042581042)"
                             altrender="archive half legal"
                             id="aspace_7c3aac15d7ee6801facc598f323cc5cd"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Air Intelligence Activities, Office of the Military Attaché, American Embassy, Berlin, Germany, August 1935 - April 1939, with Special Reference to the Services of Colonel Charles A. Lindbergh, Air Corps (Res.) (typescript)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1954-1956</unitdate>
                  <container type="box" id="d2e2">1</container>
                  <container type="reel" id="d2e5">1U</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
