<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.0431">mssa.ms.0431</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Rufus and S. Willard Saxton Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Saxton (Rufus and S. Willard) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Diane E. Kaplan and William E. Brown, Jr. and staff of Manuscripts and Archives</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>August 1986</date>
            <num>MS 431</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Thursday January 10, 2019 at 09:09</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules/>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Rufus and S. Willard Saxton papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 431</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">10.5</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(25 boxes)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1834/1934">1834-1934</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_7765b72fd8c2d42c87168323299fdf66">The papers include correspondence, journals, memorabilia, and photographs that document the life of Samuel Willard Saxton and the career of his brother General Rufus Saxton during the Civil War. The largest portion of the papers is composed of S. Willard Saxton's multi-volumed journal, which he began in 1847 while at Brook Farm and continued until the 1920s. The journal chronicles his career as a printer, aide-de-camp, and civil servant; his travels; family; his interests in the cultural life of Boston and Washington, D.C.; and his summers spent in Guilford, Connecticut. His journal highlights Saxton's ardent abolitionist and reformist interests, his work on behalf of freedmen's education, and his strong Republican loyalties. The letterbooks reflect Saxton's position as an aide-de-camp for his brother and Rufus Saxton's administration of the Department of the South and the former slaves under his jurisdiction.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88156903"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               Saxton, Rufus, 1824-1908
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local">
               Saxton, Samuel Willard, 1829-1933
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_82c7ed15adb85ade63314634ba5f4aaa">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_650a81794e4a1a9dbb690c040dd8c4ce">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator(s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_c80689360175f305a956a4b1a585330c">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Rufus and S. Willard Saxton Papers (MS 431). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_5a8312816c7203d046cebf012a1fbf75">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>A portion of the papers was given by Paul S. Seward in 1965. Additional papers were given by Paul S. and W. Saxton Seward in 1972-1973 and 1980 and by Mrs. Mary S. Williams in 2012.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <arrangement id="aspace_c52956a13834ce9b9cb8e4dd92ea9a01">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Arranged in three series: I. Letterbooks and Scrapbook, 1834-1926. II. Journals, 1847-1927. III. Personal Papers, 1849-1934, and one addition.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_db3662e8eb9dd383a70dd704cd6f8781">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Rufus and S. Willard Saxton Papers consist of correspondence, journals, memorabilia, and photographs that document the life of Samuel Willard Saxton and the career of his brother General Rufus Saxton during the Civil War. The largest portion of the papers is composed of S. Willard Saxton's multi-volumed journal, which he began in 1847 while at Brook Farm and continued until the 1920s. The journals chronicle S. Willard Saxton's career as a printer, aide-de-camp, and civil servant; his travels; family; and his interests in the cultural life of Boston and Washington, D.C. They also highlight his ardent abolitionist and reformist interests, his work on behalf of freedmen's education, and his strong Republican loyalties. Rufus Saxton's duties as military governor of the Department of the South are reflected, primarily, in contemporary letterbooks kept by his aides-de-camp.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <bioghist id="aspace_30defc02d17f2a8d04109cb85402f0cc">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Rufus Saxton, 1824-1908</emph>
         </p>
         <p>Rufus Saxton was born in Greenfield, Massachusetts in 1824 and graduated from the United States Military Academy in 1849. During the Civil War he participated in the Port Royal Expedition and in May 1862, Saxton was appointed the military governor of the Department of the South. From his headquarters in Beaufort, South Carolina, he organized the first black regiment in the United States Army. In 1865 Saxton became commissioner for the Freedmen's Bureau and a year later returned to the Quartermasters Corps. He retired in 1888 and died in 1908.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Samuel Willard Saxton, 1829-1933</emph>
         </p>
         <p>Samuel Willard Saxton was born in Deerfield, Massachusetts, in 1829. As an adolescent Saxton was apprenticed to a printer, and from 1845 to 1847 he lived at George Ripley's Brook Farm, where he worked on <title render="italic">
               The Harbinger
            </title>. When Brook Farm was dissolved he went to work in Boston, where he lived off and on for the next fifteen years.</p>
         <p>In 1862 Saxton joined his brother General Rufus Saxton in South Carolina. During the remainder of the Civil War Saxton served as his brother's aide-de-camp. He was brevetted major in 1865. Saxton remained in South Carolina on the staff of General Robert K. Howard until 1866 when he became a civilian employee of the Freedmen's Bureau. In 1869 Saxton was appointed to a position in the office of the First Comptroller of the Treasury and eventually rose to be chief of his division. Saxton retired from the government in 1921.</p>
         <p>In 1861 Saxton married Mary Grant. They had seven children: Edward, Fanny (d. 1869), Minnie, Mattie, Louise, Katharine, and Beth. Saxton died in 1933 at the age of 103.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85000188"
                  source="lcsh">
            Abolitionists
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85001906"
                  source="lcsh">
            African American soldiers
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85001946"
                  source="lcsh">
            African Americans -- Education
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026398"
                  source="lcsh">
            Civil service -- United States
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85051692"
                  source="lcsh">
            Freedmen
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85111862"
                  source="lcsh">
            Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877)
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85123317"
                  source="lcsh">
            Slaves -- Emancipation
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85139727"
                  source="lcsh">
            Unitarians
         </subject>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81134991"
                   source="lcsh">
            Beaufort (S.C.)
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008114440"
                   source="lcsh">
            Boston (Mass.) -- Social life and customs
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81149052"
                   source="lcsh">
            Guilford (Conn.)
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125633"
                   source="lcsh">
            Southern States
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="local">
            United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- African American troops
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140205"
                   source="lcsh">
            United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140391"
                   source="lcsh">
            United States -- Officials and employees
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85145361"
                   source="lcsh">
            Washington (D.C.) -- Social life and customs
         </geogname>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027112" source="aat">
            Diaries
         </genreform>
         <genreform source="local">
            Photoprints
         </genreform>
         <occupation source="local">
            Printers
         </occupation>
         <occupation source="local">
            Public officers
         </occupation>
         <occupation source="local">
            Soldiers
         </occupation>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80122814"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Alvord, John Watson, 1807-1880
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79082230"
                   source="naf">
            Burroughs, John, 1837-1921
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80017916"
                   source="naf">
            Howard, O. O. (Oliver Otis), 1830-1909
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80038470"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Parker, Theodore, 1810-1860
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88156903"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Saxton, Rufus, 1824-1908
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            Saxton, Samuel Willard, 1829-1933
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n91094949"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Scott, Robert K. (Robert Kingston), 1826-1900
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50014735"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Smalls, Robert, 1839-1915
         </persname>
         <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">
            United States. Army. South Carolina Volunteers
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80020357"
                   source="naf">
            United States. Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78096864"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            United States. Department of the Treasury -- Officials and employees
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n84024538"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            All Souls Church (Washington, D.C. : Unitarian)
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85243737"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Brook Farm Phalanx (West Roxbury, Boston, Mass.)
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n84076025"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Grand Army of the Republic
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no90025559"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States. District of Columbia Commandery
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref10" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Letters and scrapbook</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1834-1926</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_cc63b25f82ca45dd17ced74c594affd6">.75 linear feet (2 boxes)</physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_8dde4464fc3f8725d75f4693cfadf89c">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>This series includes letterbooks and a scrapbook relating to the careers of both Rufus and S. Willard Saxton. The earliest letterbooks (folders 1-4) date from Rufus Saxton's headquarters in South Carolina during the Civil War. These volumes contain letters signed by Saxton and his assistant adjutants general, including George Merrill, E.W. Hooper, and S. Willard Saxton. Folder 1 contains official communications and reports to Secretary of War Edwin Stanton, General Hunter, and O.M. Mitchell. Many of these letters concern the administration of the Sea Islands and reveal Saxton's concern for the health and safety of the black people in his jurisdiction. Some letters relate to Saxton's interest in arming contrabands. Most letters in folder 2 are addressed to civilians and relate to applicants for positions in the South Carolina Volunteers. At the reverse of the letterbook is a list of applicants. Additional letters on the same subject are found in folder 4. The letterbook in folder 3 contains routine official correspondence signed by the various assistant adjutants general by order of Rufus Saxton. These letters relate to the day-to-day administration of the Department of the South and include directions concerning provisions, education, and medical treatment for Blacks in the area and support for their employment in agriculture and commerce.</p>
               <p>Letterbooks in folders 3 and 4 carry over to the period when Rufus and S. Willard Saxton worked with the Freedmen's Bureau. Folder 3 includes lists of teachers and missionaries on duty in the department. In folder 4, beginning about February 1866, there are letters only of S. Willard Saxton. These include some by order of General R.K. Scott. The letterbook includes a lengthy report on an inspection tour of Sumter and Marion Counties. There are education reports sent to General O.O. Howard after S. Willard Saxton's transfer to the Washington, D.C., Office, and letters written by Saxton for J.W. Alvord. Some letters relate to Saxton's efforts, as treasurer of the Washington Christian Union's Board of Directors of Colored Schools, to organize freedmen's schools in Washington churches. Additional letters on Freedmen's Bureau business are included in folder 6.</p>
               <p>Letterbooks in folders 4 and 6 are marked "Private Letter Book," and in addition to Freedmen's Bureau business these volumes contain letters to S. Willard Saxton's friends and family and concern personal finances or church business. Letters at the end of the volume in folder 6 concern Saxton's work in the First Comptroller's Office, as do letters in folder 7. Certain letters in 1885 relate to Saxton's discharge from office under the new Democratic administration and to his work in Louisville, Kentucky, overseeing shipments of army horses. There are only a few scattered letters after 1887.</p>
               <p>Folder 5 contains a scrapbook of letters, orders, and memorabilia kept by S. Willard Saxton. Many items are loose, and the pages are in no particular order. The volume includes the earliest item in the papers. There are several items of memorabilia relating to Saxton's life in Boston, including membership cards, printed programs, and tickets for the Boston Union of Associationists; the fraternity of the 28th Congregational Society; and the Free Soil Party. There are numerous official communications relating to Saxton's government service and there are items of memorabilia from life in Washington, D.C., including tickets for the presidential impeachment, concert and lecture tickets and programs from the Columbian College. The scrapbook also includes biographical information on Rufus and S. Willard Saxton.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <arrangement id="aspace_1cb5897bc361109660050f16fdc2760a">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>This series is arranged roughly in chronological order.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters of Brigadier General Saxton signed by himself; through Assistant Adjutant General</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1862 June - 1864 October</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215217)"
                             altrender="archive letter"
                             id="aspace_be979309c1d20f6e687b38fabe61245a"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d826a9e485f3caae556f7791c654d6be"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_be979309c1d20f6e687b38fabe61245a">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letterbook: Headquarters Department of the South, Rufus Saxton, Military Governor</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1862 December - 1864 June</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215217)"
                             altrender="archive letter"
                             id="aspace_075b710356ffaf6804318e05ac568482"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_767921cc75ea39edd60bca6f31a2e2bf"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_075b710356ffaf6804318e05ac568482">2</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Official letters</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1863 February - 1865 December</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215217)"
                             altrender="archive letter"
                             id="aspace_449c787c6be020a26476f9dacbbae5be"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_38653509925c98c6a4bf48035118867f"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_449c787c6be020a26476f9dacbbae5be">3</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters Sent 'B'</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1863 March - 1868 April</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002109690306)"
                             altrender="archive legal tall"
                             id="aspace_baa703854c1b7aa253bf4265b0ffaf6c"
                             type="box">1A</container>
                  <container id="aspace_99b1e7009f1ed54ad24e241a234bbf44"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_baa703854c1b7aa253bf4265b0ffaf6c">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook of S. Willard Saxton</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1834-1926</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215225)"
                             altrender="archive letter"
                             id="aspace_f3f0fe56dc8ce0c60f141edbe535dbd8"
                             type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c8caea2097e8aaf8a5c5154fc8c3faee"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_f3f0fe56dc8ce0c60f141edbe535dbd8">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5ed9dfbb196c34b8828820142c07a4f9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The scrapbook includes a letter from Robert Smalls to Rufus Saxton.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters Sent 'C'</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1868 April - 1872</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215225)"
                             altrender="archive letter"
                             id="aspace_ebc49f17373df11446b7d8dee3c68ded"
                             type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7cf03797a23d979a9e6e8a4ec7dea481"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_ebc49f17373df11446b7d8dee3c68ded">6</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_80d09a3fe1c0d2475505bac6648fb77e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The letterbook includes two letters from Willard Saxton to Robert Smalls.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letterbook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1884-1903</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215225)"
                             altrender="archive letter"
                             id="aspace_4c5f81aa42fad21d0c95240ea65603c7"
                             type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3cb1951d90656d0367d30cac8e001ac0"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_4c5f81aa42fad21d0c95240ea65603c7">7</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref21" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Journals</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1847-1927</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_e5c541e9f5f1c05c490d693f7899c971">7.75 linear feet (19 boxes)</physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_253c42321d6324bfeef670df63a0c9bd">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>This series consists of 136 of the 172 volumes of Willard Saxton's life-long journal. Samuel Willard Saxton was not a national leader, but his life and career intersected with many noteworthy people, events, and movements. His journal records these as well as the day-to-day routine of a man's life from adolescence to old age in nineteenth- and early twentieth-century America. Saxton began keeping his journal in 1847 and continued daily recordings until he was well into his nineties. On almost every day he wrote one to two pages, which summarized his work, leisure time, family health and activities, and personal feelings. Often Saxton inserted newspaper clippings in the journals to more fully record the concerts and plays he attended or the world or national events he noted. Generally each volume covers from three to six months and contains between 100 to 300 pages.</p>
               <p>The first twenty-two volumes of the journal (boxes 3-6) cover Saxton's career before joining the army in the winter of 1862. These volumes document Saxton's happy life at Brook Farm, the succeeding years of financial uncertainty as a printer in Boston and elsewhere in Massachusetts, and the domestic instability of an itinerant single male. Saxton refers to his attendance at or participation in the Boston Union of Associationsts; the Young Inductive Communion; William Henry Channing's church; lectures by Theodore Parker, Joshua Giddings, and Wendell Phillips; performances by Jenny Lind and Edwin Booth; Free Soil Party meetings; events at Tremont Temple; social evenings with Elizur Wright; and abolitionist and temperance rallies.</p>
               <p>In 1849 Saxton joined a printers' union and records a printers' union strike. Unable to support himself during the strike, he resorted to working for non-union wages and petitioned to be allowed to resign from the union. With the prospect of no steady employment in Boston in 1852, Saxton first went to New York and then to Washington, D.C. Here he found work with Boyd Hamilton, a contractor for congressional printing, only to lose his job because of blacklisting by the Boston printers' union. In 1853 Saxton records his move west to Indiana to work as an axeman for the Lake Erie, Wabash, and St. Louis Railroad. After a year of this work he returned to printing and sought work in Cincinnati and Memphis. The journal reveals further union difficulties in Memphis.</p>
               <p>Saxton returned to Boston in 1856, and he filled his journals with more details of Boston cultural life as well as family troubles. He records hearing lectures by Henry David Thoreau, Ralph Waldo Emerson, and Henry Ward Beecher. By 1860 Saxton reveals his discouragement with the printing trade, his loneliness with boarding house life, and his difficult financial circumstances which resulted in an arrest for debt. At this time he became engaged to Mary Grant and went into business for himself. The journals reflect the vicissitudes of a storekeeper's life. In 1862 Saxton moved to Port Royal, South Carolina, to join his brother Rufus, who offered him financial relief in the form of steady employment.</p>
               <p>Volumes 23 through 27 (1862-1866) document Saxton's years in South Carolina. These journals are not as inclusive as those for the previous years. There are several gaps, and Saxton frequently notes that he is writing to his wife and now finds maintaining a journal "dull." He writes also of his concern for his pregnant wife in Massachusetts and for his brother's career. The journals also reveal a degree of tension between the two brothers. There is little detail of Saxton' s work; more of the entries concern social life and leisure activities. The late 1864 and 1865 entries give some detail of the disruption of the South, the prisoners, and the wounded as the Union army marched toward the sea. Saxton also notes his travels with his brother on tour as superintendent of plantations and settlements. When Rufus Saxton was relieved of his command, S. Willard Saxton remained in South Carolina on the staff of General R.K. Scott. In May 1866 he records an inspection tour of interior South Carolina. In June Saxton was ordered to report to General O.O. Howard in Washington. He was then mustered out of the army but became a civilian employee of the government. Volumes 28 through 32 cover the period of Saxton's employment in the Freedmen's Bureau (1866-1869). In these volumes Saxton writes less of his work for the bureau and more about domestic arrangements and family life, including the death of his young daughter Fanny. He does record some of the gossip concerning Andrew Johnson's appointees, his teaching duties in a freedmen's school, Unitarian church politics, the impeachment hearings, and events leading to his discharge from the Freedmen's Bureau in April, 1869.</p>
               <p>The journals from volume 33 (1869) until Saxton's retirement in 1920 (volume 156) trace Saxton's career as a government clerk in the Treasury Department and reflect the changes in the civil service system as they affected Saxton. Through examination Saxton rose through the various classes of clerk in the First Comptroller's Office to the rank of division chief in 1878. Here he made the acquaintance of John Burroughs, and visits with his friend are recorded in the journals. With the financial security of government employment, Saxton began plans for building a house. The journals are filled with routine domestic concerns, details of loans and debts, the development of his garden, and interests in the governmental administration of the Mt. Pleasant section of Washington, D.C. Saxton also records the births of his daughters, including his assistance at two of them, and his increasing level of parental responsibility. He notes all the musical and theatrical events he attends, lectures at the Unitarian Church (All Souls), public funerals, and political events. He records his and his wife's participation in women's suffrage meetings. In volume 37 he describes his 1871 trip on government business to Santa Fe, New Mexico; a similar mission to London is described in volume 48 (1877). Volume 46 contains a lengthy description of Saxton's stay in Philadelphia to view the Centennial Exhibition.</p>
               <p>Each time there is a change in administration Saxton expresses his concern over job security. He notes payments to the Republican Party's political assessor and sees this as a price for holding office. He also expresses concern over the financial situation of his son Ned and his brother Miraud. Financial worries increase during the tight money year of 1884 and come to a head after the election of Democrat Grover Cleveland and Saxton's subsequent demotion and dismissal from office. Volumes 62 and 63 (1885-1886) relate Saxton's fight to save his position, including an interview with the president, while volumes 64-68 (1886-1888) record his temporary residence in Louisville, Kentucky, once again on the staff of his brother Rufus, but separated from his family.</p>
               <p>Saxton's fortunes change with the election of a Republican president in 1888. By August, 1889 he is returned to the office of clerk in the First Comptroller's Office. The journal is once again filled with details of domestic life, the education and marriage of daughters, and the boarders that help the family budget. Numerous concerts and plays are recorded, as are meetings of the Loyal Legion and encampments of the G.A.R. Following a Democratic victory in the 1892 presidential elections, Saxton was able to retain his position, but the Financial Panic of 1893 and a reorganization of the Treasury Department in 1894 led to continuing financial hardships, which are enumerated in the journal. The journals for 1894 through 1896 also document the progressive deterioration of daughter Mattie's health and her unsuccessful pursuit of treatment for consumption in North Carolina and Saranac Lake, New York.</p>
               <p>The volumes of journals for the late 1890s include some discussion of the inequities the civil service system, but by 1898 Saxton is able to pay off his debts and to write of his enjoyment of travels, cultural events, and summer visits to his daughter Minnie Seward at Sachem's Head, Connecticut. He notes all productions at the New National Theater, seeing performances by Lily Langtry, G.A.R. meetings, and attending women's suffrage meetings.</p>
               <p>There is a large gap in the journals between 1901 and 1913; volumes 101 through 135 are missing from the papers. By 1913 S. Willard Saxton was 84 but his journal continues to chronicle a daily routine of walks to work, hours in the office, and summers spent in New England. In 1915 Saxton records a trip by himself through the West, and the 1921 journal describes a 60th anniversary trip to Atlantic City. The journals follow the lives of Saxton's children and grandchildren, and volumes 136 to 139 (1913-1915) also note the decline and death of Saxton's daughter Beth. Cultural activities recorded include plays at the Belasco; performances by the Marx brothers; and concerts by Mischa Elman, Enrico Caruso, Walter Damrosch, Leopold Stokowski, and Jascha Heifetz. Saxton also notes his participation in events at All Souls Church, hearing Billy Sunday preach, and meetings of the Loyal Legion and the Association of Oldest Inhabitants of the District of Columbia. There is no indication as to why Saxton quit making entries in the journal after May, 1927. At the time, he was 98 years old. He does not complain of failing health and he writes in the same legible hand.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <arrangement id="aspace_30b4868d22b49e279c5dcc827674c3c0">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>This series is arranged by volume number from 1 to 172. The volumes are in chronological order. Volumes 42 and 101-136 are not included in the papers.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Saxton, S. Willard</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref24" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1847 June 26 - 1849 March 11; 1849 September 1 - 1853 May 19</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215233)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_d2a33fc458add1365998354b8bdfbe40"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c8aab1e07f5ee6912b5562cea2f6cb1c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d2a33fc458add1365998354b8bdfbe40">8-16</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref25" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1853 May 25 - 1854 April 9; 1854 May 10 - 1858 June 5</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215241)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_8935f261e45633b535530189dc8531aa"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_30cb015ff6c7fd331c8191c3f916fcba"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8935f261e45633b535530189dc8531aa">17-22</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref26" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1858 June 6 - 1861 April 4</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215258)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_a6c44da92698703d085855e9c5a13719"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_46fb0b90263f28ba029a379ba52489c5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a6c44da92698703d085855e9c5a13719">23-28</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref27" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1861 April 5 - 1863 November 10; 1864 March 5 - 1867 July 20</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215266)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_ab6b4c6d3196392d25b8ea68697a1ec1"
                                type="box">6</container>
                     <container id="aspace_dc4cd8e7e2d45c15458024b9a202cf79"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ab6b4c6d3196392d25b8ea68697a1ec1">29-34</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref28" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1867 July 21 - 1871 January 31</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215274)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_90dbb05bd8d94779fd24dbda46d18109"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_829093d3c97c6ef7b24210df3c62536e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_90dbb05bd8d94779fd24dbda46d18109">35-41</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref29" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1871 February 1 - 1872 June 22; 1872 November 1 - 1873 August 25</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215282)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_30954adf90cecb96e4d2f66eccef6213"
                                type="box">8</container>
                     <container id="aspace_690448464d56452e10f67e31a4b1a2d0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_30954adf90cecb96e4d2f66eccef6213">42-47</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref30" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1874 February 25 - 1877 June 7</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215290)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_08535b8b692df524b0ecf07a27942a61"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b0d3ba8adbde3904c210ce08ccf3238d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_08535b8b692df524b0ecf07a27942a61">48-52</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref31" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1877 June 8 - 1880 July 4</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215308)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_65e1eedaec92f370d99c4171762aed76"
                                type="box">10</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e879210ffbaea7605290475621c5cce0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_65e1eedaec92f370d99c4171762aed76">53-58</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref32" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1880 July 5 - 1883 September 19</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215316)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_ca99b6caeb0793ac10afa20b9e8d0587"
                                type="box">11</container>
                     <container id="aspace_442b0e3b19faec8134d2738d9b109154"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ca99b6caeb0793ac10afa20b9e8d0587">59-64</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref33" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1883 September 20 - 1887 March 28</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215324)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_52f0f56ddc4de15ae07583872102c3d3"
                                type="box">12</container>
                     <container id="aspace_12fc9110228ee67217e5faa9d1ff2690"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_52f0f56ddc4de15ae07583872102c3d3">65-69</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref34" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1887 March 29 - 1889 December 24</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215332)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_fe28566256593d53a91558627c9a663b"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0cc8066ac0066c535dcc43e36ab271de"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_fe28566256593d53a91558627c9a663b">70-75</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref35" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1889 December 25 - 1892 August 23</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215340)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_d4e370fe84f2dcac3fd879a50e11521b"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b4eb5b64567b222f1cf2a2df4ddf2ed3"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d4e370fe84f2dcac3fd879a50e11521b">76-83</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref36" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1892 August 24 - 1895 August 10</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215357)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_96ba8915d1a8b205eb36b76116f6fc66"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_670c78548cb565e84a7a3f00e7b47042"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_96ba8915d1a8b205eb36b76116f6fc66">84-90</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref37" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1895 August 11 - 1896 December 13; 1897 May 1 - 1898 January 21</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215365)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_7c4ec221e1f079a9ce08403eef0fa8e6"
                                type="box">16</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b64061d25df9765c4102227859f112c8"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7c4ec221e1f079a9ce08403eef0fa8e6">91-96</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref38" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1898 January 22 - 1900 January 22</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215373)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_3c6526a47eb1d20fb68bf4c89e2dd179"
                                type="box">17</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3751f66e9a65941c319ab46f6c1d355b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_3c6526a47eb1d20fb68bf4c89e2dd179">97-102</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref39" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1900 January 23 - 1901 March 201; 1913 October 9 - 1915 July 9</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215381)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_5e395d4749a9a4b158f8619c32316d63"
                                type="box">18</container>
                     <container id="aspace_42f853ba67a11a34b848de1947e9ae30"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_5e395d4749a9a4b158f8619c32316d63">103-108</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref40" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1915 July 11 - 1918 August 17</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215399)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_618f7544ec0e9eccc977d2c7d883cc1f"
                                type="box">19</container>
                     <container id="aspace_71f186d9257905085424396b27ef7d1c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_618f7544ec0e9eccc977d2c7d883cc1f">109-113</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref41" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1918 August 18 - 1922 April 26</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215407)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_f2d61196de6a98b11ede49741d42829c"
                                type="box">20</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6d417aaa76bed9bc00564746e6ae3805"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f2d61196de6a98b11ede49741d42829c">114-119</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref42" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1922 April 27 - 1927 May 8</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215415)"
                                altrender="archive letter"
                                id="aspace_513e382b14cc36aed1a7ca0944cdfd45"
                                type="box">21</container>
                     <container id="aspace_36ce370bddd33599ba307116434c3d36"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_513e382b14cc36aed1a7ca0944cdfd45">120-124</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref45" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Personal papers</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1849-1934</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_437332a90648b443ab2576e33246d2f5">1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)</physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ce472f303f6ddba66a2be5e939b40075">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>This series includes personal papers of both Rufus and S. Willard Saxton, including reminiscences, clippings, photographs, and printed material. The reminiscences highlight important periods in the lives of both men, including Rufus's Civil War service and S. Willard's years at Brook Farm. Photographs include portraits of both Saxtons and photographs of Civil War Beaufort, South Carolina. Some pictures depict Blacks in their freedom schools. The album of pictures in folder 140 is stamped "Stebbins A. Smith, M.D. Charleston S.C.," but it probably belonged to S. Willard Saxton. It contains nearly two hundred photographs, which depict the Saxtons and their wives, Union military officers, friends of S. Willard Saxton, portraits of women's suffrage leaders, and vacation travel. Folder 137 contains bound volumes of papers presented to Loyal Legion meetings and folder 138 contains a partial index to the volumes. Folder 138 also includes items of Saxton's father and a letter by Thomas Wentworth Higginson to Rufus Saxton's wife.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <arrangement id="aspace_836d6fce408ab94fdf23c30009a19350">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>Material in this series is arranged by name of the creator of the papers and by record type.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c id="ref47" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Saxton, Rufus</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref48" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Biographical data</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_37b677e2d140df18ae905d3ca6162822"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3347ef67413870c6c6b0e0dd426b414c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_37b677e2d140df18ae905d3ca6162822">125</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref49" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Memorabilia</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1849-1904</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_2e748ba126bb3f853ed51960f5bdd1c4"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_649fb6f88115a043e178e0c526282e8f"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2e748ba126bb3f853ed51960f5bdd1c4">126</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref50" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"Reminiscences of a Quartermaster"</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_87bb04b606637143123c6d932d57b316"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1e9ed98e544a87658c12c204e9043142"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_87bb04b606637143123c6d932d57b316">127</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref51" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Saxton, S. Willard</unittitle>
               </did>
               <odd id="aspace_a0bd8629c4d04e87e7b04660a88b8f90">
                  <head>General</head>
                  <p>See also: <ref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="replace" target="ref16">box 2, folder 5</ref>
                  </p>
               </odd>
               <c id="ref53" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Biographical data</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1934</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_de747f19e70a261d349d89fe51c06f63"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b8725e2f5879429549d74f3c387a3bd2"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_de747f19e70a261d349d89fe51c06f63">128</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref54" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"Reminiscences of Brook Farm"</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Circa 1915</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_66b438c35b2fa948884da9611e6e9cfd"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3350c9afdaa849050c73d1f48ee6c4bc"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_66b438c35b2fa948884da9611e6e9cfd">129</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref55" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Report of a Committee Appointed to Count the Cash in the Treasurer's Office</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1869</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_d24b31a7df1103291ec238cceea697f1"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e41684a0ecf401160d52fda0e8625811"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d24b31a7df1103291ec238cceea697f1">130</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref56" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"A Trip to Santa Fe, New Mexico"</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1871</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_baf8c217ca34f72dce87fab35d1bb6ea"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_fc6bb9b1fe9e194922906a46a7de9823"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_baf8c217ca34f72dce87fab35d1bb6ea">131</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref57" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref58" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1866-circa 1920s</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_2c5dfc5dd2560bd947485554f7e721df"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_24a1da62d597828ccac6df002c8e3251"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2c5dfc5dd2560bd947485554f7e721df">132</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref59" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Papers</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1867-1925</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_9ea7bc873791f1082a11b55398fdf953"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_45e33feb0e3d2fa79598b15918fd7de5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_9ea7bc873791f1082a11b55398fdf953">133</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref60" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                  </did>
                  <odd id="aspace_d3e5550b601f05c62e6e8c89566d45ef">
                     <head>General</head>
                     <p>See also: <ref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="replace" target="ref65">Box 23, folder 139</ref>
                     </p>
                  </odd>
                  <c id="ref61" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>General</unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">Circa 1860s-1890s</unitdate>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                   altrender="archive legal"
                                   id="aspace_f90c1ba5c3c2e7f1756c98e59cbd2c30"
                                   type="box">22</container>
                        <container id="aspace_a3f2c84e0c57b6c0d7c48e0bbe854e8f"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_f90c1ba5c3c2e7f1756c98e59cbd2c30">134-135</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
                  <c id="ref62" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Daguerreotype of Beaufort, South Carolina home, "Boardwalk to bath house"</unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive">Circa 1860s</unitdate>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002112358735)"
                                   altrender="Flip top"
                                   id="aspace_b55700cd0c3fdb9dcc2ab98dbe7fd47c"
                                   type="box">22A</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
               </c>
               <c id="ref63" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Volumes: <title render="italic">
                           Military Order of the Loyal Legion
                        </title>
                     </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1887-1910</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_ba7d5a363cf226c12dab38659ef185a7"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_efad37a25352edaa7baa9bb95b0f6fb4"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ba7d5a363cf226c12dab38659ef185a7">137</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref64" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellanea</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1853-1909</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002038215423)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_7bcdab5c3c988ae0c912f02a7dcda145"
                                type="box">22</container>
                     <container id="aspace_bd6c8c4346706e01c595cbadcaf0417d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7bcdab5c3c988ae0c912f02a7dcda145">138</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref65" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Scrapbook, includes photographs</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Circa 1860s</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042583089)"
                                altrender="flat box (12d 3h 15w)"
                                id="aspace_40315c9fc039f9c0fe76b9e6d3abc718"
                                type="box">23</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a5aa78fc2b5d233074dbfbbe5e1be0c2"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_40315c9fc039f9c0fe76b9e6d3abc718">139</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref66" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Photograph album with label: "Stebbins A. Smith, M.D., Charleston, S.C."</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1866-circa 1890s</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042583071)"
                                altrender="flat box (12d 3h 15w)"
                                id="aspace_dacc46295a57584ee1b19e823a5ce7b7"
                                type="box">24</container>
                     <container id="aspace_102e773df5b66e7c8078dc743b0fcc5a"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_dacc46295a57584ee1b19e823a5ce7b7">140</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref72" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Additional material</unittitle>
               <unitid>Accession 2013-M-039</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1903-1906</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6d3dfd02849ef8ecb77b60844be083b9">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>This accession includes volumes 107-114 of S. Willard Saxton's journals. There are newspaper clippings inserted between the pages of most of the journals.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref73" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Journals of S. Willard Saxton</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1903 March 11-1906 August 9</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002112589156)"
                             altrender="archive legal"
                             id="aspace_e2e51aeeca2caf40cd17e896e0a2531e"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4cd63b7948485569b4b1bbc9e93cf709"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e2e51aeeca2caf40cd17e896e0a2531e">1-7</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
