<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.1400">mssa.ms.1400</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Henry Phelps Johnston Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Johnston (Henry Phelps) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Diane Kaplan and John Espy</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>April 1986</date>
            <num>MS 1400</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Thursday January 10, 2019 at 10:51</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules/>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Henry Phelps Johnston papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 1400</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">0.25</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(1 box)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1858/1882">1858-1882</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_d02c1f024c374414ab625f623090962d">The papers consist of correspondence, a diary, printed material, and miscellaneous papers documenting the Civil War activities of Henry Phelps Johnston.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50040314"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               Johnston, Henry Phelps, 1842-1923
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <prefercite id="aspace_e880d8fefd7ee2652fce524d50b36ea1">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Henry Phelps Johnston Papers (MS 1400), Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_c29c31d1abcce5d79a551caa2a13cdb1">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Henry Phelps Johnston Papers include correspondence, a diary, printed material, and miscellaneous papers of Henry Phelps Johnston. The earliest papers date from Johnston's freshman year at Yale, but the bulk of the material documents Johnston's military service during the Civil War with the 15th Connecticut Volunteers and the Signal Corps. Johnston wrote regularly to his mother and sisters, and his letters in 1862 and 1863 describe the daily routine of camp life in Virginia. Letters from 1864 and 1865, after Johnston was promoted to a second lieutenancy, portray encounters with rebel troops in North Carolina and a meeting with his brother Frontis, a preacher in Lexington, North Carolina. A field dary (folder 7) documents Johnston's movements at the end of the war and his return to New Haven. Letters to Johnston's father (folder 4) describe his teaching position at the College of the City of New York. Johnston's incoming correspondence includes letters from Yale classmates: Frederic Adams, Melville Cox Day, Daniel Henry Chamberlain, Merritt Cicero Page, and Henry Hamlin Stebbins. Classmates relay information about friends, Yale activities, and their own career choices. There are also letter from Johnston's father, written from Mississippi.</p>
         <p>The papers were donated to the Yale Library by Henry S. Johnston in 1942 and 1943. Related papers of Johnston's mother and sisters will be found in the Johnston-Walker Family Papers, MS 949.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_9b69291e6e3a1a831465d55dc2fde70d">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <bioghist id="aspace_3667819429ed2393f319dfcef6ae908e">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Henry Phelps Johnston, B.A. 1862.</p>
         <p>Born April 19, 1842, in Trebizond, Turkey.</p>
         <p>Died February 28, 1923, in Middletown, Conn.</p>
         <p>Henry Phelps Johnston was born April 19, 1842, at Trebizond, Turkey, where his parents were stationed as missionaries of the American Board. His father, the Rev. Thomas Pinckney Johnston, was the son of William Smiley and Mary Hall Johnston, and a descendant of Robert Johnston, who lived in Iredell County, N.C. After coming to this country from Scotland. He was graduated from the University of North Carolina with the degree of B.A. In 1828. His wife was Marianne Cassandra Howe, daughter of Curtis Howe and Sibble Phelps. She traced her ancestry to John Howe, who came to Swanton, Vt., from London in 1650. The Rev. Thomas Buckingham, who was one of the founders of Yale, was another ancestor of Henry P. Johnston.</p>
         <p>The latter received his prepatory training at the Hopkins Grammar School in New Haven, where his mother then resided. In his Sophomore year at Yale he was awarded a second prize in English composition and a second prize for excellence in declamation. He was the first president of Brothers in Unity in his Senior year.</p>
         <p>In August, 1862, he enlisted in the 15th Connecticut Volunteers. He was made an Orderly Sergeant shortly afterwards and was subsequently promoted to the rank of Second Lieutenant. He served throughout the Civil War, mainly in Virginia and North Carolina. He was in the battle fo Fredericksburg in 1862 and at the siege of Suffolk in 1863, and took part in Dix's expedition toward Richmond. He was in the battle near Kingston, N.C., in 1865, after which he marched north with Sherman's Army. During the last year of the war he was transferred to the Signal Corps. At the time when he was given his discharge in July, 1865, he was on the staff of Major General William B. Hazen. He attended the Yale School of Law from 1865 to 1867 and then went to New York City, where he practiced independently for a short time after his admission to the bar. Until 1868 he also taught at a school at Washington Heights, New York City. He was then engaged in newspaper work for some years, being connected at various times with the New York sun, the Times, and the Christian Union (now the Outlook), and holding the position of assistant editor fo the New York Observer during 1878-79. During this period he also devoted much time to the study of American history, which led to original investigations and the writing of a number of monographs on historical subjects. In December, 1897, he became instructor in history at the College of the City of New York, with which institution he was actively connected until 1916. He was made head of the department of history in 1883, and held that position until September 1, 1916, when he became professor emeritus. Through his efforts a large and valuable collection of manuscripts, maps, relics, etc., was acquired for the History Museum of the college, of which he was curator from 1902 to 1916. In 1912 a portrait of him was presented to the College by its alumni. Yale conferred the honorary degree of M.A. Upton Professor Johnston in 1889. His monographs on American history include: <title render="italic">
               The Campaign of 1776 around New York and Brooklyn
            </title>, <title render="italic">
               Observations on Judge Jones' Loyalist History of the American Revolution
            </title>, <title render="italic">
               The Yorktown Campaign
            </title>, <title render="italic">
               Yale in the Revolution
            </title>, <title render="italic">
               Connecticut in the Revolution
            </title>, <title render="italic">
               Correspondence and Published Papers of John Jay
            </title>, <title render="italic">
               The Battle of Harlet Heights, September 16, 1776
            </title>, <title render="italic">
               The Origin and Development of Popular Government in America
            </title>, <title render="italic">
               The Storming of Stony Point on the Hudson
            </title>, and <title render="italic">
               Nathan Hale, 1776
            </title>. This last work first appeared in 1901; in 1914 a revised and enlarged edition was published by the Yale University Press. Professor Johnston was associate editor of the <title render="italic">
               Magazine of American History
            </title> in 1882. He had lectured frequently and delivered many addresses on historical subjects. He was a member of the New York and Connecticut Historical societies and of the Worcester Antiquarian Society.</p>
         <p>He died at the Middlesex Hospital in Middletown, Conn., February 28, 1923, from pneumonia. Interment was in Hadlyme, where he had been living since 1917.</p>
         <p>He was married October 26, 1871, in Cleveland, Ohio, to Elizabeth Kirtland, daughter of Joseph and Maria (Selden) Holmes, who survives him with three of their four sons, Henry Selden, '96, John Holmes, '99 S., and Donald Kent, '03. Their eldest son, Thomas Pinckney, died in childhood. Professor Johnston was a brother of William C. Johnston, '60, and an uncle of James Walker, '94 S., and Curtis H. Walker, '99.</p>
         <p>-<title render="italic">
               Yale University Obituary Record
            </title>, No.22, 1923, pp. 627-29</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <userestrict id="aspace_47b9ba95efa7d32ac12b0b5986c1663d">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator(s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140205"
                   source="lcsh">
            United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
         </geogname>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027112" source="aat">
            Diaries
         </genreform>
         <occupation source="local">
            Soldiers
         </occupation>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50040314"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Johnston, Henry Phelps, 1842-1923
         </persname>
         <famname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85070634"
                  source="lcsh">
            Johnston family
         </famname>
         <famname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85144895"
                  source="lcsh">
            Walker family
         </famname>
         <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">
            United States. Army. Connecticut Volunteers, 15th (1861-1865)
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2004042123"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1862
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref9" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1861-65, 1869, 1879-82</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                             altrender="archive half legal"
                             id="aspace_f1b04cd30ec1d534c496bb1f745a044d"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e9e97c230742ec5e040a2c8570226509"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_f1b04cd30ec1d534c496bb1f745a044d">1 - 4</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Incoming Correspondence</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref12" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Adams, Frederic</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1863-67</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_9b18d752b6048dca4c067e7b5e8ddc38"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d5bf5d1695c1e3a2ae599c096bbb7601"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_9b18d752b6048dca4c067e7b5e8ddc38">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref13" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Chamberlain, Daniel Henry</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1863</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_6aee7af30c47a4ed47f4c62bdc0e740a"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ac84793e05d9b37fa64764595a1072aa"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6aee7af30c47a4ed47f4c62bdc0e740a">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref14" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Day, Melville Cox</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1863, 1866</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_d398378ea47d0259b6a285eb3f3fb992"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_219bd281f73c42585f25ce7f4c2adc4c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d398378ea47d0259b6a285eb3f3fb992">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref15" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Johnston, Thomas Pinckney</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-65</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_1aa107c1f5514a62bf2bb54e809995fd"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ed3b7f0674f5daddf0b234fa93daaa1c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1aa107c1f5514a62bf2bb54e809995fd">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref16" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Johnston, William Curtis</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1861</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_30e10ca94d98817e17be91ee8a40fa08"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_11cee35106c1c4f1ccfc4e21c3d5be96"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_30e10ca94d98817e17be91ee8a40fa08">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref17" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Morse, Richard Cary</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1863-64, undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_9cbc4554e09900e5aef77b9b2d4f10f9"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f78115646cab31e98294b6e844c59565"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_9cbc4554e09900e5aef77b9b2d4f10f9">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref18" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Page, Merritt Cicero</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1863-64</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_fd3d6d85bb4a1bab3fce26eae29dcc2e"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8a0d0f8fa47442b10db5c14c2c7f9608"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_fd3d6d85bb4a1bab3fce26eae29dcc2e">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref19" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Stebbins, Henry Hamlin</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1863-65</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_ac6776ef8ee72f503a8e4260bc869b5b"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4f8bfb65dddd4109a0eadcb0630c73f2"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ac6776ef8ee72f503a8e4260bc869b5b">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref20" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Yale College</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1858</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_a1f9d304df6a540858b2788b4a2f3545"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_20b7f6fc22af9d1eac122e22e90eed79"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a1f9d304df6a540858b2788b4a2f3545">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref21" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Unidentified</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_2f08dfaa4350051676fd1e85333f3fdc"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_bf0491c93f447f71ee343c50d2db21b4"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2f08dfaa4350051676fd1e85333f3fdc">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Field Diary</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1865</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                             altrender="archive half legal"
                             id="aspace_66829e11be124849c567433c60c23a19"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_600f076c54e858f0817a32954a455068"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_66829e11be124849c567433c60c23a19">7</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed volume, <title render="italic">
                        Soldier's Hymns
                     </title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                             altrender="archive half legal"
                             id="aspace_3f0b04c273c3f65769a8b8f926f3c4b6"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_934094cd8780af976b4eaf601de5ec79"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_3f0b04c273c3f65769a8b8f926f3c4b6">7</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous Civil War papers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-65</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002042342262)"
                             altrender="archive half legal"
                             id="aspace_7a3061db8b2ebb93ac977e49665c3778"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f187e9b94eded98ac47397074cd863f3"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_7a3061db8b2ebb93ac977e49665c3778">7</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
