<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.1777">mssa.ms.1777</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Spain Collection
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Spain Collection</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Pedro Guibovich, Philip S. MacLeod, and Christine Weideman</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>October 2001</date>
            <num>MS 1777</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Saturday December  8, 2018 at 11:04</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Spain collection</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 1777</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
    
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">7.5</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(16 boxes)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1400/1891">1400-1891</unitdate>
         
         
            <unitdate type="bulk" normal="1600/1699">1600-1699</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_ce552411f53f3163b07b71b70d7ec613">A collection of correspondence; government documents, including reports, commissions, decrees, and awards; church documents; and writings and poems from Spain on civil, military, economic, religious, and social topics.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_16be6dd71bffe3875d9ab144bf4771e3">
            <language>The collection is in Spanish.</language>
         </langmaterial>
    
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_85990606be451ede449974a1557fb1ef">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Materials have been assembled from various collections and acquired from several individuals. They include materials transferred from the Latin American Collection Curator, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_84e0bd7248d1437c30ac27865c155906">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>
         <p>The entire collection is available on microfilm. Patrons must use FILM HM 249 instead of the originals.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_9670522edb1f64024bb183bc001bc713">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Copyright status for collection materials is unknown, though much of the material in this collection is likely in the public domain. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_7ec5666cb53c295d0ad1798bc7fbb701">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Spain Collection (MS 1777). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <altformavail id="aspace_960985fe2eb718320901bc0a7a134b32">
         <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
         <p>Entire collection is available on microfilm from Gale Group, Farmington Hills, Michigan.</p>  
      </altformavail>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_c06c82098a03cc1cc5d29499fbbb64bb">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>A collection of correspondence; government documents, including reports, commissions, decrees, and awards; church documents; and writings and poems from Spain on civil, military, economic, religious, and social topics.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_be087ebc29c01e23a2cb3300dbefd7c2">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The collection is arranged in two parts: materials in each part are arranged by date.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85084579"
                   source="lcsh">
            Mexico -- History -- Wars of Independence, 1810-1821
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85125532"
                   source="lcsh">
            South America -- History -- Wars of Independence, 1806-1830
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126033"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- Church history
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh89004112"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- Colonies
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126083"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Bourbons, 1700-
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126086"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Charles III, 1759-1788
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126087"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Charles IV, 1788-1808
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126085"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Ferdinand VI, 1746-1759
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126090"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Ferdinand VII, 1813-1833
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126077"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- House of Austria, 1516-1700
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126089"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Napoleonic Conquest, 1808-1813
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126079"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Philip III, 1598-1621
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126080"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Philip IV, 1621-1665
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126082"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Philip V, 1700-1746
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85126092"
                   source="lcsh">
            Spain -- History -- Revolution, 1820-1823
         </geogname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81144554"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Ayala, Manuel José de, 1728-1805
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85265678"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Campillo y Cosío, José del, 1693-1743
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85321979"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            González de Cellorigo, Martín
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79135397"
                   source="naf">
            Jovellanos, Gaspar de, 1744-1811
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82102940"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="local">
            Olivares, Gaspar de Guzmán, conde-duque de, 1587-1645
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80152710"
                   source="naf">
            Pérez, Antonio, -1611
         </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref10" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Original accession</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Part I</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1400-1768</unitdate>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6f3d83fbcc163dd7ee8915c555ead4e1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Part I is 4.5 linear feet; the majority is comprised of both originals and copies of materials from Spain. The collection includes state documents such as decrees, ordinances and reports; ecclesiastical texts; correspondence; accounts of events; political writings; and literary texts. They cover a broad period of Spanish history, from the beginning of the fifteenth century to the middle of the eighteenth century. The texts document important events and aspects of the reigns of Philip III, Philip IV, Philip V, Ferdinand VI and Charles III.</p>
                  <p>On the reign of King Philip III (1598-1621), the collection includes letters by the Duke of Lerma, the powerful private secretary (privado) to the king; documents related to state loans; and memorials. Memorials constitute outstanding sources for studying the political, social and economic conditions of the Spanish monarchy in the two first decades of the seventeenth century. Although a long tradition of writing memorials existed in Spain, Philip III's reign was particularly rich in the composition of such texts. They addressed such issues as the origin of the "decadence" of Spain, and important political and economic problems and their solutions. There are also texts on the conduct of foreign policy by Antonio Pérez; royal policy towards Portuguese "conversos" by Martín González de Cellorigo; and the duties of the king's private secretary (privado) by Pedro Maldonado. The education of the young King Phillip III was an important issue during his reign. The "Empresas," by Juan de Mora, a book written to instruct the king on moral and political principles necessary for ruling, is beautifully illustrated with numerous drawings and is a splendid example of Spanish emblematic literature.</p>
                  <p>Documents on the reign of King Philip IV (1621-1665) are the most numerous of the collection. The main political and social events of that period, including the death of King Philip III; the political downfall of three major figures of the reign of King Philip III: the duke of Lerma, the duke of Osuna, and the marquis of Siete Iglesias; the ceremonies proclaiming Philip IV of Spain; the political career of the duke of Olivares, the private secretary (privado) of the king; the plan for a matrimonial alliance between Spain and England; the economic efforts of the Spanish crown to finance its participation in the Thirty Years War; the Castilian monetary reforms; the Spanish intervention in the Netherlands war; and the political relations between the Spanish crown and its Italian allies in Milan, are described in handwritten and printed texts.</p>
                  <p>Important aspects of the history of the reigns of three Bourbon monarchs, Philip V (1700-1746), Ferdinand VI (1746-1759) and Charles III (1559-1788) are also documented in the collection. With no direct descendants, King Charles II named Philip, Duke of Anjou, a grandson of King Louis XIV of France, as his successor. The election of a French prince was not recognized by other European states, which had potential candidates of their own for the Spanish throne and were concerned about the expansion of French power on the continent. The war of the Spanish Succession and the efforts of Philip to consolidate his rule are illustrated in an extensive account of the period from 1712 to 1725, entitled "History of the reign of King Philip V of Spain," and in other documents. Once the war was concluded, Philip started an ambitious program to reform the social, political and economic structures of the Spanish monarchy. The so-called "Bourbon Reforms" encouraged crown ministers and other citizens to develop and write projects and plans to encourage the social and economic development of Spain and its empire. Interesting examples of such writings are: "España despierta" and "Nuevo sistema de gobierno económico para la América," by José del Campillo y Cosio, a famous minister of Philip V.</p>
                  <p>The Bourbon Reforms were continued by Philip V's successors, Ferdinand VI and Charles III. Additional informative examples of reform plans and projects, from the reign of Ferdinand VI, include "Reflexiones ...sobre los medios que se pueden tomar para el fomento de fábricas de todas especies y del comercio interno y externo de España" by Juan Casaus, and "Proyecto...para fomento del comercio, agricultura y fábricas de estos reinos" by Francisco Pavia. There are also various documents on tax reform during Ferdinand's reign, and on the relationship between the Inquisition and local powers. Of particular note regarding Charles III's reign (1759-1788) is "Aniceto a Cándido," a discourse on the need to reform Spain; and an extensive "Memorial," addressed to the king, on the long controversy between the Society of Jesus and prelates and secular clergy over the payment of tithes. In addition, there are documents on the crown's attempt to exercise tight control over the Spanish Catholic Church.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c id="ref12" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal grant. Place: Valladolid. Description: Copy of a royal grant by Henry III, king of Castile, to the village of Balmaceda. Needing funds for the war against Portugal, the king had given his treasurer, Juan de Herrera, lordship over Balmaceda. In turn, Herrera had paid 15,000 florins to the king. In this grant, Henry III granted 7,500 florins to Balmaceda to be used by the village in its attempt to buy out Herrera. With this grant, the king expected that the village could obtain its freedom from the dominion of Herrera, and become part of the royal patrimony. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1400 June 30</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a3008c8a43e6afc44af221c3564a532f"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d8e86a8a5302dd9ab225eb2023ced931"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a3008c8a43e6afc44af221c3564a532f">1</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_1405cfdced605d7f46a3aa311b289b15"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref13" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Copia de las capitulaciones que se hizieron entre el ... Rey don Felipe Segundo con el conde de San Segundo." Place: Hampton Court. Description: Printed copy of a text containing the agreements (capitulaciones) between Gómez Suarez de Figueroa, general lieutenant of Milan, and Troilo de Rossi, count of San Segundo. In this document, Gómez Suares granted military protection, tax exemptions, and commercial privileges to Troilo de Rossi, a Milan noble. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1555 June 20</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f20afca71f16f28d96b14dd7bc7db78f"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_deae510c4a247625b0c6bcf05dc5d85c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f20afca71f16f28d96b14dd7bc7db78f">2</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_62173a2a472a5d6b951aa25d0a4cf811"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref14" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Sotomayor, Agustín de. Title: Texts. Place: Spain. Description: A Spanish mineralogist, Agustín de Sotomayor lived in Mexico for some years, and returned to Spain in 1574. In Spain, he explored mines by royal commission, and made experiments for the extraction of minerals. This volume contains an original and copies (in English) of texts by Agustín de Sotomayor: "Benefiçios de metales de plata" (handwritten and signed by author), "Translation of extracts from Noticia histórica documentada de las célebres minas de Guadalcanal," and "A Letter from Augustin de Sotomayor to his majesty upon the method to be followed in the discovery of mines and the manner of working them." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1555-1573</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_88f32eb4f7cb4cb8f0e8dad494a1e28e"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_49647dac0804306941d9d93ebbba0733"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_88f32eb4f7cb4cb8f0e8dad494a1e28e">3</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_e72d71a9a412871d85167cc229cf83f1"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref15" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Memorial que el cardenal don Francisco de Mendoza y Bobadilla dio al rey Phelipe 2 sobre la deçendençia de las casas más prinçipales de España." Description: Copy of an extensive report by Cardinal Francisco de Mendoza y Bobadilla, bishop of Burgos, to King Philip II of Spain, about the origins of Spanish noble families. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1560 November</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_4af43b0ace5abab0bb254146686191db"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9818c77edddcc2b36b56fb3426eb9baa"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_4af43b0ace5abab0bb254146686191db">4</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_6ade1fb6ad9fad3cc6e8165a1cdc0244"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref16" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by King Philip II. Place: Madrid. Description: Letter by King Philip II to the count of Santa Gadea, adelantado of Castile and general captain of galleys on the Andalucian coasts. In this letter, the king asked the count to obtain more news about an attack the British fleet was preparing against Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1588 January 28</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_e91e80d2606bcd3dab0dd5628d0b9f96"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3468ef40bf8c74813c44b5b7a6f14665"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e91e80d2606bcd3dab0dd5628d0b9f96">5</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_957b309a10a222c6f141f1c60b752e0e"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref17" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: García, Pablo? Title: "Modo de procesar en el Tribunal de la Santa Inquisición." Description: Book containing a copy of the ordinances to be followed by Spanish Inquisition tribunals in judicial proceedings. Includes detailed instructions on how to conduct interrogatories and torments, and issue sentences and edicts. Includes an index by subject. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Circa1591</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_1afdca46195c8e36e3d17a960707f384"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_cb2cc7665f7e37f5f2421bd6211f028b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1afdca46195c8e36e3d17a960707f384">6</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_b7eecbf623a25fddd155c94c09ee9d29"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref18" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Consult by the Council of Italy. Place: Madrid? Description: Consult by the council of Italy, addressed to King Philip II, on the state of Milan, a Spanish dominion in Italy. In this document, the council of Italy proposed different reforms for the political and economic government of that territory. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1597 December 10</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f75e625220b3d0d56bd0ce78299aa787"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5e1effb52fb11444d8e4fe86bf8c4da7"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f75e625220b3d0d56bd0ce78299aa787">7</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_6d2cdb8a8d2a98fd86e6066914c11e45"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref19" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal decree. Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copy of a royal decree by Prince Philip (future King Philip III) ordering the creation of a general militia for the defense of Spain. Details the composition, duties and privileges of the members of the militia. The document includes the authorization (licencia) by the count of Puñonrostro to Lázaro de Hojeda for printing the royal decree for one month. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1598 January 25</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_78843f02e4f5d8ef49ae27c5eaf9c822"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_64c36b58de5d61f15810a568afae3fc4"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_78843f02e4f5d8ef49ae27c5eaf9c822">8</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_1d48481d81727745f5549b388aea82a4"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref20" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Pérez, Antonio. Title: "El conocimiento de las naciones." Description: Antonio Pérez was secretary to King Philip II and one of the most controversial political figures in the second half of the sixteenth century in Spain. In this extensive copy of a memorial written from his exile, Pérez advises the young King Philip III how to rule the dominions of the Spanish monarchy in Europe and America, and how to conduct foreign policy with France, the Turkish Empire, the Italian states, and the Papal state. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1598 October 28</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_c1803e21fe22abbd3f7861ac80053083"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_abd0f343e7d01053f1f20126d6a3d7df"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c1803e21fe22abbd3f7861ac80053083">9</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_f54b2ce0b356fa55480c55f96fd5e81c"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref21" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Legal writ. Place: Spain. Description: Copy of a legal writ related to the judicial proceedings of Alvaro de Ulloa, as agent of the minors Alvaro and Teresa de Ulloa, citizens of Caceres, against García de Loayza, dean of the Cathedral of Plasencia, over the payment of a quit-rent (censo.)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[15--]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_1f15dc4824056d2151a788d6b8d5776a"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6cbec181bf878443bb49ff3860c724fa"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1f15dc4824056d2151a788d6b8d5776a">10</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_472e8583f0432367a11e9b7aa15d6854"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref22" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents related to Margaret of Austria, Queen of Spain. Places: Valladolid, San Lorenzo. Description: Printed and handwritten copies of five documents related to the testament of the Margaret of Austria, Queen of Spain. Includes: "Facultad que el rey nuestro señor dio a su magestad de la reyna, que esté en el cielo, para testar de dozientos mil ducados" (4 September 1601); "Cláusula del testamento de la reyna nuestra señora en favor del Colegio de la Compañía de Jesús de Salamanca" (n.d.); "Copia del codicilio que hizo la reyna nuestra señora" (n.d.); "Juramento del Padre Ricardo Haller sobre el codicilio de la reyna nuestra señora que aya gloria" (13 October 1611); "La reyna nuestra señora, que esté en el cielo, su testamento" </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">(undated) 1601-1611</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_7578e69f71265fd082d2822b2158f0ef"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_87e01c729d3df0f7cae01b1a08202119"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7578e69f71265fd082d2822b2158f0ef">11</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_b55fe27a70861f249db905ec837bad17"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref23" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Possesión que la magetad del rey nuestro señor don Phelipe Terzero tomó de el canonicato y prebenda de esta santa yglesia de León." Place: Leon. Description: In recognition of his victory over the Muslims in the battle of Clavijo, the pope had granted to King Ramiro I and his successors the possession of an ecclesiastical canonry at the cathedral of Leon. This text is an account of the ceremony at which King Philip III assumed title to the canonry on 2 February 1602. Includes a description of the travel of King Philip III and his retinue from Valladolid to Leon. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1602 March 8</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_30a43d1c7766a4636f308c1479e4ba2c"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0588529ebf072b602c712b0f16e3c43e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_30a43d1c7766a4636f308c1479e4ba2c">12</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_18ff4d35627c617801eacd2b3a229893"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref24" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: The re-establishment of the Society of Jesus in France. Place: Burdeos. Description: Printed account of the re-establishment of the Society of Jesus in France. In this text, apparently addressed to the Spanish Jesuits, an anonymous French Jesuit describes the social opposition to the Society of Jesus in France, the attitude of the French king towards the order, and the educational and religious tasks undertaken by the Jesuits after the French Parliament issued the edict of re-establishment. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1604 March 18</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970318)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_27ffac486e00acf451bb4c5cd6046844"
                                type="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2e059e70ec05b2c6bfe362dd725e0b48"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_27ffac486e00acf451bb4c5cd6046844">13</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_4d32b680e55162564f7e0cbb7cb4da14"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref25" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Ynstrucción que se dio... A los quatro secretarios del Consejo de Indias y al escribano de Cámara." Place: Valladolid. Description: Copy of a royal instruction concerning the duties of secretaries and notary of the Council of the Indies. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1604 December 31</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970326)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_66f48789507d4dfb56b8ebcf5bbdc960"
                                type="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d0d07fd4d767eeed79ed7737cf08da1a"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_66f48789507d4dfb56b8ebcf5bbdc960">14</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_cf6fd9372810a0926f2bbfd3e9b79879"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref26" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Ordinances for the king's service. Place: Madrid. Description: Copies of different ordinances, issued between 1608 and 1648, for the service of the Spanish king. Includes detailed instructions on the protocol and duties to be followed by the members of the royal house including secretaries, lords of the bed-chamber, valets-de-chambre, guards, and servants.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1721</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970326)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_5ca81a8aab142c53412414ce304a4e55"
                                type="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3d7e74a2cdf6d763a466f7e6e41260e1"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_5ca81a8aab142c53412414ce304a4e55">15</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_e3e12a20a10679e1ed0d9237ff9a7ff0"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref27" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by the duke of Lerma. Place: Madrid. Description: Letter by the duke of Lerma, to Secretary Matienzo, instructing him to order the condestable of Castile, governor of Milan, to use a seal (estampa), rather than a signature, in making payments to soldiers in the infantry, chivalry and fortresses. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1612 March 14</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970326)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_6c18f9579b53c3a9c9e91888f7fedb4c"
                                type="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8c85fb2d17bb6cce56ec0bfcc6a86e0c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6c18f9579b53c3a9c9e91888f7fedb4c">16</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_2cce12ee9c111d8a4e2f03b783af1ba2"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref28" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by the duke of Lerma. Description: Copy of a letter by the duke of Lerma, to the marquis of Boza, concerning King Philip III's reaction to the baptism of the marquis' grandson. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca 1612]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970326)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_d7ab474e6724982440dc73e96c9fb6e8"
                                type="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_84c2c7f998f1d77ff9a05be066fffcaf"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d7ab474e6724982440dc73e96c9fb6e8">17</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_5313c6daf7980cc93b9eb91c9e6534db"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref29" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Acuerdo en que el reyno señala la cantidad con que se ha de servir a su magestad." Description: Printed texts related to a loan to support the military campaign of the Spanish army in Flanders and Germany. The texts concern the collection of the loan in the American and Spanish territories. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1617-1623</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970326)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_437e5fe43281848510959e9241ad7571"
                                type="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c65c426856cb4b229066d9dada3ffe6c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_437e5fe43281848510959e9241ad7571">18</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_9249abb62711507ac3d9e8bda1795a7e"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref30" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents on Cádiz fortifications. Places: Cádiz, Madrid. Description: Two documents, a printed decree by the king and instructions addressed to Juan de Fuente Hurtado, concerning the collection of funds for the construction of fortifications on the Cádiz Bay. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1617-1627</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970326)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_958921911152aebd9def327bf27695f4"
                                type="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1c84d810879691fa99966e2587f869ec"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_958921911152aebd9def327bf27695f4">19</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126251)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_b2e29da9bba119f08fac234e50467d21"
                                type="reel">1U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref31" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Consulta que hiço el Consejo Real de Castilla al señor Phelipe Tercero sobre la conservación de sus reynos." Place: Madrid. Description: Report by the members of the Council of Castile, to the king, on the causes of the depopulation of Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1619 February 1</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_acada5163299202c40b949b0d9fd8997"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9b1c91c4c16f8d84a1a68385e5ce8e60"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_acada5163299202c40b949b0d9fd8997">20</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_3c5fa9e73c950feefa30b0111e541ff9"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref32" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: González de Cellorigo, Martín. Place: Madrid. Title: Memorial to the king. Description: Memorial by Martín González de Cellorigo, addressed to the king, on the royal policy towards Jews in Spain. Cellorigo believed Jews should be tolerated due to their economic and social significance, but proposed that they be converted to Christianity. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1619 July 5</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_311f2b80df106a9e9522ca29e3cab6f1"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d3ccb5a3c629ac5354615261b8b7f261"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_311f2b80df106a9e9522ca29e3cab6f1">21</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a3dd17b5965e53b65395b7a2568c891f"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref33" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Marquis of Montenegro. Title: Memorials. Place: Madrid. Description: Copies of two memorials by the marquis of Montenegro, addressed to the king, concerning the conduct of foreign policy: the first, on the alliances with Italian nobles; the second, on military strategy to follow in the war taking place in Germany. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1620</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_bf75c03072c1c7d7d195aa1a7fe37a5e"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_57ac35c78a1d5a0ae4b974ed8b36f055"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_bf75c03072c1c7d7d195aa1a7fe37a5e">22</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_10c3de17296dd4b0fd4201094e2341b0"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref34" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Copia de una carta que vino en pliego del Obispo de Gaeta, para don Juan de la Sal, obispo de Bona." Place: Naples. Description: Printed letter by the bishop of Gaeta, to Juan de la Sal, bishop of Bona, narrating the end of duke of Osuna's tenure as viceroy of Naples. In this text, the author defends the government of the duke and attributes his downfall to political intrigue. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1620</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_d4238d866a21033e24be850f8296ca6b"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_efbd4a132894a6bbaaf129ea0ba5f3b6"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d4238d866a21033e24be850f8296ca6b">23</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_ec8278482b7c04d3daeabdf0dbc4f70c"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref35" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal decree by the king. Place: Madrid. Description: Very damaged copy (difficult to read) of a royal decree by the king concerning Fernando Carrillo. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1621 April 23</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_ddda49172eee9a54e4afa3cce27c7d50"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f130f769e92ac4ff8c7fe395376c8a6b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ddda49172eee9a54e4afa3cce27c7d50">24</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_d757a2fd72709f7c35c687d5d08cc13f"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref36" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Acuerdo que se toma de parte de su magestad." Place: Madrid. Description: In 1620 the Spanish crown confiscated gold and silver which had been transported from Spanish America. This document is an agreement between the crown and the deputies of the Consulate of Seville, Pedro de Avendaño Villela and Fernando López Ramírez, over how the crown was to pay back the money it seized. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1621 July 6</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_8d7b64169268d1e56158e48e90c36d58"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4c0bd43824d62c3bc45d0aaf38fe54d7"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8d7b64169268d1e56158e48e90c36d58">25</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_d6f99a2b0f549cfac8aa08264de8057f"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref37" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Premática. Places: San Lorenzo, Madrid. Description: Printed royal decree (premática) by the king, issued on 7 October 1621, concerning quit-rents and state pensions (juros). Includes a text which notes that the decree was proclaimed on 8 October 1621 in Madrid. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1621</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a5c7d0517edb7c962fed8ee34288a48b"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1305da6184979107219e0fd0cd9c6cc9"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a5c7d0517edb7c962fed8ee34288a48b">26</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_cd6619166154ba7ecfebd5917eac546c"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref38" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Nájera, Hernando de. Title: "Relación del día." Place: Seville. Description: Printed account of the ceremony in Seville proclaiming Philip IV king of Spain. Describes, in detail, the participants, the ceremonial procession, and the decorations of public buildings. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1621</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_05893cda7339d4e2654c5ac1e296937b"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_84cccf3b77b45495de177624281cabc1"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_05893cda7339d4e2654c5ac1e296937b">27</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_c858ee4ad9b264246b92c00ef590624c"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref39" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Verdadera relación." Place: Seville. Description: Printed account of the ceremony in Madrid proclaiming Philip IV king of Spain, and the funeral held in memory of Philip III, at the Church of Saint Jerome in Madrid. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1621</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_e6ac88828f2009cb083b0e0e1c42c1b0"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b5a02583ac202aca94e990993055671f"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e6ac88828f2009cb083b0e0e1c42c1b0">28</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_42caa7bb4640469db4c98bb21a5c532c"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref40" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación de avisos." Place: Seville. Description: Seventeenth-century printed texts containing news (avisos) on politics, wars and social events are considered to be early forms of journalism. In Spain and its American colonies, these texts were printed and circulated widely. This "relación" includes news from Rome, Flanders, Sicily, Germany, France, Florence and Algeria. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1621</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_cd3e5f23de885b57f912449c7b3e2285"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_80bdcdb6b4ca1b30d66d4212fe44572e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_cd3e5f23de885b57f912449c7b3e2285">29</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_124d068de9b1bc4cac66f785240c7f42"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref41" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación de la muerte de ...don Felipe Tercero." Description: Printed biography of King Philip III. The account focuses on the religious piety and death of the monarch, and includes brief references to the beginnings of Philip IV's rule and the death of the great duke of Florence. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1621</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_95bb4929a64b1507f2dd4972a26af635"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8990a23cf8c1e3bc55d1fe76a65afd47"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_95bb4929a64b1507f2dd4972a26af635">30</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_deb247f1808f21485150d541ddb83ed0"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref42" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Decreto que el rey don Felipe Quarto." Place: Seville. Description: Printed copy of a decree by King Philip IV ordering the establishment of an assembly (junta) for the moral reform of society. Includes an account of the funeral of Philip III held at the royal palace in Madrid, and the transportation of the body of the king from Madrid to the royal burial site at San Lorenzo del Escorial monastery. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1621</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_12dfd79db9d37e921228200e97bf33fa"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a847290b366d2141d57d623ef6294fdc"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_12dfd79db9d37e921228200e97bf33fa">31</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_24d56d4d1d1ea07272f8992643a5efc1"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref43" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación." Place: Madrid? Description: Account of the death of Philip III and of the events which occurred in the Spanish court after his death. Includes some references to the French court and the war in the Netherlands. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1621]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_fcce1e7baef4463c614b5bc3949116c4"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0d33ed73647488a5ab2e2b64bd41025c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_fcce1e7baef4463c614b5bc3949116c4">32</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_8d2096a6bc4dfcae0be514973840357b"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref44" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Gasco? Torquemada, Gregorio. Title: "Nacimiento, vida, prisión y muerte de don Rodrigo Calde[rón], marqués de siete iglesias." Description: Rodrigo Calderón, marquis of Siete Iglesias, was a member of the circle of the duke of Lerma, the powerful minister of King Philip III. After the political downfall of the duke, Calderón was prosecuted by royal order. This is an account of Calderón's stay in prison and public execution. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1621]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_5a8299c7d15e1e43891c1b4547438e91"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c97afe563bb27b25699fda46de1cf6f1"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_5a8299c7d15e1e43891c1b4547438e91">33</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_34516d99238ae06d9b72d755b8996dc4"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref45" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by the duke of Lerma. Place: Valladolid. Description: Letter by the duke of Lerma, to King Philip IV, accepting that 72,000 ducados of his rent from Sicily had been confiscated by the crown. The rent had been a grant by King Philip III to the duke of Lerma. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1621] April 13</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f6a013db3524230f21c8e65e97489de4"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_83840d86df579e3acf4581584500a81b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f6a013db3524230f21c8e65e97489de4">34</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_03e5a7e85490eb37d3c8edd77762d5d8"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref46" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Glosas". Description: Paper containing copies of two compositions in verse and a text on the duke of Lerma. The first composition is entitled "Anda niño anda, que Dios te lo manda," and consists of political advice addressed to the young King Philip IV; the second composition, "Pues agua subes Carrillo," alludes to the relationship between the count-duke of Olivares and Fernando Carrillo. The third text is a full description of the noble titles and posts held by the duke of Lerma. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[1621?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_fd4bbc374bc8884e85a2ede760c3c8c8"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_aed8ee4dabbd12910721ff1057c699c0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_fd4bbc374bc8884e85a2ede760c3c8c8">35</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0e0ae78c438cc04cd4030ade4acaf333"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref47" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Capitulaciones que ofrece el rey de la Gran Bretaña en orden de los casamientos de el Príncipe de Gales con la Infanta de España." Place: Madrid? Description: Copy of the proposals by the king of England, addressed to the pope, to obtain the papal approval for the marriage of the prince of Wales (future King Charles II of England) to the princess of Spain. Includes the pope's responses to the proposals. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1622 October</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_1073da3e0f692b2144fabcfedd8e5a7c"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_22ee0eb17b653a4e91bc1853d537efb9"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1073da3e0f692b2144fabcfedd8e5a7c">36</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_aee7b9fd9a59c208090176f99eec1837"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref48" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal decree and instruction. Place: Madrid. Description: Two printed documents: the first, a royal decree by the king, issued on 14 January 1622, ordering the presidents of audiencias, viceroys, corregidores, governors, judges, alcaldes, and ministers of the royal treasury to submit inventories of their properties to the crown before assuming positions in the royal administration; the second, an instruction by the king, issued on 21 January 1622, explaining to those appointed to posts in the royal administration how to prepare property inventories. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1622</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_d87f340fb5968b14a3dcf766c017486c"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_53f8c7783865b4ec3dcbc1e4ead391c5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d87f340fb5968b14a3dcf766c017486c">37</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_99f82a00156d483de754d84b01ca05fe"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref49" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Copia de los tres capítulos últimos de la carta relación de los puertos." Place: Burgos. Description: Copy of a letter by a Spanish prelate to the king warning him about the presence of British heretics in Spain, and suggesting the nomination of visitors and overseers to administer justice in Castile. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1623 January 3</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_c2b10b019de958359aa43629c3363720"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4acdf37e1288788da033e465ec6c1e32"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c2b10b019de958359aa43629c3363720">38</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_5bbee0d93080dc7c34ef4b7e82a0a2b9"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref50" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Capítulos de reformación." Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copy of a royal decree by the king ordering the establishment of "erarios y montes de piedad." Describes the regulations for their functioning. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1623 February 10</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_8396d6d4a539a41d663bc11910ff4f13"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c053062ad956c71c715af22d5d12997d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8396d6d4a539a41d663bc11910ff4f13">39</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_27185e5e98450d9f38b32099b98aed56"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref51" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by James I, king of England. Description: Letter by James I, king of England, to Gaspar de Guzmán, count-duke of Olivares, expressing gratitude for the reception given to his son, the prince of Wales, and the marquis of Buckingham during their stay in Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1623 March 29</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_c23e10e553bdd9f25eb399cd24df9868"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8ef631fa4600e6567c462bd1df4d6587"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c23e10e553bdd9f25eb399cd24df9868">40</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_afe0d3f188644315a3afafdd08745399"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref52" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación verdadera de la procesión y solenes fiestas que se celebraron en Roma a la elección del nuevo pontífice...Urbano VIII." Place: Madrid. Description: Printed biography of Urban VIII, elected pope in 1623. Includes brief descriptions of the ceremonies held in Rome upon his election. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1623</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_d3cc0a3180bf2bc98337d3f7bb1fb15e"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_af16e864e606bf1bd56a910d9ec76bf5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d3cc0a3180bf2bc98337d3f7bb1fb15e">41</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_734ba03c6280c0ac52f94fbeeb17590c"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref53" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Primera quadrilla." Place: Madrid? Description: To honor the visit of the prince of Wales to Madrid, the Spanish royal house organized a tournament (juego de cañas) in which the Spanish king, the count-duke of Olivares, and Spanish nobles participated. The document describes the members of the teams (quadrillas) which played in the tournament, and includes some poetic compositions related to the event. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1623</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_1f638454bc8e2e2b71e1296df41d9af6"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9da55547dceb086d36bfce82ea1bbdf4"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1f638454bc8e2e2b71e1296df41d9af6">42</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_6569688626d2384576d3a7a3a39c65b7"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref54" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Titles: Texts. Description: Four texts on the Spanish Church and the end of the Netherlands War: "Historia del Concilio de Trento en su tercera convocación por el pontífice Pío Quarto escrita por don Pedro González de Mendoza, obispo de Salamanca" (n.d.); a partial printed text in Latin on papal decrees (Rome, 1623); printed copy of the Treaty of Munster between Spain and the Dutch United Provinces (1648); "Por la religión de San Basilio Magno. En la pretensión que tiene de que se use de las censuras y edictos promulgados para que se recoja la estampa y pintura que ha sacado a luz de su Fundador y Padre, con la religión de San Benito" </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">(undated). 1623-1648</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_04e24b45056f11572de314d02477f4ee"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ee9edeb739372af1e415772eea0c762d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_04e24b45056f11572de314d02477f4ee">43</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_35cc9610aab9f66e0737d9a63be45721"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref55" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by Pope Urban VIII. Place: Rome. Description: Printed copy of a letter, written in Latin by Pope Urban VIII, stating that Angelo Maria, archbishop of Mira, had been nominated as coadjutor for the archbishop of Armenia. Includes a Spanish translation of the papal letter. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1624 July 23</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_17d9cf9f2fe3213aabc35f1c0fc47f15"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d999ee8ada63c94097f29320d2e2d9e7"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_17d9cf9f2fe3213aabc35f1c0fc47f15">44</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_b0bdc3ea2fa66ffc0b1ed3713c51fb15"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref56" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Report. Place: Madrid. Description: Printed report, apparently addressed to the solicitors (procuradores) for the Spanish parliaments, informing them of the plan for the establishment of an "erario" in Castile. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1624</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_9b57af8e4400b8de0949f13b101fa8d9"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9dca4e72c9291e14774ac2096b56b36b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_9b57af8e4400b8de0949f13b101fa8d9">45</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_960adca16be7ecdd213b277c0d1e567d"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref57" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación de la entrada y famoso recibimiento... Al... Duque de Neoburs." Place: Seville. Description: Printed account of the reception given on 7 October 1624 for Guillermo de Austria y Baviera, duke of Neoburs, at the Madrid court. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1624</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_4003b45ca198ec6ddb784bd09dcbc038"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_03368422d435b16e83adc74c860f822d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_4003b45ca198ec6ddb784bd09dcbc038">46</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_3fac5359c74213315f784783d7961a87"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref58" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Report to the king. Place: Granada. Description: This report is addressed to the king and aimed to serve as a guide for the conduct of Spanish foreign policy. The text has two parts: the first explains the reasons why some European and Asian nations were against the Spanish monarchy; the second, provides advice on political alliances and economic measures to be taken during the Thirty Years War. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1625 March 29</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_cc5d0c229f1a8ce8d30efb13429b268c"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2883df5c0332f652082459f4baeffa3c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_cc5d0c229f1a8ce8d30efb13429b268c">47</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_667f1df2c7e1faefe054597a4afde72c"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref59" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter. Place: Monzón. Description: Copy of a letter which refers to the peace agreement between France and Spain, signed in Monzón. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1626 March 6</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_2412c4f3bb230919931fe55e153fc439"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8002c20d8d08c864a912c582a7636f51"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2412c4f3bb230919931fe55e153fc439">48</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_14cf44677329daa3bd283e4125d80676"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref60" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Copia de un papel que llevó don Luis de Haro al estado militar de la ciudad de Valencia." Place: Monzon. Description: Copy of document by Philip IV to the "estado militar"of Valencia censoring their conduct. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1626 March 9</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_7432ce925a4f630ada59622b304abee6"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e1c800b375f9a287270d491e41fbfbe0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7432ce925a4f630ada59622b304abee6">49</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_4d21976860072491ef2fa4dceff81fef"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref61" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Copia de una carta de...Urbano VIII." Place: Rome. Description: Printed copy of a letter by Pope Urban VIII, to the king of France, asking him to request the king of England to be tolerant of Catholicism in England. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1626 May 30</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_d848559f2e307b4d84aa2bd40cac83b3"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2e5a63750c0b9d75a6cd923a82fd70da"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d848559f2e307b4d84aa2bd40cac83b3">50</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0d00b1d4bf9123048748e30f97b839f1"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref62" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Tanto del papel que el señor presidente del Consejo de Castilla." Place: Madrid? Description: Printed copy of a text by Francisco de Contreras, president of the Council of Castile, to Pedro de Vesga, informing him of a royal decree which allowed Vesga to keep his salary and privileges in public ceremonies although he was no longer an officer of the royal treasury. 1626 Jul 25</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_725bcc53b25953e2dfec7e3a2f6f20a9"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_26e58c43a961f92a9b7d14a869a89758"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_725bcc53b25953e2dfec7e3a2f6f20a9">51</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_837f5a55ca6de16cc44409ebbed0e03c"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref63" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letters between the king and the "estamentos de Valencia." Place: Monzón. Description: Copies of two letters: the first, written by King Philip IV to the "estamentos de Valencia" asking for obedience to the crown (2 March 1626); the second, the response by the "estamentos" to the king (n.d.). 1626, n.d.</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_75e6ad9609e6837128951dbcd0ed8ab9"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_56577ebf303c4871885e9aac3c9df560"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_75e6ad9609e6837128951dbcd0ed8ab9">52</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_ed2b374539362b14d72dc15ea827ffc0"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref64" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by the count-duke of Olivares. Place: Madrid? Description: Copy of a letter (villete) by the count-duke of Olivares to the governor of Valencia commenting on Philip IV's opinion of the Valencia nobles. 1626</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_c503f3585d5a892c1cd2bcb06052e30c"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_516dc89233d855f0a0fe0e399858e2ff"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c503f3585d5a892c1cd2bcb06052e30c">53</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_bb4cd7b847acd26cf0af583e38e77ccf"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref65" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter. Description: Copy of a letter describing the defeat of the Danish army under Christian IV by the imperial army at the battle of Valverst on 28 August 1626. 1626</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_e6a6f4c7a691f52b7459128ecb00fe7a"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_fb69c8df283954db2c20f30f925e1a36"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e6a6f4c7a691f52b7459128ecb00fe7a">54</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_81b9ec1820004cea8ed4087c9ebb36a5"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref66" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Estado de las guerras de Flandes." Place: Seville. Description: Printed account of the military actions of the Spanish army in the Netherlands war. 1626</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_41bb71da40e0be2612e2eb849b35b312"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d9a676a8fb0bfbaa510f7748925f966e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_41bb71da40e0be2612e2eb849b35b312">55</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_c017edd7f85aef9c1411897337ff18ec"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref67" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Memoria de lo que pasó." Description: Copy of a report which describes the discussions between the king of England and the British parliament about relations between Spain and England and the course of the European war. [1626?]</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_7c665a3aca06f99f36c0eb2a60e4c057"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a516aff6d2e51352605a9c0654c52f7a"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7c665a3aca06f99f36c0eb2a60e4c057">56</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0ea28eb8700402b905998b6c9e71cff2"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref68" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal decree. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a royal decree by the Council of the royal treasury ordering the suspension of payments (consignaciones) to stockholders and creditors of the state. 1627 Feb 4</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_321d8967730595e59625dd728f455576"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a8291ce8289bbb44bee812249df14f0a"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_321d8967730595e59625dd728f455576">57</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_fbd147dab9a96c3b89599ab8356d69d5"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref69" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Premática que su magestad." Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copy of a royal decree concerning the depreciation in the value of "vellón" coin. 1627</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f2805e25434d321797e823d9b0964daf"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_37d48b49bead05f964b34308e4a2433a"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f2805e25434d321797e823d9b0964daf">58</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_09ad0038851d48a4bf3ee1741a7a91f9"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref70" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Premática" and "Tasa." Place: Madrid. Description: Two printed documents: the first, a copy of a royal decree, issued on 13 September 1627, ordering the regulation of the prices of merchandise, salaries and products; the second, a "Tassa general de los precios a que se han de vender las mercaderías, y de las hechuras, salarios y jornales." 1627</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_c6ed12f87ea17ca598a4bb86750f4520"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5e48d8457251221708c4e521006edb0f"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c6ed12f87ea17ca598a4bb86750f4520">59</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_769b377c6f8c33a563faf090d9fd800b"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref71" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter. Description: Copy of a letter narrating political events in France., [1627?]</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_acddd9b5df041091a89f2c57adc11913"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a7babd47ddab05770fb259f1d23f982b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_acddd9b5df041091a89f2c57adc11913">60</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_ea87e6b77a5327348b152f8ce487d28d"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref72" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents related to the Consulate of Seville. Places: Seville, Madrid. Description: Copies of five documents, four related to a loan given by the Consulate of Seville to the crown, and a memorial by the Consulate, addressed to the king, commenting on the economic effects of the royal decree which ordered the depreciation in value of "vellón" coin. 1627-1629</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_8d6c7ee57a9aaf4a8449b65014c39357"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_496babfe2cfd4bca4f98cd8cd9748b64"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8d6c7ee57a9aaf4a8449b65014c39357">61</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_2da378a9e97ec081fa03e14f34f26612"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref73" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letters by King Philip IV. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of two letters by King Philip IV to Antonio González de Legarda, governor and general captain of the province of "Tierra Firme" (Panama), warning him that a navy expedition had departed from Holland to attack Spanish America. The king instructed the governor to prepare military defenses. 1628 May 18</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_618961c845acba6b58c76fd47ddadec3"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_bfca56c4498cc67dde89c304690c1c24"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_618961c845acba6b58c76fd47ddadec3">62</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_37942b5bbdce05aa134df22b44bdee46"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref74" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by the of the Holy Roman Emperor. Description: Copy of a letter by the Holy Roman Emperor to ambassador count of Fraquenburg, instructing him to advise King Philip IV to monitor more closely the actions of the duke of Alba and Gonzalo de Córdoba. 1629 May 8</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_3ba1ddeacd89557e857750bf9b27180c"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c62ace0bdeaf249bd817adab7f183753"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_3ba1ddeacd89557e857750bf9b27180c">63</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_7ee6b27ebeacfe15d94a8c4edce28f1a"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref75" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by Miguel de Ipinarrieta. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a letter by Secretary Miguel de Ipinarrieta concerning a loan of a million ducados to the crown. 1629 Jul 3</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_71b1b81c236d5ebe5974f8d952b49565"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4abf84a13c48696933cf7a99ce4b50f2"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_71b1b81c236d5ebe5974f8d952b49565">64</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_fb15b3c95a46b6000fe6bcc43217baa4"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref76" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by Alonso Fernández de Quirós. Place: Cartagena. Description: Copy of a letter by Alonso Fernández de Quirós narrating the defeat by the Spanish fleet of the British garrison established on the island of San Cristobal, in the Caribbean Sea. 1629 Oct 23</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970342)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_eac20f8330f23fbf849f682a6a588a32"
                                type="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4ec51551ae12c3dbda4440629523ea5b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_eac20f8330f23fbf849f682a6a588a32">65</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126244)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_044cb5421c1787b7950da58027845e74"
                                type="reel">2U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref77" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Pasquín que se halló en Roma por junio de 630." Place: Rome? Description: Copy of a composition in verse (pasquín) in which rulers, nobles and military officers state what they hope to gain from the European war. Participants include the king of Spain, the king of France, the Holy Roman Emperor, the pope, the duke of Saboya, the duke of Florence, and the marquis of Spinola, among others. 1630 Jun</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_574f376bd2bb9c90575a79997e1db765"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_aa09a005c59cff5a1de6083619db7230"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_574f376bd2bb9c90575a79997e1db765">66</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_1af8ec05a5bc7cb27edce9bcb54666a1"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref78" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Pregón y vando." Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copy of a decree by King Philip IV, issued on 28 September 1630, ordering various measures to be taken to prevent the spread of disease in Spain. Includes a text which notes that the royal decree was proclaimed in squares and places of Madrid on 28 September 1630. 1630</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a8660407a615eed775ee52e353446510"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_7b9ff9b8cf9524279b3f81c44ce2b8f1"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a8660407a615eed775ee52e353446510">67</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_bd661b77619ecc0b4d531e3b7f54aea6"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref79" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents re/by: Juan de Chumacero y Carrillo. Places: Madrid. Description: Politician and diplomat, Juan de Chumacero y Carrillo was one of the most prominent figures during the reign of Philip IV. This group of documents consists of letters, consults, and memorials related to Chumacero's tenure as member of the Council of Castile. Includes an extensive report on the government and the administration of justice in the Spanish monarchy. 1631-1632</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_804409030e99d36b659dcc3e164a9dc4"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f2a8ad14dcb84d5dcdbcbcc9b63975e2"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_804409030e99d36b659dcc3e164a9dc4">68</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_152b186360de9dfc94838a5721c3be5b"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref80" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Yo Martín Ochoa de Aioravide." Place: Bilbao. Description: Printed copy of a text concerning the conflict between the general deputies, magistrates and community agents (sindicos) of Vizcaya, and the corregidor over the establishment of a state monopoly (estanco) of salt in that jurisdiction. 1632 Oct 16</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_6710025f7b3846650680af70fa2c70ac"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_44617bd1c1fd548fd659a3c1dce03ba6"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6710025f7b3846650680af70fa2c70ac">69</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_3a8f43c7f3d5b9fd774ba4bbca7bd6b4"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref81" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Traslado de diferentes cartas escritas por... El cardenal Albornoz, siendo gobernador de Milán, al Conde San Segundo." Place: Milan. Description: Printed text containing copies of nine letters, eight by Cardinal Gil de Albornoz, governor of Milan, and one by the great chancellor of Milan, to the count of San Segundo, concerning military and government issues. 1633-1635</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_4a4d8b3b288e1589ad43426aa288c476"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e326da5903521cbdd9d9a751e308a707"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_4a4d8b3b288e1589ad43426aa288c476">70</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_2e091ba0611a633ebc2b11aa5aa369fa"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref82" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Title of tax collector. Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copy of a title, issued by the king, to be used by tax collectors. Includes a copy of a royal decree, issued on 8 November 1636, concerning the collection of taxes for the crown. 1636</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_cc2695612a2bb544153bafc05310f612"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a240004ce2b40a05eabc890f82ca356a"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_cc2695612a2bb544153bafc05310f612">71</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_7b60c5758d591ec1f86014e945c73af0"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref83" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Premática en que su magestad." Place: Madrid: Printed copies of two royal decrees by the king: the first, issued on 15 December 1636, ordering that public scriptures, titles, and decrees be written on stamp paper (papel sellado); the second, issued on 15 December 1636, listing in detail the types of documents to be written on stamp paper. 1637</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_36083b7d91a30549cb90c7a43eedd4bd"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6641c0991e1bc8bfaa35abc3234f4097"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_36083b7d91a30549cb90c7a43eedd4bd">72</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_3570df067e31a7fb1f9502fbcaffe215"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref84" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Premática en que su magestad." Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copy of an order by the king, issued on 20 Mar 1637, concerning the reduction in the value of the "vellón" coin. Includes a text which notes that the decree was proclaimed on 20 March 1637 in the streets and squares of Madrid. 1637</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_b5918bd57ed4ee00af478384b8327913"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1b2c54288d4fd1702c47ae521d1ad745"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_b5918bd57ed4ee00af478384b8327913">73</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_8a77836c63f428c7329ca10b8f736c67"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref85" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Vuestra Magestad." Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copy of a royal decree, addressed to Fernando de Valdés, archbishop of Granada, informing him of the new regulations regarding genealogical information to be provided by candidates for various offices (informaciones de limpieza). According to the decree, candidates for the Council of Inquisition, military orders, colegios mayores, and other "comunidades de estatuto" had to declare the services their ancestors and/or relatives had performed for the crown (actos positivos). 1638 Mar 22</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_33dc693127cd69d961489470eecc66cf"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4515ac4278b8d9ee3b0084cdca63c348"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_33dc693127cd69d961489470eecc66cf">74</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_6e1ff03a9e50a25b30f2036e6a46b965"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref86" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal decrees by the king. Place: Madrid. Description: Copies of three royal decrees by the king, addressed to Sebastián Hurtado de Corcuera, governor and general captain of the Philippine Islands. In the first decree, the king acknowledges Hurtado for his military services in that region; in the other two, the king grants Hurtado license to travel to Spain. 1639</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_98eab6bf47fe6d5afec457a0816d96f0"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9d81fecd3a010460d7b465505795b205"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_98eab6bf47fe6d5afec457a0816d96f0">75</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_f46a240b1fe13b9d783aa4e00680efff"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref87" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Texts on Honorato Juan. Description: Two printed texts on Honorato Juan, who was "gentilhombre" of Emperor Charles V, preceptor of King Philip II's son, Charles, and bishop of Osma. The first text, entitled "Elogios," is a collection of eulogies and quotations, in prose and verse, and letters documenting the life of Honorato Juan. The eulogies and quotations are from texts by prominent Spanish scholars (including Luis Vives, Benito Arias Montano, Gonzalo de Illescas, Juan Ginés de Sepulveda); the letters are written by Philip II. The second text is entitled "Parafrasi que traduze dos fragmentos del Libro IV de retórica de Benedicto Arias Montano en que trata de ...Honorato Juan... Por el dotor Roque Iasón Verja." 1659, n.d.</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_eaa16480602d80cd530e6ca4e77acfd9"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d39e0b5da4b07950a684f6c62f9887f0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_eaa16480602d80cd530e6ca4e77acfd9">76</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_81cccc3c85e21335896b6ab4f70ec603"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref88" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación política de las más particulares acciones de el Conde Duque y sucesos de la monarquía de España, con la forma de su gobierno. Escrita de un embaxador de Venecia a su república haviendo estado en Madrid." Place: Naples. Description: Account of the life and political career (1618-1630) of the count- duke of Olivares. This is a copy of the text, written originally in Italian, translated by Juan Antonio Dighero. Dighero was servant of the count of Peñaranda, who was viceroy and general captain of Naples. 1661 Feb 26</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a02e62aa8b84c103b8990e87899b26b1"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e41b8741d159d0bb44a24232ac38a42c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a02e62aa8b84c103b8990e87899b26b1">77</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_cb1329d2c1afd90c8580510953f654bc"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref89" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación política de las más particulares acciones de el Conde Duque de Olibares y sucesos de la monarquía de España." Place: Naples. Description: Copy of the text described above. 1661</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_e8a34863799b22a31c94698627960f6e"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b9997ddef40a212a3db352b55a13247d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e8a34863799b22a31c94698627960f6e">78</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_498bb8bdffc5aaf1ba7e4ea1c4224e4b"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref90" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Ramos del Mançano, Francisco. Title: A letter and a memorial. Places: Madrid, Irún. Description: Two documents by Francisco Ramos del Mançano: a letter, addressed to King Philip IV, concerning the resignation of the Spanish Queen, Isabel of Bourbon, and the royal succession (Madrid, 30 April 1662); and a memorial entitled: "El doctor don ... Pone en la real mano de Vuestra Magestad el papel inclusso sobre la justicia, conveniencia y exemplares de la renunciación de la señora reina christianíssima a la sucessión de estos reinos" (Irún, 30 October 1669). 1662-1669</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_61c80b9100bde88f9368a9eec8c85fd1"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c5bcb0f962542bf2dad317cb3f5ec342"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_61c80b9100bde88f9368a9eec8c85fd1">79</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_24f6c3a9b36e741264b789dcf647ccd9"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref91" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Papeles y cartas tocantes al señor don Juan de Austria." Description: Copies of documents related to Juan José de Austria, the illegitimate son of King Philip IV. Concerns the conflict between Juan José de Austria and Father Juan Everardo Nithard, confessor and private secretary of Queen Mariana. 1668-1669</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_6a31580a418a1fc9a46cbb2ada919d60"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_191af47f1baf5a3e0a96e3718d73e91a"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6a31580a418a1fc9a46cbb2ada919d60">80</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_9b796a499752bbfff21db9f35336231d"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref92" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Certification. Place: Milan. Description: Printed certificate by Secretary Diego Patiño, general overseer of the state of Milan, on the military status and services of the counts of San Segundo. 1679 Sep 18</unittitle>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_1f065f5037461bc9b82a425c2ea9c35b"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c074c258ffb2ab646d90e70590005173"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1f065f5037461bc9b82a425c2ea9c35b">81</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_4a34132d91a6bbd97d0a193f39a59923"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref93" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Papel con varios exemplares sobre que lo indiferente que ocurre al Consejo de Indias pertenece al secretario más antiguo de él." Place: Madrid? Description: Copy of a text which details the administrative duties of the senior secretary of the Council of Indies. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1697]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_305dc44ed899565ce6667f8385bea582"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4038fc6701c23c7ab9f844b5336294f3"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_305dc44ed899565ce6667f8385bea582">82</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_57735c217990649e6b37df21d92af2f1"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref94" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Echeverría y Orcolaga, Sancho de. Title: "Diario ... De las operaciones militares exequtadas en la defensa de la plaza de Peñíscola en el reino de Valencia." Description: Collection of documents related to the military services of Sancho de Echeverría y Orcolaga. Includes a handwritten account by Sancho de Echeverría y Orcolaga of the military defense of Peñíscola, Valencia; and four letters to his brother, Sebastián, describing other military services. These documents belonged to historian Mariano Fernández de Echeverría y Veytia, author of the note on the cover page. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1697-1720</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_712732192c12bb4014b2919797132cb6"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_7f879686e13cf896b3408e0a1a32859d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_712732192c12bb4014b2919797132cb6">83</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_762837bdfb7f4c77046e5c567858316f"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref95" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Papel político sobre el govierno y la forma que debe observarse." Description: Copy of a text addressed to the King [Philip III?] on how to rule the Spanish dominions. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f6f6269f22ca5e404f90bb860f2ed117"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6c98f5f34ff470ec0cc4371515571123"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f6f6269f22ca5e404f90bb860f2ed117">84</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_6da91bb59fc779105f002624499fec41"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref96" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Moreno, Miguel. Title: "Discurso...sobre un retiro eroyco." Description: In this text, addressed to the Spanish king, the author discusses the duties and risks of being private secretary of the king (privado); and the conduct to be followed by the king with his private secretary. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16--]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_7dd55950f241b5a9d10afe028a93a80e"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5d04863e0b92fd9a834e863d8bd34245"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7dd55950f241b5a9d10afe028a93a80e">85</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_cc49a5ea4afe71ec854aa6a7cb97539d"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref97" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Text on the University of Salamanca's chancellor. Description: Text containing a commentary about the nomination and rents of the University of Salamanca's chancellor. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16--]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970359)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_12665558ef9a11f0e338a66297c530af"
                                type="box">4</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5fb662270f929a2993a9fadeda1f95ce"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_12665558ef9a11f0e338a66297c530af">86</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126236)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_842f8108a79e3c8491e82859a58fe70b"
                                type="reel">3U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref98" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación de prebendados de iglesias cathedrales y collegiales de la corona de Castilla." Description: Copy of a detailed report on ecclesiastics of cathedral chapters and dioceses in Spain. Includes information on the ages and positions held by ecclesiastics. This report was probably to be used as a guide for future ecclesiastical promotions by one of the councils of the Spanish crown. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16--]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_90806d533de9cfdddc1c2956068360ca"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_7e124e0e8496e9aab0e221b5e6a4417f"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_90806d533de9cfdddc1c2956068360ca">87</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a5ece4ce3d441f93840e2c9d14369012"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref99" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Interrogatorio por donde se han de examinar los testigos que huvieren de deponer acerca de la santidad, virtudes, fama y milagros de la venerable virgen doña Mariana de Escobar, vezina de la ciudad de Valladolid." Place: Valladolid? Description: According to canonical law, an interrogatory of witnesses was the first step in the proceedings for the acceptance of sainthood of men and women by the Catholic Church. This printed interrogatory was to be used in the proceedings of Mariana de Escobar (1554-1633), a Spanish mystic writer and founder of the reformed religious order of Saint Brigid. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_5c9094c7767dd072cce1f6ff651ed7bd"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_578b9faf2eed86eea114d3462fd8de10"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_5c9094c7767dd072cce1f6ff651ed7bd">88</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0624cc46a7ebf38cf878012c64e68b79"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref100" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter. Description: A letter apparently concerning Francisco de Quevedo (damaged document; difficult to read). </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_9a316045ab2253ded5c93643d7b52fbc"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ac133459c0d92fbc49f19e54f342326e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_9a316045ab2253ded5c93643d7b52fbc">89</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_8ccccb68ee003693b2482a98bc5fe976"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref101" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Nuebas." Place: Madrid? Description: Paper containing news on the political changes in the Spanish court after the death of King Philip III. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_b5c7930ffcf8f35e112b402050ae4bbd"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f2620d792fec4b4b4b6c7847187ea352"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_b5c7930ffcf8f35e112b402050ae4bbd">90</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_596b48cc94d965b96acd880dcb054fa6"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref102" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Instrución que el... Señor duque de Medina-Sidonia dio a don Lorenzo Dábila y Estrada, su contador mayor, en ocassión de yr a besitar de su parte al ...Duque de Braganza." Description: Copy of the instructions given by the duke of Medina-Sidonia to his accountant, Lorenzo Dávila y Estrada, for his visit to the Portuguese duke of Braganza. Primarily concerns protocol and courtesy rules. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_17388f0896cb766ca528a3f8ce22f5fb"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_babafa488d42b115515cb7478010c9d1"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_17388f0896cb766ca528a3f8ce22f5fb">91</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_617ceabd165e28d54a49bea642f889c8"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref103" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Maldonado, Pedro. Title: "Discurso de perfecto privado." Description: Copy of a text by Pedro Maldonado (1576-1614) about the private secretary of the Spanish king (privado). The text justifies the existence of the post of private secretary; describes its moral duties and religious obligations; and considers its political responsibilities towards the king, ministers and nation. The text is dedicated by the author to Francisco de Rojas y Sandoval, duke of Lerma. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_8ad547aa798efda02ecbb4af05c25d07"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1e87c88e9c20cb293569235c3fab43f3"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8ad547aa798efda02ecbb4af05c25d07">92</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_df616b7aea2052edd4d63092642b2fbb"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref104" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Legal writ. Description: Copy of a legal writ related to the judicial proceeding of Diego de Auñón, citizen of Murcia, against Pedro Martil del Castillo, over the donation of properties made by Ana de Auñón, wife of Pedro Martil del Castillo. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_559c41d7593287a4503f16306726727f"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a8f1cca2938a8136bf8c91b4103ecf68"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_559c41d7593287a4503f16306726727f">93</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_edc3b3475ba89311e168e15fefbd1fd2"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref105" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: González de Cellorigo, Martín? Title: Memorial on Portuguese conversos. Description: Copy of a memorial, written probably by Martín González de Cellorigo, on the community of Portuguese Christians who were descendants of Jews (conversos). Addressed to the king of Spain, it asked for tolerance to be shown them. The author asked for a ban on the use of the term "new christian" in legal documents and laws, and asked that the crown order the Inquisitions of Portugal and Spain to comply with royal and ecclesiastical laws. Includes a text entitled "Alegación de derecho al memorial de la gente de la nación de Portugal." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_79576b1fdda22022ef0b5aa3fd36abed"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3ed19d3fc3dd9c1a90002e685cd2b958"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_79576b1fdda22022ef0b5aa3fd36abed">94</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_b2d19e7d0260d0a74f5c6a43b43514ac"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref106" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Memorial to the king. Description: Copy of a memorial, addressed to the king, on the reform of Spanish society. According to the anonymous author, the memorial was written to provide the king with useful advice for "the conservation of these [Spanish] kingdoms and cleaning them of insolent and vagabond people." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_b7697990e6186d326b4fca733a9fb9c3"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_38c38e0e857744cdfdaf3b1b6fafa22e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_b7697990e6186d326b4fca733a9fb9c3">95</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_7b1ca4eff7c95bd27d488c82913d32f3"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref107" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Lo que me a parecido advertir en cumplimiento del aucto de los señores del Consejo." Description: This text, probably written by a member of one of councils of the Spanish monarchy, deals with different issues related to the civil and ecclesiastical administration of justice. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_f31947be84ba5004eccd97f32830b998"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e5340c10f00137592c6d985ec79e8ead"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f31947be84ba5004eccd97f32830b998">96</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_30d4d7973f5d4a13039a319f6510f358"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref108" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents on Catalonia political institutions. Description: Copies of two documents: "Memorial del tiempo que ha que se fundó la Audiencia real de Barcelona, sacado de las constituciones del Principado de Cataluña;" and "Memorial de lo que se ha podido saber tocante al virrey y governador y veguer de Barcelona." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_b599324c8810a36f13b81f93d3bd965a"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a8901829d571ff213415e8802c17dec9"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_b599324c8810a36f13b81f93d3bd965a">97</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_dae36a32c3c9083fb650537744817a8f"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref109" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Memorial by the owners of "juros." Description: Copy of a memorial by the owners of "juros," addressed to the king, about the payment of interest by the crown. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_6cfcaacdec79fa71eae66a36ebb71802"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d00bdb2b5adf35aa617b7677682508c2"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6cfcaacdec79fa71eae66a36ebb71802">98</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_588bbb10711d85eaac485f73e0d23f79"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref110" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "L'origine della natione françese." Description: Text in Italian which describes the origin of the French monarchy; the establishment of the Salic Law; the prerogatives of the nobility; the succession of King Philip IX, "The Saint;" and the division of royal lineage between the Bourbons and the Valois. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_e83083ac9521923c5c609206bae0218d"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5d17702d61dcff18ecf8127b67277f9d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e83083ac9521923c5c609206bae0218d">99</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_ce65912e4280b7fb9f67fafb98e8d96e"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref111" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Copia de un papel que su magestad." Description: Copy of a note by the king of Spain, to the president of the Council of Castile, ordering him to impose social discipline by punishing "public sins and extortions of alguaciles and notaries, abuses of ministers, and lazy and vagabond people." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_d24024e0d15f4d54e64f7639e674d967"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9bf1e650f6ac5b90def7874c1e2110c4"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d24024e0d15f4d54e64f7639e674d967">100</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_634e50a26b15fe9d723e4783ca26345f"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref112" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "El Consulado de Sevilla contra el arbitrio de Tomas de Cardona." Place: Seville? Description: Printed copy of a memorial by the Seville Tribunal of Consulate, to the king, commenting on Tomas de Cardona's proposal for increasing the value of "marco de plata." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970367)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_0ab01da630ef869bf527df52592c96c6"
                                type="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_743f222831dd87d580f53dc5619160f5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0ab01da630ef869bf527df52592c96c6">101</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_d9d1bee7c9b85e052918e340a3e65441"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref113" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Mora, Joan de. Title: "Empresas del licenciado... Natural de la imperial ciudad de Toledo, dirigidas a la magestad del rey don Phelipe nuestro senor tercero deste nombre en los reynos de Spaña [sic], Indias _ Nuevo Mundo. Con anotaciones de algunos authores para su mejor inteligencia." Place: Toledo? Description: Since the Renaissance, emblems (also called hieroglyphs or "empresas") were a privileged literary genre for expressing political and moral teachings. Emblems were widely used to decorate triumphal arcs and funeral monuments. Usually the emblems consisted of two elements: an illustration, and a text which explained the meaning of the illustration. Written in the early seventeenth century and dedicated to Philip III, this book of emblems contains texts and numerous drawings with handwriting notations by the author. Although unfinished, it is a beautiful example of Spanish emblematic literary genre. The book belonged to the Public Library of Lima, Peru. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16-]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970375)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_8bde68dd7e30ef87e8cd0b4804d9b90a"
                                type="box">6</container>
                     <container id="aspace_05b76364c086e9d0b6cec9ab6d76e682"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8bde68dd7e30ef87e8cd0b4804d9b90a">102</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_7fce0986dde55f511e71c657c66901d7"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref114" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Copia de cláusulas del testamento que otorgó el rey nuestro señor don Carlos Segundo." Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copies of two clauses of King Charles II's testament: one instructing Queen Ana and the Council of Castile how to rule the Spanish dominions, and the other declaring Philip, duke of Anjou, as his successor to the Spanish throne. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1700 November 2</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_cf05f760cc76f588c3f2feab5a3ed5c4"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_645d417df60d5d5821f4e88b0dd65c91"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_cf05f760cc76f588c3f2feab5a3ed5c4">103</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_155b2f807c68e4ce3bf6a67d4c1e2306"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref115" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Consulta que hizo el Consejo real de Castilla al rey ... En las dependencias de don Balthasar de Mendoza, obispo de Segovia y entonces ynquisidor general, con el padre maestro fray Froylán Díaz, oy obispo electo de Ã&#x81;vila." Place: Madrid? Description: Copy of a consult addressed to King Philip V concerning the inquisitorial process against the confessor of King Charles II, Froylán Díaz, who was suspected of practicing sorcery. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1704</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_08b62c651de5b25278bee52c94a0953f"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_694ad7076e2a0abc704d12fb489db3a6"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_08b62c651de5b25278bee52c94a0953f">104</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a1a06098e2fc35ce9c051c06c05192f0"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref116" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Historia de lo que pasó con el padre fray Froilán Díaz." Place: Madrid? Description: During his life, King Charles II suffered constant illnesses. In 1697, the King got very sick, and rumors that he had been bewitched starting circulating in the Spanish court. This copy is an account of the magical and religious practices used by the confessor of Charles II, Dominican Froilán Díaz, to cure the king, and the inquisitorial process against the Dominican for practicing sorcery. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1704]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_470f394dc9aff1632da69d983d09367b"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d1c4a8f71126fd26c2a4f0bef41b34a3"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_470f394dc9aff1632da69d983d09367b">105</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_841e4f3f5f5ed06790c6aa085f645156"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref117" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Salazar, Luis de. Title: "Memorial que formó ... Por el duque de Medina Coeli, don Luis de la Cerda, y se dio por éste al rey nuestro señor." Description: Copy of a memorial, addressed to King Philip V, on the rents and privileges of the dukes of Medina Coeli. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1706]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_e293b64c1fb7460938810f3db2d585c2"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1d80134a97b3f3bb4597f984e437e953"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e293b64c1fb7460938810f3db2d585c2">106</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_ccb4681948394481ee8b9b66c5177358"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref118" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Consult. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a consult by the Royal Council of Castile, to King Philip V, on the authority of that Council to expel members of religious orders from Spain and confiscate their properties. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1708 September 22</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_96550099adfcd4054627a4886daa193a"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ddf9efb8e6a33089fe69d0eda685690f"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_96550099adfcd4054627a4886daa193a">107</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126228)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_8ec827049d9d6b0a762592a7354ee6f2"
                                type="reel">4U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref119" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Salazar, Luis de. Title: "Satisfacción a una consulta del Consejo de Castilla, formada ... A instancia de un ministro de el gavinete." Place: Madrid? Description: Extensive legal writ by Luis de Salazar on the authority of the Council of Castile to expel ecclesiastics from Spain and confiscate their properties. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1708</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_6f7c921073d9c94de6d45612c9c16ea1"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_663f4c128e6ebba839c285ca6898e4a8"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6f7c921073d9c94de6d45612c9c16ea1">108</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a6152b9ff5086a0bf26f50f4be6b97d7"
                                type="reel">5U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref120" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Abcdario índice de las materias que se contienen en los dos tomos de instrucciones y cartas acordadas que se an expedido por el Consejo de la Santa General Inquisición para el mejor govierno de los tribunales del Santo Oficio, según y conforme se guardan y registran en el Consejo hasta el presente año de 1687." Place: Madrid. Description: Book containing an index/summary of the ordinances and agreements (cartas acordadas) issued by the Council of the Supreme and General Inquisition of Madrid concerning the administration of the provincial tribunals, duties and privileges of the personnel, publication of edicts, and rents. The ordinances and agreements are arranged by subject in alphabetical order. This copy was made at the request of a Spanish American tribunal, most probably the tribunal of Lima. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1709 July 23</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_aeb6a9734d6ae19f271918d844c39d14"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_30de31555ed105f9cfea152b04736111"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_aeb6a9734d6ae19f271918d844c39d14">109</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_4929e8e949f16a9b0973163e5806fdf2"
                                type="reel">5U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref121" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Cardinal Portocarrero. Title: "Papel en que se hace presente a su magestad ...los prejuicios y graves inconvenientes que resultarían de las providencias dadas para extinguir en el todo el comercio con la corte de Roma." Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a memorial, addressed to Philip V, evaluating the consequences of suspending commercial and diplomatic relations between Spain and the papacy. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1709 July 31</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_c5bc8a5f6abec377a45a813c4718ec05"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f3669cd77bef54c147c2b378498d2645"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c5bc8a5f6abec377a45a813c4718ec05">110</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_51231a3b8530570fc2d3cf8dfad91e4f"
                                type="reel">5U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref122" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Consulta del Consejo a su magestad." Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a consult by the council, to King Philip V, on the sanctions to be applied to deserters in war. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1711 February 16</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_828335493f6baa694d60aa029a261339"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_202f3a59c005ca3ceeada60f0cee7200"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_828335493f6baa694d60aa029a261339">111</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_ef8db038e5a5757175bf9c5024dd01de"
                                type="reel">5U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref123" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Copia de carta que escribió al rey... Luis Primero el rey... Don Phelipe Quinto, su padre." Place: San Ildefonso. Description: Printed copy of a letter by King Philip V, to his son Luis, in which Philip renounces succession to the Spanish crown in favor of his son. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1724 January 14</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_5a7e565752fb3a11d5b81a6e394b3fb1"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_7703eed8587157ab8e2dcb549dade214"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_5a7e565752fb3a11d5b81a6e394b3fb1">112</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_47134ee97cd42fd26f0c4ed1242c9c96"
                                type="reel">5U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref124" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by the Council of Castile. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a letter by the Council of Castile, to King Philip V, expressing its condolences upon the death of Luis I. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1724 September 7</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970383)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_26ab1434637986b311c4d804c75e8f14"
                                type="box">7</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c0ca51f870a16a76bbd19af79ed050d3"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_26ab1434637986b311c4d804c75e8f14">113</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_956d20fa429a7e76e5b6334ffc2e7bfe"
                                type="reel">5U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref125" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Guerra y Sandoval, Juan Alfonso de. Title: "Despacho y blasón de armas." Place: Madrid. Description: Book containing the family genealogy of Juan Bautista de Peñarredonda Belaz Paraya y la Quintana. Contains six water colors on vellum, including four coats of arms. Genealogy accounts were usually compiled to obtain the title of noble. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1724</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970391)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_9ec67c028ab41ba58f8496fe16626d54"
                                type="box">8</container>
                     <container id="aspace_760154ff25c1a6d58c993e88e38f9c80"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_9ec67c028ab41ba58f8496fe16626d54">114</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_38965b401fbe1e16eb6581d312213075"
                                type="reel">5U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref126" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: History of the reign of King Philip V of Spain. Description: Partial copy of a history of the reign of King Philip V of Spain between 1712 and 1725. Describes events such as the end of the war of the Spanish Succession, the Treaty of Utrecht, the war of the Triple Alliance against Spain, the conflict between the Inquisition and Melchor Rafael de Macanaz, the brief reign of Luis I, and the assumption of Philip V to the Spanish throne after Luis I's death. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1725]</unitdate>
                  </did>
                  <c id="ref127" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Sections 1-11</unittitle>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970391)"
                                   altrender="archive legal"
                                   id="aspace_973e017cfea26243be0f9aff418c0e53"
                                   type="box">8</container>
                        <container id="aspace_cf1f86530de24a22fad6ab00d331c571"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_973e017cfea26243be0f9aff418c0e53">115</container>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                   altrender="microfilm box"
                                   id="aspace_847304025c64f9eaa1e9b7d8ac651163"
                                   type="reel">5U</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
                  <c id="ref128" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Sections 12-25</unittitle>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970391)"
                                   altrender="archive legal"
                                   id="aspace_ee1c17c0e83314c45b1a577e638c192f"
                                   type="box">8</container>
                        <container id="aspace_3f0f8edcf54a61eb9917352e9b70d52c"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_ee1c17c0e83314c45b1a577e638c192f">116</container>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075126996)"
                                   altrender="microfilm box"
                                   id="aspace_76a7b90e07f8957f22c1b956d97d57e8"
                                   type="reel">5U</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
                  <c id="ref129" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Sections 26-34</unittitle>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970391)"
                                   altrender="archive legal"
                                   id="aspace_2fe5cd8d15089a4f4e18b28b7d1efd73"
                                   type="box">8</container>
                        <container id="aspace_a696a5e5c0bd2c355584b87c86532d83"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_2fe5cd8d15089a4f4e18b28b7d1efd73">117</container>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                   altrender="microfilm box"
                                   id="aspace_902b1c590903b41a63fa131f0a86acae"
                                   type="reel">6U</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
                  <c id="ref130" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Sections 35-44</unittitle>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970391)"
                                   altrender="archive legal"
                                   id="aspace_746cfa2bffd55df09324ae1ab25b9880"
                                   type="box">8</container>
                        <container id="aspace_444452754c915f5bc1dcfa78b5f7b0c5"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_746cfa2bffd55df09324ae1ab25b9880">118</container>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                   altrender="microfilm box"
                                   id="aspace_93f49c398daa25435c3f60585a332eab"
                                   type="reel">6U</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
               </c>
               <c id="ref131" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Report to the king. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of an extensive report, addressed to King Philip V, analyzing requests made by the French ambassador to Spain.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive"> [ca.1730]</unitdate>
                  </did>
                  <c id="ref132" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Pages 41-134</unittitle>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970391)"
                                   altrender="archive legal"
                                   id="aspace_7b5579949abd57c2d9f89fff1ff1e673"
                                   type="box">8</container>
                        <container id="aspace_26b0a3d775442cd83f8f1092c3cd9940"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_7b5579949abd57c2d9f89fff1ff1e673">119</container>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                   altrender="microfilm box"
                                   id="aspace_631a08738dabd3580aa071f4d3889d66"
                                   type="reel">6U</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
                  <c id="ref133" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>pages 135-250</unittitle>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970391)"
                                   altrender="archive legal"
                                   id="aspace_459c53c15b59cee7895750cba4b211d7"
                                   type="box">8</container>
                        <container id="aspace_0db414b63999a992f0d35a39aea470bc"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_459c53c15b59cee7895750cba4b211d7">120</container>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                   altrender="microfilm box"
                                   id="aspace_99e10521dfa1ec19e07be3a54432e87e"
                                   type="reel">6U</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
               </c>
               <c id="ref134" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Marquis of Castelar. Title: "Declaración dada en 28 de henero, en nombre del rey de España, a los ministros de Ynglaterra, de Francia y de los Estados Generales de las Provincias Unidas." Place: Paris. Description: Memorial by the marquis of Castelar, plenipotentiary ambassador of King Philip V, addressed to the ministers of England, France and the Netherlands, announcing his withdrawal from the diplomatic negotiations held in Paris. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1731 January 28</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_4d23ca72ba79cc30eecf57cc8ec2635c"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_52d3e78d408b5c37215d52f1647257b6"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_4d23ca72ba79cc30eecf57cc8ec2635c">121</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_32b6249119dec182b2956f8781a3f038"
                                type="reel">6U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref135" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Memorial addressed to the General Inquisitor. Place: Madrid? Description: Copy of a memorial, addressed to the General Inquisitor, concerning the banning of Jesuit Gaspar de Astete's "Doctrina Christiana" by the Inquisition. The tribunal had banned the edition of the "Doctrina," printed in Valladolid by Alonso de el Riego, because it contained several doctrinal misinterpretations. The author of this memorial asked the Tribunal to allow the circulation of those editions printed prior to the Valladolid edition. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1736]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a67463cb123f602763bf240e8cbb66ba"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_76ccb33965f869ae511a97fea74c0c2d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a67463cb123f602763bf240e8cbb66ba">122</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_349c49b34c8008dcf2e64d9a6cbc7600"
                                type="reel">6U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref136" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal decree by the king. Place: El Pardo. Description: Copy of a royal decree by King Philip V nominating his son, Prince Philip, as general admiral of the Spanish naval forces. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1737 March 14</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_2ec5e1e559dcbf6332f89e35fa2d3e32"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_7b5e4a4c2daface9e3a7d121b1c8fc62"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2ec5e1e559dcbf6332f89e35fa2d3e32">123</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a4bcabdbe367b0ed3b5e1cbd81045d5c"
                                type="reel">6U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref137" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents on the Society of Jesus. Description: Three documents, two printed and one handwritten, related to the controversy between the city of Vitoria and the Society of Jesus over the plan for establishing an institution (college, asylum or residence) by the Jesuits in that city. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1737-1745</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_6b0402ae49b378837993972047947965"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b14a9fc47dfbab1c98023ba9f35a096e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6b0402ae49b378837993972047947965">124</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0bddb8f1a54478092046f2e78bbb6cad"
                                type="reel">6U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref138" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Dictamen político." Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a memorial by Joseph Laysequilla, the marquis of la Regalía, Joseph de la Quintana and Joseph de Carvajal, addressed to King Philip V, concerning the sanctions against foreigners who practiced illegal commerce in Spanish America. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1739 January 25</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_412db4f8e3219634b2aaa39f3ab9a527"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_16063662856585fb8ac596acead73b8d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_412db4f8e3219634b2aaa39f3ab9a527">125</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0c39acef4378d2886c82c354aafbb26a"
                                type="reel">6U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref139" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Memorial to King Philip V. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a memorial by the Council, addressed to King Philip V, establishing the policy to be followed by the Casa de Contratación of Seville with foreigners expelled from Spanish America for practicing illegal commerce in that region. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1739 April 18</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_cbf192b53a909be127bea9a2fc5bc361"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f10e67e09afec627f9c37e97563dec34"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_cbf192b53a909be127bea9a2fc5bc361">126</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127002)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_b34cb5b759c0bac484b85f6b9c8d2e2c"
                                type="reel">6U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref140" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter to José del Campillo y Cosio. Place: Madrid. Description: Letter by Diego de Bordick? To José del Campillo y Cosio, minister of the hacienda, in which Bordick? Presented a political plan for commercial development in the Spanish dominions. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1741 March 29</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_41a58258de1c954f39946b47683bb996"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5a303b02f27bf48e417ee34c5504a211"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_41a58258de1c954f39946b47683bb996">127</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127010)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_4deac6d0b3506096970436272cf80cfb"
                                type="reel">7U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref141" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Campillo y Cosio, José del. Title: "España despierta. Críticas e ynstructibas reflexsiones correspondientes a varios e importantísimos asuntos para la mejor organización y régimen de la monarquía española." Place: Madrid? Description: Copy of a plan by José del Campillo y Cosio for the reform of the government, administration, agriculture, commerce, legislation and society in Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1742 February 27</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_ed2a171bb4b6485e6b20cb4b660ac909"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3e085511442368eb362a05ac356dc015"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ed2a171bb4b6485e6b20cb4b660ac909">128</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127010)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_c37a95ed02107721e9286fb2b30c592b"
                                type="reel">7U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref142" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Memorials by the Spanish Catholic church. Places: Madrid, Zaragoza. Description: Copies of documents related to the collection of ecclesiastical contributions for the Spanish crown: "Memorial de la Santa Iglesia de Toledo, primada de España, al Nuncio de Su Santidad, sobre la contribución del ocho por ciento que se mandó exigir de los eclesiásticos" (n.d.); "Memorial de la Santa Iglesia de Toledo al rey" (n.d.); "Copia de carta de la Santa Iglesia de Toledo... En respuesta de otra del ... Señor arzobispo de Edesa, nuncio de su santidad, sobre la contribución del ocho por ciento" (n.d.); "Carta escripta al ... Señor nuncio de España por el ... Cavildo metropolitano de Zaragoza" (22 Feb 1742); "Respuesta del ... Nuncio a la antecedente" (Madrid, 3 Mar 1742); and "Carta del... Cavildo al ... Nuncio de España respondiendo a la antezedente" (Zaragoza, 13 Mar 1742). </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1742</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_32bbc8d723b7ddaf86d3df1a6e7590c9"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_fc802a9d55c5cf5429bed47866ff59b7"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_32bbc8d723b7ddaf86d3df1a6e7590c9">129</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127010)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0dc94248ff3c9776f521f0f3484fdfe5"
                                type="reel">7U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref143" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Campillo y Cosio, José del. Place: Madrid. Title: "Nuevo sistema de gobierno económico para la América. Con los males y daños que le causa el que hoy tiene de los que participa copiosísamente España. Y remedios universales para que la primera tenga considerables ventajas y la segunda mayores intereses. Primera parte." Place: Madrid. Description: Among the numerous texts written by Spanish authors to provide useful guides for economic and political reforms in colonial Spanish America, the "Nuevo sistema" by Campillo was perhaps the most significant and influential. Some historians have considered Campillo's text a source which inspired the Bourbon reforms. The text is handwritten and is probably a copy made at the time of the original. It is organized in ten chapters, and examines the role of colonial authorities as promoters of reforms, the development of commerce and agriculture, and control over local production and manufacture by the Spanish crown. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1743 February 8</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a0947041f505b0925b6c468e55f8f521"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_cc72366e30a032bccb429016e3ac4d57"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a0947041f505b0925b6c468e55f8f521">130</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127010)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a3c74cfe7dc91daa52e2d133a675f1b4"
                                type="reel">7U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref144" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents on the Inquisition of Llerena. Place: Buen Retiro, Madrid. Description: Copies of two documents related to the controversy between the Inquisition and the local authorities of Llerena: a consult by Alonso de Muñiz, bishop of Teruel and general inquisitor, to the Council of Castile, on the legal status of the officers (familiares) of the Inquisition; and a response by the Council of Castile. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1747</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_549fa91fbcc03e6a142a020884ed544a"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e10237c1abd4e54c091f39b99969a966"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_549fa91fbcc03e6a142a020884ed544a">131</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127010)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a909ea7aaa0e3f134dacc083d89cc9bb"
                                type="reel">7U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref145" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Casaus, Juan. Title: "Reflexiones de... Sobre los medios que se pueden tomar para el fomento de fábricas de todas especies y del comercio interno y externo de España." Description: Copy of plan by Juan Casaus for promoting manufacture and commerce in Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1748</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a604fba0bd037c32ac38f64fb62bd16c"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_18e9878f069237979a7f4bb5444030fd"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a604fba0bd037c32ac38f64fb62bd16c">132</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127010)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_30902b58db5875408060e2a0bd2d8fd8"
                                type="reel">7U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref146" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Pavía, Francisco. Title: "Proyecto... Para fomento del comercio, agricultura y fábricas de estos reinos." Description: Copy of a plan by Francisco Pavía for developing commerce, agriculture and manufacturing in Spain, and colonizing its territory.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1749</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970409)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_27760fa7b91de3ff5e2ab3ebf5b5e362"
                                type="box">9</container>
                     <container id="aspace_52d7517cb6dc3d8121682f91997b788c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_27760fa7b91de3ff5e2ab3ebf5b5e362">133</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127010)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_feefac5cd6face4f253715d2ce27389d"
                                type="reel">7U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref147" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents on tax reform. Place: Madrid. Description: Two documents on the plan to reform taxes: a printed "Real decreto de su magestad para que, con arreglo a la instrucción, formularios y planes que le acompañan, se averiguen los efectos en que pueden fundarse una sola contribución, para el mayor alivio de sus vasallos, en lugar de las que componen las rentas provinciales" (Buen Retiro, 10 October 1749); and a compilation entitled "órdenes y resoluciones de la Real Junta de la única contribución, desde diez y ocho de abril de 1750." The compilation includes an index. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1749-1754</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970417)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_4d5b0e77d461cba0489fb97b6135a9e3"
                                type="box">10</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1aa62b5d884c11a5aa5840b0c9affcc0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_4d5b0e77d461cba0489fb97b6135a9e3">134</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127010)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_6af5827500ccfc1293746180b35a0249"
                                type="reel">7U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref148" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Ordenanzas que en lo particular de la marina, navíos y buques... Ha formado la real compañía de comercio establecida en Barcelona." Description: Original text of the ordinances issued by the Real Compañía de Comercio, founded in Barcelona, to be followed by the crews of its ships involved in commerce with the islands of Santo Domingo, Puerto Rico and Margarita, and Honduras. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1756 May 4</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970417)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_ab56554f0982f6e313592053d28d6d07"
                                type="box">10</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e891cfc26270792c89daba2eed2db6de"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ab56554f0982f6e313592053d28d6d07">135</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_e2ed9141d2a0ace448bdfe24fae1c4e4"
                                type="reel">8U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref149" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Gandara, Miguel Antonio de la. Title: Report. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a report by Miguel Antonio de la Gandara, to the marquis of Campo de Villar, on a legal controversy with the bishop of Avila. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1760 March 31</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970417)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_306647485f87f9ae9d9759f77c5fae7c"
                                type="box">10</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9de5fe959f3a148fab853ea78ac5f48b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_306647485f87f9ae9d9759f77c5fae7c">136</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_d93504c631bf045c6320b67150284b05"
                                type="reel">8U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref150" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents related to the banning of the "Exposición de la doctrina christiana." Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of documents related to the controversy between the Spanish crown and the Inquisition over the banning of the catechism entitled "Exposición de la doctrina christiana sobre las principales verdades de la religión cathólica." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1761</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970417)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_7088c1183951606ca2a653c4fb949857"
                                type="box">10</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ec44d5d82dc5eea21bf1ad59918bf1bd"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7088c1183951606ca2a653c4fb949857">137</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_db099e92a848cdca90f321c57e5b5a51"
                                type="reel">8U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref151" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Aniceto a Cándido." Description: Partial draft of a discourse, with annotations probably by the author, on a plan to reform the society and economy of Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1762]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970417)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_be854ce068ce77fa43869556b36ecdb4"
                                type="box">10</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6478edf27c6267e5e0f17e4f0b372d78"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_be854ce068ce77fa43869556b36ecdb4">138</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_b4c0152676985b029b1413f7d7ae5a06"
                                type="reel">8U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref152" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Aniceto a Cándido." Description: Copy of text previously described.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive"> [ca.1762]</unitdate>
                  </did>
                  <c id="ref153" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Sections 1-12</unittitle>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970425)"
                                   altrender="archive half legal"
                                   id="aspace_b3be220cf62fdbc63fa5f74b089f791a"
                                   type="box">11</container>
                        <container id="aspace_7d2c21701ddaa3acb53e2b9a70c47a03"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_b3be220cf62fdbc63fa5f74b089f791a">139</container>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                   altrender="microfilm box"
                                   id="aspace_23e421b5f3d7acf7442afc38179ecf46"
                                   type="reel">8U</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
                  <c id="ref154" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Sections 13-29</unittitle>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970425)"
                                   altrender="archive half legal"
                                   id="aspace_5e5f1f076915503966a2dd0e2ad1f107"
                                   type="box">11</container>
                        <container id="aspace_34b2091a0a2b6f31d4b6567fcf771989"
                                   type="folder"
                                   parent="aspace_5e5f1f076915503966a2dd0e2ad1f107">140</container>
                        <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                   altrender="microfilm box"
                                   id="aspace_183e43a9266411be9daa22b701dd8969"
                                   type="reel">8U</container>
                     </did>
                  </c>
               </c>
               <c id="ref155" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Valle Salazar, Luis del. Title: Legal writ. Description: Draft of a legal writ by Luis Valle Salazar on the admission into Spain of the Jesuits expelled from France. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1762]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970425)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_4841efaaf307e76a96d08c3edf82f28a"
                                type="box">11</container>
                     <container id="aspace_273d812a1493f5feaf2360a7e7fc544f"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_4841efaaf307e76a96d08c3edf82f28a">141</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_361a80ab594bd8944769bb5bb7ae23f1"
                                type="reel">8U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref156" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Consult. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a consult by the Council of Castile, to King Charles III, on the election of the provincial of the Trinitarian order in Andalusia. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1765 January 9</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970425)"
                                altrender="archive half legal"
                                id="aspace_adfeb1aa92b5cef3d96d27c0dbfeaa3a"
                                type="box">11</container>
                     <container id="aspace_97f1d049a27c7185ed6b83bdbafb5a85"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_adfeb1aa92b5cef3d96d27c0dbfeaa3a">142</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_55d9a29a704148e32300e565e9fff159"
                                type="reel">8U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref157" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Memorial. Place: Madrid? Description: Draft and final version of an extensive memorial, addressed to King Charles III, on the payment of tithes by the Society of Jesus in Spanish America. Contains information on the three century controversy between the Society of Jesus and prelates and secular clergy over the payment of tithes. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca.1765]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970433)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_6761ba1bafa45c60570d5bf2968d4762"
                                type="box">12</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c65dfb7b56c6a161a10ee99269281efd"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6761ba1bafa45c60570d5bf2968d4762">143 - 144</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127028)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_065de0ee66304d26a39da31d5f1e2921"
                                type="reel">8U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref158" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Documents on the "labor de la nueva moneda." Place: Madrid. Description: Collection of consults and reports related to the minting of the new "vellón" coin. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1766-1773</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970433)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_63ca32dfc2a76709f6e7dc4f083e6f8f"
                                type="box">12</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9125917aa57f7a0fff8672bdb5618346"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_63ca32dfc2a76709f6e7dc4f083e6f8f">145 - 148</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127036)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_39da56bf7da7bfa35f8967a6f94cf464"
                                type="reel">9U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref159" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Correspondence between the pope, the Austrian empress and the king of Spain. Places: Rome, Viena, San Ildefonso. Description: Copies of three letter between the pope; Maria Theresa, empress of Austria; and Charles III, king of Spain; related to the papal censorship of the duke of Parma. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1768</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051970433)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_6e62e1be9d22b3fe0e152fc4a7d3c912"
                                type="box">12</container>
                     <container id="aspace_44e52bcf8cc10bd38218f16daad64527"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6e62e1be9d22b3fe0e152fc4a7d3c912">149</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127036)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_4fa2653b76e1ad64203c1275867a397e"
                                type="reel">9U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref161" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Part II</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1505-1891</unitdate>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_77f99a1933e11f94f0a04bcc04f84509">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Part II is 1.5 linear feet; the majority is comprised of originals and copies of materials from Spain. The collection includes state documents such as decrees, ordinances, wills and reports; ecclesiastical texts; church documents; correspondence; accounts of events; political writings; and literary texts. They cover a broad period of Spanish history, from the beginning of the sixteenth until the end of the nineteenth century. The majority of documents date to the period of the monarchs of the Bourbon dynasty: Philip V (1700-1746), Ferdinand VI (1746-1759), Charles III (1759-1788), and Charles IV (1788-1808).</p>
                  <p>Because King Charles II named a member of France's House of Bourbon, Philip, the duke of Anjou and a grandson of Louis XIV, as his successor, the French became deeply involved in Spanish affairs. This is best documented by a report on the conduct of the princess of Ursino in Spain, who came to dominate the royal court in the early years of the reign of Philip V (1700-1746).</p>
                  <p>The "Bourbon Reforms" were aimed at encouraging the social and economic development of Spain and her colonies. Most useful for the study of the reforms is a report by Francisco Cabarrus dealing with the need to grant the Banco de San Carlos a monopoly on silver extraction. There are materials by Manuel José de Ayala, a distinguished jurist, who sought to modernize and publish Spanish laws governing the Indies. They include an index to numerous volumes of Ayala's materials which show what he considered important to his legal thinking. Finally, there is a report urging the establishment of a new royal trading company for the Indies so that Spain, rather than other foreign powers, would profit from the Iberian empire.</p>
                  <p>The reign of Charles III (1759-1788) witnessed the beginning of the "Age of Revolution" when England's North American colonies fought for their independence. A report (1783) examining the threat that the newly independent United States posed to Spain's colonies sheds light on the impact of this event on Spain.</p>
                  <p>The reign of Charles IV (1788-1808) witnessed the French Revolution and its subsequent events, which culminated in the invasion of Spain by the forces of Napoleon in 1808. Several manuscripts capture the turbulence of the era, including a letter from the Spanish ambassador in Paris describing the state of Franco-Spanish relations; an appeal by Gaspar de Jovellanos, a dominant figure of the Spanish enlightenment, for justice after his imprisonment on Majorca; a report dealing with the Spanish defeat at the Battle of Trafalgar; and a denunciation of the French invasion by Pascual Solono y Noboa.</p>
                  <p>The Napoleonic invasion of Iberia led to the beginnings of independence movements in Spain's Latin American colonies. Spain's struggle to maintain its empire is documented in a series of reports discussing foreign trade in the Americas and seeking the re-establishment of the system of "comercio libre," as it had functioned prior to the wars; plans for the reconquest of the colonies detailing the means by which Spain could achieve this feat; and a diplomatic note from the American minister to Spain urging the king to accept the loss of the American colonies. In addition, a series of orders from the king of Spain addressed to the count of Cartagena detail the restoration of the "liberal" order in 1820.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c id="ref162" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal decree. Description: Decree issued by Queen Juana concerning the property rights of the duke of [Infantado?] in the Spanish cities of Guadarama and Colmenar Viejo. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1505 February 4</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_47fccd36067d0ba88b95df87616a045b"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4728456414cad701cbf86874c209231d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_47fccd36067d0ba88b95df87616a045b">1</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_cab4141ffa17ba3a4da2ca48052a33f4"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref163" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Miscellaneous index. Place: Madrid? Description: Index to a volume of miscellaneous documents. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1555-1632</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_949c6ce687db6f9791c0b4b8380fdd92"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0e9ed888f4a2d0f31d8a5be2135c1205"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_949c6ce687db6f9791c0b4b8380fdd92">2</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0b8cb492ee9f8aec6214680432b3dc05"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref164" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal grant. Description: Royal grant by King Philip II to Pedro Ribero, his heirs and successors. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1574 December 14</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_cb90bd8b8701505bc81eaf29b87e3f57"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9a98bec6059d72f4d733db5d84ffb441"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_cb90bd8b8701505bc81eaf29b87e3f57">3</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_987eed1a675f4643fe8a5bdf088ac1d7"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref165" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal instructions. Place: Vienna. Description: Series of instructions issued by King [Charles I?] of Spain to the heads of tribunals and civil departments concerning the conduct of public business. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[15--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_ea501ce0db0a98c62e96bd5ae4d53c9d"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_78d27902230d0cd558bf053d49fb5df4"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ea501ce0db0a98c62e96bd5ae4d53c9d">4</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_93bf961c7ad7c246777c4d721a58e756"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref166" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Brandon, Lorenco. Title: Report on money. Description: Handwritten copy of a report dealing with the value of silver and other issues related to currency. "British Museum, Papeles Varios 1322 l. 7 MS 1(3)" appears on the first page. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1623 August 18</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f39f1c2849874d6542e44b291e227ffe"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c61d3340d2638d1a87822e5e94da8d2c"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f39f1c2849874d6542e44b291e227ffe">5</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_2360fe4d94bc0aaa633db65f9f2df9d0"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref167" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Report on the seizure of Evora. Description: Report about the seizure of Evora, Portugal, by Spanish troops. The document includes a copy of a letter written by the Ottoman sultan to the king of Spain, and a listing of other news and events. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1663-1664</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_e7beea94ad97b1fec1a226459c1a1296"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9be24d68acfd6788da9060dfe1478c01"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e7beea94ad97b1fec1a226459c1a1296">6</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_f532df74d3d2f88a1c4d4cf17826ffa2"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref168" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación del memorial que el Señor Duque de Medina presentó a su magestad...." Place: Madrid. Description: Request by the duke of Medina Celi that he be allowed to resign as prime minister. King Charles II grants the request., </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1685 April 18</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_0678c01c2cde1839cceb0f9871f25209"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_591a5cbd396df9e9380adcbb04cdf091"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0678c01c2cde1839cceb0f9871f25209">7</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_32717e44fb4cdfd824d66139862bb79b"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref169" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Archival guide. Description: Handwritten guide to an unidentified record group in a [Spanish?] archive. A brief summary of each document is provided. These documents mainly deal with currency issues and the silver trade. In Spanish with some English passages. "Papeles Varios 1322, L. 7, 1-40" appears on the first page of the text. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1686</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_39bc5ad807a6a621cf56e5101713f4ef"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8a1203de151f2ab2c929fdf6dd10887b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_39bc5ad807a6a621cf56e5101713f4ef">8</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_8caed3d00099f016f5deaaa4997e1550"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref170" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter from the king of Spain to the bishop of Pamplona. Place: Madrid. Description: Letter dealing with the resolution of a conflict over ecclesiastical immunity in the Kingdom of Navarre. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1695 March 24</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a05365be65538ea2869f93c058ca6cf8"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2e37bfe49d24a970a055093e01c20679"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a05365be65538ea2869f93c058ca6cf8">9</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a5f116812f29da4956f8e9a5d2dc2b6c"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref171" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by the Emperor Leopold to Pope Innocent XII. Place: Vienna. Description: Letter concerning the way in which the Spanish Inquisition was proceeding against banned texts. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1696 January 20</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_db153d79aaa210a3724f91a7e193be09"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_7fab31983fc13f2e7156f6cb3c0eba6a"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_db153d79aaa210a3724f91a7e193be09">10</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_dc9a229d3eee98b04f5e915c28addab0"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref172" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Last will and testament of the Queen Mother. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of the last will and testament of Mariana de Austria, wife of Philip IV, and mother of Charles II of Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1696 May 10</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_54d36b088bf73112710175f37b007482"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_bfce3bf910d46f2b02287686a2658aa3"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_54d36b088bf73112710175f37b007482">11</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0bb5bbe6f8d2a52936cde4ee88375d85"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref173" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación de achaques y muerte de su magestad la reyna madre de nuestro monarcha." Place: Madrid? Description: Report which briefly describes the illness suffered by the Spanish queen mother. Also detailed are the funeral honors accorded her. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1696</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_e152c649556e5f394217ff92bb21035f"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_87aec451673cdbfcbdfb0c1bb7b267e1"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e152c649556e5f394217ff92bb21035f">12</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_49dc9a03a81940253dd8ef4a63cceaaf"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref174" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Defensa de la Valtelina en su procedimientos contra los Grisones." Description: Brief document stating offenses committed against the Catholic faith, and within the temporal realm, by the Grisones, a confederated people living in northern Italy, who controlled the Valley of Valtelina. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[16--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_8c07ae8ff798e2d4a33732f4cd558c4b"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a12ad2382862684cabb94461e8f815df"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8c07ae8ff798e2d4a33732f4cd558c4b">13</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_1191b499e47d54df698235f983c97942"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref175" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by Miguel Calderon de la Barca to the duchess of Medina Sedonia. Description: Correspondence about the loss of letters concerning an encomienda in Campeche. Copies of the original letters are also included. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1712 May 30</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_8e87ab79e85c88be7177dc3ec9ad3078"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_fb5696a39b4b74a29b061f90687c1ff7"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8e87ab79e85c88be7177dc3ec9ad3078">14</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_7ef1b6ac46304c84964dacea4bff359b"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref176" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Papeles varios." Description: Bound handwritten volume which contains speeches, discourses, poetry, proclamations, military documents, and other writings by, or copied by, [François Antoine Boissy 'Anglas?] </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1744-1813</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_260f28585a74ba8f991c3b4c51bd2838"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_36752bb9714c8ce55dac565b6c33144e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_260f28585a74ba8f991c3b4c51bd2838">15</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_6f0463acf9b2b2d801bdbef3d0e64763"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref177" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Valuation. Place: New Orleans. Description: Handwritten English language copy of a valuation of all buildings owned by the king, in New Orleans, made by public officials and representatives from the building trades. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1769, 1819</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_84137ff3aaa3a8467cde8432e20940be"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_040bf864f6a54402dd5f4f02fdc625df"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_84137ff3aaa3a8467cde8432e20940be">16</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_dd77d169c38ae4cc06833f11af8945aa"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref178" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Confirmation of baptism. Description: Document confirming that on January 4, 1756, Manuel Silvestre de Conde was baptized in the Catholic faith. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1774 April 15</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_532ad913f1547b633b8960e35ef48612"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0ab4644aa04d95bcec6fe7ebf54b5ec5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_532ad913f1547b633b8960e35ef48612">17</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_5c0869612355ffe914475d7ce8351dbf"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref179" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Ship Registries. Place: Cádiz. Description: Printed registries of the "fragata" La Aguila and the "navio" La Concepción. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1776 January 11-18</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_3061310bfa1c8c4d0d071f516e313f16"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3f40cc8e1569212b9fbe3c842ef04784"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_3061310bfa1c8c4d0d071f516e313f16">18</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_ea672f7934bb9d89fe59a21d6b42a3f0"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref180" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Diary. Place: Rome? Description: The diary, in Spanish, of an unidentified individual, probably written in Rome. The text records notable events of the time in Spain, Italy, Germany, Russia, Turkey, and other locations. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1782 January - 1783 February</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_573e9cbb876064a69a3425a93d0ee8fa"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ce47116b165ee5410b77a32d22e98916"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_573e9cbb876064a69a3425a93d0ee8fa">19</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_c37c0aaf71aa1c724cbc379172fc9219"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref181" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Cabarrus, Francisco. Title: Report concerning silver extraction. Description: Report concerning the need to grant the recently established Banco de San Carlos (national bank) a monopoly on silver extraction (extracción). </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1783 September 5</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_6d8bbd2728dc2e59f83b88a75917be3a"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d053da0e3b5a0ae1e03def4d85dd15ca"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6d8bbd2728dc2e59f83b88a75917be3a">20</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_bbf37e50fbb136cee4d9f1166f4abb95"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref182" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Dictamen reservado que el Conde de Aranda dió al rey sobre la independencia de las colonias ingleses, después de haber firmado el tratado de paz ajustado en Paris en el año de 1783." Description: Handwritten report to the king of Spain analyzing the threat that the newly independent United States posed to the Spanish empire. The report proposed creating three new Spanish kingdoms in the New World. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1783</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_0c619997785c823803e2adeb1de4adb7"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ebcd1626879960f0c4dcfed2e92792d0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0c619997785c823803e2adeb1de4adb7">21</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_04b65b132b516aabb47b4123e0088016"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref183" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Dictamen reservado que el Conde de Aranda dió al rey sobre la independencia de las colonias ingleses, después de haber firmado el tratado de paz ajustado en Paris en el año de 1783." Description: Copy, identical to previous entry. NOT FILMED. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca. 1783]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_c3f24ec0a81718e3629c56502b01f862"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5d6ac42910fee74501e1795c9b0448b8"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c3f24ec0a81718e3629c56502b01f862">22</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_5160a208839e65706db7fa2f1a2f9e31"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref184" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Memoria secreta presentada al rey Carlos III por el S.E. el Conde de Aranda sobre la independencia de las colonias ingleses después de haber firmado el tratado de Paris de 1783." Description: Copy, identical to previous entry. NOT FILMED. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca. 1783]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_03ef0451c4c8c0f13e93cbe6bb4cfa84"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_80115149b0df21c6c4054885ba187aec"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_03ef0451c4c8c0f13e93cbe6bb4cfa84">23</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_d195fac0eccbd15d8da84753b43963c1"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref185" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter. Place: Havana. Description: Letter in French by Bernardo de Galvez to Mr. Le Cheval de Montaill concerning Louisiana. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1787 August 16</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_812f5954dac3595f3ab228fa3ce8bbcd"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b680a3a9cee5dcc206a06c1a16f569ec"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_812f5954dac3595f3ab228fa3ce8bbcd">24</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_2bda6a6c956fa214150b3f17f60cb24b"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref186" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Report on the Kingdom of Galicia. Description: Report on the Spanish region of Galicia, covering population, migration, agriculture, industry, commerce, economic geography and development issues. ]</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[ca. 1787</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_30734387fe3d7b35f0969469928792b0"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2e5249a93737408d8d828ad1f5b657d6"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_30734387fe3d7b35f0969469928792b0">25</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_92f2575827fd47b74684aa566d9a4a7d"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref187" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Ayala, Manuel José de. Title: Índice del diccionario de gobierno y legislación de Indias y España. Place: Madrid. Description: A printed alphabetical index listing of subject headings. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1792</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_0c7e9c1446d48186e2aa56a8454962b8"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_be9394427d33c34fabb334cf40dd9266"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0c7e9c1446d48186e2aa56a8454962b8">26</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_56191e6a608772b84dbd1072def7ecd7"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref188" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter by the Marquis of Feria. Place: Madrid. Description: Letter from the Marquis of Feria to his brother, José, concerning the death of the Marquis of Valdelirios and other personal matters. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1793 May 25</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_baedf8b2cdeeb2859fbecad9fc1a9f13"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c6474f7789a78ca1fd4e078c1b931534"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_baedf8b2cdeeb2859fbecad9fc1a9f13">27</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_12b9d0129e61565ce05046ea41f427e9"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref189" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Carta del Señor Azara, embajador en Paris al exmo. Señor príncipe de la paz." Place: Barcelona. Description: Handwritten copy of a letter from the Spanish ambassador to France to the prince of Spain concerning Franco-Spanish relations and the ambassador's activities in Paris. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1799 November 26</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_69e33de47535b9e3184bbd93a87d8793"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3b47e39599866ea79ff4c405293c3c93"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_69e33de47535b9e3184bbd93a87d8793">28</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_128b8cbc048e43e97e5473d5ed98c576"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref190" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Relación de como se entienda los nobles ydalgos y los labradores pecheros del Señorío de Vizcaia y las rentas y y tierras que se le dieron a Juan Zuria por los vizcainos y sus antigüedades el año 773." Description: History which traces the lineage of the occupants of the office. The text also lists the lands and income the Vizcainos (Basques) ceded to Juan Zuria, the first señorío. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911874)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_bff18541cac9c1f8d4c9ce5f3ad698db"
                                type="box">13</container>
                     <container id="aspace_aabc42fe2bd64fc6203a546139216bb2"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_bff18541cac9c1f8d4c9ce5f3ad698db">29</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_866b909760ddfad85678d6f2a3ed709c"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref191" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Índice general de todos los papeles contenidos en los tomos de miscelanea." Description: Handwritten bound volume describing every document found in forty three volumes of miscellaneous papers belonging to Manuel Joséde Ayala, the distinguished Spanish jurist. Many documents deal with the New World. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_2cce195b93cbabf34849f61fc165a694"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ad177626a4c0eb1be426c234b8baeb62"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2cce195b93cbabf34849f61fc165a694">30</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_1c7d7b7704f63252733cb945c8467579"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref192" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Proyecto del establecimiento de un compañía de Indias en España en beneficio evidente del real erario...." Description: Detailed plan for the creation of a new royal trading company so that Spain, rather than other European powers, would profit from its empire. The plan called for dramatically increasing the size of the Spanish navy. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_2aca0e89b4db367731dd2ba81f57296a"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3356b9f3cdf3af635227edef5a3c1216"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2aca0e89b4db367731dd2ba81f57296a">31</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_aad0f7ebe4a29e702b15b30798e093a3"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref193" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Tratado de la navegación de Beregeron, Capítulo 23." Description: Portion of a text written by an unidentified [French?] author refuting Spain's claims to exclusive control over the New World. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_7c8d35bb3dba0876da96e33766d106bf"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5eb117373a609afdfcb8ca2f6f0d4960"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7c8d35bb3dba0876da96e33766d106bf">32</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_3ec9fa2c5a3d2b1b0045d32272cc2d87"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref194" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Noticia general de el estado de todas las dependencias que incluie la Nueva España y de el desorden conque actualmente subsisten." Description: Brief report dealing with problems facing New Spain at all levels of government. The text also describes the challenges facing the church, the treasury, the army, and the navy. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_3aa24df157a8e0d2f6f6572ca61b7bce"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1206961ca6550977db007952f6deb222"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_3aa24df157a8e0d2f6f6572ca61b7bce">33</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_148ab83c4ff5f7ae25fef863a7f9c32f"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref195" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Mariana, Juan de. Title: "Discurso de las cosas de la compañía escrito por el Padre Juan de Mariana." Description: An attack on the Society of Jesus (Jesuits) by a member of the order.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_17b827da8716648d6d62a0f9e94da709"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_427fcddace3d2a6bc5f88d9edff08910"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_17b827da8716648d6d62a0f9e94da709">34</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_c472a2c82dcbdbed0a1bb67a37c78f67"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref196" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Carta del....Antonio de Monroy....Arzobispo de Santiago, escrita al Marqués de Mejorada en respuesta de los decretos y manifestos que se expedieron en Madrid contra el summo Pontífice el Senor Clemente Undecimo." Description: Letter written by the archbishop of Santiago de Compostela to a member of the Spanish cabinet concerning denunciations of Pope Clement XI emanating from the Spanish court. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f5e89329fc4c6219c52574cc368b7868"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4c4a3cda5dd61f1f2853f9ccfaf0e899"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f5e89329fc4c6219c52574cc368b7868">35</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127044)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_6cb31b449aa7f79ca3940dfaa56e1a6d"
                                type="reel">10U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref197" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Arias Montaño, Benito? Title: "Monita secreta de los jesuitas"? Description: Handwritten copy of an anti-Jesuit treatise falsely attributed to Montaño, who was a confessor of Philip II of Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_0fd3bbdb98ba31e784aa52884302f2f1"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f852aadc95a9ce87ac3991c1863a5ca0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0fd3bbdb98ba31e784aa52884302f2f1">36</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a45d16e52edd907c30385e0a9dabdc9e"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref198" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: [Ayala, Manuel José de?] Title: Dictionary. Description: Handwritten transcript of dictionary entries (abastos-artilleria) of legal terms. This copy was made in 1849 from the Ayala collection of the Royal Library in Madrid by Domingo del Monte. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_81b8e677d0ed3eba9e3c133a458983ca"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b88cfce034fb364c4b10ca8d2f1be180"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_81b8e677d0ed3eba9e3c133a458983ca">37</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_2197176feaa2e62c2bff08092a05f527"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref199" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Conducta de la Princesa de los Ursinos en el gavinete del rey cristianisimo en presencia de Madama de Maintenon...." Description: A report about the Princess Ursino, who dominated the Spanish court in the early eighteenth century. The text reviews Spanish affairs at the time and describes the princess's activities. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_884713b2c6a281bbd178ecb382a35b79"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2bf84d987a1202d56004491b1040fd27"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_884713b2c6a281bbd178ecb382a35b79">38</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_512165518ed54813c403325c5cee263c"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref200" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Descripción de la corte de Roma." Place: Madrid? Description: Report detailing the composition and duties of officials in the Papal court in Rome. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_1baa0ce4a8a4982855f487e25561af72"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c89b2333b8748f616ce79022557097e1"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1baa0ce4a8a4982855f487e25561af72">39</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_26b8774be8912736964633d3555f66b2"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref201" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Concordia fratrum minorum de observantia cum serenissimo et catholico Rege Ferdinando intia impressa et subscripta a ministro et vicario generalibus, signata sigillis suis sic incipiens." Description: Copy of a document in Latin concerning King Ferdinand of Spain.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_a7b16383e5ea0f54265fa842ac583d37"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_72aea11098129db38d8ab81921bf67ff"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a7b16383e5ea0f54265fa842ac583d37">40</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_97747c67b49320f8c8dab48644d1f318"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref202" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "En la casa real de España los confesores de los reyes...." Place: Madrid? Description: Document describing the history and duties of the confessor to the king of Spain. Also included are lists of the confessors of the kings and queens of Spain. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[17--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_796d4cb59fdca123baf79942b402a790"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_56e88c334b338b7d16b2cfbb82717b29"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_796d4cb59fdca123baf79942b402a790">41</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_f17e1f6f31e2fea08493e604d17accfa"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref203" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Notarial act. Place: New Orleans. Description: Notarized act of sale of a plantation, located up river from New Orleans, by Eduardo Fortall to Pedro Sauve. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1801 September 19</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f42285e9888335faa0377c267759e6b9"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0beffa32ea2629cad4ee08ffb99601d3"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f42285e9888335faa0377c267759e6b9">42</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_b6ffc783c8e715827e42abf0c9080246"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref204" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Jovellanos, Gaspar de. Title: "Representationes." Place: Mallorca. Description: An appeal to the king of Spain for justice by this well-known figure of the Spanish enlightenment following his arrest and imprisonment. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1801</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_1542e6a01272f9baf517d33eca2f4458"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_186a32b563b42ed13633711d4e3bec29"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1542e6a01272f9baf517d33eca2f4458">43</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_8d8bc2ba2ca4cdf78f1c86c7869d9131"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref205" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter and article. Places: Lisbon, Madrid. Description: Copy of a short laudatory letter to the [king of Portugal?] about the restoration of silk factories in Braganza. Also included is a handwritten copy of an article that appeared in the Gazeta de Madrid, with the dateline Paris, about a debate on the French divorce law. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1803</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_853d022ff01e51e77e2095ba8fd68b95"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f532bdcd50b2d5fc85f1fdf85cf7c4bd"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_853d022ff01e51e77e2095ba8fd68b95">44</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_59ef7cab8078082d0c93cfd14be54593"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref206" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Suplemento a la orden del día 6 de noviembre del 1805 en la guarnición de Cádiz." Place: Cádiz. Description: Report which describes the French victory at the battle of Caldiero. The text also discusses the battle of Trafalgar in detail. Included are lists of the condition of each Spanish and French ship after Trafalgar, and rosters of dead and wounded Spanish naval officers. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1805 November 6</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_9fd2d2eb0cad7b34ae7a3318100921ae"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_135e1439e52b45a83bc73cb35246f397"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_9fd2d2eb0cad7b34ae7a3318100921ae">45</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_a9da85f17c9dd00b1ae15ef824463357"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref207" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal order. Place: Aranjuez. Description: Royal order dealing with the establishment of a fund to cover the expenses of the "juzgado de artillería." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1807 January 22</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911882)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_3feb7997d5f801e02ddb22daf96e73dd"
                                type="box">14</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2e2e983e4030276ae8414b9a6a6da761"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_3feb7997d5f801e02ddb22daf96e73dd">46</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_8a52c8c7d6a14e86a99c33efcfbd7808"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref208" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Solanos y Noboa, Pasqual. Title: "Acusación contra el gobierno francés." Place: Cádiz? Description: A denunciation of the French government for its invasion of Spain. The accusations are principally based on arguments of natural law. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1808</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_46582536cb6d28cf157e0ac84087e711"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_faa218aeca675e78cedcc86f8b449b59"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_46582536cb6d28cf157e0ac84087e711">47</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_8f381472038410cc941ad1adb8952d6c"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref209" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Complaint concerning a merchant. Place: Madrid. Description: Letter written by Martin Antonio de Huizi to the count of Cabarras concerning the character of a merchant. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1809 February 10</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_9a53512a13f5f3c6dedc366bcbe4f1af"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_77938f848eee79b0fb4058c105f65627"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_9a53512a13f5f3c6dedc366bcbe4f1af">48</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_7f59338c774e0c68b6f998a1be559d73"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref210" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal decree. Place: Madrid. Description: Printed copy of the royal decree in which the king of Spain re-established the Council of the Indies. Also included are handwritten lists of the council's members and a statement of the body's finances. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1814</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_b2b8482877743aa478feac4c346fc0a3"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_eb4d26a83594b00ff485475ab7cd184b"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_b2b8482877743aa478feac4c346fc0a3">49</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_cf29d81a40c271726fffee8892bbab8d"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref211" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Report on trade with the Americas. Place: Madrid. Description: Report by a Spanish commission concerning the issue of foreign trade with the Americas. The report examines the economic relations other European powers maintained with their colonies, and refutes arguments about Spain's inability to carry on trade with her colonies. The group endorses the restoration of the system of "comercio libre," established in 1778. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1817 July 24</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_af5d8cd03c49f0f07e1979a67b9c259d"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5b696b9fb1e849dfbad4452b1937847e"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_af5d8cd03c49f0f07e1979a67b9c259d">50</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_f9e3fbd1171866efce6f94698bb85658"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref212" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Sobre la pacificación de América." Place: Madrid. Description: Lengthy defense of Spain's rule of the American colonies, by an unidentified author. The text blames the Americans for the various independence movements in the region; details the virtues of the Spanish imperial system; discusses trade by foreigners with the colonies; and concludes by laying out the bases for imperial trade within the framework of the 1778 decree of "comercio libre." </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1817</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_fc3f096911d970df5ffe56068e647453"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1f7fab015a550359331922a99d469a6f"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_fc3f096911d970df5ffe56068e647453">51</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_871915d60e6199d9b8da38ecaddee246"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref213" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Royal orders. Place: Madrid. Description: A series of handwritten and printed orders by the king of Spain directed to the count of Cartagena. The dispatches deal with royal appointments, political affairs, constitutional reform and military matters; many are on the letterhead of the Ministry of War. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1820 March - October</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_f8db14ab9c04b07de108bc5d68ecb232"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_85d6b64ddf944e197abac5adfea891ca"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f8db14ab9c04b07de108bc5d68ecb232">52</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_f1a93d3362c98af92a8cb14154b2d504"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref214" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Diplomatic correspondence. Place: Madrid. Description: Copies of two brief letters exchanged by the French and American ministers to Spain, written in French. Also included is a letter from the papal nuncio to the Spanish minister of state, written in Italian. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1823</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_cddc1b47ffadba20fa547c434dc72e1d"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_103915b3169978f41f1a14eaf941a0e5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_cddc1b47ffadba20fa547c434dc72e1d">53</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_3e5c268f9eb319b8a8ac4e5a6db0209b"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref215" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Everett, A. H. Title: Diplomatic note to the king of Spain. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy of a letter from the American minister to Spain which explains United States policy towards Latin America, and urges the king of Spain to accept the independence of the Latin American colonies. The letter explains how Spain could prosper from increased trade with its former colonies. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1826 January 20</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_ac739cd02e5d4d5e8f696d073249b38a"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_02ac7d7cbef3329714917b237e9db635"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_ac739cd02e5d4d5e8f696d073249b38a">54</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_ed7ba3cefee4fed7aead4649c98d9f74"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref216" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Author: Everett, A. H. Title: Diplomatic note to the king of Spain. Place: Madrid. Description: Copy, identical to previous entry. NOT FILMED. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1826 January 20</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_d78b53e7b83476bd41144de93cecb2c4"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_66ac9b5492799333e32836d8638128c2"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d78b53e7b83476bd41144de93cecb2c4">55</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_cf8a37500415a06830404d48976ef411"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref217" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Letter to Reverendo Alcala. Place: Madrid. Description: Letter to the bishop of Madrid from A. W. Wheeler, requesting a promised letter of introduction, with typescript English summary. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1891 March 30</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_919c9243ae6c73bdbc5e38f86b206e1a"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c64dc4a4dfc17328b77d9e24b03350c0"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_919c9243ae6c73bdbc5e38f86b206e1a">56</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_85dce1ec8e38932598e8685870a4ba8a"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref218" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Demonstración de la facilidad en los medios para que se efectué la reconquista de América, indicada en los observaciones anteriores." Description: Report, by an unknown author, laying out a plan for the reconquest of Spain's American colonies. The majority of the report deals with how to carry out the plan and how to pay for it. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[18--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_d0f8fc322c7df5d1584f8d0beee44532"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2d7bed8f1616aed67074a23528a168b3"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d0f8fc322c7df5d1584f8d0beee44532">57</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_38b9f6ebda0198f6bfea6a44c54cb0c2"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref219" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Observaciones sobre los estados de América Española y su restauración." Description: Treatise dealing with the effect which the permanent loss of the American colonies would have on Spain and the means available to the Spanish crown to deal with the situation. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">[18--?]</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_062a77c1d0c394bcc78b1dc5eedc341a"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c0a47c3def85e7d4d47d28bfbd08b037"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_062a77c1d0c394bcc78b1dc5eedc341a">58</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0973ddb2dfe65e9b3cecf9930394ee1f"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref220" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Carta al rey del....Fray Juan de Montalvan." Description: Letter from the bishop of Guadix to the king of Spain dealing with problems facing the monarchy. </unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_e01bdeba23c0b319ef2d9c148ade5a9d"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_61b9a8cfa3cb55a587652fb46f3800ad"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e01bdeba23c0b319ef2d9c148ade5a9d">59</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_3f09538c8a1c281d6116a9ce7aa135d3"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref221" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Report on an earthquake. Place: [Philippines?] Description: Report detailing the damage resulting from an earthquake that occurred on November 30 [no year given] at 8:00 P.M.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_8e2c10738e84c1cfe0ae34f36fe71be0"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0bd03ebc3010113464ad663bc04054e5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8e2c10738e84c1cfe0ae34f36fe71be0">60</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_d604ef0f2675b315aa62930b86b0517c"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref222" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Fiestas de ceremonias para el cabildo." Description: List of official days of religious ceremonies observed by the members of the cabildo of an unidentified city.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_108ca5262576c0fbfcaeb72864c52082"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c12276a1332d53cc8fb77b051ba7e15d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_108ca5262576c0fbfcaeb72864c52082">61</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_4ec6183174d8cd90c4ee00f070be7e42"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref223" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: "Origen de los Agotes." Description: Brief text describing the origins and history of the Agotes, a linage or clan group who lived in Navarre and Aragon.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_2304a0127ec100fd00bce25708c91612"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1e2b9a4b4d986c00e9f1de346ebf367d"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2304a0127ec100fd00bce25708c91612">62</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_0069532c4c6e295daf112781c84c4f3e"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref224" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Title: Miscellaneous index. Description: One page index listing documents from unknown volume.</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051911890)"
                                altrender="archive legal"
                                id="aspace_6edb4085a383125ff86e1a637b875e9b"
                                type="box">15</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9a1707e07dfef3368978c94fe71870e5"
                                type="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6edb4085a383125ff86e1a637b875e9b">63</container>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075127051)"
                                altrender="microfilm box"
                                id="aspace_646bd949f52ffc002ba5856bc02a242d"
                                type="reel">11U</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref226" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Duplicating negatives</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002051990696)"
                             altrender="card box (4d 9h 11w)"
                             id="aspace_96be5a7a8d650f795fa9120f19aaf96a"
                             type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
