<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ru.1058">mssa.ru.1058</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Women Faculty Forum, Yale University, Records
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Women Faculty Forum, Yale University, Records</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Daniel Hartwig</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:title="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>January 2007</date>
            <num>RU 1058</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Friday January 11, 2019 at 09:43</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Women Faculty Forum, Yale University, records</unittitle>
         <unitid>RU 1058</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">1.75</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(1 box)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2006/2006">2006-2006</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_bdba02fd6dac141c04d2dcedb5bff680">The materials consist of posters created during a campus-wide poster session "Scholarship by Women/Research on Gender," hosted by the Yale Women Faculty Forum, November 7-9, 2006.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="local">
               Yale University. Women Faculty Forum
            </corpname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <odd id="aspace_be594ecd7ab7e905abbe6f15f1e10ac5">
         <head>General note</head>
         <p>Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG-37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.</p>  
      </odd>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_162b204425a34feee49efc8bb3d2a1a5">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The materials were transferred from the Women Faculty Forum, 2007.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_2ae358c6b2b37b5387ed5587f54159f2">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_f5735d4a064f33714872a23b500c4e27">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Women Faculty Forum, Yale University, Records (RU 1058). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_29fc87c599e2c9c7321c71f4deeac7e0">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Yale University records are arranged and described at the accession level by the creating office. The University Archives creates collection level descriptive records, but typically does no further arrangement and description at the accession level.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <arrangement id="aspace_8e25e329e146b8ec16b5483f3f22c3f7">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The records are arranged by poster number.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <bioghist id="aspace_0ccd69ad72267d4e2e969b82449ae382">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Yale Women Faculty Forum (WFF) emerged from the effort, during Yale's tercentennial year, to highlight the presence of women at the university and the accomplishments of Yale alumnae. The WFF is supported by the offices of the president and provost and administered by the Council of the WFF. The WFF works in conjunction with alumni/alumnae and interested faculty and students to foster community for women at Yale and to deepen the understanding of the effects and implications of gender on all fields of thought.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_483a849e8a90b2f6e210745c2296ffbc">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The materials consist of posters created during a campus-wide poster session "Scholarship by Women/Research on Gender," hosted by the Yale Women Faculty Forum, November 7-9, 2006.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="local">
            College teachers -- Societies, etc.
         </subject>
         <subject source="local">
            Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Societies, etc.
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85060757"
                  source="lcsh">
            Women -- Education (Higher)
         </subject>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043367"
                   source="naf">
            Yale University -- Employees -- Societies, etc.
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043367"
                   source="naf">
            Yale University -- Faculty -- Societies, etc.
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043367"
                   source="naf">
            Yale University -- Societies, etc.
         </corpname>
         <corpname source="local">
            Yale University. Women Faculty Forum
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref11" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Women Faculty Forum poster session, "Scholarship by Women/Research on Gender"</unittitle>
               <unitid>Accession 2008-A-025</unitid>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">2006</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6d19134d2e823db4dcac51cb43a38755">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The Yale Women Faculty Forum hosted a campus-wide poster session on November 7-9, 2006. The session encouraged faculty, students and staff to use a visual medium to present research, advocacy, and discussions taking place on campus by, for, and on women. Poster size was limited to 11 x 17. Some were handmade; other posters were developed electronically. Contributions were received from across the disciplines at Yale and represent an array of work being done on campus from the Nursing school to the Divinity school and almost every campus location in between.</p>
               <p>The posters were hung on Beinecke Plaza for three days using a system of "clothesline" hanging for display. The method is similar to that used by the Yale Women's Center during the Take Back the Night rally. The clothesline also referenced the stereotypes surround women's household labor juxtaposed with the poster content on scholarship, research, writing, and activism by women and on gender.</p>
               <p>The posters have toured libraries across campus - Medicine, Social Sciences, Forestry, and Divinity, and the MacMillan Center for International and Area Studies.</p>
               <p>The following abstracts were written by the the poster creators.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1. Ivy Alexander, Associate Professor of Nursing (collaborators: Susan Wysocki, R.G. Miller, M. Bolognese).</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_2291d110b898eb373e0235b7f2962565"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_941b35bc856d136697278675ec3c65d9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Study described intended to explore practice patterns and continuing education needs for identifying and treating OP, criteria used for testing, and knowledge about OP amongpracticing APNs. An internet survey was administered to APNs nationwide asking fordemographics, OP knowledge and interest, BMD testing patterns, prevention and treatment strategies, and sources used and preferred for continuing education. Data were analyzed using nominal statistics. APNs are actively involved in OP screening, prevention, and treatment. Important areas identified for further education include screening guidelines; medication selection, side effects, and long term effects; and BMD monitoring. Abstract and Poster presented at North American Menopause Society Meeting, October 12- 14, 2006, Nashville, TN.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>2. Ivy Alexander, Associate Professor of Nursing (collaborators: Susan Wysocki, Redonda I. Miller, Michael A. Bolognese, and Thomas R. Lengle).</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_79970294226d4d4633f6938ef9b59064"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c59bc4bd63855f336faa3e2d52c6a639">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Osteoporosis and osteopenia are silent processes. Although the Surgeon General has estimated that 44 million Americans have bone loss, the prevalence may be higher. This study was undertaken to identify risk factors and frequency of positive heel scan screenings for osteoporosis and osteopenia in a convenience sample of essentially healthy women attending NP conferences. Implications for women's health: The actual prevalence of low or osteoporotic bone density may be greater than currently estimated. A significant number of participants had low or osteoporotic HBMD screenings, suggesting the need for further testing (eg, DXA). Additionally, despite greater risk factors and older age, fewer NPWH NPs had low or osteoporotic HBMD, perhaps reflecting a protective effect from their higher use of HT and lower use of alcohol and carbonated beverages. Further study is needed to determine the significance of these factors. Abstract and poster presented at the National Association of Nurse Practitioners in Women's Health Meeting, September 28-30, 2006.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>3. Linda Anderson, Women's, Gender and Sexuality Studies Senior Administrative Assistant.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_871027ab699de8b995c7ee85fca1f43e"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e7c2405054aac50a01f2dda0f3c79115">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>In September of 2001, I went shopping at the local Urban Outfitters store in New Haven, walked up the stairs to the men's department, and came across a red t-shirt emblazoned with the design depicted in the photo. I was horrified by the implication of violence against women, and told the saleswoman that I thought the shirt should not be sold. She said, "Oh, you'll have to talk with the manager about that." I asked if the manager was in, and several minutes later, another woman came over to me, and I explained how I felt this t-shirt design was extremely offensive towards women. She said, "Oh, we don"t choose the merchandise; you'll have to talk with the buyer about that."in her Introduction to Women's Studies class as an example of what one person can do. A student in her class happened to work for the <title render="italic">
                        Yale Daily News
                     </title>, was interested in my action and interviewed me. The story was printed in the newspaper with numerous responses to what I had done, ranging from support for my part in trying to end violence against women, to tirades against me for trying to curtail free speech.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>4. Seyla Benhabib, Eugene Meyer Professor of Political Science and Philosophy.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_93ba688ee67f2da0e85043245e51821d"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cea3352614f5a086c4e6abf0fd54c62e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Professor Seyla Elenhabib is the Eugene Meyer Professor of Political Science and Philosophy at Yale University and Director of its Program in Ethics, Politics and Economics. Professor Benhabib is the President of the Eastern Division of the American Philosophical Association in 2006-07. Professor Benhabib teaches about contemporary debates concerning cultural and group rights within liberal democracies. The frequency with which these claims are heard in recent years suggests a paradigm change in contemporary politics: it is claimed that liberal individualist notions of equality and freedom are unable to accommodate demands for cultural self-expression, be they individual or collective. Often such cultural rights are voiced by groups who may themselves be illiberal vis a vis their own members. What should the liberal state do in such cases: respect collective rights for cultural self-expression or guarantee all individuals equal civil, political, and social rights?</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>5. Kimberly Bloom-Feshbach, Calhoun College '09.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_400801f64c3a7ef3a041bcb63085ed52"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_df0e5a38a5da2290ff2b9b921b41b39e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>"Miss America 2007" represents the changing ideals through time of what an "American Woman" is or has been, and her appropriate roles. Rosie the Riveter, found in the bottom right hand corner of the poster, was a historic World War II figure, initially used by the U.S. government to encourage women to join a male-starved (and thus labor-starved) WWII workforce. This increase in working women launched a new era of the ideals of-the strength and meaning of femininity as an ideology. While, with the end of WWII, many women retired from the U.S. workforce, WWII-time use of female labor made working women more socially acceptable. A closer look at this poster"s "Rosie" (and a glimpse at the other images on the poster) bring to light an issue of increasing importance and controversy to and among women: access to emergency contraception and its implications. This issue of access raises broader questions, as well: What is today's version of "Miss America?" A beauty queen? An updated Rosie the Riveter? An activist? Additionally, what defines today"s strong modem woman--and her ideals? If we could choose a Miss America to accurately and strongly represent us, what causes would she champion? [Abstract drafted by Lisa Campbell]</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>6. Hannah Bruckner, Associate Professor of Sociology.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_69243da6cac66ff80ce17331b5066805"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5c5f50e00daf8b40d33e436100fcfe14">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gender Inequality in the Life Course - How do women fare in a society that is characterized by a set of institutions that promote income stability over the life course and thereby maintain and even amplify status difference? Using recently issued public files of social security records with longitudinal earnings data of well over half a million persons, this book describes gender inequality in earnings and labor market participation in contemporary Germany between 1975 and 1995. Because of the advanced industrial base of Germany, its relevance to other nations at the high end of production and consumer indices becomes apparent. Bruckner's work is a unique combination of empirical and theoretical work. She takes seriously the effect of marriage status on labor supply and wages: married men work more and earn more, while married women work less and earn less. But to this rather conventional measure she introduces a second important consideration: the life course, multiple social contexts that help explain the unfolding of social action and economic status. In this way the family becomes a critical factor in explaining such crucial sources of inequality as tax laws, property transference, and transfer payments--and how these are regulated by the welfare state. The results from a life course analysis are contrasted with cross-sectional trends and a traditional lifecycle model to show that much depends in part on the data and methods used to explore it. The work closes with a solid social scientific analysis of systems choices: the private market in contrast to the social democratic welfare state solution. While recognizing that the latter is a direct effort at resolving the gender gap in wages and welfare, Professor Bruckner also appreciates that there are high costs to the overall economy, not the least being a taxation that erodes the earning power of families and individuals as a whole, and hence is less of a solution than the spreading of the problem.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>7. Hannah Bruckner, Associate Professor of Sociology.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_d27b2609b5ed4bdfc945091a08379c03"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6f2f75e4ae7cb11bc841b40a9045b658">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Center for Research on Inequalities and the Life Course at Yale University sponsors several research projects on trends in the timing and sequencing of family formation and career and work-life strategies of young men and women in the U.S. and Europe.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>8. Alicia Schmit Camacho, Assistant Professor of American Studies and Director of Undergraduate Studies for the Ethnicity, Race, and Migration Program.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_ad8a5df90752703232e4ed8dae18f924"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4e968348a23ba6169b3e1a98626305cc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Her current scholarship concerns the feminicidio in Ciudad Juarez, transnational migration, border governance, and social movements in the Americas. She also serves on the board of Junta for Progressive Action, a community agency serving the Latina/o community of Fair Haven and is a consultant for the Connecticut Immigrant Rights Project.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>9. Geetanjali Singh Chanda, Lecturer in Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_378b34921d17c9980e7d10e7d5a3a9e3"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_388603d8e024b37f4ece0ed1fd08a085">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Like homeless wanderers, Indo English women writers are constantly yearning for a home-be it a nation, a house, a community or any other collective in which they can locate their identity. Gender, generation and cultural values shape lifestyles at home and condition lives abroad. Women are crucial to evolving notions of home. InSearch of Home traces how women recreate an idea of home through their fiction. Notwithstanding the popularity of Indo English literature the anxiety of what constitutes Indianness still haunts authors and their works. The home, for Indian women authors, is often the site for the preservation, pedagogy and performance of Indianness. Chanda maps both Indian and diasporic English fiction and situates them within the larger framework of world literatures.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>10. Kamari Maxime Clark, Associate Professor of Anthropology and African American Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_e4eaf67b873360684cea40e3260c32a1"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_51031b875359c4925eeea89cfa2a8a55">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Over the years, Clarke's research has ranged from studies of diasporic and religious movements in the United States and West Africa to related transnational legal movements, to inquiries into the cultural politics of power and new international justice regimes connected to nongovernmental organizations and international criminal legal institutions. She is the author of <title render="italic">
                        Mapping Yoruba Networks: Power and Agency in the Making of Transnational Networks
                     </title> (Duke University Press, 2004), <title render="italic">
                        Globalization and Race: Transformations in the Cultural Politics of Blackness
                     </title> (Duke University Press, 2006), and <title render="italic">
                        Testimonies and Transformations: Reflections on the Uses of Ethnographic Knowledge
                     </title> (forthcoming). Her current project explores issues related to human rights movements and the cultural politics of international treaties, tribunals, courts, and the increasing roles of Non Governmental Organizations (NGOs) in new relations of governance. Her specialization is the cultural aspects of globalization, relationships between religion and law, and social theory and the micro processes of governance.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>11. Kelly P. Cosgrove, Associate Research Scientist, Psychiatry Department (collaborators: E Frohlich, MS, F Bois, PhD, E Perry, MD, Tamagnan, PhD, J Seibyl, MD, N Epperson, MD, C Mazure, PhD, S O"Malley, PhD, J Staley, PhD).</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_60d52e38328b4f36ecb56ef36c19f71e"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cc44a2c01a8c68daa863fbbc9b64d68e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Women demonstrate different sensitivity to nicotine and exhibit a poorer response to nicotine replacement therapies compared to men, and across the menstrual cycle. We hypothesized that these differences are due to variations in nicotinic acetylcholine receptors (nAChR) in brain. nAChRs containing the beta2 subunit (beta2-nAChR) are one of the initial sites of action of nicotine in brain, and are critical for reinforcing effects of nicotine. We evaluated beta2-nAChR availability using single photon emission computed tomography (SPECT) and the nicotinic agonist radiotracer [I-123]5-IA-85380 ([I-123]5-IA) (1) in men versus women nonsmokers to examine sex differences and (2) in women nonsmokers over the course of the menstrual cycle. Ten men (age 27.7 + 7.3) and 19 women (aged 26.2 + 6.8) participated in one [I-123]5-IA scan and one MRI. Nine women (age 18-39 y) participated in a second [123I]5-IA scan. Scans were performed during the early follicular (days 4-7 and one subject on day 11) and midluteal (days19-25) phases of the menstrual cycle. beta2-nAChR availability was approximately 20% higher in women versus men nonsmokers throughout the brain. beta2-nAChR availability did not vary with menstrual cycle. Thus, women have higher beta2-nAChR availability compared to men; however, this does not appear to be a function of menstrual cycle phase. This suggests that sex differences may be determined in utero or during brain maturation. Higher beta2-nAChR availability in women compared to men explains the differential sensitivity to nicotine, and may explain why it is more difficult for women to quit smoking.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>12. The Council on Middle East Studies at the Yale Center for International and Area Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_63d488ff996784e43e196e7f6eda7887"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1d81bc2d04152197d3da01cef1d40873">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Malalai Joya is a 27-year-old Afghani parliamentarian and women's literacy and health worker. According to the BBC, she has survived at least four assassination attempts as one of the most prominent winners in Afghanistan"s landmark parliamentary elections. Elected to represent the remote province of Farah, she is an outspoken critic of Afghanistan"s warlords.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>13. Deborah Davis, Professor of Sociology and Member of the Council on East Asian Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_9b2b3e9261a625ef1678a81667e2163b"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f07e43f130d277f55e29180ceab4a997">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Deborah Davis' primary teaching interests are historical and comparative sociology, inequality and stratification, contemporary Chinese society, and methods of fieldwork. Past publications have analyzed the politics of the Cultural Revolution, Chinese family life, social welfare, class cleavages and occupational mobility. Her most recent work is on the consumer revolution in urban China. In addition to teaching at Yale, she runs a summer fieldwork seminar where Yale students work collaboratively with students from Hong Kong and China.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>14. Joann Delenick, Department of Biology (MCDB) '83.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_3cc9f6f24eb743898a3b9b8bd99d6009"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_19ea8afba021990a6d6036e67c446a7f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Informed Consent Requirements in Human subject Research Arising from Subjects of World War II Bone and Tissue Regeneration Protocols at Ravensbruck Concentration Camp-Subjects of experimental protocols conducted during World War II at Ravensbruck, a civilian prison camp for women near Furstenburg Germany, survived the war and provided witness testimony at the Nuremberg Doctors Trial. At the conclusion of this trial, international in scope and prosecuted by American military, a formal list of requirements for the ethical conduct of medical research with human subjects known as the Nuremberg code was appended.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>15. Joann Delenick, Department of Biology (MCDB) '83.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_2d47d528d0f5121cbf92d7a790ffcd7f"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_46a89c0cce630b202a1a99c6e553f13e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Comparative Analysis of the Human Red Blood Cell Proteome with SDS-Page Banding Patterns Obtained from Endogenous Labeled Embryonic Chick Erythroid Cell Plasma Membrane Glycoproteins - Erythroid cell plasma membrane fractions obtained from 6 day chick embryos labeled with 3H fucose or 3H mannose (Delenick 1983) and membrane preparations from human red cells (Pasini, et.al. 2006) ! were subjected to gel electrophoresis in 4-12 % continuous gradient polyacrylamide gels (SDS-PAGE). Sample gels were stained with Coomassie Blue to visualize protein banding patterns. The chick erythroid sample gels were further exposed to x-ray film for up to 12 months and human red cell membrane preparations were subjected to high accuracy, high-sensitivity protein identification technology--quadrupole time of flight and Fourier transform mass spectrometry (MS). Coomassie Blue stained proteins from human and chick erythroid cell plasma membranes demonstrate comparable electrophoretic mobility patterns in SDS-PAGE. As indicated by combined gel and proteomic analysis (Figure 5, Pasini, et.al.) there are a number of identified human red blood cell membrane proteins which migrate in SDS gels with unexpected molecular weight characteristics. In comparison, the banding patterns obtained from radioautographic analysis of sugar labeled erythroid membrane proteins demonstrate a similar level of complexity for erythroid plasma membrane glycoproteins subjected to active endogenous in toto labeling with tritated fucose or mannose for a period of up to 24 hours. Embryonic chick erythroid cells provide a useful in vitro experimental model for high accuracy comparative studies of plasma membrane glycoprotein structure, function and biosythesis in human red blood cells.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>16. Elizabeth Dillon, Associate Professor of English and American Studies (collaborator: Serene Jones, Titus Street Professor of Theology, Yale Divinity School)</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_37763e45bf38466cdb2040676608c8a9"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_db234926bdeb8c251cc7287f6a84beab">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gender, Religion and Globalization, a course examines constructions and practices of gender in a multi-religious, transnational, and global framework. Focusing specifically on the practices, narratives, and religious beliefs that inform the lived experience of gender in different locations around the world, the course aims to understand the variety of ways in which gender is a structuring aspect of culture, politics, religion, and economics in the developing global system. We look, in particular, at the production of narratives of the self in a variety of colonial and post-colonial contexts and at the practices of adornment, rest (Sabbath), and marriage. Taught from an interdisciplinary perspective, this course includes methodologies from literary studies, religious studies, visual culture, and, more broadly, gender theory and the study of globalization. As a graduate-level course in the Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies program, it fulfills the feminist theory requirement for the program qualification.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref44" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>17. Jennifer Dominguez, Yale Medical School Student '08.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_5347438e57bc28f8b9d21f1d111de45b"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_064a1ea5d07870649e8f3d8302e97c87">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The MOTHERS Study-Ms. Dorninguez aims to determine the impact of the early postpartum period on occipital cortex GABA concentrations and its relationship to plasma ALL0 using H-MRS and venous sampling, respectively. Their hypothesis is that occipital cortical GABA and plasma ALLO concentrations will be suppressed in healthy, postpartum women compared to follicular phase women, and that a gradual increasing trend in CNS GABA and plasma ALLO will be seen across the postpartum period. Her mentor is Cynthia Neil Epperson, M.D., and her co-investigator is Graerne F. Mason, Ph.D.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref46" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>18. Cheryl Doss, Director of Graduate Studies MA Program in International Relations; Lecturer in Department of Economics; Associate Chair, International Affairs Council.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_00f0a2f44e4048193283757c02e8ce6a"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ec964c34d4430bcdbd1537e52377c8bc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>While much literature has examined the gender income gap, relatively little has examined the gender gap in asset ownership. A special issue of <title render="italic">
                        Feminist Economics
                     </title> brought together ten papers addressing these issues in both developed and developing countries: What assets do women own? How do women accumulate assets? Are the patterns different by gender? And finally, why is it important for women to own assets? The introductory paper by Cheryl Doss and Carmin Diana Deere analyzes the broader literature on these issues and also explores the methodological issues facing the study of gender-asset gap. It emphasizes the importance of legal, marital and inheritance regimes on women's access to assets. Ongoing research examines the gender-gap in asset ownership in Africa and the development of a template for collecting household survey data on intrahousehold asset ownership.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref48" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>19. FAIR Forum.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_d01c655be426f15eacf240debacaa0d8"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9117e8941d44f0346f0607476bb6c565">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Since 1978, Yale Law School has upheld its commitment to equality in part through a firm policy that denies access to its Career Development Office to employers who discriminate against LGBT students. Faced with the government"s threat to withhold.$300 million in essential federal grants from all of Yale University, the Law School faculty voted in 2002 to suspend its non-discrimination policy with respect to the US. Military until it won an injunction against the government"s enforcement of the Solomon Amendment in the case Burt v. Rumsfeld in2005. This year, the Supreme Court in FAIR v. Rumsfeld held that "the Solomon Amendment regulates conduct, not speech. It affects what law schools must do-afford equal access to military recruiters-not what they may or may not say." In light of this decision, Yale Law School must again resolve a difficult situation. Argued Justice Breyer, "The remedy for such a situation is not less speech, it is more speech." The FAIR Forum responds to the FAIR decision by examining the reasons for discrimination in our armed forces and the effectiveness of the Don"t Ask Don"t Tell policy. Participants will consider alternatives to DADT, will discuss current efforts to eliminate the military"s policy of discrimination, and will ask whether and how Yale students can engage a military legally bound to inequality.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref50" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>20. Margaret Farley, Gilbert L Stark Professor of Ethics; Yale Divinity School and Professor of Religious Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_ba45a9be5372690d0377d97c9f744937"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3b70dfc326403e71d676fc8d9718c863">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Just Love
                     </title> - This long-awaited book by one of American Christianity's foremost ethicists proposes a framework for sexual ethics whereby justice is the criterion for all loving, including love that is related to sexual activity and relationships. It begins with historical and cross-cultural explorations, and then addresses the large questions of embodiment, gender, and sexuality. Following this is a normative chapter that delineates the justice framework for sexual ethics. Though the particular focus is Christian sexual ethics, the framework is broad enough to have relevance for multiple traditions of sexual ethics. The remaining chapters focus on specific issues in sexual ethics, including same-sex relationships, marriage and family, divorce and second marriage, celibacy, and sex and its negativities.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref52" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>21. Daniela Grunow, Postdoctoral Associate in the Center for Research on Inequalities and the Life Course, Department of Sociology</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_cf5b20a89a25d730c5664aabc0016d1a"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9f8cf4890f048031689979a8d5d2d5a0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>This study seeks to explore the interaction between individual acts of gender display, specialization, resource-bargaining, mutual trust, and the relative impact of opportunity structures, as shaped by national institutional frameworks, on a couple's decision-making processes concerning the division of labor. One can observe a traditionalization of gender roles among couples in the process of relationship development, especially following entry into parenthood, when the volume of reproductive work increases. In fact, this pattern is still applied by couples with comparable labor market resources and an initially egalitarian division of roles, challenging the body of theories on the gender-based division of labor. I propose to study this phenomenon in an event-related, longitudinal, and cross-national perspective, in order to link couple-level dynamics in the division of labor with institutional and cultural explanations. The specific aim is to study how dual-earner couples in two distinctly different national contexts, Germany and the United States, decide how to divide paid and unpaid market and familial work across the transition to parenthood, and how they frame this decision. The poster discusses preliminary findings from the first-wave interviews with nascent parents in Germany.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref54" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>22. Lillian Guerra, Assistant Professor of History.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_3c87346c29034e4726622da94413d900"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d1724d49b94548578f56f1d5c68c112c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        The Myth of Jose Marti
                     </title>-Focusing on a period of history rocked by four armed movements, Lillian Guerra traces the origins of Cubans" struggles to determine the meaning of their identity and the character of the state, from Cuba"s last war of independence in 1895 to the consolidation of U.S. neocolonial hegemony in 1921.Guerra argues that political violence and competing interpretations of the "social unity" proposed by Cuba"s revolutionary patriot, Jose Marti, reveal conflicting visions of the nation-visions that differ in their ideological radicalism and in how they cast Cuba"s relationship with the United States. As Guerra explains, some nationalists supported incorporating foreign investment and values, while others sought social change through the application of an authoritarian model of electoral politics; still others sought a democratic government with social and economic justice. But for all factions, the image of Marti became the principal means by which Cubans attacked, policed, and discredited one another to preserve their own vision over others". Guerra"s examination demonstrates how competing historical memories and battles for control of a weak state explain why polarity, rather than consensus on the idea of the "nation" and the character of the Cuban state, came to define Cuban politics throughout the twentieth century.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref56" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>23. InSight. Michelle Wong, Morse College '08</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_777d4541376882b1cd2ada437bf70ef4"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b05f680c8db46999de83f23168576def">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>InSight is the Yale chapter of the National Asian Pacific American Women's Forum, a national organization dedicated to forging a grassroots movement for the social, economic and political empowerment of Asian Pacific American Women through organizing, education, and advocacy. The Yale chapter hopes to give a stronger voice to the historically underrepresented population of Asian Pacific American women through leadership and empowerment; by creating a network of strong and dynamic women, we share our common experiences and concerns on issues that affect us.</p>
                  <p>InSight attempts to gain insight into important issues specific to APA women through discussion and research. Once these concerns are further explored, our goal is to put them in sight through awareness campaigns and sponsorships of events relevant to those issues. Most importantly, we use insight to look introspectively at ourselves as APA women and to examine our role in the community. But we always remind ourselves to look outward and keep our goals in sight. "Listen and know," that the conceptions of Asian girls being submissive, quiet, and subservient, the "geisha girls" and the "china dolls," are only misconceptions. We too are strong individuals who are not afraid to speak our mind and work boldly towards our goals. Our voices will be heard.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref58" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>24. Adam Jones, Associate Research Fellow for 2005-07 in the Genocide Studies Program at Yale.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_a7c343b441def9ef48571f8206f0e5e0"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_449c040ed9b94e94b7b7a3875219ce38">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Men of the Global South: A Reader
                     </title> is the most diverse and accessible volume yet published on men and masculinities throughout the developing world. Combining previously-published materials with a wide range of original contributions, the book explores male experience in a uniquely vivid and accessible way. The editor, Adam Jones, provides a framing introduction that surveys the growing literature on Southern men and masculinities, and links it to the broader study of gender and development. Six main sections portray different aspects of male experience in the global South: "Family and Sexuality," "Ritual and Belief," "Work," "Governance and Conflict," "Migrations," and "Masculinities in Motion." Eye-catching photographs complement a text that serves as an ideal introduction to the lives of men and boys from Africa, the Middle East, Asia, and Latin America, the Caribbean. Men of the Global South is sure to hold great appeal for students and scholars of gender and development, as well as for general readers interested in gaining a greater understanding and appreciation of men"s roles, challenges, and contributions worldwide. Adam Jones, Ph.D., is Associate Research Fellow for 2005-07 in the Genocide Studies Program at Yale. His most recent book is <title render="italic">
                        Genocide: A Comprehensive Introduction
                     </title> (Routledge, 2006). He has edited two further books on genocide and authored two on mass media and political transition. His writings on gender and international politics have appeared in Review of International Studies, Ethnic and Racial Studies, Journal of Human Rights, and other publications.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>25. Serene Jones, Titus Street Professor of Theology, Yale Divinity School</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_631a3b24a0bc31991b6c69fddad10fe0"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_730935bfb566b8a4646dcb3853a39a23">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        In Feminist Theory and Christian Theology: Cartographies of Grace
                     </title> (2000) Jones introduces the primary concerns that animate feminist theory through discussion of critical texts and through women's narratives. She shows how they pose uncomfortable questions, and leave no corner of the Christian tradition unchallenged. Jones unfolds feminist theory in three broad categories that analyze human identity and gender, oppression, and ethics. She then illustrates their potential for illuminating theological categories of experience, truth, text, and norm to revitalize three key traditional Christian doctrines: faith, sin, and church. Professor Jones is the author of <title render="italic">
                        Feminist and Womanist Essays in Reformed Dogmatics
                     </title> (2006), <title render="italic">
                        Constructive Theology
                     </title> (2006), <title render="italic">
                        Feminist Theory and Christian Theology: Cartographies of Grace
                     </title> (2000) and <title render="italic">
                        Calvin and Rhetoric: Christian Doctrine and the Art of Eloquence
                     </title> (1995), and co-editor of <title render="italic">
                        Liberating Eschatology: Essays in Honor of Letty Russell
                     </title> (1999) and <title render="italic">
                        Setting the Table: Women in Theological Conversations
                     </title> (1995). She is also a contributor to the recently published <title render="italic">
                        Dictionary of Feminist Theologies
                     </title> (1996). Ordained in both the Christian Church (Disciples of Christ) and the United Church of Christ, Professor Jones serves on the Advisory Committee for the Wabash Center for Teaching and Learning in Theology and Religion and on the Yale University Women's and Gender Studies Council. She also has a faculty appointment in the Department of African American Studies.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref62" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>26.Claire Kaplan, Associate Professor, School of Nursing.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_af0fc6f1f0dad8671b7ab2748bb19ce5"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c80b3dfba3c5b6844c562871bc55eb94">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Welner's Guide
                     </title> - This is an editorial about a book on women and disability that was recently published: <title render="italic">
                        Welner's Guide to the Care of Women with Disabilities
                     </title>, by Sandra L. Welner, MD, and Florence Haseltine. 2004. Lippincott Williams and Wilkins. <title render="italic">
                        Welner's Guide to the Care of Women with Disabilities
                     </title> provides a comprehensive overview of some of the most important gynecologic and obstetrical considerations for health care providers who care for women with chronic diseases, injuries and disabilities. One of its strengths is that it offers practical advice without oversimplifying or assuming that all women with a particular condition or limitation are the same.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref64" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>27. Claire Kaplan, Associate Professor, School of Nursing.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_3b9ae3d01ca00ea3c6bf7ebb66638aad"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ce2691278da2a9c46ed9350b4524ca06">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Take the Time to Speak Out
                     </title>is about the turf-battles between physicians and nurse practitioners published in <title render="italic">
                        The Nurse Practitioner Journal
                     </title>, September 2005</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref66" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>28. Claire Kaplan, Associate Professor, School of Nursing.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_90213434312f0b01d6778e8108bef764"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1cac4636976a84f97e661e263cd11818">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Advocacy Through Clinical Practice
                     </title>, Yale School of Nursing faculty has been involved in this advocacy group and in a clinical joint appointment to address these disparities. In Connecticut, a coalition of women called the Connecticut Women with Disabilities Network (CWDN) advanced a bill mandating gynecologic services for vulnerable women in in-patient facilities.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref68" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>29. Tirza True Latimer, Lecturer in Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies and History of Art.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_55ee6fd30c4402d62a5c532a6b5fc487"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7c94c5131ebd528c402a8af070b8a4e5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>In <title render="italic">
                        Women Together Women Apart: Portraits of Lesbian Paris
                     </title>, Latimer explores the tumultuous period between World War I and World War II when women artists working in Paris and other European capitals began to shape the first visual models defining lesbianism as a category of social subjectivity. Their self-representations in visual culture served as sites of both identity formation and community formation enabling women who refused to assume the mantle of conventional femininity to recognize themselves and each other.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref70" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>30. LGBT Co-op. Anna Wipfler, Branford College '09</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_4dd80bfe42698d39602d3929087e8d2c"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cb130dcadf130c0202db37fdf2382b46">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Student Cooperative is Yale's full service undergraduate queer organization. Membership is open to the entire Yale community. The Co-op serves to foster community between LGBTQ identified people and their allies at Yale. The Co-op represents the community at Bulldog Days and the extracurricular bazaar, and organizes events such as Queer Dinners, Movie Nights, Coming Out Day, Pride Week, Trans Issues Week and the notorious school-wide Co-op Dance in the Fall. In addition, the Co-op serves as the umbrella group for most other undergraduate LGBTQ related groups on campus, and provides funding and support for each group. Co-op actions include film festivals, speaker series, and activist campaigns. The Co-op's ongoing mission is to make Yale a safe, accepting, fun place to be queer.</p>
                  <p>This has already been a year of historical note for queer/gender issues as we saw the University finally follow in the footsteps of all of its peers and add protection of gender identity and expression to its Equal Opportunity Statement in late September. This move came after a year's worth of campaign efforts by one of the Co-op's Member Groups the Queer Political Action Committee, which raised 1,000 signatures from students, faculty, and staff on a petition submitted to the administration demanding the addition of this protective clause. We hope that this change in policy will mark the beginning of an ongoing project to make the Yale campus more welcoming to transgender individuals and all people who express themselves in non-traditional ways.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref72" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>31. Kristen Leslie, Associate Professor Pastoral Care &amp; Counseling, Yale Divinity School</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_8baae1bfce9cde8c22f2eab85a000cff"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0a2887d6a7233e69f33c433ec511f311">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        When Violence Is No Stranger: Pastoral Counseling With Survivors of Acquaintance Rape
                     </title> - The paucity of resources for pastoral care of acquaintance-rape survivors highlights the invisibility of this growing crime and its largely uncharted pastoral challenges. In fact, most rape is by an acquaintance. Only 16 percent of such cases are reported; and, because they are difficult to prosecute, only 5 percent of those reported result in guilty verdicts.</p>
                  <p>Focusing on the psychospiritual effects of this sexualized violence, Kristen Leslie offers the psychological and theological tools to religious professionals for understanding the deep spiritual trauma of the survivor and how best to work with her to reconstruct a personal world of meaning, trust, and faith. Based on extensive interviews with survivors, Leslie explains the personal and theological issues they raise, what they found helpful from religious professionals, the images and metaphors most germane to their trauma and recovery, and how they coped with or healed from the experience of rape.</p>
                  <p>An exemplary and important study in practical theology, Leslie's volume will not only equip pastoral caregivers and counselors with specific guidelines. It will also enlighten them on the crucial role that theology can play in the re-construction of shattered lives.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref74" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>32,33,34. Lisa Link, MFA Photography and Media Arts, Web Specialist Yale School of Nursing.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_7f6984392af09a157b068683019cdff6"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2287ec13ba5a1c571584a630f7b78fec">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>For the last 15 years Lisa has been doing work on the history of women's reproductive health care. She created an exhibition called "Warnings" which toured nationally from 1992-2003 and is now based in the Center for the Study of Political Graphics in Los Angeles. The <title render="italic">
                        Warnings
                     </title> series of digital photomontages, texts, and video juxtaposes the collapse of the women"s movement in late Weimar Germany with critical issues facing women in the United States today. <title render="italic">
                        Warnings
                     </title> embraces a propagandist style of poster design to respond to the barrage of current antifeminist messages. Through designs that address racist steriliza tion practices, class discrimination in the surrogate mother industry, antiabortion violence, and bias in the legislative/judicial process, Warnings invites viewers to reflect on the Power, Propaganda, and Politics surrounding women's reproductive health care. <title render="italic">
                        Warnings
                     </title> toured nationally to over 45 galleries from 1991-2003 and is now in the permanent collection of the Center for the Study of Political Graphics in Los Angeles and the Special Collections of the Norlin Library, University of Colorado, Boulder. Galleries included: Joseph Gross Gallery, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ, Wankelman Gallery, Bowling Green State University, Bowling Green, OH. Art Gallery, Bethune-Cookman College, Daytona Beach, Fine Arts Gallery, Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, NC. Louise Jones Brown Gallery and the Women"s Center, Duke University, Durham, NC, The Main Gallery, Hampshire College, Amherst, MA, Roland Dille Center for the Arts, Moorhead State University, Moorhead, MN, and the Women"s Building, San Francisco, CA. For information on how all or part of Warnings can visit your institution, please contact: lisa.link@yale.edu. The web site with information on this project is:http://lisalink.netlart/warn_state.html.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref76" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>35. Medical Students for Choice at Yale Margaret Reynolds, Yale Medical School Student '10.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_1557adc8a4ecb8ff8adc65f0ce0ec334"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_030ddd058805e6e2b6b5943cc1c192d5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Medical Students for Choice (MSFC) is dedicated to ensuring that women receive the full range of reproductive health care choices. MSFC recognizes that one of the greatest obstacles to safe and legal abortion is the absence of trained providers. As medical students and residents, we work to make reproductive health care, including abortion, a part of standard medical education and residency training. MSFC was founded by Jody Steinauer, then a medical student at the University of California, San Francisco, in 1993 in response to the decreasing number of abortion providers, the lack of education at the medical school and residency level, and the increasing hostility toward abortion providers and abortion rights. The non-profit organization currently embodies a network of over 10,000 medical students and residents.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref78" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>36. Joanne Meyerowitz, Professor of History and American Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_65f531e64f5c90e35e590a7dae990e52"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_676c0cde96e2380a4f02d97279048ef5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Over the past century, when many challenged the social categories of race, class, and gender, transsexuals questioned biological sex itself, the category that seemed most fundamental and fixed of all. <title render="italic">
                        How Sex Changed
                     </title> shows how new definitions of sex circulated in populated culture, science, medicine, and the law, and it elucidates the tidal shifts in the twentieth century, away from sex as an evident biological certainty and toward an understanding of sex as something malleable and complex.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref80" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>37. Alice Moore, Ph.D. Student, American Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_a4d2681f678f3b9fda1c54bfd802125b"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_00bf0eaf224cd6420b2ed44e93740a15">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>In Adrienne Kennedy's 1992 play <title render="italic">
                        Ohio State Murders
                     </title>, the character Suzanne (Present) notes that "a city should have a sacred geography never arbitrary but planned in strict accord with the dictates of a doctrine that the society upholds." <title render="italic">
                        Re-Membering the Yale Fence
                     </title> revisits the powerful mythology of an old Yale institution through its current memorialization on the periphery of Old Campus. This essay seeks to intervene in the construction of an exclusionary collective memory by examining the historical elements of that construction and by showing an alternative history through place, time, and embodiment. Alice Rebecca Moore is a second year PhD student in the American Studies program. Her current research centers on an exploration-through history of the US West, feminist and performance theory, and American visual culture-of the invisible (and sometimes visible) performance of straight white masculinity, the violence inherent in that performance, and the potential for change.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref82" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>38. Kate Ott, Director of Research, Women Faculty Forum.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_125cca9374860663f7d632ff7c894457"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e3f26bdd0ef9a3c20c6e7aac01620c8d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Saying "No" Is Not Enough: Rethinking Adolescent Sexual Ethics
                     </title> - This poster describes my passion, my dissertation project, and my commitment to the many young women and men that I have worked with over the past 10 years. This project is my effort to talkback to current public policy makers pushing abstinence-only-until-marriage education that is ineffectual and unsafe. I also speak to Christian communities who continue to send mixed messages at best, and harmful ones at worst, to adolescents struggling to sort out the meaning of influential and life altering relationships. I hold a PhD in Christian Social Ethics from Union Theological Seminary in the City of New York.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref84" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>39. Rachel Pepper, Coordinator of Lesbian and Gay Studies at Yale.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_754dc5fc774f43075d95bd43ac7f4f14"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3066a507eb5362e39b53c39d08d612fb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gender</p>
                  <p>Explore it</p>
                  <p>Embrace it</p>
                  <p>Don't assume it</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref86" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>40. Raj Persaud '10</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_52c9239e168bb86e755375c0ccefd30f"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f8ba180a45587557c2915e57ba46cfbb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>[Abstract not available]</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref88" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>41. PMS and Perinatal Research Program Lori Spoozak, Doris Duke clinical Research Fellow, Yale School of Medicine.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_24a94a8b96565391be9c6bfbe19cc8ea"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0f3fdeaea575c0de8be6d2983442c458">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Dr. Kimberly Yonkers, Associate Professor of Psychiatry, Ohtetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Health Sciences, and Instructor in Epidemiology and Public Health at the Yale School of Medicine. The PMS and perinatal Research Program provides information and treatment on a variety of women's health issues. Currently, we have research studies investigating Mood and Anxiety Disorders in Pregnancy and their Effects on Birth Outcomes, Substance Use during Pregnancy, Premenstrual Syndrome and Premenstrual Cysphoric Disorder. The PMS and Perinatal Research Program is staffed by women and men with diverse educational backgrounds including MD, RN, MPH, MS W, CNW, and PhDs. Additionally, the program hosts many students for internships from Yale College, Quinnipiac University, Yale School of Medicine, Epidemiology and Public health, and Southern CT State University School of Social Work.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref90" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>42. Mariana Preciado, Research Assistant in Psychology</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_6f19f5ef407c42d644110b6aa4df7855"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_dfe1737891f220c610ebd150f94411c2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Perceptions of fluidity in sexual orientation - Researchers have found that a person's sexual orientation is not always fixed or immutable. This study was interested in investigating whether lay people also believe that a person's sexual orientation can change. Specifically, individuals were asked whether their own sexual orientation has or could change as well as whether they believed that the sexual orientation of men in general and women in general is susceptible to change. Male and female respondents were asked to rate the fluidity (likelihood to change over time and/or context) of their own sexual orientation, the sexual orientation of other women, and the sexual orientation of other men on a seven-point scale. Results showed that both female and male respondents rated the sexual orientation of women in general to be significantly more fluid than either their own sexual orientation or that of men in general. This results was unaffected by respondent demographic characteristics (age, race, and sexual orientation) or personality differences in the need to see things as stable or malleable (Personal Need for Structure Scale) (Neuberg &amp; Newsom, 1993). In addition, female respondents rated the fluidity of their own sexual orientation as similar to the ratings they gave for men in general and male respondents rated their own sexual orientation to be the least fluid.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref92" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>43, 44, 45. Rape and Sexual Violence Prevention Group -RSVP.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_361beca8793fd7a98f250d32710d43d9"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8ed56e605b349fd1dd8fafa1064d23aa">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Rape and Sexual Assault Prevention aims to monitor and enhance Yale's system for addressing rape and sexual assault, as well as to reduce sexual violence and raise awareness of its continued existence.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref94" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>46. Judith Resnik, Arthur Liman Professor of Law.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_03c83e010a118141aa56369596f179a6"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fe7ff85fd7d96a84b59baf1d5087449b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Legal theorists are engaged in understanding the legitimacy of techniques by which principles of rights-holding travel across borders. Sovereigntists in the United States object to that migration. The history of both protest about and the incorporation of "foreign" law provides important lessons for contemporary debates. Through examples from conflicts about slavery, the rights of women, and the creation of the United Nations, I chart the anxiety occasioned when American law interacts with human rights movements: At times, through silent absorption rather than express citation, some of the "foreign" sources become lost in translation, and the new rights become constitutive elements of "American" identity. To conceive of these debates as engaging only questions of national boundaries is, however, to miss the reliance on federalism as a justification for declining to participate in transnational rights work. Yet America's federalist structure also serves as a path for the movement of international rights across borders. As illustrated by the adoption by mayors, city councils, state legislatures, and state judges of transnational rights stemming from the U.N. Charter, the Convention to Eliminate All Forms of Discrimination Against Women (CEDAW), and the Kyoto Protocol on global warming, the debate about transnationalism is deeply democratic, with significant popular engagement reframing American norms. Such local government actions require revisiting legal doctrines that presume the exclusivity of national power in foreign affairs-as that which is "foreign" is domesticated through several routes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref96" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>47. Susan Richman, Assistant Professor Obstetrics and Gynecology</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_52ba8b257be2c9450b438ac992b87590"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d925df9d1c7d5ae78bc5de04c9969209">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The objective of this study was to assess the prevalence, demographics and characteristics of VIE in lactating woman in the postpartum period, and objectively record their occurrence. Healthy multiparas, who had previously breast fed satisfactorily, between the ages of 18 and 35 years, were enrolled. There were 110 surveys adequate for analysis. The average age of the subjects was 29.5 years, and the mean gravidity was 2.5 pregnancies. 61% of the lactating women in the total sample experienced VIE on postpartum day 1, and 77% on postpartum day #2. Skin conductance measurements in the sampled lactating subjects demonstrated the identical increase in skin conductance with each suckling episode. In all cases, the temporal relationship of VIE was repetitive, as re-initiation of feeding in the contra-lateral breast prolonged the duration of the VIE. The VIE of these postpartum lactating women were inducible and reproducible with the initiation of each suckling episode. A unique data set provided the opportunity for this method-proving study: measuring palmar skin conductance levels reliably and reproducibly measured VIE accompanying breastfeeding. The equipment is noninvasive and portable.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref98" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>48. Rosie Fund. Lori Spoozak, Doris Duke clinical Research Fellow, Yale School of Medicine</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_25228a60e63800ea8f87b81e73051ee7"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_62d503d7c15471c16f6ec878e0269877">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>On October 3, 1977, Rosie Jimenez died in McAllen General Hospital in Texas, where she had been brought following an illegal, back alley abortion. An unsterilized rubber tube had been used by to induce abortion. Within 24 hours, she had contracted an infection similar to tetanus that progressively worsened until her death.</p>
                  <p>She was a 27 yr old Mexican-American woman, who was a single mother of a five year old girl, a welfare recipient, part-time employee at an electronics plant, and a university student. She died with a $700 scholarship check in her pocket which she refused to use for a legal abortion because that would have meant abandoning her education.</p>
                  <p>The Rosie Fund was founded in 2003 and is committed to helping women overcome financial barriers placed around abortion services. Restrictions on government funded public insurance and private insurance for abortion services make this fund urgently necessary for women throughout the state of CT. One of 105 member funds in the National Network of Abortion Funds, the Rosie Fund provides funding for women who would not otherwise be able to obtain the abortion services that they require. The Rosie Fund is staffed by all volunteers who include many students and professionals from the Yale community.</p>
                  <p>For more information about the Rosie Fund please call: (860) 559-1004 or email rosiefundct@hotmail.com.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref100" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>49. Edith Rotkopf, Howard R. Lamar Center and Women Faculty Forum, Administrative Assistant.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_e129f63677e1e1c5c25838547544a346"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_993a3a102f6a259796c7843515a2ecd2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>TO-DO LISTS-Busy women rely extensively on TO-DO lists. Some of us prefer one big list; others prefer smaller fists and use a number of these agendas to cover all facets of our lives. Some people don"t get out of bed until they check their TO-DO'S. Often, we get ahead of ourselves on our TO-DO and then, we become paralyzed by it. So, we start another one. We think To-Do lists will save us and they do, sometimes. This poster honors the modern American woman's devotion to the TO-DO list. Art: courtesy of Microsoft On-Line Clip-Art.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref102" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>50. Nancy Ruther, Associate Director of the MacMillan Center, International Higher Education and African Development.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_5b9653b77c90cce25518dae78a0fe6a4"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_04a6a37c90a46d064151f1bd4aa26152">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The conference brought together an interdisciplinary group of international experts on higher education in Africa, development in Africa, and for comparative purposes, higher education in Latin America, Europe and the U.S. Although many of the participants regularly attend conferences on Higher Education in Africa, the participation of experts from other sectors and with other approaches brought new insights and new directions to the discussions. The goal of the conference on "International Higher Education and African Development" was to explore research and policy issues for higher education and international development with special focus on Africa. More specifically, it aimed to generate new perspectives and approaches for both applied research and policymaking in this field. The two keynote addresses, of broad scope and vision, were delivered to the invited experts. Five "anchor papers," of more targeted scope and detailed analysis, received commentary from two experts from different regions or disciplines.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref104" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>51. Carolyn Sharp, Associate Professor of Hebrew Scriptures, Yale Divinity School.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_7721d8945eee8fe6f4127dee88e3cc47"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_440599432ae9307873b8bb419bc79eff">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Irony and Meaning in the Hebrew Bible: The Power of the Unspoken in the Scriptures of Ancient Israel
                     </title>, a book-length manuscript in progress analyzes irony in diverse narratives and poetry from across the Hebrew Bible. I examine contemporary theories of irony and their significance for modernist/postmodernist debates about author and meaning, making reference to specific texts from Genesis, Numbers, Joshua, Judges, Hosea, Amos, Jonah, the Psalms, Job, Ruth, Qohelet, Esther, and Daniel. The book is cross-disciplinary in its approach, working out both local exegetical insights and broader-reaching metatextual implications from the place of intersection of hermeneutics, literary studies, and traditional historical criticism. The chapter dealing most directly with gender is Chapter 3,"The Prostitute as Icon of the Ironic Gaze," which interprets ironic gestures in the Biblical stories of Tamar, Rahab, Jael, Gomer, and Ruth. In this chapter, I build on methodological insights from Judith Butler, Elizabeth Grosz, and Hebrew Bible scholars who have worked on women and sexuality in antiquity. This book should contribute to the establishment of a comprehensive hermeneutical paradigm for understanding how the notion of "sacred text" may be reconceived in a multivocal corpus in which foundational ideologies are proclaimed by certain textual witnesses and ironically subverted by others.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref106" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>52. Helen Siu, Professor of Anthropology and Member of the Council on East Asian Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_e665d1caab675ce3a03f4d5a196c04ca"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e6116991a0e56c1a412bf097c28bb00c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Since the 1970s, she has conducted historical and ethnographic fieldwork in South China and Hong Kong, examining socialist and post-socialist transformations, the revival of market towns, community festivals and rituals, and lately, migration and vernacular modernity. She served as an overseas member of the University Grants Committee and the Research Grant's Council in Hong Kong for which she was awarded the Bronze Bauhinia Star. In the U.S. she served on the Committee for Advanced Study in China and the National Screening Committee for Fulbright awards. In 2001, she set up the Hong Kong Institute for the Humanities and Social Sciences. The Institute promotes creative, interdisciplinary research that aims to bond scholars in major universities in North America, Europe, China and Hong Kong. Her teaching interests are historical and political anthropology, urban anthropology and global change, culture, history, power and representation. She has written numerous articles and book chapters.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref108" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>53. Christine Slaughter,Calhoun College "07.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_483d0240f25dd855ab8c32b0588274c3"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2196fec3546223fc98f456729265c1b5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Thanks to the Reproductive Rights Action League at Yale (RALY), the Yale chapter of the ACLU, and the work of thousands of organizers nationally, I was able to attend the March for Women's Lives in Washington, D.C., April of my freshman year at Yale. It was a wonderful experience that galvanized my commitment to feminism and made me all the more excited about getting involved with feminist groups at Yale, including RALY and the Yale Women"s Center. As a senior I look back with immense affection for the people I've been able to work with and the work that I've been able to do through these organizations.</p>
                  <p>But even so, these experiences stand in marked contrast with the ways that I often see women depicted on campus. Last year, the cover of the Sex Week at Yale magazine featured a female student dressed in nothing but a pair of panties; the inside of the magazine was filled with half-naked women alongside fully clothed male students. The fact that not many students seemed to give a second thought to this (or did not see any effective ways to voice their frustration) is indicative that there is still much work to be done for the feminist cause on-our own campus, even as enlightened as many of us Yalies like to think we are.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref110" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>54. Jessica Svendsen, Morse College '09.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_e8157df4f29dff384bec32f434642021"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ca8aca9dfef9bd4deeaa80c54e2fbfa8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Published in 1963, Betty Friedan's <title render="italic">
                        The Feminine Mystique
                     </title> quickly became a classical feminist text. Friedan suggests that women were living solely through the lives of their husband or children, desperately trying to find fulfillment in the ideal image of what Friedan terms, the feminine mystique. But as the beginning quote from the book indicates, many of these housewives felt discontent and unfulfilled. I found this text for the first time in 2002, after my sophomore year in high school and eager to understand the women"s rights movement. I lived in a rather patriarchal neighborhood, where in the majority of the homes surrounding me, women would have to check "Occupation: Housewife." As a girl growing up in such a community, even where the local university is the site where some women only attend to find a husband, I felt I would never be able to transform into the feminine ideal. Yet, this opening paragraph provided an alternative perspective on my future. It was reassuring to read an author who acknowledged that feminity had been mystified and manipulated into something detrimental to a woman's sense of being. I was then no longer alone in believing that combining motherhood and a career is not only achievable, but also beneficial to both the woman and her family.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref112" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>55. Laurie Novick Sylla, Research Project Director at the Yale AIDS Program.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_d07634391766fee266be71c125ac6625"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_17194e00af2eeb74374b215856c60dc0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Use of a Simulated Microbicide in Two-week Trials by High-Risk Women in Hartford, Connecticut(U.S.A.)-To determine if high-risk, primarily African American and Puerto Rican women in Hartford, Connecticut (United States) would successfully use a simulation microbicide with their primary, casual, and/or paying sex partners, and document their sexual experiences and product use. To explore factors affecting the acceptability and feasibility of these high-risk urban women using a microbicide with their primary, casual, and/or paying sex partners. The report has the following conclusions: High risk urban U.S. women would be able and willing to use an effective microbicide with paying, casual, and primary partners. The availability of a microbicide would allow these women to feel more in control of protecting themselves, and increase their percent of protected sex acts.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref114" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>56. Laurie Novick Sylla, Research Project Director at the Yale AIDS Program.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_ea573948f4ddf02f7a182e8535ef5b76"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2844783cbd0a1520320eedce28ec8255">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gender, Power and Heterosexual Risks: The Promise of Microbicides as a Women-Initiated HIV Prevention Option-The project aims to explore concepts and experiences of HIV and pregnancy prevention (using ethnographic data) and the acceptability of different microbicide prevention methods (using quantitative survey data). The researchers conducted simulation trial of microbicidal use by using an over-the-counterproduct similar to microbicides (using sex diary self-report data) in order to assess acceptability of the female condom for HN/STI prevention with high-risk women (using survey and trial). The study concluded that microbicides offer a prevention option that may be most suitable for women who find currently available options insufficient, undesirable, or impossible to use with specific partners or in specific contexts.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref116" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>57. Nora Tubbs Tisdale, Clement-Muehl Professor of Homiletics, Yale Divinity School.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_84312123d49c760f78c0048ccaeaec43"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5ff35c345b2abe0358a6ebd322bc893a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>My own research regarding gender issues includes the following publications: three volumes of <title render="italic">
                        The Abingdon Women's Preaching Annual
                     </title> (Nashville: Abingdon Press: 1999, 2000, &amp; 2001), which include sermons and worship elements crafted by outstanding women preachers; a chapter entitled "Women's Ways of Communicating: A New Blessing for Preaching," in the book <title render="italic">
                        Women, Gender, and Christian Community
                     </title>, eds. Jane Dempsey Douglass &amp; James F. Kay (Westminster/John Knox Press, 1997); and another chapter entitled "Women, Worship, and God's Reforming Spirit" in the book <title render="italic">
                        Christian Worship in Reformed Churches Past and Present
                     </title>, ed. Lukas Vischer (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2003). In addition, I will be regularly teaching a course at the Yale Divinity School (beginning this spring) called "Women's Ways of Preaching." In my writing and teaching I am particularly interested in the ways in which women's ways of theologizing, interpreting scripture, re-envisioning authority in the pulpit, and communicating continue to shape and reshape the practice of preaching and worship in the 21st century.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref118" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>58. Cindy Tobery, Director of Programs and Projects, Women Faculty Forum</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_4615ac8c63d666df60b26a8b78aecaab"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_df488ca3f2e5137212c3b5242671894d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Essentials for Tapping One's Full Potential - This poster is my souvenir from the "Science Revolution in Minority Communities: What Progress Have We Made?" SACNAS (Society for Advancement of Chicanos and Native Americans in Science) conference in October 2006. Although I do not remember which exhibitor gave me this poster, I do remember being told: "We want people at Yale to reach their full potential too. Hang this up where people can see it." And I couldn't think of a better place than the WFF poster session.</p>
                  <p>The content was developed by Howard G. Adams, PhD, president and founder of H.G. Adams &amp; Associates, Inc. a consulting company that provides a full range of career, personal and professional development services to educational, governmental and industrial organizations. Prior to incorporating H.G. Adams &amp; Associates, Inc., Dr. Adams served as Executive Director of the National Consortium for Graduate Degrees for Minorities in Engineering and Science, Inc. (The GEM Program) headquartered at the University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, Indiana (1978-1996). Here he specialized in designing strategies and implementing programs to enhance the participation and success of ethnic minorities and women in engineering, science and other technical areas. Dr. Adams is a highly sought after seminar facilitator and keynote speaker, who has delivered numerous papers before professional, scientific, and educational associations and has spoken at more that 500 colleges and universities. He has written extensively in the areas of mentorship programs, human resource development, and student academic success. His latest book, entitled <title render="italic">
                        Get Up With Something On Your Mind
                     </title>, offers 25 lessons for leading a meaningful and successful life. (Biography from www.michagep.org/news/adams_bio.pdf)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref120" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>59. Cindy Tobery, Director of Programs and Projects, Women Faculty Forum</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_7372486efe8c4b2978dc483f49b69b4a"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3bbeb2059411986940cbaa2867c1b680">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>One focus of the Women Faculty Forum is to work with the administration and others on campus to foster gender equity throughout the university and thus "fix the institution." As the recent National Academy of Sciences publication indicates, unintentional bias (for which we should hold people accountable by using the term "unexamined stereotyping") and outdated institutional structures are still hindering talented women from reaching their full potential in academia. We need to remove the barriers - both at work and at home - that can hold women back.</p>
                  <p>Why So Slow gives examples of how both women and men rely on gender schemas, which usually lead to different evaluations of women than men. Valian emphasizes how small biases accumulate and that "mountains are molehills piled one on top of another." Babcock and Laschever also demonstrate how disadvantages can accumulate over time, such as a slight decrease in initial salary costing thousands over years of raises based on that salary, and how different negotiation styles and responses influence outcomes. Mahoney shows how personal decisions usually lead to traditional gender roles and division of labor at home, even when unintended. All of these references, including the ACE publication on flexibility in faculty positions, provide institutions and individuals with recommendations to bring about necessary change and don't rely on the idea that we need to teach women to survive in a man's world.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref122" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>60. Emilie M. Townes, Andrew W. Mellon Professor of African-American Religion and Theology, Yale Divinity School.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_374a7935d55cf9d9fbb16c6f433bfa1b"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2785d00d50d5e27d9b83ef342a6d5970">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Dr. Townes' teaching and general research interests focus on Christian ethics, womanist ethics, critical social theory, cultural theory and studies, as well as postmodernism and social postmodernism. Her specific interests include health and health care; the cultural production of evil; analyzing the linkages among race, gender, class, and other forms of oppression; and developing a network between African American and Afro-Brazilian religious and secular leaders and community-based organizations. Among her many publications is <title render="italic">
                        Womanist Ethics and the Cultural Production of Evil
                     </title>.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref124" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>61.Sarah Weiss, Assistant Professor of Ethnomusicology.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_29b5cb0588498ee26a0bc13a79c25abb"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3d4e899e23faf63f576691397da08b0a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Listening to an Earlier Java: Aesthetics, Gender and the Music of Wayang in Central Java
                     </title> - In 'old-style' Central Javanese wayang, still known to many shadow-puppet performers and musicians in Java today, the male dhalang and his primary accompanist, usually a female player of the gender (a metallophone with 13 or 14 keys), are gendered embodiments of a Javanese aesthetic that has its origins in early Java. Analysis of the musical tradition known as 'female style' - makes it possible to reconstruct aesthetics for Javanese performance that can be felt in literary sources as early as the twelfth century and that has endured into the present through cultural and political upheaval and globalized change during the colonial and postcolonial periods. Ethnomusicologist Sarah Weiss, herself a gamelan musician who has directed ensembles in Australia and the United States over many years, examines for the first time the musical practices, concepts, stories, changing historical circumstances, and myths that have shaped 'female-style' gender playing into a uniquely significant mode of artistic practice. This study is the first large-scale treatment of gender issues in Indonesian music. Integrating the analysis of gender and music with that of aesthetics, this study of the musical synergy between the puppeteer and his female accompanist describes the ways in which shifting gender constructions have helped to shape and change Central Javanese music and theatre performance practice while throwing new light on the history of Javanese gender relations and culture, as well as on the aesthetics of Central Javanese shadow-puppet theatre.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref126" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>62. Laura Wexler, Professor of American Studies, Professor and Chair of Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_65f9e17cb768cbf32f2d3cc7f9b7292c"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_51768eba59e6a219596e7f7472924df4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Tender Violence
                     </title> is an incisive analysis of how the first American female photojournalists contributed to a "domestic vision" that reinforced the imperialism and racism of turn-of-the-century America. These women photographers, white and middle class, constructed images of war disguised as peace through a mechanism Wexler calls the "averted eye," which had its origins in the private domain of family photography. Wexler examines the work of Frances Benjamin Johnston, Gertrude Kasebier, Alice Austen, the Gerhard sisters, and Jesse Tarbox Beals. The book includes more than 150 photographs taken between 1898 and 1904, such as photos Johnston took aboard Admiral Dewey's flagship as it returned home from conquering Manila, Austen's photos of immigrants at Ellis Island, and Beals' images of the St. Louis World's Fair of 1904. In a groundbreaking approach to the study of photography, Wexler raises up these images as "texts" to be analyzed alongside other texts of the period for what they have to say about the discourses of power. <title render="italic">
                        Tender Violence
                     </title> won the Joan Kelley Memorial Prize of the American Historical Association in 2002.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref128" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>63. Whitney and Betty MacMillan Center for International and Area Studies at Yale.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_b098f2b88e0b02acde8196044b28fdfe"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1c08d267b93465e258b81182c5b104d3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Iraq's Collateral Damage
                     </title> - Samantha Power is the Anna Lindh Professor of Practice of Global Leadership and Public Policy at Harvard's John F. Kennedy School of Government. Her book, <title render="italic">
                        A Problem from Hell": America and the Age of Genocide
                     </title>, was awarded the 2003 Pulitzer Prize for general non-fiction, the 2003 National Book Critics Circle Award for general non-fiction, and the Council on Foreign Relations' Arthur Ross Prize for the best book in US. foreign policy. Powers' <title render="italic">
                        New Yorker
                     </title> article on the horrors in Darfur, Sudan won the 2005 National, Magazine Award for best reporting. Power was the founding executive director of the Carr Center for Human Rights Policy (1998-2002). From 1993-1996, she covered the wars in the former Yugoslavia as a reporter for the <title render="italic">
                        U. S. News and World Report
                     </title>, <title render="italic">
                        The Boston Globe
                     </title>, and <title render="italic">
                        The Economist
                     </title>. Power is the editor, with Graham Allison, of <title render="italic">
                        Realizing Human Rights: Moving from Inspiration to Impact
                     </title>. A graduate of Yale University and Harvard Law School, she moved to the United States from Ireland at the age of nine. She spent 2005-06 working in the office of Senator Barack Obama and is currently writing a political biography of the UN's Sergio Vieira de Mello.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref130" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>64. Women Faculty Forum.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_02d31c1bf65b9944ebaaba670d77f71a"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_95485b4723e5e7ab55d6e0b6ecbf4109">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Yale Women Faculty Forum (WFF) emerged from the effort, during Yale's tercentennial year, to highlight the presence of women at the university and the accomplishments of Yale alumnae. Professors and staff from across the campus from diverse fields in the college, the professional and graduate schools - came together to develop programs for the Tercentennial. We learned not only that we enjoy doing work together but also that there is a great deal more that we could yet do. To that end, with the support of the President and administration, the Council of the WFF is continuing to work in conjunction with alumnae and interested faculty and students to foster community for the many women at Yale and to deepen our understandings of the effects and implications of gender on all fields of thought. The purposes of WFF include: Promote scholarship on gender and scholarship about and by women across all schools of the university; Foster gender equity throughout the university.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref132" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>65. Women's Health Interest Group (WHIG) Margaret Reynolds, Yale Medical School Student '10.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_42746e99129037c466d3e3dc2118768c"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7cbee059fd13a781db4867da607ec853">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WHIG organizes events for men and women surrounding women's health topics and women's careers in medicine. WHIG promotes networking related to women's health education, research, clinical care, and activism. The following activities are organized by WHIG: Brown Bag Lunch Discussions: Lunch series with female physicians in Yale community focused on life and career choices; Women's Health Journal Club: Biweekly meetings on current topics in women"s health lead by expert faculty members (Spring semester); Women Physician Mentorship Program: Matches up 1st and 2nd year medical students with female physicians in the Yale community based on personal and academic interests; Selected Speakers: Recruitment of speakers addressing recent women's health research and activism.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref134" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>66. Elisabeth Jean Wood, Professor of Political Science.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_83c140775f4bcea616a6f0da313367cf"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_86e3a3266afd4952a669a9f97065bae9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Variation in Sexual Violence during War-Sexual violence during war varies in extent and takes distinct forms. In some conflicts, sexual violence is widespread, yet in other conflicts-including some cases of ethnic conflict-it is quite limited. In some conflicts, sexual violence takes the form of sexual slavery; in others, torture in detention. I document this variation, particularly its absence in some conflicts and on the part of some groups. In the conclusion, I explore the relationship between strategic choices on the part of armed group leadership, the norms of combatants, dynamics within small units, and the effectiveness of military discipline.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref136" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>67. Tina Wu, Calhoun College '08</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_debab9d8693dd3bbf9baf6eb5c856732"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a6fff021f122206a230e6399039bfb42">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>[Abstract not available]</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref138" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>68. Meg Urry, Israel Munson Professor of Physics and Astronomy.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_49b5d59497e94dfde4ea48a36622526f"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e56862eb8297b7d8f526dbe628f4d0a5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>A Multiwavelength View of the Kiloparsec - scale jet in 3c273 - For the past decade, large-scale jets have been studied in X-rays with Chandra and at optical wavelengths with Hubble. Now with the Spitzer Space Telescope, it is also possible to detect these jets in the infrared. The first such detection was in PKS 0637-752 (Uchiyama et al. 2005). Here we report the second infrared detection of a kiloparsec-scale jet, in the well-known quasar 3C273 (Uchiyama et al. 2006). Two different models have been proposed for X-rays from jet knots: direct synchrotron emission and inverse Compton scattering of cosmic microwave background photons. The infrared data offer new clues to distinguish these possibilities. The results of the study were the following: Spectra of the first, X-ray-brightest knots (Fig. 3) show clearly that the infrared emission is the high-frequency end of the radio-synchrotron component, while much of the optical emission is associated with the X-ray component. Given the similarity between the radio and optical polarization of 3C273 (although the latter has not yet been measured for individual knots), this suggests the X-rays are produced by the synchrotron process rather than inverse-Compton scattering of CMB photons. Sensitive, spatially-resolved polarization measurements of the knot, with HST, are needed to confirm this suggestion.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref140" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>69. Yale Center for International and Area Studies.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_554090dfdce0c8c981f0e0c0c5de0475"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4438f95bf9f79cefe8ebbca63d8be623">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Marnphela Ramphele - Dr. Ramphele became the first black person to be vice chancellor of a previously white academic institution, University of Capetown, South Africa. She became the first African to be the managing director of the World Bank in 2000. She has been responsible for human development activities in the areas of education; health, nutrition, and population; and social protection. She also launched Circle Capital, a unique venture capital investment company that she heads as chairperson. It operates as a black-owned building company that helps organizations of various sizes with varying needs, such as strategic leadership and access to investment and operational management. Dr. Ramphele has received numerous national and international awards, several honorary doctorates, including a Doctor of Humane Letters from Yale University in 2005, and has written numerous books. She serves on the boards of major corporations and non governmental organizations, including the Nelson Mandela Children's Trust.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref142" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>70. Yale Law Women.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_2a29a74e6636b77af57ed801b539fe00"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e6f5e6e20ad9a7babe02e0081a177a9a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Yale Law Women congratulates the Top Ten Family-Friendly Firms - This analysis is based on self-reported data from www.nalpdirectory.com, including the NALP Form and the Workplace Questionnaire. YLW analyzed the 53 law firms that received the highest number of bids from YLS students during the 2005 Fall Interview Program (any firm receiving more than 14 bids from YLS students). In the first phase, YLW identified the top ten firms with the most generous policies regarding family leave, child care facilities, and benefits for part time lawyers. In the second phase, to further differentiate between the top ten, YLW evaluated other factors important to female law students, including the percentage of women partners, associates, and summer associates and percentage of lawyers who have alternative work schedules (flextime/part-time). While the first phase examined the substance of each firm's policies, this second level of analysis evaluated how those policies worked in practice. While YLW believes childcare and family responsibilities should be shared equally between partners in a relationship, it is a reality that women currently perform the vast majority of childcare duties. Thus, the number of women working at a firm provides one indication of how easily attorneys find their working lives combine with familial responsibilities.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref144" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>71. Yale Program for Women's Reproductive Behavioral Health.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_fd1c1e84cd0f9099fd7e85656aa6676e"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_55d50673a2120c60f983d415b3e562fb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Yale Program for Women's Reproductive Behavioral Health (WRBH) is a multidisciplinary research program and clinical consultation service in the Departments of Psychiatry and Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Sciences and an affiliate of the Women's Health Research at Yale. C. Neil1 Epperson, M.D., founder and Director of WRBH, leads a team of clinicians and investigators that includes post-doctoral fellows, psychologists, a therapist, an advanced practice nurse, Yale medical and undergraduate students, and research assistance. Research conducted includes menstrual cycle studies, menopause studies, and perinatal studies.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref146" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>72. 30 Years of Sisterhood.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075329087)"
                             altrender="flat box (16d 1h 20w)"
                             id="aspace_ff652ce977bf0c7dca492aa6458176fa"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ddd061e6a3c1a0ad0a5e9ffc21d57077">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>
                     <title render="italic">
                        Thirty Years of Sisterhood: Women in the 1970s Women's Liberation Movement in Japan
                     </title> is a documentary film on the 1970s genesis of the Japanese women's liberation movement. The film explores the Japanese women's liberation movement, which began in the 1970s and continues today. It features recent interviews with women who were involved in the movement and includes rare video footage and photos of 1970s activism. It has been called a highly significant attempt to record this important but neglected history. It was screened on Wednesday, February 15, 2006 at Yale University, and included the following participants: Yarnagami Chieko (Film Director), Seyama Noriko (Film Director), Akiyama Yoko (Professor of Chinese Studies, Surugadai University), Miki Soko (Professor of English and Women's Studies, Kyoto Seika University), Karen Nakamura (Assistant Professor of Anthropology, Yale University), Christopher Gerteis (Postdoctoral Associate, Council on East Asian Studies, Yale University).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
