<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY-BR"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.lockerlamp">beinecke.lockerlamp</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Frederick Locker-Lampson Correspondence
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Locker-Lampson (Frederick) Correspondence</titleproper>
            <author>Beinecke Staff</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:title="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2014 May 14</date>
            <num>OSB MSS 152</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Wednesday April 24, 2019 at 03:01</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Frederick Locker-Lampson Correspondence</unittitle>
         <unitid>OSB MSS 152</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
            </corpname>
         </repository>
    
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">11.89</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(33 boxes)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1770/1897">1770-1897</unitdate>
         
         
            <unitdate type="bulk" normal="1853/1885">1853-1885</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_fede83d1f379df9fdf6ade0ea88d3d3c">The Frederick Locker-Lampson Correspondence is a collection of over 2,000 letters, accompanied by a few manuscripts and family papers, consisting primarily of letters received by Frederick Locker-Lampson. In addition to substantial quantities of letters from members of his immediate and extended families, the collection contains letters from scores of English literary figures, including F.T. Palgrave, Simeon Solomon, James Gibbs, and Richard Garnett. Some of Locker-Lampson's better-known literary friends and colleagues, Including Lord Alfred Tennyson, Robert Browning, and Austin Dobson, are represented by single letters, although there are no substantive correspondences with them.

The collection also contains correspondence pertaining to Frederick's father, Edward Hawke Locker, including letters to his wife written during his naval career, and letters from the Irish author John Wilson Croker.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_548bdfa0ca81bc9d37ec4fd51f74ae21">
            <language>In English; some letters in French and Italian.</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50051442"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               Locker-Lampson, Frederick, 1821-1895
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_7cef3784a6b6ea49cf63b5ff267e537d">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4564dc2ab07d1f3d2f79fbfc7438c0d0">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Frederick Locker-Lampson Correspondence is a collection of over 2,000 letters, accompanied by a few manuscripts and family papers, consisting primarily of letters received by Frederick Locker-Lampson. In addition to substantial quantities of letters from members of his immediate and extended families, the collection contains letters from scores of English literary figures, including F.T. Palgrave, Simeon Solomon, James Gibbs, and Richard Garnett. Some of Locker-Lampson's better-known literary friends and colleagues, Including Lord Alfred Tennyson, Robert Browning, and Austin Dobson, are represented by single letters, although there are no substantive correspondences with them.</p>
         <p>The collection also contains correspondence pertaining to Frederick's father, Edward Hawke Locker, including letters to his wife written during his naval career, and letters from the Irish author John Wilson Croker.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_0efeb07452b3b2a1984cf81b91a01dc5">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Purchased from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. on the James Osborn and Marie-Louise Osborn Fund, 1993.</p>
         <p>Ex libris Jonathan Locker-Lampson. Formerly on deposit at the East Sussex Record Office Library, United Kingdom.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_5bb5d08b0f935266142e423894bde277">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Frederick Locker-Lampson Correspondence. James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <arrangement id="aspace_d15b82051a203a075e8470bd627a938e">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The collection is arranged in the exact order in which it was received, which is the order followed by the Historical Manuscript Commission in their item-level volume and bundle list. To quote from their introduction: "The bulk of the papers listed here are mounted and bound in six large albums; the remaining (mainly later) papers are in a number of bundles. The contents of the albums were mounted by James Gibbs in an approximately chronological sequence, which has been preserved in the Contents list." With the exception of the physical re-housing of the material in boxes and folders, no further arrangement work has been done on this collection.</p>
         <p>Researchers should note that this guide can be used only in conjunction with the <title>
               List of Locker-Lampson Mss.
            </title>; a copy is housed in Box 1 of this collection. A second copy has been cataloged as Osborn e18. To search for a particular correspondent or topic in that index, look in the alphabetical lists in Parts II and III of that work, note the volume, page and document (or bundle and document) numbers given in the entry, and match them to the volume/bundle and item number spans given for boxes in the listing below. Part I of the<title>
               List
            </title> is the item level contents list of the collection. Researchers should look through this as well to determine if there are other items of interest that were not included in the alphabetical index.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <processinfo id="aspace_6ce71d992c0d5b1de31703080dc56c31">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>The collection was received in 1993 in six folio albums and nine bundles of varying size, all of which had been listed at the item level by the British Historical Manuscripts Commission for their National Register of Archives.. The material was removed from these binders and housed in acid-free boxes and folders in the exact order in which it was received. The folders are annotated with volume, page, and document numbers in the case of the volumes, and bundle and document numbers for the bundled materials.</p>
         <p>This finding aid is a key to the item-level HMC/NRA list, one copy of which is housed in Box 1 of this collection. A second copy has been cataloged as Osborn e18. Folder titles, consisting of a volume or bundle number followed by a page number (or numbers), were supplied by staff during initial processing.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_97da82b6e3245096ae796a07571beb0b">
         <head>Frederick Locker-Lampson, 1821-1895</head>
         <p>Frederick Locker-Lampson was born Frederick Locker at the Royal Naval Hospital in 1821, the third child of Edward Hawke Locker, the civil commissioner for the hospital. He was educated at several preparatory schools before becoming a junior clerk in a colonial broker's office in 1837. From 1841 to 1849 he held a series of offices with the Admiralty, including deputy reader and précis writer for Lord Haddington. He received a leave of absence for health reasons in May 1849, and began extensive travels in Europe.</p>
         <p>On July 4,1850, Locker married Lady Charlotte Christian Bruce, a daughter of the Earl of Elgin and a friend of Queen Victoria. They had one daughter, Eleanor, who in 1878 married Lionel Tennyson, the son of the poet. Locker retired from government service, and despite his continued poor health was a member of several London clubs; his literary friends included Thackeray, Tennyson, Trollope, Kinglake, Lamartine, Lord Lytton, and George Eliot. He also collected fine and rare books, particularly Elizabethan imprints, Louis XVI furniture, and Chinese porcelain. The Lockers often summered at Frogmore House, one of the royal retreats.</p>
         <p>In 1857 he published his first and only collection of original verse, London Lyrics, a ninety page volume that received several editions during his lifetime. Lyra elegantiarum, an anthology of occasional verse, appeared in 1867. Lady Charlotte Bruce Locker died in 1872, and in 1874 Locker married Hannah Jane Lampson, a children's author who was also the heiress of Sir Curtis Miranda Lampson of Rowfant, first baronet. The couple had four children, two sons and two daughters.</p>
         <p>Locker published Patchwork, a collection of extracts he referred to as his "little Commonplace-Book," in 1879. His father-in-law died in 1885, and Locker took the name Lampson in order to inherit the family estates. Locker-Lampson settled at Rowfant, and in 1886 privately published The Rowfant Library, A Catalogue. Edited by Alfred W. Pollard and R. H. Lister, the catalogue described the books, manuscripts, autographs, and works of art owned by Locker-Lampson. In the same year, his son-in-law Lionel Tennyson died of jungle fever during his voyage home from India. Two years later, Eleanor Locker Tennyson married the literary critic and politician Augustine Birrell.</p>
         <p>Frederick Locker-Lampson died at Rowfant on May 30th, 1895. A volume of memoirs and genealogical information, My Reminiscences, was published in 1896, edited by Augustine Birrell, who also compiled a list of Locker-Lampson's late additions to his library. The Rowfant Library itself was sold to an American bookdealer, almost certainly Robert Dodd, in 1905.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <userestrict id="aspace_16e9b0423e7911aaf5ebb98813b7246e">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Frederick Locker-Lampson Correspondence is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="local">
            Authors, English -- 19th century -- Archives
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85043782"
                  source="lcsh">
            English literature -- 19th century
         </subject>
         <occupation source="local">
            Authors -- Great Britain -- 19th century
         </occupation>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79043688"
                   source="naf">
            Browning, Robert, 1812-1889
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79045428"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Croker, John Wilson, 1780-1857
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50030908"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79059978"
                   source="naf">
            Garnett, Richard, 1835-1906
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            Gibbs, James, 1825-1886
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n84128854"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Locker, Edward Hawke, 1777-1849
         </persname>
         <famname rules="aacr" source="local">
            Locker-Lampson family
         </famname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50051442"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Locker-Lampson, Frederick, 1821-1895
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50051781"
                   source="naf">
            Palgrave, Francis Turner, 1824-1897
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/nr88006277"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Solomon, Simeon, 1840-1905
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79142936"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892
         </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref1" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Volumes</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <physdesc>
                  <extent unit="Linear Feet">9.59</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(24 boxes)</physdesc>
               
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1770/1876">1770-1876</unitdate>
               
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a3e910e3f62becf9314fa1625e2723ae">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The original order has been retained. The material in Volumes I-V is in rough chronological order; the letters in Volume VI are in rough alphabetical order. Volumes I-III contain the papers of Edward Hawke Locker. Volumes IV and V contain the papers of Frederick Locker-Lampson. Volume VI holds "the remains of an autograph collection."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>List of Locker-Lampson Mss.</unittitle>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449598)"
                             id="aspace_381edf8ea086da023ff50608acc7892a"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume I, page 1, item i - Volume I, page 100, item i</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1780-1808</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449630)"
                             id="aspace_eb2d4261c60e159dcd291488150c3158"
                             type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_da4cbd5c77ec85be9190fefb35ef7d51"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_eb2d4261c60e159dcd291488150c3158">1-71</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume I, page 101, item i - Volume I, page 157, item i</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1808-1815</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449648)"
                             id="aspace_6340d00125c96abd5650b775556ea985"
                             type="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_302af78c25df77e41ccbb5598243e374"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_6340d00125c96abd5650b775556ea985">72-151</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume II, page 14, item i - Volume II, page 63, item ii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1807-1815</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449655)"
                             id="aspace_c651d483df488d5430620f8d3bcc3f9b"
                             type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_467450a2bce02e24dd92c566968e3195"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c651d483df488d5430620f8d3bcc3f9b">152-230</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume II, page 64, item i - Volume II, page 103, item ii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1815-1820</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449663)"
                             id="aspace_b64c7af89baa284eb01d66761b03e2e0"
                             type="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d99da2ecca38060130c7a3ee89c98deb"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b64c7af89baa284eb01d66761b03e2e0">231-305</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume III, page 20, item i - Volume III, page 65, item ii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1820-1826</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449671)"
                             id="aspace_e4334be53e0d5703e3115dcff88e492b"
                             type="box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e4ee5699762db3b7994bfdca61ba8239"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e4334be53e0d5703e3115dcff88e492b">306-384</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume III, page 66, item i - Volume III, page 102, item ii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1827-1834</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449689)"
                             id="aspace_4faab333c3748ac08f6219a061f358b7"
                             type="box">7</container>
                  <container id="aspace_dc510660a29e109fa187b6934366f55b"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_4faab333c3748ac08f6219a061f358b7">385-445</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume IV, page 1, item i - Volume IV, page 9, item xxxviii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1841-1859</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449697)"
                             id="aspace_a543b963bf1b9320fea8a35b89bb4351"
                             type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0cd1180d57cd228352938582c3136c94"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_a543b963bf1b9320fea8a35b89bb4351">446-540</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume IV, page 10, item i - Volume IV, page 19, item xii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1859-1863</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449705)"
                             id="aspace_b29802cf4e24fb01dbe2a93e86b73116"
                             type="box">9</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d2777bd273c80d7806d3ab324b6bc4f7"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b29802cf4e24fb01dbe2a93e86b73116">541-636</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume IV, page 20, item i - Volume IV, page 29, item xxvi</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1862-1865</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449713)"
                             id="aspace_51d1bf686ac7f5451bd4b644e78f4238"
                             type="box">10</container>
                  <container id="aspace_46890a6c158ea1c1656856a8a5f2b078"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_51d1bf686ac7f5451bd4b644e78f4238">637-728</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume IV, page 30, item i - Volume IV, page 50, item xxii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1866</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449721)"
                             id="aspace_b93c15ca232dcdc00e7bee68a8cc7679"
                             type="box">11</container>
                  <container id="aspace_dc76e3ef1544be9d2c8a189616ac0913"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b93c15ca232dcdc00e7bee68a8cc7679">729-829</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume IV, page 51, item i - Volume IV, page 59, item xiii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1866-1867</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449739)"
                             id="aspace_af4a604fe5d9889a138313fca7b2d754"
                             type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e3dfd26b3abdffcdc9176e7a285072fa"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_af4a604fe5d9889a138313fca7b2d754">830-959</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume IV, page 60, item i - Volume IV, page 65, item xx</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1867</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449747)"
                             id="aspace_603cabf84846ae8521e8a8cea4e7557f"
                             type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_88f09fe2811af7b1f14e8f93116548c0"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_603cabf84846ae8521e8a8cea4e7557f">960-1034</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume IV, page 66, item i - Volume IV, page 85, item vii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1867-1890</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449754)"
                             id="aspace_f8cc945f50e24e8466836c6958883cf6"
                             type="box">14</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1bea672f4f7d380fccd91a152d081118"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_f8cc945f50e24e8466836c6958883cf6">1035-1128</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, preliminary page - Volume V, page 26, item vi</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1868-1869</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449762)"
                             id="aspace_779f4221d04144c5e73f8892269d8d30"
                             type="box">15</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f2f68b51a929ea058572cbb998560b0e"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_779f4221d04144c5e73f8892269d8d30">1129-1270</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, page 27, item i - Volume V, page 49, item ii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1869-1870</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449770)"
                             id="aspace_b5f261fd77f96e0fe75b219737223a82"
                             type="box">16</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d2b4ee6c1f7f05e55e5a0df205367f03"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b5f261fd77f96e0fe75b219737223a82">1271-1410</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, page 51, item i - Volume V, page 82, item v</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1870-1871</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449788)"
                             id="aspace_69b3f27cc7569d83b878d10b237d2434"
                             type="box">17</container>
                  <container id="aspace_39a3c8ea52284a5ae0de0b4e7a1e4cd8"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_69b3f27cc7569d83b878d10b237d2434">1411-1550</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, page 83, item i - Volume V, page 110, item iv</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1871-1872</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449796)"
                             id="aspace_6581eeaa03977e5c0a597c0de0e55024"
                             type="box">18</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4ba0cc8f977bac9939dc4fc07fba3d60"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_6581eeaa03977e5c0a597c0de0e55024">1551-1693</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, page 111, item i - Volume V, page 144, item vii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1872-1873</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449804)"
                             id="aspace_4bb3739161347e7250de8118d7a23e29"
                             type="box">19</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7895452fd8cfb38332a26a44a33b7c95"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_4bb3739161347e7250de8118d7a23e29">1694-1834</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, page 145, item i - Volume V, page 171, item vi</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1873-1874</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449812)"
                             id="aspace_05f085aa5025756a69afbe76173ced0a"
                             type="box">20</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c6dd67baeee9cab3275472e0ed2916b9"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_05f085aa5025756a69afbe76173ced0a">1835-1979</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, page 172, item i - Volume V, page 195, item v</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-1875</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449820)"
                             id="aspace_2ff38a59aa355b4c80212f75cd760b8a"
                             type="box">21</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8e4fb3c8aa995b198fd5b9e3ef1ab60b"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_2ff38a59aa355b4c80212f75cd760b8a">1980-2120</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, page 196, item i - Volume V, page 220, item iv</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1875-1876</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449838)"
                             id="aspace_e7ee5efe786da4f6320e1d2bc27eedec"
                             type="box">22</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7539fa46827f759cf46e2b9e37151d62"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e7ee5efe786da4f6320e1d2bc27eedec">2121-2260</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume V, page 221, item i - Volume V, page 232, item vii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1876</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449846)"
                             id="aspace_48b3be95fac807e69db692aaf8879e1e"
                             type="box">23</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d66ffab0f399be50ca3e4d9e20fa9601"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_48b3be95fac807e69db692aaf8879e1e">2261-2323</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume VI, page 28, item i - Volume VI, page 85, item ii</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1770-1867</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449853)"
                             id="aspace_eeb599d44a8d69aefa3fe4c3bab37100"
                             type="box">24</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8fe622fd9c8a1ce332506b4951c2b048"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_eeb599d44a8d69aefa3fe4c3bab37100">2324-2379</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref2" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Bundles</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
               <physdesc>
                  <extent unit="Linear Feet">2.3</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(9 boxes)</physdesc>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1847-1897</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_cf3a6c43dc4559cda98a431154d5e887">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The received order has been retained. For further information, see<title>
                     List of Locker-Lampson Mss.
                  </title> in Box 1.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle VII, preliminary pages - Bundle VII, item 109</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1886-1888</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449861)"
                             id="aspace_a394b040f291b97e7ce2de01f80f2618"
                             type="box">25</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1d43fc77743d16930b66cec9c0124e66"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_a394b040f291b97e7ce2de01f80f2618">2380-2498</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle VII, item 110 - Bundle VII, item 135</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1886-1887</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449879)"
                             id="aspace_76c48cb89f7c2a0057b7088312d9f3c5"
                             type="box">26</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e7c36a384f2c1dd9de7b5a2e4897f3d2"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_76c48cb89f7c2a0057b7088312d9f3c5">2499-2524</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle VIII, preliminary pages - Bundle VIII, item 33</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1874-1892</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449887)"
                             id="aspace_b16b07cc5b9b06afb9333eb07b9b8db9"
                             type="box">27</container>
                  <container id="aspace_12a78cce0262403502f2f057ddfe2943"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b16b07cc5b9b06afb9333eb07b9b8db9">2525-2559</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle IX, preliminary pages - Bundle IX, item 18</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1880-1885</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449895)"
                             id="aspace_aabbe32c75e6e3fc199e8372d9bfbbc9"
                             type="box">28</container>
                  <container id="aspace_92dbcc2a2074d490f1d736358bfef7ea"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_aabbe32c75e6e3fc199e8372d9bfbbc9">2560-2580</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle X, preliminary pages - Bundle X, item 19</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1895</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449903)"
                             id="aspace_86e1a7939cfcd8e068c114cdac7633f5"
                             type="box">29</container>
                  <container id="aspace_856729bd66cc4b305f5d263c08d7a57e"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_86e1a7939cfcd8e068c114cdac7633f5">2581-2601</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle XI, preliminary pages - Bundle XI, item 105</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1885</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449911)"
                             id="aspace_eff249edde3b4219dc1b992028d07c91"
                             type="box">30</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2ff13cb04ab8f9001e2c37016f20fb66"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_eff249edde3b4219dc1b992028d07c91">2602-2711</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle XII, preliminary pages - Bundle XII, item 20</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1858-1887</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449929)"
                             id="aspace_8366ccbffcc920d53ecfe7c7bf2b02cd"
                             type="box">31</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b045ca687641835ba9b733209770d64a"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_8366ccbffcc920d53ecfe7c7bf2b02cd">2712-2732</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle XIII, preliminary pages - Bundle XIII, item 24</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1880-1884</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449937)"
                             id="aspace_a7db372cddbaf3b0cf28f3a6e15b1706"
                             type="box">32</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e8399be7fe4c5f7304cbfd3eba7cc695"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_a7db372cddbaf3b0cf28f3a6e15b1706">2733-2757</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bundle XIV - Bundle XV, item 7</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1847-1897</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002099449945)"
                             id="aspace_ff400875ea007ec6a1aa068ad449c9ed"
                             type="box">33</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a24eea49162f3398097ea614cdc5899e"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_ff400875ea007ec6a1aa068ad449c9ed">2758-2768</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
