<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY-BR"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.sfaustin">beinecke.sfaustin</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Thomas W. Streeter Collection of Austin Family and Texas Revolution Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Streeter (Thomas W.) Collection of Austin Family and Texas Revolution Papers</titleproper>
            <author>by Alison Clemens</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:title="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2014</date>
            <num>WA MSS S-3000</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Wednesday March 20, 2019 at 03:01</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Thomas W. Streeter Collection of Austin Family and Texas Revolution Papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>WA MSS S-3000</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">0.63</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(2 boxes)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1786/1942">1786-1942</unitdate>
         
         
            <unitdate type="bulk" normal="1814/1858">1814-1858</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_cbf9eb3649d108bdca3ee21f505befb9">Legal and financial documents, correspondence, and military records documenting the history of Texas and the Spanish Southwest. Included is manuscript material generated by the families of Moses and Stephen F. Austin during the settlement of Texas; military records pertaining to the Mier Expedition and the capture of San Antonio de Bexar during the Texas Revolution; and Thomas W. Streeter's research files on the history of Texas and the Spanish Southwest.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/nr89006048"
                      role="col"
                      source="naf">
               Streeter, Thomas W. (Thomas Winthrop), 1883-1965
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <arrangement id="aspace_fdccd2955383d277fc853a1b7d4089f6">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Organized into three series: I. Austin Family Papers, 1786-1858. II. Texas Revolution Papers, 1836-1852. III. Thomas W. Streeter Research Files, 1942, undated.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_cf4329d6a257b32aa85fb5ceadef03ce">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_6f8d91709606b09b74c5b65b1325fef0">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Thomas W. Streeter Collection of Austin Family and Texas Revolution Papers is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_515f408fdbbb63141511d8720469348b">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Thomas W. Streeter Collection of Austin Family and Texas Revolution Papers. Yale Collection of Western Americana, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist id="aspace_29aa5afa43d57a252940a166ff28431d">
         <head>Thomas W. Streeter</head>
         <p>Thomas W. Streeter (1883–1965), businessman, collector, and bibliographer, was born in New Hampshire and received degrees from Dartmouth College (B.L., 1904) and Harvard Law School (LL.B., 1907). Streeter worked as a businessman, including in the oil industry. He retired in 1939 and devoted his time to collecting and bibliography for Americana and Texana.</p>
         <p>Streeter compiled the five volume <title render="italic">
               Bibliography of Texas 1795-1845
            </title>, published in three parts. In 1957, he sold his collection of Texas imprints to Yale University.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <bioghist id="aspace_a14bedd1611bc441bc05d5d23c4d1601">
         <head>Stephen F. Austin</head>
         <p>Stephen F. Austin (1793–1836), founder of Anglo-American Texas, was born in Virginia to Moses Austin and Maria Brown Austin. Moses Austin moved his family from Virginia to Missouri in pursuit of opportunities managing lead mines. After this pursuit failed, Moses traveled to San Antonio in 1820, where he made a successful request for a land grant in Spanish Texas and the ability to bring 300 families to the region. Moses was aided in this endeavor by his association with the Baron de Bastrop, who encouraged the governor of Spanish Texas, Antonio Maria Martinez, to accept Austin's bid.</p>
         <p>Moses Austin died of pneumonia shortly after his return to Missouri, and Stephen assumed responsibility for the settlement charge. Austin began bringing settlers to Texas in 1821, shortly after Mexico achieved independence from Spain. Austin managed immigration and established and maintained the land system from the colony's capital, San Felipe de Austin. He also had civil and military control over the colony until 1828, when the Constitution of Coahuila and Texas went into effect and facilitated integration of the colony into the larger Mexican government.</p>
         <p>Upon Mexico's independence from Spain, the Mexican government began to have growing concerns about revolutionary activities in Texas. In 1831, Austin was arrested in Mexico City on allegations of attempting to incite insurrection; he was freed in July 1835 and returned to Texas. Later that year, the Texas Revolution began. Texas achieved independence in June 1836, and Austin was appointed the Republic's first Secretary of State. He died in office two months later, on December 27, 1836. His sister Emily Austin Perry's husband, James F. Perry, served as executor of his estate. After Austin's death and the independence of the Republic of Texas, border disputes with Mexico continued, such as in the Mier Expedition of 1842.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_960bc74595407ec49d2a3b154d0bb887">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Manuscript legal and financial documents, correspondence, and military records documenting the history of Texas and the Spanish Southwest. Included is manuscript material generated by the families of Moses and Stephen F. Austin during the settlement of Texas, including an 1827 transcription of the will of Baron de Bastrop; military records pertaining to the Mier Expedition and the capture of San Antonio de Bexar during the Texas Revolution; and Thomas W. Streeter's research files on the history of Texas and the Spanish Southwest.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <processinfo id="aspace_0f268a3ef792150849f429884f745d13">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived research value, the availability of staff, competing priorities, and whether or not further accruals are expected. The library attempts to provide a basic level of preservation and access for all collections, and does more extensive processing of higher priority collections as time and resources permit.</p>
         <p>This collection received a basic level of processing in 2014, including rehousing and minimal organization.</p>
         <p>Information included in the Description of Papers note and Collection Contents section is drawn from information supplied with the collection and from an initial survey of the contents. Folder titles appearing in the contents list below are often based on those provided by the creator or previous custodian. Titles have not been verified against the contents of the folders in all cases. Otherwise, folder titles are supplied by staff during initial processing.</p>
         <p>This finding aid may be updated periodically to account for new acquisitions to the collection and/or revisions in arrangement and description.</p>
         <p>Former call number: Uncat WA MS 92</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_e764ca6f6d8cc8c2c59a43cde896e7a6">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Purchased from Thomas W. Streeter, 1962.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh90001971"
                  source="lcsh">
            Land grants -- Texas
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008110494"
                  source="lcsh">
            Real property -- Texas
         </subject>
         <geogname source="local">
            Coahuila and Texas (Mexico) -- Colonization
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81035576"
                   source="lcsh">
            Coahuila (Mexico : State)
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="local">
            Mexico -- Foreign relations -- Texas
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="local">
            Texas -- Colonization
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="local">
            Texas -- Emigration and immigration
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="local">
            Texas -- Foreign relations -- Mexico
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85134269"
                   source="lcsh">
            Texas -- History -- 1846-1950
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85134268"
                   source="lcsh">
            Texas -- History -- Republic, 1836-1846
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85134265"
                   source="lcsh">
            Texas -- History -- Revolution, 1835-1836
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85134262"
                   source="lcsh">
            Texas -- History -- To 1846
         </geogname>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85134274"
                   source="lcsh">
            Texas -- Politics and government
         </geogname>
         <genreform source="local">
            Land grants -- Texas -- 19th century
         </genreform>
         <genreform source="local">
            Legal documents -- Texas -- 19th century
         </genreform>
         <genreform source="local">
            Military records -- Mexico -- 19th century
         </genreform>
         <genreform source="local">
            Wills -- Texas -- 19th century
         </genreform>
         <genreform source="local">
            Conveyances -- Texas -- 19th century
         </genreform>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/nr89006048"
                   source="naf">
            Streeter, Thomas W. (Thomas Winthrop), 1883-1965
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80119510"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Austin, Moses, 1761-1821
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50028886"
                   source="naf">
            Austin, Stephen F. (Stephen Fuller), 1793-1836
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no97065899"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Bastrop, Felipe Enrique Neri, Baron de, 1759-1827
         </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref11" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Austin Family Papers</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <physdesc>
                  <extent unit="folders">8</extent>
               </physdesc>
               
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1786/1858">1786-1858</unitdate>
               
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_a11bbd84720c22853c7378090fb8d819">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>The order in which this previously uncataloged collection was arranged has been maintained.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Moses Austin and John Rice Jones papers concerning the dispute over the Mine à Breton</unittitle>
                  
                     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1786/1797">1786-1797</unitdate>
                  
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797668)"
                             id="aspace_7919781cc0b96249fc0a40392fb5b022"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>San Felipe de Austin and early Texas papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc>
                     <extent unit="folders">3</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  
                     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1814/1858">1814-1858</unitdate>
                  
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797668)"
                             id="aspace_33408309d34efbedb8ed60661a51e758"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4e71b1996301a7ac3a16a3e93f42b106">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes a 1827 manuscript transcription of the will of Baron de Bastrop; land grants for territory in San Felipe de Austin, San Antonio de Bexar, and the Matagorda League; correspondence concerning land allocations; financial records concerning the Austin family's finances; a 1843 letter to Santa Anna concerning a plan to make peace with the Texans; and a 1831 manuscript petition from Hosea H. League and Seth Ingram to be released from the San Felipe de Austin jail.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Stephen F. Austin estate papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc>
                     <extent unit="folders">4</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  
                     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1837/1854">1837-1854</unitdate>
                  
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797668)"
                             id="aspace_800b5384e5ed65957215d846e3350cb3"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref12" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Texas Revolution Papers</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
               <physdesc>
                  <extent unit="folders">5</extent>
               </physdesc>
               
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1836/1852">1836-1852</unitdate>
               
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_6c016087b98300e4663719339cd667c2">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>The order in which this previously uncataloged collection was arranged has been maintained.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mier expedition papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc/>
                  <physdesc altrender="container_summary">2 folders</physdesc>
                  
                     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1842/1843">1842-1843</unitdate>
                  
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797668)"
                             id="aspace_f2aa508153d8dec13077cd8c4d1e7f73"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5ab5ab5eff82a6ee4b9dc8ba5de45b14">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes original manuscript documents, 20th century typed English translations, and photostats of unidentified related documents.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Capture of San Antonio de Bexar</unittitle>
                  
                     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1836/1836">1836-1836</unitdate>
                  
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797668)"
                             id="aspace_b7d5d4d87934db663a714bbc52d64209"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d5cfc29f2cc5702d63bc568e741b65ca">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Manuscript inventory of soldiers defending San Antonio, 1836; manuscript description of the dead and wounded, 1836; manuscript document justifying the capture of San Antonio, 1836; and photostats and 20th century English translations of unidentified related documents.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Military records documenting the court martial of Brigadier Major General Gabriel R. Paul</unittitle>
                  
                     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1852/1852">1852-1852</unitdate>
                  
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797668)"
                             id="aspace_440a0312bf26e6dc1af009c9cfd37b05"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Manuscript letter from the Convention of Massachusetts concerning the annexation of Texas</unittitle>
                  
                     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1845/1845">1845-1845</unitdate>
                  
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797668)"
                             id="aspace_348b5d6bedc222fd9672f842dfc8aa45"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref16" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Thomas W. Streeter Research Files</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
               <physdesc>
                  <extent unit="folders">3</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1942</unitdate>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_589842c96916cd1fb0fa9675dd5c4465">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>The order in which this previously uncataloged collection was arranged has been maintained.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photostats and other copies of material related to the Spanish Southwest from the John Carter Brown Library</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1942, undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797676)"
                             id="aspace_647bc0124157c3b13d61405b76647a76"
                             type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Typed transcriptions and translations of unidentified material relating to the history of the Spanish Southwest</unittitle>
                  <physdesc/>
                  <physdesc altrender="container_summary">2 folders</physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002104797676)"
                             id="aspace_e3353ac6828bda169846d1e9e5f69380"
                             type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
