<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY-BR"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.walkerfam">beinecke.walkerfam</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Walker Family Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Walker Family Papers</titleproper>
            <author>by Beinecke staff</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:title="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <num>WA MSS 501</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Thursday January 10, 2019 at 06:18</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Walker Family papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>WA MSS 501</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="box">1</extent>
         </physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1839/1854">1839-1854</unitdate>
         
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88295098"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               Walker, Elkanah, 1805-1877
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_634de0a6d6e5e38c0bb0f427d7795cc8">
         <head>Elkanah Walker, 1805-1877</head>
         <p>The Rev. Elkanah Walker and Cushing Eells, with their wives, were sent to Oregon in 1838 by the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions to reinforce the Mission established in 1836 by Dr. Marcus Whitman, the Rev. H. H. Spalding and their wives, and W. H. Gray. They were joined in New York by the Rev. and Mrs. Asa Bowen Smith, and in Cincinnati by Cornelius Rogers, and reached Waiilatpu August 29.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <userestrict id="aspace_d9cd51e1f68ebd3c94ca8c9e07ed22bd">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Walker Family papers collection is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_e39f43ef54aa3fa75d65b2ba4e231141">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4c6c29e57799ea2d14a5dd2a4d2fed72">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Walker Family Papers (WA MSS 501) consist of drafts or copies of
letters written by Elkanah Walker during the years 1839-54. Many of the
letters are unsigned and unfinished. The collection also includes letters
written to Elkanah and Mary Richardson Walker and a number of family papers.
Among the papers is a typewritten copy of a diary of Mary Richardson Walker,
covering the period June 10-December 31, 1838, as well as material concerning
the Columbia Maternal Association. The latter consists of  the Association's
Constitution and minutes for the period September 3, 1838-June, 1842. The
Constitution is written in a careful, copperplate hand, possibly Mary
Richardson Walker's, and is evidently the Constitution as drawn up at the
first meeting, when Mrs. Spalding was elected president, Mrs. Walker
vice-president, and Mrs. Gray recording secretary. It is followed by the
minutes of the first meeting, September 3, 1838, in Mrs. Walker's hand, and
the records of the meetings she attended through August 26, 1840, and an
account of the general meeting of June, 1842.</p>
         <p>The manuscripts cover the foundation and history of the Oregon Mission; the relations with other religious denominations; the overland emigrations; the administration of Indian affairs and work among the Indians; Marcus Whitman and the purpose of his journey of 1843—1844; the Whitman Massacre, 1847; the establishment of the Lapwai Press; and the final settlement of the Territory.</p>
         <p>In all, there are 576 pages in
the Walker Family Papers.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <processinfo id="aspace_53be74688289362c5d53cf00d91646de">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived research value, the availability of staff, competing priorities, and whether or not further accruals are expected.  The library attempts to provide a basic level of preservation and access for all collections [as they are acquired], and does more extensive processing of higher priority collections as time and resources permit.</p>
         <p>This finding aid, created before the advent of computer-generated files, has been converted into a ASCII data file by means of scanning and Optical Character Recognition software. While attempts have been made to retain the complete information from the original document a number of format changes have been made to present the structure of this archive in accordance with current practice.</p>
         <p>This finding aid may be updated periodically to account for new acquisitions to the collection and/or revisions in arrangement and description.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_068548e9e30d058eaf87e704d3dccddf">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Walker Family Papers. Yale Collection of Western Americana, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2010102158"
                  source="lcsh">
            Missions -- Oregon
         </subject>
         <subject source="local">
            Nez Percé Indians -- Missions
         </subject>
         <subject source="local">
            Nez Percé language -- Dictionaries
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85116798"
                  source="lcsh">
            Salish Indians -- Missions
         </subject>
         <subject source="local">
            Salish language -- Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.
         </subject>
         <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85095430"
                   source="lcsh">
            Oregon -- History
         </geogname>
         <occupation source="local">
            Missionaries -- Oregon
         </occupation>
         <persname source="local">
            Greene, David
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88295098"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Walker, Elkanah, 1805-1877
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88295099"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Walker, Mary Richardson, 1811-1897
         </persname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50060748"
                   source="naf">
            American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80089976"
                   source="naf">
            Hudson's Bay Company
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref7" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Papers</unittitle>
               <unitid>WA MSS 501</unitid>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_2bb81e2f8c36be57617f2cb665e0a76b">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <list>
                  <head>The following letters and papers are included in the collection:</head>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Two letters to the editor of The
Christian [Mirror?]. October 6, 1846 [n.d.]. 9 pp.

</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to the members of the Columbia Mission. Chimakine [SIC], October 27, 1839. Endorsed, in Whitman's hand: "Oct. 1839, Mr. Walker to the members of the Mission." 4 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to Chief Factor James Douglas. March 8, 1842. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to "My dear friends." October 26, 1847. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Eight letters to the Rev. David Greene, Secretary, American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. February 7, 1839-January 18, 1847. 58 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to Edwin O. Hall. June 28, 1842. 6 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Two letters to the Hudson's Bay Company. March 17, 1847, one enclosing an order for goods. 5 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Three letters to John L. Lewes. January 13, 1847-March 9, 1848. 14 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to Archibald McDonald. September 22, 1845. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Two letters to Dr. John McLoughlin, Chief Factor, Hudson's Bay Company. March 20, 1840. Drafts. 6 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to the editors of the New England Puritan. February 3, 1846. 7 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Two letters to the Rev. H. H. Spalding. March 12, 1840, August 10, 1842. 5 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to John Mix Stanley. Undated, probably after November 1847. 7 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to Mrs. Walker. June 21, 1847. 8 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter [or journal] probably to Mrs. Walker, without beginning or end, with entries for Saturday through Tuesday, 12-15 [July 1851], while accompanying Dr. Dart as interpreter on his ex¬pedition to the Indians. 7 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Letter to "My dear Boy" [Cyrus Walker?]. April 1847. Fragment.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Copy of a form letter promising a donation to Pacific University, Tualatin, O.T. August 22, 1854. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Oregon Mission meeting, Elkanah Walker, secretary, and later moderator. Draft of minutes and votes at meetings of September 1838, February 1839, and January 1841; and a letter to the members of the Sandwich Island Mission, April 15, 18[?]. 9 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Miscellaneous manuscripts; notes for sermons; parts of letters; memoranda; receipts, bills, orders; a note¬book containing a table of distances and days crossing the continent, notes on earlier missionaries, the country trav¬ersed, the natives and their customs [12 pp.]; certificate of baptism of Michel Ogden, April 21, 1848; account book, 1849-1851 [24 pp.] ; statement of Walker's views "written on or near the tenth of March, 1854, at Tualatin Plains during a sitting of a council at this place" [8 pp.] ; Commission of the American Home Missionary Society ap¬pointing the Rev. Elkanah Walker missionary at the First Congregational Church of Hillsboro, Ore., February 11, 1867, printed form filled in by hand with a note added by Milton Badger, New York, April 22, 1867. 100 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, MARY RICHARDSON (MRS. ElKANAH). Diary, June 10-December 31, 1838. Typewritten copy. Endorsed: "Copied by J. E. Walker." 34 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, MARY RICHARDSON (MRS. ElKANAH). Part of a letter describing the journey west, arrival at the Whitmans', their arrival and home at Tshimakain, written during the summer of 1839. 4 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, MARY RICHARDSON (MRS. ElKANAH). Letter to the Rev. S. A. McLean. June 7 [1842?]. Draft. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, MARY RICHARDSON (MRS. ElKANAH). Part of a letter to Sister C. [Charlotte Richardson?]. October 26, 1847. Draft. 1 p.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, MARY RICHARDSON (MRS. ElKANAH). Three letters to Mrs. Mercy L. Whitney. July 28, 1839-April 16, 1847. Drafts. 9 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, MARY RICHARDSON (MRS. ElKANAH). Memorandum in pencil, regarding raising money for Sunday school books, May 8 [1836]; manuscript poems, and memoranda. 6 pp.</item>
                  <item>COLUMBIA MATERNAL ASSOCIATION. Constitution and minutes, September 3, 1838-June 1842. 10 pp. 

The Constitution is written in a careful, copperplate hand, possibly Mrs. Walker's, and is evidently the Constitution as drawn up at the first meeting, when Mrs. Spal¬ding was elected president, Mrs. Walker vice-president, and Mrs. Gray recording secretary. It is followed by the minutes of the first meeting, September 3, 1838, in Mrs. Walker's hand, and the records of the meetings she attended through August 26, 1840, and the general meeting of June 1842.</item>
                  <item>ALLEN, RUTH C. Letter to Mary Richardson. December 19, 1832. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>DOUGLAS, JAMES. Letter to Mr. Walker. February 7, 1849. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>ERMATINGER, FRANCIS. Letter to C. Rogers. January 14, 1839. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>FLETT, JOHN. Letter to Mr. Walker. April 13, 1857. 1 p.</item>
                  <item>FLETT, THOMAS. Three letters to Mr. Walker. January 21-April 26, 1845. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>FRASER, PAUL. Letter to Mr. Walker. March 18, 1845. 1 p.</item>
                  <item>GRIFFIN, MRS. DESIRE. Letter to Mrs. Walker. February 15, 1840. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>HALE, HORATIO. Two letters to Mr. Walker. October 8, 1841. 5 pp.</item>
                  <item>HALL, EDWIN O. Three letters to Eells and Walker. May 5, 1839-March 16, 1840. 9 pp.</item>
                  <item>HATCH, SARAH C. Letter to Mrs. Walker. July 13, 1858. 4 pp.</item>
                  <item>JOHNSON, ROBERT E. Letter to the Ladies of the Mission [May 1841]. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>JOHNSON, ROBERT E. Letter to Eells and Walker. June 27, 1841. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>JORDEN, WILLIAM V. Letter to Mr. Walker. October 25, 1846. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>LITTLEJOHN, PHILO B. Two letters to Walker and Eells. February 25, September 11, 1843. 5 pp.</item>
                  <item>LITTLEJOHN, MRS. ADELINE S. Letter to Mrs. Walker. February 1, 1844. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>MCLEAN, DONALD. Letter to Mr. Walker. February 1842. 1 p.</item>
                  <item>MCPHERSON, JOHN. Letter to Mr. Walker. February 17, 1846. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>MACTAVISH, DUGALD. Letter to Mr. Walker. April 18, 1845. 1 p.</item>
                  <item>PELLY, A. E. Letter to Mr. Walker. October 30, 1844. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>[RICHARDSON], CHARLOTTE. Two letters to Mr. Walker, one with no date, the first part missing; the other January 2 [1850]. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>RODGERS, ANDREW. Two letters to Mrs. Walker. October 8, 1846, June 26, 1847. 5 pp.</item>
                  <item>TOD, JOHN. Letter to Mr. Walker. July 7, 1844. 3 pp.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, JOSEPH M. Letter to his uncle, Elkanah Walker. April 22, 1850. 2 pp.</item>
                  <item>WHITMAN, PERRIN B. Order on Mr. Walker to pay Albion Post $50. Oregon City, August 1, 1851. Endorsed by A. R. Post, March 17, 1852. 1 p.</item>
                  <item>WALKER, ELKANAH. Manuscript booklets in the Indian tongue; extracts from Matthew, lists of words and phrases, and vocabularies in the Flathead language; an English-Nez Perce dictionary; and a hymnbook for children in English in Mrs. Walker's hand. 20 pieces. 181 pp.</item>
               </list>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters of Elkanah Walker</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1839-1857</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002091493370)"
                             id="aspace_d1f3365eb89c8c7de6ca56d4e9c99c0d"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1ddf7be95041bceca3941cf2ab0f9152"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_d1f3365eb89c8c7de6ca56d4e9c99c0d">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters of Elkanah Walker</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1839-1857</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002091493370)"
                             id="aspace_d8fa66f637fae42e2e551542f2e67704"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_609f6b8e8922c9210dc44d1bd00fda74"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_d8fa66f637fae42e2e551542f2e67704">2</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters of Elkanah Walker</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1839-1857</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002091493370)"
                             id="aspace_c129ffeaab5ca794c389db16b4f142b5"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_57a5904b15b5ac3a3578b4c2cb15ef36"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c129ffeaab5ca794c389db16b4f142b5">3</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters of Elkanah Walker</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1839-1857</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002091493370)"
                             id="aspace_c1982b95306e5d9ea7d88d16d518cc75"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_284ebf946bf66dbd19c8a026dca87680"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c1982b95306e5d9ea7d88d16d518cc75">4</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Manuscripts, booklets, etc. in the Indian tongue.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1838-1840</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002091493370)"
                             id="aspace_9842d45f79a2beb9962f65fe4360c2c8"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8b316c6be811e6ffdf627382a090e1ae"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9842d45f79a2beb9962f65fe4360c2c8">5</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Manuscripts, booklets, etc. in the Indian tongue.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1838-1840</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002091493370)"
                             id="aspace_0b9d631db8af00dfbe987a1f72a5e63d"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d2e2ee855620a6ed5b8443a14df5e296"
                             type="folder"
                             parent="aspace_0b9d631db8af00dfbe987a1f72a5e63d">6</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
