<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY-BR"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.eisner">beinecke.eisner</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Dorothy Eisner Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Eisner (Dorothy) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>by Sandra Markham</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:title="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2008</date>
            <num>GEN MSS 778</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Tuesday April 23, 2019 at 03:17</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Dorothy Eisner papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>GEN MSS 778</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                    id="aspace_6b32de4128aff1122c44711d291b537f"
                    type="box">1</container>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">1.25</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(2 boxes)</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1923/2008">1923-2008</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_8e35a2fdd6036f2db78c88137f6601d1">The Dorothy Eisner Papers consist of correspondence, photographs, and ephemera that document periods of her personal life and artwork. Eisner's correspondence files contain letters from fellow painters: nearly thirty from her friend Dorothy Andrews (1918-2008), who wrote mostly from her home in Khania, Crete; three from William Kienbusch (1914-1980); and one each from Sarah Freedman McPherson (1894-1978) and Emil Holzhauer (1887-1986); there are also letters from her stepdaughter, the painter Joan McDonald Miller. However, the bulk of the correspondence is between Eisner and her parents William and Florine Eisner, and includes letters in which she describes her interactions with Leon Trotsky during the Dewey Commission's hearing in Mexico City. Additional items related to that experience are the nearly fifty informal snapshot photographs taken in and around the hearing, Eisner's admission card, and one letter from Trotsky. Other friends in the correspondence files include the writers Tess Slesinger (1905-1945) and Diana Trilling (1906-1996). Other papers include copies of the constitution of the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, and an autobiographical memoir written by her grandfather Moritz Eisner, who had emigrated from Vienna to the United States. A folder of miscellaneous personal papers holds some childhood letters and drawings, a bank book from the early 1930s, and a few financial papers from the late 1970s-early 1980s. A binder of photographs and a scrapbook of clippings, photographs, and ephemera, supplemented by folders of announcements, brochures, and installation photographs, document Eisner's paintings and collages, and exhibitions of her work. The collection also includes two published books of photographs by Walker Evans.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n87822094"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               Eisner, Dorothy
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
               Eisner, Moritz, 1852-1938
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_f2bcb70e7a5d72475dc95c37a5feef4b">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Christie McDonald and Joan McDonald Miller, 1999-2008.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_91e9c9941807c8573a52cddfb0a37847">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_6f258498cee23761d053e22a79412f8b">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Dorothy Eisner Papers is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_a4dd2dcc79e5c564f1edec279a7a6018">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Dorothy Eisner Papers. General Collection, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_4c691562a1fce6a2f9c0260cdb163d4a">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived research value, the availability of staff, and competing priorities. The library attempts to provide a basic level of preservation and access for all collections as they are acquired, and does more extensive processing of higher priority collections as time and resources permit.</p>
         <p>This collection received a basic level of processing, including rehousing and minimal organization. Descriptive information is drawn in large part from information supplied with the collection and from an initial survey of the contents.</p>
         <p>The collection contains correspondence, photographs, and printed matter that were culled from several accessions (2000-2008) of John McDonald and Dorothy Eisner papers, specifically Uncat MSS 76, Uncat MSS 386, Uncat MSS 997, and Uncat MS Vault File (1938), as well as material donated separately in 2008. It was formerly filed under two different call numbers: Uncat MSS 1048 and Uncat MSS 1069.</p>
         <p>This finding aid may be updated periodically to account for new acquisitions to the collection and/or revisions in arrangement and description.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_98d2b5008573c82f625abac8ba5d05c2">
         <head>Associated Materials</head>
         <p>Correspondence between Dorothy Eisner and her husband, and between the couple and their daughters, can be found in the John McDonald Papers (GEN MSS 622).</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <bioghist id="aspace_eb0faf8f90b9d5f45fc0d95d50f114f7">
         <head>Dorothy Eisner (1906-1984)</head>
         <p>Dorothy Eisner was an American painter whose career spanned more than five decades. She was born in New York on January 17, 1906, the daughter of Florine (1883-1974) and William J. Eisner (1880-1975). Though William Eisner was a businessman and manufacturer, he and his wife were also painters active in art circles in the city and in Woodstock, New York, where they had a second home. Their two children, Dorothy and Anne (1911-1967), also became artists, studying at the Art Students League then briefly in France, and spending a summer (1931) with other artists on Monhegan Island off the coast of Maine.</p>
         <p>Dorothy Eisner met the writer John McDonald in New York in 1935; they were married on November 7, 1936, while each was employed by the federal government, McDonald with the Federal Writers' Project, and Eisner with the Resettlement Administration. The following spring the couple left their jobs and traveled to Mexico City with members of the American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky, a group of American liberals and intellectuals who supported the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials (also known as the Dewey Commission after its chairman, John Dewey). While McDonald worked on Trotsky's administrative team, Eisner painted portraits of Trotsky and the hearing room.</p>
         <p>With the exception of living in Croton-on-Hudson, New York, from 1942-1945, Eisner resided and had painting studios in the Greenwich Village section of New York City. She generally spent her summers painting in rural settings including Linville, North Carolina (1932-1935), Liebhardt, New York (1937-1942), Cape Breton, Nova Scotia (1947), and Livingston, Montana (1949-1958); the latter three were places to which she was introduced by her husband, an avid fisherman. From 1960 through her death, Eisner summered and painted on Cranberry Island, off the coast of Maine. She died in New York on April 28, 1984, survived by her husband, stepdaughter Joan (born 1929), and daughter Christie (born 1942).</p>
         <p>Dorothy Eisner was a member of the Society of Independent Artists and the American Artists' Congress, and was a founding member of the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors. She also exhibited with the National Association of Women Painters and Sculptors.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_e94799a0cbb47ed1c0058bc5eab4d9a8">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Dorothy Eisner Papers consist of correspondence, photographs, and ephemera that document periods of her personal life and artwork. Eisner's correspondence files contain letters from fellow painters: nearly thirty from her friend Dorothy Andrews (1918-2008), who wrote mostly from her home in Khaniá, Crete; three from William Kienbusch (1914-1980); and one each from Sarah Freedman McPherson (1894-1978) and Emil Holzhauer (1887-1986); there are also letters from her stepdaughter, the painter Joan McDonald Miller. However, the bulk of the correspondence is between Eisner and her parents, and includes letters in which she describes her interactions with Leon Trotsky during the Dewey Commission's hearing in Mexico City. Additional items related to that experience are the nearly fifty informal snapshot photographs taken in and around the hearing, Eisner's admissions card, and one letter from Trotsky. Other friends in the correspondence files include the writers Tess Slesinger (1905-1945) and Diana Trilling (1906-1996). Other papers include copies of the constitution of the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, and an autobiographical memoir written by her grandfather Moritz Eisner, who had emigrated from Vienna to the United States. A folder of miscellaneous personal papers holds some childhood letters and drawings, a bank book from the early 1930s, and a few financial papers from the late 1970s-early 1980s. A binder of photographs and a scrapbook of clippings, photographs, and ephemera, supplemented by folders of announcements, brochures, and installation photographs, document Eisner's paintings and collages, and exhibitions of her work. The collection also includes two published books of photographs by Walker Evans.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_17f483c7c663972a151e6e47dff6bfa0">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The collection is largely grouped by material type.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85007815"
                  source="lcsh">
            Art, American -- 20th Century
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh86003655"
                  source="lcsh">
            Artists -- United States
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85087446"
                  source="lcsh">
            Moscow Trials, Moscow, Russia, 1936-1937
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh86007877"
                  source="lcsh">
            Painters -- United States
         </subject>
         <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh86003835"
                  source="lcsh">
            Women artists -- United States
         </subject>
         <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300127104" source="aat">
            Photographic prints
         </genreform>
         <occupation source="local">
            Artists
         </occupation>
         <occupation source="local">
            Painters
         </occupation>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2009019066"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Andrews, Dorothy, 1918-2008
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n87822094"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Eisner, Dorothy
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2009011083"
                   source="naf">
            Eisner, Florine, 1883-1974
         </persname>
         <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
            Eisner, Moritz, 1852-1938
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2008102693"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Eisner, William J., 1880-1975
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50009155"
                   source="naf">
            Evans, Walker, 1903-1975
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n92116620"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Holzhauer, Emil, 1887-1986
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81143333"
                   source="naf">
            Kienbusch, William, 1914-1980
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2006164869"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            McPherson, Sarah Freedman, 1894-1978
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no97040735"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Putnam, Anne Eisner
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n83135255"
                   source="naf">
            Slesinger, Tess, 1905-1945
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50011794"
                   source="naf">
            Trilling, Diana, 1905-1996
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50049846"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Trot︠s︡kai︠a︡, Natalii︠a︡ Ivanovna, 1882-1962
         </persname>
         <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79054261"
                   source="naf">
            Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940
         </persname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/nb2005004772"
                   source="naf">
            Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made Against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials, New York, 1937
         </corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/nr97032896"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref12" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="accession">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Dorothy Eisner papers</unittitle>
               <physdesc>
                  <extent unit="Linear Feet">1.25</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <physdesc altrender="container_summary">(2 boxes)</physdesc>
            </did>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Card of admission to Trotsky hearing: Tarjeta de admision Miss Dorothy Eisner. Para las sesiones de la Comision Preliminar de investigastion de los cargos hachos contra Leon Trotsky en los jurados de Moscu. Presidente John Dewey [signed], Secretario Suzanne La Follette [signed].</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1937</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_f20e3d92252d9f4536785f98f6bfa929"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs taken during the Dewey Commission investigating the Moscow Trials: 48 photographs including images of: Dorothy Eisner and John McDonald with Leon Trotsky; participants in the Dewey Commission including Herbert Solow, Jan Frankel, Albert Goldman, Jean van Heijenoort, as well as two of Diego Rivera with Trotsky; portraits of Leon Trotsky, inscribed by him to John McDonald and Dorothy Eisner; Eisner's painting of the Dewey Commission (now at the Dewey Study Center, University of Illinois, Carbondale); Eisner's portrait of Trotsky (now at Houghton Library, Harvard University); a lost painting by Eisner of Trotsky.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1937</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_470dccfeabb17d43e0b4c7e5a00fb6c8"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title type="simple" render="italic">
                        Encounter
                     </title> magazine issue containing a letter by Eisner about the Dewey Commission</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1982</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_07572012d1f2eabb43b67eb61b8702d3"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Review of Trotsky's <title type="simple" render="italic">
                        The Revolution Betrayed
                     </title>, in the <title type="simple" render="italic">
                        Evening Star
                     </title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1937 Mar 13</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_fc460fb2091459169151b776b183d683"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs of two paintings: "The McDonald House, Croton-on-Hudson, New York" (1943) by Walker Evans, and "Walker Evans Painting the McDonald House" (1943-1944), by Dorothy Eisner.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_b0d221a8081f8bec5dc03c0b032b3533"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title type="simple" render="italic">
                        Dance International 1900-1937
                     </title>: exhibition catalog with Eisner drawings reproduced; letter of permission</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_9f4f33bb720bfc16622b14636b200107"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ephemera from Eisner's exhibitions</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref21" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Delphic Studios, New York, Mar 25-Apr 8, 1934:checklist</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1934</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_c26aaae7b237692d7297bb6d2c957b76"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref22" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>James Gallery, New York, Feb 17-Mar 10, 1961:advertising poster, checklist of paintings, and 15 installation photographs by Walker Evans (one signed)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1961</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_185a232b53fa549c3b169ec3a99bbfaa"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref23" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cisneros Gallery, New York, Nov-Dec 17, 1966: announcement</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1966</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_835c6ddc9b96d11d568043db3d764f65"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref24" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Cisneros Gallery, New York, Apr 5-25, 1969: announcement</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_1fb7fd85948bc402081262d434e3338f"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref25" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Ashby Gallery, New York, May 17-Jun 6, 1980: announcement cards, signed catalog, notecard</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1980</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_f4b4436cd48c34ca56f2065450d3e44e"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref26" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Ashby Gallery, New York, April 16-May 6, 1983: announcement, review by Carl Little, press release, and photocopy of guest book</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1983</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_f9bd2c05783509de88422ca256f2a7d4"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref27" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Farnsworth Art Museum, Rockland, Maine, May 3-Jul 5, 1992: announcement, catalog, reviews, slides</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1992</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_3e319f30db0bac80207351a1f0863eb8"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref28" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Announcements and brochures</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">2005-2008</unitdate>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Biographic time line with exhibition histories</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_c8926b96e8fbdf6a18cb95dba17c2db1"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref31" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Andrews, Dorothy</unittitle>
                     <physdesc>
                        <extent unit="folders">2</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1954-1983</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_d709093fe9e559d10539a22e8548f864"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref33" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Clark, Eleanor</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1959 Jan 8</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_1f49e9740c1c0940ac29c95c57e2c283"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref34" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Eisner, William and Florine, letters from</unittitle>
                     <physdesc>
                        <extent unit="folders">2</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1925-1961</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_84b80eaa239da669c81594b01f83b090"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref36" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Eisner, William and Florine, letters to</unittitle>
                     <physdesc>
                        <extent unit="folders">7</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1925-1959, undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_133f4f6de47c877cdd796d1eb03705d3"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref38" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Kienbusch, William</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-1962</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_f0e96a53f7d4fe6d28ad49d76c1349c2"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref39" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letters from Linville, North Carolina, friends</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1932-1941</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_7098e6b649a195674657dcfad2889ad4"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref40" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miller, Joan McDonald</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1956-1962</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_07384f5b9dd7e0d79ea491104ad572b1"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref41" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Moore, Edie</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_612ea3caa2ba33c6cc7b269df31bc8bf"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref42" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Putnam, Anne Eisner</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1936-1962, undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_d1f9f5e91d206d5ed96eac2e75eefe53"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
                  <odd id="aspace_d0f256d37485c435ebd06c350bec7caa">
                     <head>General note</head>
                     <p>Includes one letter from John McDonald about Dorothy Eisner and the Works Progress Administration</p>
                  </odd>
               </c>
               <c id="ref44" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Slesinger, Tess</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1923-1938</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_6c461d0b549cff3611c455a664eeca53"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref45" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Trilling, Diana</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1965</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_a2b1c5b3882d2d28bf727325c660f1c4"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref46" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Trotsky, Leon</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1938</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_8e5b6b08c699d5cb162861b91b7a35c0"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref47" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
                     <physdesc>
                        <extent unit="folders">3</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1984, undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_ffe59199096a93db86583ac3ff04bdcd"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref49" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letters to Florine Eisner (third-party)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1937-1951</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_b9823634d569cd56beffcee24551d422"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref50" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Drawings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_246be110336380345794a4ecd84614a0"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref51" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Holiday cards (printed) designed by Eisner</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1940, 1951, undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_b598f02354d5e35ea64c494bd31c241d"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref52" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref53" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Constitution</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1940</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_bfc056fe8f915e9131185d56797993ff"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref54" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>List of names and titles of works for exhibition</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1964</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_ec0c65765c40f7fb17e9e79bb05577c8"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal Papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc>
                     <extent unit="folders">2</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1982, undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_6edc823faab3d6e925f3e7f2c804b18a"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref57" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs, miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_96d4e2ef4f88126d3c92cd5c9b4ed19b"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref58" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Moritz Eisner autobiographical memoir, 1936; mimeograph</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_7374b10816d2f43f681cd3f59ece3119"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref59" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Christie McDonald, "Brushes with History"; offprint from <title type="simple" render="italic">
                        Harvard Review
                     </title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">2006</unitdate>
                  <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                             id="aspace_ac6b19249ce349e7d4362ae5f076e219"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Books by Walker Evans</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref61" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title type="simple" render="italic">
                           American Photographs
                        </title> (New York: Museum of Modern Art)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1938</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_004b1e6c66d24586f8d0b236b8c62146"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref62" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title type="simple" render="italic">
                           Walker Evans
                        </title> (New York: Museum of Modern Art)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">1971</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002075172941)"
                                id="aspace_746b1bc07441648b1fb43aa639d058d1"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref63" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oversize</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref64" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Scrapbook relating to career of Eisner (assembled posthumously)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1927-1947, undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002091594094)"
                                id="aspace_228a62d13d08a7bb053d879c10df435f"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref65" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Photographs of art work by Eisner (in binder)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                     <container label="Mixed Materials (39002091594094)"
                                id="aspace_4c7daa063e69a5586dab603d860cbfaf"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
