<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctFmHsm/default_ead_ctFmHsm.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="ctFmHsm" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctFmHsm/pope_riddle_papers.xml">pope_riddle_papers</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Pope-Riddle Family Papers, 1869-1946</titleproper>
<author>Collection guide written by Melanie Bourbeau. Collection processed by Melanie Bourbeau.</author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>Hill-Stead Museum</publisher>
<address><addressline>35 Mountain Road</addressline>
<addressline>Farmington</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06032</addressline>
<addressline>email: bourbeaum@hillstead.org</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://www.hillstead.org</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: 860-677-4787, ext. 122</addressline></address>

<date>Dec 11, 2017</date>
<p>http://www.hillstead.org</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: MS 1</num>
<publisher>Hill-Stead Museum
<lb/>35 Mountain Road
<lb/> Farmington, CT  06032</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection guide written by:</label>
<item>Melanie Bourbeau</item>
</defitem>
<defitem>
<label>Collection processed by:</label>
<item>Melanie Bourbeau</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2017 Hill-Stead Museum. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Creators">
<persname source="DA:CS">Pope, Ada Brooks, 1844-1920; </persname>
<persname source="DA:CS">Pope, Alfred Atmore, 1842-1913; </persname>
<persname source="DA:CS">Riddle, John Wallace, 1864-1941; </persname>
<persname source="DA:CS">Riddle, Theodate Pope, 1867-1946 </persname>
</origination>
<unittitle>Pope-Riddle family papers, 1869-1946</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1869-1946">1869-1946</unitdate>
<unitdate type="bulk" normal="1880-1930">Bulk 1880-1930</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="ctFmHsm" countrycode="us">MS 1</unitid>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>64 linear feet; </extent>
<extent>127 boxes</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Hill-Stead Museum</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> 35 Mountain Road</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
    <abstract label="Abstract">The Pope-Riddle family papers collection includes letters, diaries, genealogical information, family Bibles, and other documents and material generated by, or pertaining primarily to, Theodate Pope Riddle, her parents, Alfred Pope and Ada Brooks Pope, and Theodate&apos;s husband, John Wallace Riddle. </abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langmaterial>
<physloc label="Physical Location">Third-floor archives</physloc>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection open for research by appointment only.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>For copyright status, please contact the Hill-Stead Museum.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
    <p>Pope-Riddle family papers, 1869-1946, Archives, Hill-Stead Museum, Farmington, CT
       </p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo>
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Bequest of Theodate Pope Riddle, 1946.</p>
</acqinfo>
<bioghist>
<head>Biography</head>
    <p>Alfred Atmore Pope (son of Alton Pope and Theodate Stackpole Pope; born N. Vassalboro, Maine, July 4, 1842 &#45; died Farmington, Connecticut, August 5, 1913). Alfred Pope was one of five children, born to Quaker parents. In 1861, when Alfred Pope was 19, he and his family moved to a Quaker community in Salem, Ohio. Later, in Cleveland, he joined his father and two brothers as partners in a woolen business. Alfred married Ada Brooks in 1866, and their only child, Effie, was born one year later. (Effie later renamed herself &quot;Theodate&quot; after her paternal grandmother.) In 1869 Alfred borrowed $5,000 to become a principal in the Cleveland Malleable Iron Company. He transformed the company product line from agricultural machinery to components for the booming railroad industry. In his late 40s, self-educated and wealthy, Alfred developed a great love and enthusiasm for art. He began collecting French Impressionist paintings when he took his family on a European Grand Tour in 1888-1889. Alfred&apos;s business associates, J. H. Whittemore and his son Harris, of Naugatuck, Connecticut, became steadfast friends and fellow collectors of Impressionist paintings. Alfred developed his personal aesthetic and bought only artwork he &quot;could rise to.&quot; Hill-Stead was his retirement home, designed by his daughter and planned, in part, to showcase his collection.</p>
        
    <p>  Ada Brooks Pope (daughter of Joseph Judson Brooks and Judith French Twing; born Salem, Ohio, March 31, 1844 &#45; died Pasadena, California, May 6, 1920). Ada Brooks was the third of eight children. While she was in her teens each of her parents died. As a result, she and her siblings remained very close to each other all their lives, often gathering in Vermont where their parents had been raised and where several relatives still lived. After marrying Alfred Pope, her childhood sweetheart, in 1866, directing the Pope household became her life&apos;s work. Her skill and grace were legendary. She enjoyed living in Cleveland, Ohio, where the couple eventually built a Queen Anne-style house, in 1885, on fashionable Euclid Avenue. The family kept an apartment, as well, in New York City. At first, Ada was less than enthusiastic about the move to Farmington. Yet, she adapted to country living, and much of what we know about daily life at Hill-Stead derives from her avid letter writing and fastidious keeping of accounts. Ada never fully recovered from Alfred&apos;s death in 1913. In her later years she found it difficult to spend long winters at Hill-Stead and, annually, spent time California with some of her Brooks family.</p>
        
    <p> Theodate Pope Riddle (born Salem, Ohio, February 2, 1867 &#45; died Farmington, Connecticut, August 30, 1946). Effie Brooks Pope, an only child, grew up in Salem, Ohio, and later Cleveland.  At the age of 19, she changed her name to &quot;Theodate&quot; after her paternal grandmother, and thereafter was known by the name that means &quot;gift of God.&quot;  She attended Miss Mittleberger&apos;s School, a private girls&apos; school in Cleveland. Among her classmates were the daughters of Presidents Garfield and Hayes. In 1886, she went east to continue her education at Miss Porter&apos;s School in Farmington, Connecticut. There, amid the historic structures along Farmington&apos;s Main Street, she fell in love with a romanticized version of life in Colonial times. While accompanying her parents on a European Grand Tour, 1888-1889, she began to articulate her ambition of becoming an architect.  Upon the family&apos;s return, Theodate received permission to live on her own in the rural Connecticut village she had grown to love. She purchased and restored an eighteenth-century farmhouse&#151;her introduction to house design and construction. During this time she became further enamored of the Colonial Revival movement that had swept the nation. After living on her own for nearly ten years, Theodate persuaded her parents to buy hilltop property and retire in Farmington.  She designed and built Hill-Stead, her first architectural project, assisted by the noted firm of McKim, Mead &amp; White, who completed construction drawings. Spacious, yet comfortable, the house also provided a showcase for her father&apos;s magnificent art collection. The landmark project was completed in 1901. Later architectural accomplishments included designing several private homes and schools, including Westover School in Middlebury, Connecticut, and Avon Old Farms School, in Avon, Connecticut. As a single woman Theodate took in a toddler to raise as her child. At the age of 49, following her remarkable survival of the sinking of the RMS Lusitania, Theodate surprised family and friends by marrying diplomat John Wallace Riddle, whom she had known for nearly a decade. The couple had no children of their own, but, following the death of her first ward, from polio, two more foster sons were added to the household. In addition to her architectural practice, Theodate oversaw management of Hill-Stead&apos;s extensive, and progressive-minded, farm operations. Theodate wanted Hill-Stead to remain intact for the benefit of future generations. To that end, her Will specified that the house she had designed, with all its contents, become a museum for the education and enjoyment of all.</p>
        
    <p> John Wallace Riddle (born Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, July 12, 1864 &#45; died Farmington, Connecticut, December 8, 1941). John Wallace Riddle never knew his father, who had died before his son&apos;s birth. When he was seven his mother married Judge Charles Flandrau of St. Paul, Minnesota, a widower with two daughters, and John was raised there in a blended family. The couple eventually had two sons together. Although John funded his own education from a small inheritance, his stepfather&apos;s important political connections helped advance his diplomatic career. After graduating from Harvard in 1886, John attended Columbia Law School and then the &#201;cole des Sciences et Politiques in Paris. He became a skilled linguist proficient in several languages. His early diplomatic posts included Turkey, Egypt, Romania, and Russia while it was under Tsarist rule. During World War I, he worked for the Army War College, in Washington, D.C. before embarking on his final diplomatic posting to Argentina in 1922. John met Theodate in 1905 through their mutual friend and Farmington resident Anna Roosevelt Cowles, Theodore Roosevelt's sister. The couple married in 1916. If John and Theodate&apos;s marriage was a relationship based partly on mutual convenience, it also was affectionate. She called him &quot;Totem&quot; because of his height, and he called her &quot;Dearest of Geniuses.&quot;
    </p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
    <p>The Pope-Riddle Family Papers collection consists of approximately 64 linear feet of material including 13,000 family letters, diaries, genealogical documents, family Bibles and documents related to the fine and decorative arts collection acquired by Alfred Pope. In addition, there are a few financial records from the end of Theodate Pope Riddle&apos;s life and papers related to the settling of her parents&apos; estates. Theodate Pope Riddle&apos;s diaries, kept intermittently from 1880-1890 and 1898-1905, have been transcribed. The collection contains very few architectural drawings and only minimal references to her architectural career. The diplomatic career of John Wallace Riddle is minimally documented.  The variety of materials available for study include: </p>
    
       <p> Series 1: Pope-Riddle Family Papers</p>
    <list type="marked"><item>&#9642;      Pope and Brooks family correspondence</item>
        <item>&#9642;      Theodate Pope Riddle&apos;s adolescent and young adult diaries (1886-1890), which include her writing on her years as a secondary school student in Cleveland and at Miss Porter&apos;s School, a detailed description of the family&apos;s 1888-89 grand tour to Europe, her life on her own in Farmington prior to the construction of Hill-Stead, and, throughout, her search for an identity of her own.</item>
        <item>&#9642;	Theodate Pope Riddle&apos;s correspondence with friends such as Henry James, William James, Mary Cassatt, August Jaccaci, Lady Helena Gleichen, Jane Addams, Anna Roosevelt Cowles, Mariana Van Rensselaer.</item>
        <item>&#9642;	Receipts for many items in Hill-Stead&apos;s collection (1888-1936), including many but not al the French Impressionist paintings.</item>  
        <item>&#9642;Alfred Pope&apos;s correspondence with James McNeill Whistler (1890s).</item>
        <item>&#9642;	A significant volume of correspondence related to Theodate&apos;s interest in psychical research with notable persons such as Dr. Richard Hodgson and James Hyslop. Transcriptions of &quot;psychical&quot; sittings undertaken by Theodate Pope Riddle and William James with medium Leonora Piper (c.1904-6), and Theodate&apos;s later investigations into spiritualism.</item>
        <item>&#9642;The correspondence of Theodate Pope Riddle&apos;s husband, John Wallace Riddle, from his student days at Harvard; his diplomatic posts in Turkey (1890s) and Russia (1906-08); and copies of his WWI translations of intelligence documents.</item>
        <item>&#9642;Other items include Pope and Brooks family Bibles with key dates of births, marriages, and deaths</item>
        <item>&#9642;	Copies of Wills, probate documents, including those for the family&apos;s long time butler,  Earnest Bohlen </item>
        <item>&#9642;      More than 120 items representing multiple facets of the interests and experiences of the Pope family. Highlights include: items related to art collecting, such as auction catalogs of various fine art collections, 1899-1913; discreet items pertaining to Connecticut history; European and Asian travel; family genealogy; James McNeill Whistler catalogs/pamphlets of his works, exhibitions, writings; personal mementoes; RMS Lusitania memorabilia, including stateroom map, commemorative medal and detailed accounting of the May 7, 1915 sinking;  Theodate Pope's design of Avon Old Farms School, photographs, articles and other items that document its impact in architectural and design spheres upon opening; Theodate Pope Riddle architecture related memorabilia, documents and awards, and personal  notes and papers, including art history notebook (1894-95) and adolescent/ young adult sketchbook; Colonial Dames memorabilia;  including a bound copy of lecture by Julius Gay given a meeting of the Dames, 1906; examples of Asian calligraphy (ancient scrolls); period magazines, including American Homes and Gardens, Feb. 1910, North American Review, May 1905 (“New England Impressions” by Henry James), Kunst und Kunstler, in German, Nov. and Dec. 1910; Paris Transportation Map, pre-1900; books, including art books and first and limited editions, some inscribed by the authors.</item>
    </list>
    <p>Series 2: Estate Papers of Alfred Atmore Pope, Ada Brooks Pope and Theodate Pope Riddle (CERTAIN RECORDS CLOSED TO RESEARCHERS)</p>
    <p><list type="marked"><item>&#9642;  Alfred A. Pope&apos;s papers span 1906-1917 (1913-17 bulk dates) and generally relate to settling his estate following his death in August 1913. Examples include: invoices, receipts, taxes, cancelled checks, and papers related to commercial property owned in Cleveland, Ohio</item>
        <item>&#9642;  Ada B. Pope&apos;s papers span 1913-1926 and include account summaries, bank statements, correspondence, appraisals, and taxes. Of special interest are her detailed households accounts (likely maintained by her secretary F.W. Swenston, about whom Hill-Stead has little information.) Recurring categories include: expenses for: automobiles; California trips; Hill-Steads exterior; farm; furnishings; gratuities (mostly recurring, monthly payments to certain of her siblings); home maintenance and repair; housekeeping; Other documents relate to insurance, loans to employees, repair for paintings in the fine art collection, etc.; also personal expenses for Ada Pope, stable expenses (through 1916), travel and currency, and payments to Theodate Pope / Theodate Pope Riddle. Accounts reflect payments made only by check with no indication as to how Ada Pope spent cash. Accounts also do not reflect presumed, shared expenses with Theodate and there is no true sense of how such expenses were managed.</item>
        <item>&#9642;  Theodate Pope Riddle&apos;s papers span 1944-1946 and include primarily information related to farm operations at Hill-Stead and Old Farms (located on what was then part of Avon Old Farms School property). Other papers include those related to household operations at Hill-Stead. There are no business papers related to Theodate Pope, Architect.</item>
    </list></p>
    
    </scopecontent><arrangement>
<head>Arrangement</head>
        <p>The collection is cataloged at the item level with a distinct numbering schema and management system that includes a card file and register. Items are boxed sequentially according to the number assigned. Some are grouped within particular number ranges according to their subjects, such as psychical
            research.</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<famname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Brooks family</famname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Brooks, Joseph Judson</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Brooks, Judith French Twing</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Cassatt, Mary, 1844-1926</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Cowles, Anna Roosevelt, 1855-1931</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Flandrau, Grace, 1889-1971</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Hillard, Mary Robbins</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Hodgson, Richard, 1855-1905</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Hyslop, James H. (James Hervey), 1854-1920</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">James, Henry, 1843-1916</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">James, William, 1842-1910</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Manet, &#201;douard, 1832-1883</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Monet, Claude, 1840-1926</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Piper, Leonora, 1859-1950</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Pope, Ada Brooks, 1844-1920</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Pope, Alfred Atmore, 1842-1913</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Pope, Alton</persname>
    <famname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Pope family</famname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Rand, Ellen Emmet, 1875-1941</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Riddle, John Wallace, 1864-1941</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Riddle, Theodate Pope, 1867-1946</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Whistler, James McNeill, 1834-1903</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Whittemore, Harris, 1864-1927</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Whittemore, John Howard, 1837-1910</persname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Avon Old Farms School</corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Cleveland Malleable Iron Company</corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Lusitania (Steamship)</corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">McKim, Mead &amp; White</corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">National Malleable and Steel Castings Co.</corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Westover School</corpname>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Agriculture</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650">Architects</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Architecture</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Art</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Authors</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Collectors and collecting</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Diplomats</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Diplomatic and consular service</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Impressionism (Art)</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Poets</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Psychical Research</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Spiritualism</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Travel</subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="650">Women--Suffrage</subject>
    <geogname encodinganalog="651" role="subject">Farmington (Conn.)</geogname>
    <geogname encodinganalog="651" role="subject">Middlebury (Conn.)</geogname>
    <genreform encodinganalog="655">Accounts</genreform>
    <genreform encodinganalog="655">Bibles</genreform> 
    <genreform encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform encodinganalog="655">Diaries</genreform>
    <genreform encodinganalog="655">Estate records</genreform>
    <genreform encodinganalog="655">Financial records</genreform>
    <genreform encodinganalog="655">Inventories</genreform>
    <genreform encodinganalog="655">Receipts (financial records)</genreform> 
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial>
<head>Related Collections</head>
<p>Pope-Riddle Family Photographs</p>
    <p>Harris Whittemore Trust Papers</p>
</relatedmaterial>


<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>