<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="default_ead_ctuh.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader scriptencoding="iso15924" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" countryencoding="iso3166-1" 
audience="internal" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="ctuh" countrycode="us"  url="http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/cao/ctuh/HMSRecords.xml">HMSRecords</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Hartford Medical Society Records</titleproper>
<author>Collection guide written by Jennifer Miglus. Collection processed by Miriam Neiman.</author>
<sponsor>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</sponsor>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>Hartford Medical Society</publisher>
<address><addressline>PO Box 4003</addressline>
<addressline>263 Farmington Ave</addressline>
<addressline>Farmington</addressline>
<addressline>CT</addressline>
<addressline>06030-4003</addressline>
<addressline>email: miglus@uchc.edu</addressline>
<addressline>URL: http://library.uchc.edu/hms/</addressline>
<addressline>Phone: 860-679-3200</addressline></address>

<date>Nov 27, 2017</date>
<p>http://library.uchc.edu/hms/</p></publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>.</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
Description is in <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<num>Collection number: 2016-01</num>
<publisher>Hartford Medical Society
<lb/>PO Box 4003
<lb/>263 Farmington Ave Farmington, CT  06030-4003</publisher>
<p>This project was made possible in part through a grant from  the Institute of Museum and Library Services  to the Connecticut State Library on behalf of the State Archives and Conservation ConneCTion.</p>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Collection guide written by:</label>
<item>Jennifer Miglus</item>
</defitem>
<defitem>
<label>Collection processed by:</label>
<item>Miriam Neiman</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<p>&#x00A9; 2017 Hartford Medical Society. All rights reserved.</p>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<origination label="Creator">
<corpname source="DA:CS">Hartford Medical Society</corpname>
</origination>
<unittitle>Hartford Medical Society Records</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive">1846-2009</unitdate>
<unitid label="Collection Number" repositorycode="ctuh" countrycode="us">2016-01</unitid>
<physdesc label="Extent">
<extent>18</extent>
<extent>35</extent>
</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><corpname>Hartford Medical Society</corpname>
<!-- <address><addressline> PO Box 4003</addressline></address> -->
</repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">Non-current records of the Hartford Medical Society up to 2009.  </abstract>
<langmaterial label="Languages Represented">
<language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.
</langmaterial>
<physloc label="Physical Location">Hallway, HMS Library</physloc>
</did>
<accessrestrict>
<head>Restrictions</head>
<p>Not all records are open for research use. Contact librarian/archivist for more information.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict>
<head>Publication Rights</head>
<p>For copyright status, please contact the Hartford Medical Society.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Identification of item], , [Box no]., Hartford Medical Society</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo>
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Records donated by the Hartford Medical Society.</p>
</acqinfo>
<processinfo>
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was processed with the invaluable help of archives intern Miriam Neiman, 2016.</p>
</processinfo>
<bioghist>
<head>Biography</head>
<p>The Hartford Medical Society has been in continuous existence for over 160 years.  The Society's rules, adopted September 15th, 1846, state: "The object of this Society, is to maintain the practice of Medicine and Surgery in this city upon a respectable footing; to expose the ignorance and resist the arts of quackery; and to adopt measures for the mutual improvement, pleasant intercourse, and common good of its members."  The rules were specific, not only about how meetings should be conducted, but how to enroll new members and what fees should be charged for services rendered.</p>
<p>The nineteenth century was a time of great change in the practice of medicine.  During that century medical training went from an apprenticeship or classes where texts were learned by rote, to the beginnings of a regulated curriculum including clinical training in a hospital.  The disciplines of scientific observation and experimentation were thriving and were increasingly informing medical practice.  HMS members met twice monthly for a talk on a medical topic.  Initially these meetings were in members' homes, but in 1890s the Society built its own building at 38 Prospect St., Hartford.  By the middle of the 20th century, the Society had outgrown this building and in 1955 they built a second home at 230 Scarborough St., Hartford.</p>
<p>In its heyday the Society had multiple committees which dealt with topics of societal importance such as a Babies' Hospital, Illegal Practitioners, Municipal Health, and topics of more interest to the Society itself, such as Building and Programs committees.  Members enjoyed rituals such as the award of the Loving Cup use of the snuff box and the award of personalized gavels to outgoing presidents.  The Society also hosted special events with dinner and invited speakers.</p>
<p>The Hartford Medical Society shared its Scarborough St. building with the Hartford Dental Society, and in the 1970s several members of the two societies established a museum of medical and dental objects.  The Menczer Museum of Medicine and Dentistry was listed in a directory of Offbeat Museums, and was a destination for buses of schoolchildren in the 1980s and 1990s.  The museum contained standing exhibits of early dental offices, examples of early medical instruments and apparatus and portraits of Connecticut physicians.  Members created special exhibits on topics of medical historical interest.</p>
<p>By the mid-1990s it was becoming clear that the Society could no longer sustain a building of such size.  After much consideration, the museum collection was significantly dispersed, the book and journal collection weeded and in 2009 a select collection of books, journals, artwork and artifacts was moved to a newly renovated space in the then named UConn Health Center (now UConn Health).  This collection is now named the Hartford Medical Society Historical Library.  It is located near the main library at UConn Health.  The HMS building on Scarborough Street, Hartford was sold that same year.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent>
<head>Scope and Content of Collection</head>
<p>This collection documents the structure and function of the Hartford Medical Society from its inception in 1846 through 2009.  Gaps in the record and inconsistencies in the volume of materials are a consequence of multiple moves and the number of years represented.  There are naturally more records from more recent years; more records for the building of the Society's second building on Scarborough Street than for the Society's first building on Prospect Street.  The volume of records for individual members is a reflection of how active they were in the Society.</p>
    <p>A large number of records are devoted to the Museum from the 1970s through 2009.  The Museum generated publications and exhibits and the records document these efforts, along with events surrounding them.  The collection also documents the ceremonial traditions of the Society, such as the Loving Cup, the Snuff Box and the Gavel.  The Library is well represented, as is the art collection.  The Society's logo contains a profile of Horace Wells, the Hartford dentist who pioneered the use of nitrous oxide in dentistry.  Horace Wells' failure to get credit for the introduction of inhaled anesthesia in surgery was a cause célèbre for the Hartford Medical Society.  A significant part of the collection documents their efforts to celebrate Wells' inspiration.</p>
<p>The quotidian work of the Society is not well documented here.  This information is available in the minutes of the Society which are not included in the collection.  The HMS Minutes are slowly being transcribed and digitized.  These digital objects may be found in the Connecticut Digital Archive.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement>
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This is a complex arrangement given the time span and scope of the materials.  There are multiple levels to the hierarchical structure.  Some records are filed chronologically and some alphabetically as subject files.</p>
<p>The collection is organized into ten series.  The records for each series are housed together with the exception of one legal-sized box of records from multiple series.  Records in other formats such as slides, large sets of photographs and floppy discs are housed at the end.  Where there were only a few photographs documenting an exhibit or an event, they were left in the folder with the other records.</p>
</arrangement>
<controlaccess>
<head>Indexing Terms</head>
<p>The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in
the library's online public access catalog.</p>
<subject encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Medicine--Societies, etc.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="600" role="subject">History of Medicine, 19th Cent.--Connecticut</subject>
<genreform encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Correspondence</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Photographs</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Reports</genreform>
</controlaccess>
<relatedmaterial>
<head>Related Collections</head>
<p>See also the HMS Minutes, available online at the Connecticut Digital Archive.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<odd>
<head>Collection series</head>
<p>Series I: Governance	</p>
<p>Series II: Financials</p>
<p>Series III: Meetings and Events		</p>
<p>Series IV: Publications		</p>
<p>Series V: Membership		</p>
<p>Series VI: Real Estate		</p>
<p>Series VII: Museum		</p>
<p>Series VIII: Library		</p>
<p>Series IX: Horace Wells		</p>
<p>Series X: Multi-media</p>
</odd>


<!-- Insert DSC here -->


</archdesc>
</ead>
