<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">

<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">


<eadid mainagencycode="US-ct" url="http://www.ctstatelibrary.org/RG003_LCC_Minorities.html" countrycode="us">RG003_LCC_Minorities</eadid>

<filedesc>
	<titlestmt>
		<titleproper>RG 003, Litchfield County Court Minorities Collection</titleproper>
		<subtitle>Inventory of Records</subtitle>
		<author>Finding aid prepared by Debra Pond.</author>
	</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
	<publisher>Connecticut State Library</publisher>
	<date type="publication">July 07, 2008</date>

	<address><addressline>231 Capitol Avenue</addressline><addressline>Hartford, Connecticut, 06106-1537</addressline></address>
	<p>Copyright © <date>2008</date> by the Connecticut State Library</p>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>

<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by Damon M. Munz on
<date>July 07, 2008</date>
</creation>
<langusage><language></language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
	<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
	<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
		<corpname>Connecticut State Library</corpname>
		<address><addressline></addressline><addressline></addressline></address>
	</repository>

	<origination label="Creator:">
		<corpname encodinganalog="110">Connecticut. County Court (Litchfield County)</corpname>
	</origination>

	<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Litchfield County Court minorities collection</unittitle>

	<unitdate label="Dates:" datechar="creation" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1753/1854">1753-1854</unitdate>

	<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">1.5 cubic feet</physdesc>

	<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">The Litchfield County Court Minorities Collection is an artificial collection consisting of photocopies of cases involving African Americans and Native Americans from the <emph render="italic">Files</emph> and <emph render="italic">Papers by Subject</emph> series of Litchfield County Court records. All originals have been retired and second copies have been inserted in the places where the originals were once located.</abstract>

	<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" 
		repositorycode="US-ct">RG003_LCC_Minorities</unitid>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2004-034</unitid>

	<langmaterial>The records are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.
	</langmaterial>
</did>


<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->
<bioghist altrender="history" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
	<head>Historical Note</head>
	<p>The Litchfield County Court Minorities Collection is an artificial collection consisting of photocopies of cases involving African Americans and Native Americans from the <emph render="italic">Files</emph> and <emph render="italic">Papers by Subject</emph> series of Litchfield County Court records. All originals have been retired and second copies have been inserted in the places where the originals were once located.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
	<head>Scope and Content</head>
	<p>The collection consists of records of 188 court cases involving either African Americans or Native Americans. A careful search of the <emph render="italic">Files</emph> for the Litchfield County Court discovered 165 on African Americans and 23 on Native Americans, about one third of the total that was found in <emph render="italic">Files</emph> for the New London County Court for the period up to the American Revolution. A couple of reasons exist for this vast difference in numbers. First, Litchfield County was organized much later than New London, one of Connecticut's four original counties. New London was the home of four of seven recognized tribes, was a trading center, and an area of much greater wealth. Second, minority population in the New London County region has been tracked and tabulated by Barbara Brown and James Rose in <emph render="italic">Black Roots of Southeastern Connecticut</emph>.<emph render="super">1</emph> Although this valuable work does not include all of Negro or Indian background, it provides a wonderful starting point and it has proven to be of some assistance in tracking down minorities in Litchfield County. In most instances, however, identification is based upon language in the documents and knowledge of surnames or first names.<emph render="super">2</emph> Neither surname nor first name provides an invariably reliable guide so it is possible that some minorities have been missed and some persons included that are erroneous.</p>
	<p>In thirteen of 188 court cases, the person of African or Native American background cannot be identified even by first name. He or she is noted as "my Negro," a slave girl, or an Indian. In twenty-three lawsuits, a person with a first name is identified as a Negro, as an Indian in two other cases, and Mulatto in one. In the remaining 151 cases, a least one African American or Native American is identified by complete name.<emph render="super">3</emph> Thirteen surnames recur in three or more cases.<emph render="super">4</emph> A total of seventy surnames, some with more than one spelling, are represented in the records.</p>
	<p>The Jacklin surname appears most frequently represented in the records. Seven different Jacklins are found in eighteen cases, two for debt and the remaining sixteen for more serious crimes like assault, breach of peace, keeping a bawdy house, and trespass.<emph render="super">5</emph> Ten cases concern Cuff Kingsbury of Canaan between 1808 and 1812, all involving debts against Kingsbury and the attempts of plaintiffs to secure writs of execution against him. Cyrus, Daniel, Ebenezer, Jude, Luke, Martin, Nathaniel, Pomp, Titus, and William Freeman are found in nine cases, some for debt, others for theft, and one concerning a petition to appoint a guardian for aged and incompetent Titus Freeman.<emph render="super">6</emph> Six persons with the surname Caesar are found in seven court cases.</p>
	<p>Sixty-one of 188 cases concern debt.<emph render="super">7</emph> Litchfield County minorities were plaintiffs in only about ten of these lawsuits, half debt by book and half debt by note. The largest single category of court proceedings concern cases of crimes against person or property. They include assault (32 cases), theft (30), breach of peace (5), and breaking out of jail (1). In cases of assault, the Negro or Indian was the perpetrator in about two thirds of the cases and victim in one third. In <emph render="italic">State v. Alexander Kelson</emph>, the defendant was accused of assaulting Eunice Mawwee.<emph render="super">8</emph> Minority defendants in assault cases included Daniel K. Boham, William Cable, Prince Comyns, Adonijah Coxel, Homer Dolphin, Jack Jacklin, Pompey Lepean, John Mawwee, Zack Negro, and Jarvis Phillips. One breach of peace case, <emph render="italic">State v. Frederic Way</emph>, the defendant, "a transient Indian man," was accused of breach of the peace for threatening Jonathan Rossetter and the family of Samuel Wilson of Harwinton.<emph render="super">9</emph></p>
	<p>In cases of theft, African Americans appeared as defendants in 27 of 30 cases, the only exceptions being two instances in which Negroes were illegally seized by whites and the case of <emph render="italic">State v. William Pratt</emph> of Salisbury. The State charged Pratt with stealing $35 from the house of George Ceasor.<emph render="super">10</emph> More typical, however, are such cases as <emph render="italic">State v. Prince Cummins</emph> for the theft of a dining room table and <emph render="italic">State v. Nathaniel Freeman</emph> for the theft of clothes.<emph render="super">11</emph></p>
	<p>Another major category of lawsuits revolves around the subject of slaves as property. The number and percentage of such cases is much lower than that for New London County due to the fact that the county was only organized one generation before the American Revolution and the weaker grip the institution of slavery had in that county. The cases may be characterized as conversion to own use (4), fraudulent contract (3), fraudulent sale (3), runaways (3), illegal enslavement (2), and trespass (2).<emph render="super">12</emph> The Litchfield County Court in April 1765 heard <emph render="italic">George Catling v. Moses Willcocks</emph>, a case in which Willcocks was accused of converting a slave girl and household goods to his own use.<emph render="super">13</emph> In the 1774 fraudulent contract case of <emph render="italic">Josiah Willoughby v. Elisha Bigelow</emph>, the plaintiff accused Bigelow of lying about York Negro's age and condition. Willoughby stated that York Negro was twenty years older that he was reputed to be, was blind in one eye, and "very intemperate in the use of Speretuous Lickor." He sued to recover the purchase price of £45, the court agreed, and the defendant appealed.<emph render="super">14</emph> Cash Africa sued Deborah Marsh of Litchfield in 1777 for illegal enslavement. He claimed that he was unlawfully seized with force and arms and compelled to labor for the defendant for three years.<emph render="super">15</emph> In another case, <emph render="italic">David Buckingham v. Jonathan Prindle</emph>, the defendant was accused of persuading Jack Adolphus to run away from his master. The plaintiff claimed that Adolphus was about twenty years old and bound to service until age twenty-five, when he would be freed under terms of Connecticut's gradual emancipation law.<emph render="super">16</emph></p>
	<p>Other subjects found in Litchfield County Minorities include defamation, gambling, keeping a bawdy house, and lascivious carriage. The defamation cases all included the charge of sexual intercourse with an Indian or Negro. In one such case, <emph render="italic">Henry S. Atwood v. Norman Atwood</emph>, both of Watertown, the defendant defamed and slandered the plaintiff by charging that he was "guilty of the crime of fornication or adultery with [a] Black or Negro woman," the wife of Peter Deming.<emph render="super">17</emph> Three cases, two from 1814 and one from 1821, accuse several Negroes accuse Harry Fitch, Polly Gorley, Violet Jacklin, Betsy Mead, and Jack Peck alias Jacklin, of running houses of ill repute.<emph render="super">18</emph></p>
	<p>The records on African Americans and Native Americans from Litchfield County are relatively sparse, but they do provide some indication of the difficulties encountered by minorities in white society. They also provide some useful genealogical data on a handful of families in northwestern Connecticut.</p>

<list>
<head id="footnotes2">Endnotes</head>
<item><emph render="super">1</emph>Barbara W. Brown and James M. Rose, joint authors, <emph render="italic">Black Roots in Southeastern Connecticut, 1650-1900</emph> (Detroit: Gale Research Co., 1980).<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">2</emph>The court cases often identify minorities by the words Negro, mulatto, colored, or Indian.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">3</emph>Two or more African Americans or Native Americans are found in 27 lawsuits, but a maximum of two people are included in the Litchfield County Minorities database.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">4</emph>Surnames with spelling variations: Boston (3), Botsford (4), Caesar (7), Coxel (3), Freedom (3), Freeman (9), Gauson (5), Jacklin (17), Kingsbury (10), Leopen (4), Mawwee (5), Quomenor (4), and Smith (3).<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">5</emph>George, Harvey, Isaac, Jack, Philip, Violet, and William Jacklin. Also included is Jack Peck, alias Jack Jacklin.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">6</emph>For the last case, see Conservators and Guardians, Box 2, folder 42.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">7</emph>Fifty-seven suits for debt, the vast majority of which a minority was plaintiff or defendant, and four concerning writs of execution to recover debt owed.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">8</emph>Dec. 1836, Box 3, folder 16.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">9</emph>Sep. 1796, Box 3, folder 6.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">10</emph><emph render="italic">David King v. Stephen Walton</emph>, Mar. 1791, Box 1, folder 17;<emph render="italic">Simon Mitchel v. Edward Hinman</emph>, Dec. 1793, Box 1, folder 18; <emph render="italic">State v. William Pratt</emph>, Oct. 1848, Box 2, folder 37.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">11</emph>Apr. 1828, Box 2, folder 23; Oct. 1837, Box 2, folder 29.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">12</emph>Three additional conversion cases concern livestock and hay.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">13</emph>Apr. 1765, Box 1, folder 5.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">14</emph>Dec. 1774, Box 1, folder 9.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">15</emph>Sep. 1777, Box 1, folder 9.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">16</emph>Dec. 1813, Box 1, folder 49.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">17</emph>Dec. 1814, Box 2, folder 2.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">18</emph>Sep. 1814, Box 2, folder 3, Sep. 1814, Box 2, folder 4; Sep. 1821, Box 2, folder 15.<lb/></item>

</list>
</scopecontent>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
	<head>Related Material</head>
	<p>Related information can be found in <emph render="italic">Trials</emph> for Litchfield County and in the records of the Superior Court for Litchfield County.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<odd><head>List of Cases</head>
<p>Following the one-page box and folder list, is a list of 188 cases stored in an Access database concerning Litchfield County minorities covering the years 1754-1854. The records are arranged alphabetically by name of town and then chronologically by court session. The database also includes the names of up to two minorities found in each court case, the names of the plaintiffs and defendants, subject, note, and box and folder in which each case is found. The letter A indicates that the person of interest is African American and N Native American.</p>
</odd>


<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->

<!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->
<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>

 <controlaccess>
 <head>Organizations:</head>
 <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="lcnaf">Connecticut. County Court (Litchfield County)</corpname>
	</controlaccess>
 

	<controlaccess>
		<head>Subjects:</head>
 			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">County courts -- Connecticut -- Litchfield County -- History</subject>
 			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Indians of North America -- Connecticut -- History -- 18th century</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African Americans -- Connecticut -- History -- 18th century</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Connecticut. County Court (Litchfield County) -- History</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Connecticut. Judicial Dept. -- History</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Connecticut -- History -- Sources</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Litchfield County Native Americans Collection</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Litchfield County African Americans Collection</subject>
	</controlaccess>


	<controlaccess>
		<head>Document Types:</head>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Civil court records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Criminal Court records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Judicial records</genreform> 
	</controlaccess>

</controlaccess>

<!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->

<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->

<accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
	<head>Restrictions on Access</head>

	<p>The collection consists of photocopies of original documents. Second photocopies have been placed in <emph render="italic">Files</emph> for the Litchfield County Court and all originals have been restricted.</p>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="http://libguides.ctstatelibrary.org/hg/using-archival-records" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Rules and Procedures for Researchers Using Archival Records and Secured Collections"/> policy. 
</p>
</accessrestrict>

<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
	<head>Restrictions on Use</head>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="https://ctstatelibrary.org/reproduction-publication/" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title=" Reproduction and Publications of State Library Collections"/> policy. 
</p>

</userestrict>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
	<head>Provenance</head>
	<p>The Litchfield County Minorities Collection consists entirely of photocopies of court cases involving African Americans and Native Americans from records of the <emph render="italic">Files</emph> of the Litchfield County Court. This artificial collection was created to provide more convenient access to materials on Indians and Negroes in Litchfield County.</p>

</acqinfo>

<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->


<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Container List</head>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>1. African Americans</unittitle>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead> 
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Files</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-50</container>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1753 - 1813</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-40</container>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1813 - 1854</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">41-45</container>
	<unittitle>Papers by Subject</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>2. Native Americans</unittitle>
 </did>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-18</container>
	<unittitle>Files</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1765 - 1840</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">19-22</container>
	<unittitle>Papers by Subject</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>

<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->

</archdesc>
</ead>
