<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">

<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">

<eadid mainagencycode="US-ct" url="https://ctstatelibrary.org/RG069_150.html" countrycode="us">RG069_150</eadid>

<filedesc>
	<titlestmt>
		<titleproper>RG 069:150, Truman Smith Papers</titleproper>
		<subtitle>Inventory</subtitle>
		<author>Finding aid prepared by Allen Ramsey.</author>
	</titlestmt>
	<publicationstmt>
		<publisher>Connecticut State Library</publisher>
		<date type="publication">April 01, 2010</date>


	<address><addressline>231 Capitol Avenue</addressline><addressline>Hartford, Connecticut 06106-1537</addressline></address>
 <p>Copyright © <date>2010</date> by the Connecticut State Library</p>
	
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>

<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by Allen Ramsey on
<date normal=" ">>April 01, 2010</date>
</creation>
<langusage><language></language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
	<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
	<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
		<corpname>Connecticut State Library</corpname>
	</repository>

	<origination label="Creator:">
		<persname encodinganalog="100">Smith, Truman, 1791-1884</persname>
	</origination>

	<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Truman Smith papers</unittitle>

	<unitdate label="Dates:" datechar="creation" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1811/2009 ">1811-2009</unitdate>
 <unitdate label="Dates:" datechar="creation" type="bulk" encodinganalog="245$g" normal="1811/1889">bulk 1811-1889</unitdate>
	
 <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">2.75 cubic feet</physdesc>

	<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">Truman Smith was a lawyer, Connecticut Legislator (1831-1832, 1834), US Representative (1838-1843, 1845-1849), and US Senator (1849-1854) from Stamford, Connecticut. Included in his papers are correspondence, writings, publications, legal cases, speeches, and spiritual writings.</abstract>

	<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" 
		repositorycode="US-ct">RG069_150</unitid>

	<unitid label="Accession:">2009-041</unitid>

	<langmaterial>The records are in <language>English</language>.
	</langmaterial>
</did>



<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->
<bioghist altrender="biography" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
	<head>Biographical Note</head>
	<p>Truman Smith was born on November 27, 1791 to Phineas Smith and Deborah Ann Judson in Roxbury, Connecticut. He was the nephew of US Senator Nathan Smith and US Representative Nathaniel Smith. Smith graduated from Yale in 1815 and then studied at Litchfield Law School. In 1818 he was admitted to the Litchfield Bar and then began practicing law. He married his first wife Maria Cook on June 2, 1832. Truman and Maria had a son and one or two daughters. Maria died in April 1849. On November 7, 1850, he married his second wife Mary Ann Dickinson. Truman and Mary had six sons. Truman Smith's daughter Jeannie Penniman was the second wife of U.S. Senator Orville Hitchcock Platt.</p>
 <p>Truman Smith was elected to the Connecticut State legislature in 1831-1832 and 1834. In 1838 he was elected to the United States House of Representatives as a member of the Whig Party and served until 1843. Representative Smith served again in the United States Congress from 1845 to 1849. Smith in 1847 organized and was de-facto leader of a Whig national committee dedicated to organizing, fundraising, and managing General Zachary Taylor's campaign for president. In 1848, Truman Smith along with Alexander H. Stephens (Georgia), Robert Toombs (Georgia), Abraham Lincoln (Illinois), William Ballard Preston (Virginia), Thomas Flournoy (Virginia), and John S. Pendleton (Virginia) formed a pro-Zachary Taylor club referred to as "the Young Indians." The group of Congressmen early in the 1848 presidential campaign backed Taylor. At the June 1848 Whig nominating convention Smith played a pivotal role in the nomination of Zachary Taylor. On the third ballot the Connecticut delegation, having been instructed to vote for Henry Clay, led by Truman Smith along with two other delegates voted for Taylor out of six total delegates. The change in vote on the third ballot led other Whig Party delegates to change their vote on the fourth ballot. After the fourth ballot Zachary Taylor was nominated as the Whig Party's candidate for president.</p>
 <p>On March 3, 1849 Representative Smith resigned from the United States House of Representatives and was elected to the United States Senate on March 4, 1849. Truman Smith, after working on getting Taylor elected, turned down a cabinet post in President Taylor's administration as the first Secretary of the Interior. Senator Smith resigned from the United States Senate on May 24, 1854. Several reasons are stated in various sources for Smith retiring from the US Senate including for financial reasons and his disgust over passage of the Nebraska-Kansas Act. He returned to practicing law by opening an office in New York but had few noteworthy court cases.</p>
 <p>In July 1862, President Abraham Lincoln appointed Truman Smith to the Court of Arbitration in New York, established by a treaty with Great Britain, which was tasked with bringing to trial suspected American and British vessels engaged in the slave trade. In 1870 Congress terminated the Court of Arbitration and he returned back to private law practice. In 1873 he was the successful counsel for the defense in the US Supreme Court case <emph render="italic">New York Central Railroad v. Charles C. Lockwood</emph> in which the railroad argued it was not negligent for injuries sustained to Charles Lockwood during the transport of cattle from Buffalo to Albany, New York. Lockwood had signed an agreement with the railroad taking responsibility for any injury to him or the cattle in exchange for a free ticket. The court ruled for Smith's client, Charles Lockwood, finding the company was negligent and could not exempt itself from being liable for workers injured on the job. After the court case he retired from practicing law but remained active in local, state, and national politics. Truman Smith died in Stamford, Fairfield County, Connecticut on May 3, 1884.</p>
<p><title render="bold">Genealogy</title></p>
 <p>Truman and Maria (Cook) Smith were married June 2, 1832 and according to several sources had at least one son and one or two daughters. The one daughter known of by Truman and Maria Smith was Jeannie Penniman Smith who was born in 1835 and married George Hoyt. Jeannie became a widow and in 1897 would marry US Senator Orville Hitchcock Platt who had lost his first wife Annie Bull in 1893.</p>
 <p>Truman and Mary (Dickinson) Smith were married on November 7, 1850 and according to several sources had six sons. The sources consulted only provided the names of three sons: Truman H., Edmund D., and Robert Smith. Edmund D. Smith was born on September 25, 1857 in Stamford Connecticut to Truman and Mary Smith. Edmund graduated from West Point on June 13, 1879. Edmund married Mary Burkett Dewing on June 28, 1892. Edmund and Mary Burkett Dewing Smith had two children: Truman and Charlotte. Captain Edmund Dickinson Smith was killed in action on Cebu Island, Philippines during the Spanish American War on February 4, 1900. Truman Smith, the son of Edmund and Mary, was born on August 25, 1893 at West Point, New York. Truman graduated from Yale University in 1915 with a Bachelor of Arts degree and served in the United States Military from 1916 to 1948. Truman Smith married Katherine Alling Hollister on July 14, 1917 at Greenport, Long Island. Katharine Truman Smith Coley is the daughter of Truman and Katherine Alling (Hollister) Smith.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
	<head>Scope and Content</head>
	<p>The papers were arranged into seven series which reflect Truman Smith's personal, political, legislative, and legal career in Connecticut, New York, and Washington, D.C. The series include Personal and Political Papers, Legislative Records, Legal Papers, Speeches, Press Files, Spiritual Writings, and Duplicates.</p>
 <p><emph render="bold">Series 1. Personal and Political Papers, 1811-2009,</emph> include biographical information, correspondence to and from Smith and his family and friends, job recommendation letters, an engraved print of Truman Smith, miscellaneous publications, and miscellaneous writings and manuscripts. The series also consists of two bound volumes of Smith's writings which contain printed speeches, court cases, and various writings on topics such as civil service reform, slavery, anesthesia, and temperance.</p>
 <p><emph render="bold">Series 2. Legislative Records, 1836-1872,</emph> include bill files on the boundaries of the Republic of Texas, Choctaw Indian Nation Treaty, crime and punishment, and an act pertaining to the licensing and sale of liquor in Connecticut. The records also contain a committee report and act regarding liquor sales, a state inebriate asylum, and the outlawing of the "trafficking of spirituous or intoxicating liquours" in Connecticut.</p>
 <p><emph render="bold">Series 3. Legal Papers, 1871-1879,</emph> consist of published and written documents on the court cases of <emph render="italic">Cothren v. Nathan Smith</emph>, <emph render="italic">Humaston v. American Telegraph Company</emph>, and <emph render="italic">New York Central Railroad v. Charles C. Lockwood</emph>. The series also includes two handwritten sheets of notes on the <emph render="italic">Hepburn v. Griswold</emph>, <emph render="italic">Knox v. Lee</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Parker v. Davis</emph> legal tender cases of 1870-1871.</p>
 <p><emph render="bold">Series 4. Speeches, 1848-1883,</emph> include speeches by Smith and a miscellaneous printed speech by Senator Morrill on a "bill proposing a reduction of internal taxes and of the tariff." The Smith speeches cover the following topics: physical character of the northern state of Mexico, removals and appointments to office, French spoliation claims, response to Senator Douglas proposal of levying a higher tonnage duty for the improvements of rivers and harbors, and the Nebraska question.</p>
 <p><emph render="bold">Series 5. Press Files, 1874-1889,</emph> contain newspaper clippings and editorials.</p>
 <p><emph render="bold">Series 6. Spiritual Writings, 1879,</emph> include a published sermon and handwritten Bible verses.</p>
 <p><emph render="bold">Series 7. Duplicates, 1850-1880,</emph> consist of duplicate printed court briefs, publications, sermons, and speeches already contained within the papers.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351$b" id="a5">
	<head>Arrangement</head>
	<p>Series 1. Personal and Political Papers, 1811-2009</p>
 <p>Series 2. Legislative Records, 1836-1873</p>
 <p>Series 3. Legal Papers, 1871-1879</p>
 <p>Series 4. Speeches, 1848-1883</p>
 <p>Series 5. Press Files, 1874-1889</p>
 <p>Series 6. Spiritual Writings, 1879</p>
 <p>Series 7. Duplicates, 1850-1880</p>
 <p>Restricted</p>
</arrangement>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
	<head>Related Material</head>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="https://ctstatelibrary.org/RG069_011.html" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="RG 069:011, Orville H. Platt Papers"/>, Connecticut State Library.</p>
 <p>Truman Smith Papers (1893-1970), Herbert Hoover Presidential Library and Museum.</p>
 <note><p>The Truman Smith Papers (1893-1970) document the life and military career of US Senator Truman Smith's (1791-1884) grandson.</p></note>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf2h4n98v1" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Truman Smith Papers (1916-1991)"/>, Hoover Institution Library and Archives, Stanford University.</p>
 <note><p>The Truman Smith Papers (1916-1991) document the life and military career of US Senator Truman Smith's (1791-1884) grandson.</p></note>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://www.stamfordhistory.org/" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Stamford Historical Society, Stamford, Connecticut"/></p>
 <note><p>The Smith/Cruikshank collection, located at the Stamford Historical Society, consists of letters, diaries, account books, and other papers documenting the life of US Senator Truman Smith, his wife Mary Ann (Dickinson) Smith, and their children, including Captain Edmund Smith, who was killed in action in the Philippines in 1900.</p></note>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://special.lib.umn.edu/findaid/html/ymca/yusa0015.phtml" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Cephas Brainerd Papers (1865-1947)"/>. Kautz Family YMCA Archives. University of Minnesota.</p>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009016" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Thomas Corwin Correspondence"/>, Manuscript Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</p>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://memory.loc.gov/ammem/alhtml/malhome.html" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Abraham Lincoln Papers"/>, Manuscript Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</p>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms003053" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Gideon Welles Papers"/>, Manuscript Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</p>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://www.chs.org/research" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Connecticut Historical Society Research Center, Hartford, Connecticut"/></p>
 <p><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Litchfield Historical Soceity, Litchfield, Connecticut"/></p>
</relatedmaterial>
<bibliography id="a10">
	<head>Bibliography</head>
	<p><title render="bold">Books</title></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author">Cutter, William Richard, et al. </persname><title render="italic">Genealogical and Family History of the State of Connecticut: A Record of Achievements of Her People in the Making of a Commonwealth and the Founding of a Nation.</title> Vol. 2. <imprint><geogname>New York: </geogname><publisher>Lewis Historical Publishing Company, </publisher><date type="publication">1911.</date></imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author">Garraty, John A. and Mark C. Carnes, eds. </persname><title render="italic">American National Biography. </title><imprint><geogname> New York: </geogname><publisher>Oxford University Press, </publisher><date type="publication">1999. </date></imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author">Gienapp, William E. </persname><title render="italic">The Origins of the Republican Party, 1852-1856. </title><imprint><geogname> New York: </geogname><publisher>Oxford University Press, </publisher><date type="publication">1987. </date></imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author">Holt, Michael F. </persname><title render="italic">The Rise and Fall of the American Whig Party: Jacksonian Politics and the Onset of the Civil War. </title><imprint><geogname> New York: </geogname><publisher>Oxford University Press, </publisher><date type="publication">1999. </date></imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author">Malone, Dumas, ed. </persname><title render="italic">Dictionary of American Biography. </title><imprint><geogname> New York: </geogname><publisher>Charles Scribner's Sons, </publisher><date type="publication">1935. </date></imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author">McPherson, James M. </persname><title render="italic">Battle Cry of Freedom: The Civil War Era. </title><imprint><geogname> New York: </geogname><publisher>Oxford University Press, </publisher><date type="publication">1988. </date></imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><title render="bold">Articles</title></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author">Simon, John Y. </persname><title>“Lincoln and Truman Smith.” </title><imprint><geogname></geogname><publisher><emph render="italic">Lincoln Herald </emph></publisher>67 <date type="publication">(Fall 1965)</date>: 124-130.</imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><title render="bold">Newspapers</title></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author"></persname><title render="italic">Hartford Courant, </title><imprint><geogname></geogname><publisher></publisher><date type="publication">1764-1922. </date></imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><bibref><persname role="author"></persname><title render="italic">New York Times, </title><imprint><geogname></geogname><publisher></publisher><date type="publication">1851-2006. </date></imprint></bibref></p>
 <p><title render="bold">Websites</title></p>
 <p><title render="italic">Biographical Dictionary of the United States Congress. </title><extptr linktype="simple" href="http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=S000621" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Smith, Truman, (1791-1884)"/></p>
</bibliography>



<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->

<!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->
<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>
<p>This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.</p>
<controlaccess>
 <head>Subjects:</head>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Speeches in Congress</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">United States. Congress. Senate</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">United States. Congress. House</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Slavery -- United States -- Speeches in Congress</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">United States. Kansas-Nebraska Act</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Legislators -- Connecticut</subject> 
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">United States -- Territorial expansion</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- 1845-1849</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Whig Party (U.S.)</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Whig Party (U.S.). National Convention</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1861-1865 </subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950 </subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Legislators -- United States</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lawyers</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Temperance</subject>
 </controlaccess>
 <controlaccess>
 <head>Places:</head>
 <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">Stamford (Conn.) -- History</geogname>
 <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">Stamford (Conn.)</geogname>
 <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">Roxbury (Conn. : Town)</geogname>
 <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">Litchfield (Conn.)</geogname>
 <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Yale College (1718-1887)</geogname>
 <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Litchfield Law School</geogname>
 <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
 </controlaccess>
 <controlaccess>
		<head>Persons:</head>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Smith, Truman, 1791-1884</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="local">Smith, Maria Cook</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="local">Smith, Edmund Dickinson, 1857-1900</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="local">Smith, Truman, 1893-1970</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="local">Smith, Mary Ann Dickinson</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Taylor, Zachary, 1784-1850</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Weed, Thurlow, 1797-1882</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Platt, Orville Hitchcock, 1827-1905</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Welles, Gideon, 1802-1878</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Johnson, Reverdy, 1796-1876</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Wentworth, John, 1815-1888</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="local">Brainerd, Cephas</persname>
 <persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872</persname>
 </controlaccess> 
 <controlaccess>
		<head>Document Types:</head>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Clippings</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Prints</genreform>
 <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Publications</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Reports</genreform>
 </controlaccess>

</controlaccess>
 
<!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->

<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->

<accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
	<head>Restrictions on Access</head>
 <p>The original correspondence of Sherman, William T. and Taylor, Zachary have been removed and are restricted. Use copies of the correspondence are located in the folders. See Series 1. Personal and Political Papers, 1811-2009.</p>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="http://libguides.ctstatelibrary.org/hg/using-archival-records" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Rules and Procedures for Researchers Using Archival Records and Secured Collections"/> policy. 
</p>
</accessrestrict>

<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
	<head>Restrictions on Use</head>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="http://ctstatelibrary.org/reproduction-publication/" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title=" Reproduction and Publications of State Library Collections"/> policy. 
</p>

</userestrict>


<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
	<head>Provenance</head>
	<p>The Truman Smith papers were donated by Katharine Truman Smith Coley to the State Library in 2009.</p>

</acqinfo>

<processinfo encodinganalog="583" id="a20">
	<head>Processing Information</head>
	<p>Allen Ramsey processed the papers in March and April, 2010</p>
</processinfo>


<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->


<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Container List</head>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 1. Personal and Political Papers</unittitle>
	<unitdate normal="1811/2009">1811-2009</unitdate>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Biographical file</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1811/2009 undated">1811-2009, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">2-6</container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1848/1883">1848-1883</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">7</container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence - Federal Departments</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1873/1881">1873-1881</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">8-9</container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence - Smith, Mary</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1860/1866">1860-1866</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-3</container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence - Smith, Mary</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1860/1866">1868-1869</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Correspondence - VIP</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Grant, Ulysses</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1877">1877</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle>Lincoln, Abraham</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1862">1862</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle>Platt, Orville H.</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1880/1881">1880-1881</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file" id="restricted">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">7</container>
	<unittitle>Sherman, William T.</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1879">1879</unitdate>
 </did>
 <userestrict><p><emph render="bold">Restricted:</emph> Original correspondence restricted but use copies of the correspondence are located in the folder.</p></userestrict>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">8</container>
	<unittitle>Taylor, Zachary</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1848/1849">1848-1849</unitdate>
 </did>
 <userestrict><p><emph render="bold">Restricted:</emph> Original correspondence restricted but use copies of the correspondence are located in the folder.</p></userestrict>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle>Weed, Thurlow</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1877">1881</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">10</container>
	<unittitle>Wentworth, John</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1882/undated">1882, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>Job recommendations</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1879/1882">1879-1882</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Print</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="undated">undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">13</container>
	<unittitle>Publications - miscellaneous</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1879/undated">1879, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-3</container>
	<unittitle>Writings and manuscripts</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1862/1879 undated">1862-1879, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle><title render="italic">Writings of Truman Smith</title>
 </unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1848/1879">1848-1879</unitdate>
 <physdesc>2 volumes</physdesc>
 <note><p>The two volumes contain printed publications of writings, speeches, and court cases.</p></note>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 2. Legislative Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate normal="1836/1873">1836-1873</unitdate>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Bill files</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1836/1873 undated">1836-1873, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Committee report</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1870/1871">1870-1871</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 3. Legal Papers</unittitle>
	<unitdate normal="1871/1879">1871-1879</unitdate>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">3-4</container>
	<unittitle><title render="italic">Cothren v. Nathan Smith</title></unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1876/1879">1876-1879</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle><title render="italic">Humaston v. American Telegraph Company</title></unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1873/1874">1873-1874</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle><title render="italic">New York Central Railroad Company v. Charles C. Lockwood</title></unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1871/1873 undated">1871-1873, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">7</container>
	<unittitle>Notes</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="undated">undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 4. Speeches</unittitle>
	<unitdate normal="1871/1879">1848-1883</unitdate>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">8</container>
	<unittitle>Speeches - miscellaneous</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1883">1883</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle>Speeches - Smith, Truman</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1848/1876">1848-1876</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Speeches - Smith, Truman</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="undated">undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 5. Press Files</unittitle>
	<unitdate normal="1871/1879">1874-1889</unitdate>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1874/1889 undated">1874-1889, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Editorials</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1880">1880</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 6. Spiritual Writings</unittitle>
	<unitdate normal="1879">1879</unitdate>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Sermons and verses</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1879/undated">1879, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 7. Duplicates</unittitle>
	<unitdate normal="1850/1880">1850-1880</unitdate>
 <note><p><emph render="bold">The series consists of duplicate legal papers, publications, sermons, and speeches already contained within the papers.</emph> </p></note>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle>Duplicate legal papers</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1874/undated">1874, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">6-7</container>
	<unittitle>Duplicate publications</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1862/1880">1862-1880</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">8</container>
	<unittitle>Duplicate sermons</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1879">1879</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle>Duplicate speeches</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1850/1852">1850-1852</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle><emph render="bold">Restricted</emph></unittitle>
 </did>
<accessrestrict><p><emph render="bold">The original correspondence is restricted. See Series 1. Personal and Political Papers, 1811-2009.</emph></p></accessrestrict>
 
 
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Correspondence - VIP</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">6</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Sherman, William T.</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1879">1879</unitdate>
 </did>
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">6</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Taylor, Zachary</unittitle>
	<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1848/1849">1848-1849</unitdate>
 </did>
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>













<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
</archdesc>
</ead>

