<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">

<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">


<eadid mainagencycode="US-ct" url="http://www.ctstatelibrary.org/RG062_075.html" countrycode="us">RG062_075</eadid>

<filedesc>
	<titlestmt>
		<titleproper encodinganalog="title">RG 062:075, Town of Lyme</titleproper>
 <titleproper encodinganalog="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Lyme Records, Inventory of Town of</titleproper>
		<subtitle>Inventory of Records</subtitle>
		<author>Finding aid prepared by Bruce P. Stark.</author>
	</titlestmt>
	<publicationstmt>
		<publisher>Connecticut State Library</publisher>
		<date type="publication" normal=" ">December 28, 2006</date>
		<address>
			<addressline>231 Capitol Avenue</addressline>
			<addressline>Hartford, Connecticut 06106-1537</addressline>
		</address>
 		<p>Copyright © <date>2007</date> by the Connecticut State Library</p>
	</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>

<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by Paul E. Baran on
<date>March 08, 2007</date>
</creation>
<langusage><language></language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
	<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
	<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
		<corpname>Connecticut State Library</corpname>
	</repository>

	<origination label="Creator:">
		<persname encodinganalog="100">Lyme (Conn.)</persname>
	</origination>

	<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Town of Lyme records</unittitle>

	<unitdate label="Dates:" datechar="creation" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1781/1948">1781-1948</unitdate>

	<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">2.75 cubic feet</physdesc>

	<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">Administrative, poor relief, land, court, military, vital, school, election, and tax records.</abstract>

	<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" 
		repositorycode="US-ct">RG062_075</unitid>

 <unitid label="Accession: ">Multiple</unitid>

	<langmaterial>The records are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.
	</langmaterial>
</did>


<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->

<bioghist altrender="history" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
	<head>Historical Note</head>
	<p>	The town of Lyme in New London County was set off from Saybrook in 1665 and named in 1667. The original town included the present towns of Lyme, Old Lyme, most of East Lyme, and part of Salem. Salem was incorporated as a separate town in 1819, East Lyme in 1839, and Old Lyme in 1855. The original town was organized into three and one half ecclesiastical societies – the First Society (Old Lyme), Second Society (East Lyme), and Third or North Society (Lyme). An area in the northwest part of Lyme, called Hadlyme because it encompasses two towns, was established as an ecclesiastical society in 1742 from parts of Lyme and East Haddam but never became a separate town. Some records also refer to Chesterfield Society, an area that includes part of the present towns of East Lyme and Montville.</p>
</bioghist>

<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
	<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>
The records of the Town of Lyme consist of six boxes of materials divided into nine different series. Administrative Records comprise the largest series, followed by Tax Records.
</p>
<p>
Series 1, <emph render="bold">Administrative Records, 1817-1888,</emph> is by far the largest series and treasurer records form the heart of the collection. Series 1, however, also includes two folders of abatements, one of indentures, and two of selectmen records, plus nine folders of printed <emph render="italic">Public Acts of the State of Connecticut</emph> covering scattered years between 1836 and 1853.
</p>
<p>
Treasurer's records make up by far the largest quantity of papers in Series 1 and they contain the most valuable research information, although considerable diligence is required to carefully examine and extract the data they contain. They begin with six folders of booklets of town orders that cover most of the years between 1817 and 1850. Town orders provide general information on who was paid and for what amount. For more detailed information on the nature of charges incurred against the town, researchers must examine treasurer bills, comprising two and one half boxes, covering many but not all years between 1820 and 1882. The bulk of the bills span the years 1820-1849 and they provide documentation on town expenses for administrative costs like the payment of town officials, care of the poor, repairs of roads and bridges, and miscellaneous expenses like bounties for foxes. 
</p>


<p>
A significant proportion of treasurer bills concern care of the poor and these records provide unsurpassed documentation of the lives of those at the lowest rung of society, individuals that may be represented in no other sources. One of the earliest documents, for example, is the $61.11 bill of Ezra Pratt to the Town of Lyme for the care of the family of David Buttler between December 22, 1818 and February 19, 1821. It includes charges for moving the family, house rental, food, and for the burial of a child.<emph render="super">1</emph> A second item from the same folder has the bill for the transportation of Meraby Smith "a Black woman" from New London to Lyme and a third the expenses for a case of bastardy involving Delia Bramble and the reputed father Benjamin Banning.<emph render="super">2</emph> An 1823 bill from Dr. Vine Utley requests reimbursement of $11.47 for treating James Rogers and for Isaac Beckwith and his wife.<emph render="super">3</emph> 
</p>
<p>
Although it appears, that the largest single category of expense was for care of the poor, the town also devoted considerable resources to repairs of roads and bridges. On January 25, 1824, for example, the treasurer paid George H. Chadwick, James Gates, Benjamin Griffing, Nathan Griffing, Charles Harrison, Jonathan Laplass, Charles L. Peck, and William Sterling for gravel, labor, and timber to repair several town bridges.<emph render="super">4</emph> In addition, small but regular outlays were made to town officers to reimburse them for such activities as service as assessor, board of relief, and selectmen, to attorneys for representing the town in legal proceedings, and reimbursement to church societies for use of the meetinghouses to hold town meetings. On December 11, 1826, the treasurer paid Henry M. Waite $18.44 for legal services, Charles Smith $12 for making twenty-four highway rate bills, and the Strict Congregational Society $4.00 for using the meetinghouse four days for town meetings and elections.<emph render="super">5</emph> In 1840, a single town bill listed payments to four men totaling $4.00 as bounties on foxes.<emph render="super">6</emph> 
</p>
<p>
The remaining series are all quite small and not all are worthy of mention. Series 2, <emph render="bold">Poor Relief Records, 1818-1882,</emph> consists of just four folders, but contains valuable information to supplement that found in Series 1. Two folders hold booklets of accounts and two contain correspondence. The first booklet records payments to thirty individuals for the care of poor children, elderly, and widows, including reimbursement to two people of color for supporting other people of color, Cato Huntley for the care of Basil and John Crosley for the Prince children.<emph render="super">7</emph> The first folder of correspondence contains two letters of particular interest. The first is a January 25, 1831 letter from Comptroller Elisha Phelps to Oliver Raymond concerning the support of Prince Brown, while the second from 1838 concerns his widow Phillis Brown, described as "an old Coulered Woman an inhabitant of Lyme the Widow of the Late Prince Brown of or near Pleasant Valley."<emph render="super">8</emph> 
</p>
<p>
Series 4, <emph render="bold">Court Records, 1825-1872,</emph> consists of three folders of writs and attachments. The largest number of cases is suits for debt. One writ of attachment for October 17, 1843 on a promissory note, for example, notes that the defendant, Jonathan T. Warner, was formerly a resident of Lyme but at the time of "the province of California in Mexico."<emph render="super">9</emph> In another case, five men from Lyme and East Haddam, joint owners of the schooner <emph render="italic">John W. Smith</emph> of Lyme, sued William Smith of New London, master of the vessel, for carelessly transporting coffee, white lead, and clocks worth $2,000 from New York to Baltimore.<emph render="super">10</emph> One of the few lawsuits not concerning debt is <emph render="italic">Moses Maynard v. George Dorr</emph>, by which the plaintiff accused Dorr of slandering him by saying in the hearing of several others, "Damn you, you (meaning the plaintiff) stole my boards."<emph render="super">11</emph> 
</p>
<p>
The materials in Series 6, <emph render="bold">Vital Records, 1855-1872,</emph> are comprised of two folders of abstracts of "Records of Births, Marriages and Deaths." The abstract for 1859, as an example, records the births of 7 males and 13 females, 8 marriages, and 28 deaths, 15 male and 13 female. One female was "colored." Causes of death are also tabulated. They include 4 from scarlet fever, 4 from pneumonia, and 3 from consumption.<emph render="super">12</emph> 
</p>
<p>
Series 8, <emph render="bold">Election Records, 1855-1868,</emph> consists of one folder of certifications of electors, e.g., persons who were admitted as voters in one town and subsequently moved to Lyme, two folders of election returns, a printed copy of legislation relating to elections and the admission of electors, and a partial list of voters for 1858. The returns for 1860, for example, show the firmness of party loyalty, as votes for candidates of the two parties were virtually identical from the top to the bottom of the ticket. Governor William A. Buckingham received 155 votes and his Democratic opponent Thomas H. Seymour got 116. The party candidates for lieutenant governor, secretary of the state, treasurer, and comptroller were identical, while the Republican candidate for county sheriff received one vote less, the candidates for state senator received 153 and 115 and judge of probate 152 and 115.<emph render="super">13</emph> 
</p>
<p>
Two items have particular importance in Series 9, <emph render="bold">Tax Records, 1781-1783, 1948,</emph> five volumes of tax lists covering the years 1781-93 and two folders of abstracts of town assessments. The latter, titled "List of Polls and Taxable Property," and the earliest dates from 1855, the year Old Lyme separated from Lyme. As of October 1, 1855, Lyme had 214 dwellings and 15,347 acres of land. Figures are also included for such other categories of taxable property as neat cattle (1,652 valued at $28,424), bank stock ($17,986), and investments in vessels, steamboats, and commerce ($9,950). Also, includes a three page document on grant in lieu of taxes for state property in Lyme, 1948.
</p>

<list>
<head id="footnotes">Endnotes</head>
<item><emph render="super">1</emph>Series 1, Administrative Records, Treasurer bills, Box 2, folder 5.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">2</emph>Ibid.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">3</emph>Ibid, Box 2, folder 8.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">4</emph>Ibid, Box 2, folder 8.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">5</emph>Ibid, Box 2, folder 19.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">6</emph>Ibid, Box 3, folder 14.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">7</emph>Series 2, Poor Relief Records, Box 4, folder 19.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">8</emph>Elisha Phelps to Oliver Raymond, Hartford, January 25, 1831; Charles Bliss to Selectmen of Lyme, Norwich, December 21, 1838, Ibid, Box 4, folder 21.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">9</emph>Series 3, Court Records, <emph render="italic">Richard Warner v. Jonathan T. Warner</emph>, Oct. 17, 1843, Box 4, folder 24.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">10</emph>Ibid, <emph render="italic">Horace Ely &amp; others v. William Smith</emph>, Oct. 14, 1841, Box 4, folder 24.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">11</emph>Ibid, <emph render="italic">Moses Maynard v. George Dorr</emph>, Apr. 9, 1851, Box 4, folder 25.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">12</emph>Series 6, Vital Records, Box 4, folder 28.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">13</emph>Series 8, Election Records, Box 5, folder 4.<lb/></item>
</list>
</scopecontent>

<arrangement encodinganalog="351$b" id="a5">
	<head>Arrangement</head>

<p>Series 1. Administrative Records (1817-1888).
</p>

<p>
Series 2. Poor Relief Records (1818-1882).
</p>

<p>
Series 3. Land Records (1829).
</p>

<p>
Series 4. Court Records (1825-1872).
</p>

<p>
Series 5. Military Records (1820-1871).
</p>

<p>
Series 6. Vital Records (1855-1872).
</p>

<p>
Series 7. School Records (1837, 1910).
</p>

<p>
Series 8. Election Records (1855-1868).
</p>

<p>
Series 9. Tax Records (1781-1873, 1948).
</p>

<p>
Series 10. Old Accession (1781-1858).
</p>
</arrangement>

<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
	<head>Related Material</head>
	<p>	The State Archives holds additional records of the town of Lyme. They include two volumes of Lyme Town Records, the first of town meetings, 1667-1727 and the second of land grants and ear marks, 1667-1929; Town Day Book, 1810-27; and many volumes of records of the Lyme First Congregational Church, Hadlyme Congregational Church, Grace Chapel in Hadlyme, North Lyme Baptist Church, East Lyme Baptist Church, East Lyme First Congregational Church, Old Lyme First Congregational Church, Old Lyme First Baptist Church, and St. Ann’s Protestant Episcopal Church in Old Lyme.</p>
</relatedmaterial>


<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->

<!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->

<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>

 <controlaccess>
 	 	<head>Alternate Creators:</head>
				<corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Connecticut. Justice of the Peace (Lyme)</corpname>
	</controlaccess>
	
	<controlaccess>
		<head>Subjects:</head>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Public welfare -- Connecticut -- Lyme</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Deeds -- Connecticut -- Lyme</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Justices of the peace -- Connecticut -- Lyme</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Writs -- Connecticut -- Lyme</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Elections -- Connecticut -- Lyme -- Statistics</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Voting -- Connecticut -- Lyme -- Statistics</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Lyme -- Registers</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Taxation -- Connecticut -- Lyme -- Registers</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Lyme -- Registers</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Property tax -- Connecticut -- Lyme -- Registers</subject>
	</controlaccess>

	<controlaccess>
		<head>Places:</head>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" role="subject" source="lcsh">Lyme (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence</geogname>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" role="subject" source="lcsh">Lyme (Conn.) -- Statistics, Vital</geogname>
	</controlaccess>
	 
	<controlaccess>
		<head>Document Types:</head>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Civil court records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Deeds</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Election returns</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Military records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">School records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Tax records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Vital records</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Voters' lists</genreform>
	</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>


<!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->

<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->

<accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
<head>Restrictions on Access</head>

 <p>	The records are freely accessible to researchers, although they must take care not to disarrange the many extremely small documents.</p>

	<p>These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.</p>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="http://libguides.ctstatelibrary.org/hg/using-archival-records" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Rules and Procedures for Researchers Using Archival Records and Secured Collections"/> policy. 
</p>

</accessrestrict>

<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
	<head>Restrictions on Use</head>
<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="http://ctstatelibrary.org/reproduction-publication/" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title=" Reproduction and Publications of State Library Collections"/> policy. 
</p>
</userestrict>

<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
	<head>Acquisition Information</head>
	<p>Boxes 1-5 represent a December 2006 donation to the Connecticut State Archives, while Box 6 came at an earlier time. Accession 2017-022 was transferred to the State Library on October 31, 2016.</p>

</acqinfo>



<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->


<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->

<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Container List</head>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 1. Administrative Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1817/1888">1817-1888</unitdate>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead> 
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-2</container>
	<unittitle>Abatements</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1822-1850</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Indentures</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1851-1853</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Papers, miscellaneous</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1881, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<unittitle>Public laws of Connecticut</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">The Public Statute Laws of the State of Connecticut 1836</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts of the State of Connecticut, May and December 1836 and May 1837</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">7</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts of the State of Connecticut, Passed May Session, 1839</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">8</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts of the State of Connecticut, Passed May Session, 1840</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts, Passed by the General Assembly of the State of Connecticut,
May Session, 1842</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">10</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts, Passed by the General Assembly of the State of Connecticut,
May Session, 1845</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts, Passed by the General Assembly of the State of Connecticut,
May Session, 1847</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts of the State of Connecticut, Passed May Session, 1850</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">13</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts of the State of Connecticut, Passed May Session, 1853</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">14</container>
	<unittitle>Roads and highways</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1831-1835</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">15-16</container>
	<unittitle>Selectmen</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1825-1882, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">17-19</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Statement of the Financial Affairs of the Town of Lyme</emph></unittitle>
	<unitdate>1880-1888</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">20-22</container>
	<unittitle>Town orders</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1817-1826</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-4</container>
	<unittitle>Town orders</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1830-1850</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<unittitle>Treasurer</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">5-25</container>
	<unittitle>Bills</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1820-1834</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-26</container>
	<unittitle>Bills</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1834-1844</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-16</container>
	<unittitle>Bills</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1834-1882, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">17</container>
	<unittitle>Check stubs</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1866</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">18</container>
	<unittitle>Receipt book</unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 2. Poor Relief Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1818/1882">1818-1882</unitdate>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>	
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">19-20</container>
	<unittitle>Accounts</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1818-1824</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">21-22</container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1821-1882, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 3. Land Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1829">1829</unitdate>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>	
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">23</container>
	<unittitle>Deed</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1829 June 24</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 4. Court Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1825/1872">1825-1872</unitdate>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>	
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">24-26</container>
	<unittitle>Writs and attachments</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1825-1872</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 5. Military Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1820/1871">1820-1871</unitdate>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>	
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">27</container>
	<unittitle>Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1820-1871</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 6. Vital Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855-1872">1855-1872</unitdate>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>	
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">28</container>
	<unittitle>Abstracts</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1855-1864</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Abstracts</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1865-1872</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 7. School Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1837/1910">1837, 1910</unitdate>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>	
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>4th School District receipt</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1837 November 5</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Laws Relating to Schools</emph></unittitle>
	<unitdate>1910</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 8. Election Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855/1868">1855-1868</unitdate>
 </did>	
<c02 level="otherlevel" otherlevel="accession">
 <did>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Certifications of electors</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1855-1868</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">4-5</container>
	<unittitle>Election returns</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1857-1867</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Public Acts Relating to Elections, and the Admission of Electors in the State of</emph></unittitle>
	<unitdate>1852</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="otherlevel" otherlevel="accession">
 <did>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">T000375</unitid>
 </did>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">6</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Voter list</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1858</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 9. Tax Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1781/1948">1781-1873, 1948</unitdate>
 </did>	
<c02 level="otherlevel" otherlevel="accession">
 <did>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2007-027</unitid>
 </did>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">7-8</container>
	<unittitle>Abstracts of town assessments</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1855-1873</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle>Miscellaneous tax records</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1824-1828</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="otherlevel" otherlevel="accession">
 <did>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">T000375</unitid>
 </did>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">6</container>
	<container type="Folder"> </container>
	<unittitle>Tax lists</unittitle>
	<unitdate> 1781-1793</unitdate>
 <physdesc><extent>5 volumes plus index</extent></physdesc>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="otherlevel" otherlevel="accession">
 <did>
 <unitid label="Accession: ">2017-022</unitid>
 </did>
<thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Envelope</entry>
 <entry></entry>
 </row>
 </thead> 
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Grant in lieu of taxes</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1948 July 1</unitdate>
 <physdesc><extent>3 typescript pages</extent></physdesc>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>


</dsc>











<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->

</archdesc>
</ead>
