<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">

<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">


<eadid mainagencycode="US-ct" url="http://www.ctstatelibrary.org/RG069_120.html" countrycode="us">RG069_120</eadid>

<filedesc>
	<titlestmt>
		<titleproper>RG 069:120, Foote Family Papers</titleproper>
		<subtitle>Inventory</subtitle>
		<author>Finding aid prepared by Bruce P. Stark.</author>
	</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
	<publisher>Connecticut State Library</publisher>
	<date type="publication">December 16, 2008</date>

	<address><addressline>231 Capitol Avenue</addressline><addressline>Hartford, Connecticut, 06106-1537</addressline></address>
 		<p>Copyright © <date>2008</date> by the Connecticut State Library</p>

</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>

<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by Paul E. Baran on
<date>December 16, 2008</date>
</creation>
<langusage><language></language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
	<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
	<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
		<corpname>Connecticut State Library</corpname>
		<address><addressline> </addressline><addressline> </addressline></address>
	</repository>

	<origination label="Creator:">
		<corpname encodinganalog="100">Foote Family</corpname>
	</origination>

	<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Foote family papers</unittitle>

	<unitdate label="Dates:" datechar="creation" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1728/1867">1728-1867</unitdate>

	<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">2 cubic feet</physdesc>

	<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">The papers consist of materials pertaining to three generations of members of the Foote family of Marlborough, principally Asa Foote (1728-1806), his son Joel Foote (1763-1846), the children of Joel Foote and their spouses, and other relatives. Asa, a farmer by trade, and Joel Foote, a clothier and merchant, were both well to do and prominent political figures in Marlborough Society in Colchester and in the town of Marlborough.</abstract>

	<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" 
		repositorycode="US-ct">RG069_120</unitid>
	<unitid label="Accession: ">2003-027</unitid>

	<langmaterial>The records are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.
	</langmaterial>
</did>


<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->

<bioghist altrender="biography" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
<head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>The papers consist of materials pertaining to three generations of members of the Foote family of Marlborough, principally Asa Foote (1728-1806), his son Joel Foote (1763-1846), the children of Joel Foote and their spouses, and other relatives.<emph render="super">1</emph> Asa, a farmer by trade, and Joel Foote, a clothier and merchant, were both well to do and prominent political figures in Marlborough Society in Colchester and in the town of Marlborough. </p>

<list>
<head id="footnotes">Endnotes</head>
<item><emph render="super">1</emph>For information on the Foote family and how the major figures in the collection are related to one another, see Abram W. Foote, <emph render="italic">Foote Family: Comprising the Genealogy and History of Nathaniel Foote of Wethersfield, Conn. and his Descendants</emph>, Vol. I (Rutland, Vt.: Marble City Press, 1907).<lb/></item>
</list>

</bioghist>

<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>
The papers are divided into two series, the first consisting of Justice of the Peace Records and the second of Family Papers.
</p>
<p>
<emph render="bold">Series 1, Justice of the Peace Records, 1781-1849,</emph> consists of court papers kept by several members of the Foote family who were justices of the peace in Marlborough Society in Colchester and then Marlborough.<emph render="super">2</emph> For civil cases, the typical document is a writ or summons ordering a defendant to appear before a named justice of the peace at a designated time and place to answer a specific charge. The verso of the writ typically contains information on it being served to the defendant and sometimes includes documentation on the disposition of the case. A second kind of writ is also found, a writ of execution demanding that the losing party in a civil lawsuit pay of specific sum for the debt incurred and costs of case determined at trial by a single justice of the peace. The bulk of civil cases consist of debts by book or note, although other subjects are represented, including assault and trespass. In criminal cases, the representative document is a presentment by a grand juror containing an accusation against a defendant for being suspected of having committed a specific crime.
</p>
<p>
The first two documents are 1781 writs of execution in debt cases. In the first instance, a writ of execution in favor of Laton Porter of Hebron against Edward Luther of Colchester, the verso contains the notation that Capt. Asa Foote paid the sum due.<emph render="super">3</emph> The second execution was completed and signed by justice Daniel Foot.<emph render="super">4</emph> The majority of court records, however, consist of summonses in minor debt cases, as when Elihu Marvin of Hebron sued Eliphalet Davenport of Colchester in a debt by book to collect $2.00.<emph render="super">5</emph> In a second example, Aaron Foote sued in August 1815 to collect $7.00 to balance book accounts.<emph render="super">6</emph> Not all civil cases brought before justices of the peace concerned debt. In 1801, for example, the selectmen of Colchester asked Joel Foote to consider the case of Benjamin Curtis who had reduced his family to "Distressd Circumstances by his Idleness, Mismanagement and bad husbandry." Foote determined that the charges were true and ordered the selectmen to appoint an overseer or conservator over him.<emph render="super">7</emph> In a second example, Andrew Warner accused John Blackman and John W. Chappel of assaulting him. Joel Foote heard the case on Oct. 8, 1813, found the defendants not guilty, and order the plaintiff to pay $1.13 court costs.<emph render="super">8</emph> In a case of trespass in 1815, William Buell, Jr. sued for trespass, claiming the defendants entered his land and cut down twenty trees to damages of $7.00. Foote ruled for the plaintiff and awarded him $3.60 damages and $5.74 costs of suit<emph render="super">9</emph>. 
</p>
<p>
Joel Foote and other justices received complaints or presentments from grand jurors in criminal cases covering such subjects as adultery, assault, burglary, election fraud, fornication, illegal sale of alcoholic beverages, intoxication, malicious mischief, unnecessary travel on the Sabbath, passing counterfeit bills, profane swearing, riotous assembly, and theft. For lesser offenses, those charged were tried before the justice of the peace, but the accused were bound over to higher courts for trial for more serious crimes. In a case tried before Joel Foote, transient Henry Freeman was accused of assaulting Candace Bunce. Foote found Freeman guilty.<emph render="super">10</emph> On January 5, 1824 grand juror Sylvester C. Dunham accused John Button, George Button, and James Finley of "sinfully, wickedly and profanely God damning" Edward Root and Oliver Northam. Joel Foote found George Button and James Finley guilty and John Button not guilty.<emph render="super">11</emph> When Jonathan Palmer of Chatham was accused of committing adultery with Roxanna Bogue of Marlborough, wife of Edwin Bogue, justice of the peace Enos Buell bound the two over to Hartford Superior Court for trial.<emph render="super">12</emph> Six years later justice George Foote heard a complaint that William G. Huxford of Marlborough was illegally made a voter on October 28, 1844. This case was also bound over to the Hartford Superior Court for trial<emph render="super">13</emph>. 
</p>
<p>
The overwhelming majority of justice of the peace records consisted of writs signed by a member of the Foote family or ordering delinquents to appear before a Foote justice of the peace. On occasion, however, others are represented and sometimes they are prominent political figures like Calvin Goddard, Sylvester Gilbert, William Hillhouse, and Thomas Seymour. The records also include scattered court cases in which African Americans from Marlborough and surrounding towns are found. The individuals include Candace Bunce, Enoch Freeman, Zilpha Freeman, Prince Hyde, Primus Negro, Gideon Quah, Asher Russell, Prince Swan, Absalom Thomas, and James White.
</p>
<p>
Series 1 concludes with two folders of record books kept by Joel Foote covering the period between November 3, 1794 and May 13, 1811 (Box 2, folders 8-9). About half the entries correspond with the records found in justice of the peace file papers.
</p>
<p>
<emph render="bold">Series 2, Family Papers, 1728-1867,</emph> contains a variety of papers, among them bills and receipts, business records, deeds, estate papers, indentures, and school papers. 
</p>
<p>
The first subject grouping of importance in Series 2 consists of four folders of business records kept by Cyrus Bingham who married Abigail Foote, daughter of Joel Foote (Box 2, folders 15-18). These daybooks span the years 1814-49. Two folders of business records of H. A. Johnson follow. His relationship to the Footes is yet to be determined. Box 2, folders 22-23 holds correspondence, primarily letters to Joel Foote and his daughter Rachel C. Foote and is followed by three folders of deeds. The largest section of Series 2 consists of estate papers of members of the Foote family and of persons whose estates are at least in part administered by a Foote. The papers include copies of the will of Asa Foote, estate papers of Joel Foote, and a large quantity of estate papers of Joel Foote's father-in-law Samuel P. Lord (Box 3, folders 2-17)<emph render="super">14</emph>. Asa Foote served as administer to the estates of Mary Owen and Lawrence Power and Joel Foote as one of the executors of the estate of Sarah Miller.
</p>
<p>
One folder contains the indentures of six boys and one girl to Asa Foote and Joel Foote between 1787 and 1822<emph render="super">15</emph>. Asa Foote accepted one apprentice to learn the trade of farming and Joel Foote the other six to learn the clothier business. The next folder of Marlborough Society papers includes a copy of the May 1747 act of the General Assembly establishing the society from parts of Colchester, Glastonbury, and Hebron and a copy of a 1781 act concerning quotas of recruits needed for the Continental Army; two documents relating to the appointment of Joel Foote and four others to collect the federal 1798 direct tax; and a copy of minutes an 1808 meeting of the Episcopalians in Marlborough that was chaired by Joel Foote. Miscellaneous Papers includes the 1771 sale of "A Negro Girl named Juda about four years old" to Asa Foote by Lemuel Fitch of Colchester<emph render="super">16</emph>. The papers conclude with several folders of school papers of Cyrus Bingham, husband of Abigail Foote, the third child of Joel Foote, and the sons of the couple.
</p>

<list>
<head id="footnotes2">Endnotes</head>
<item><emph render="super">2</emph>Marlborough in Hartford County was incorporated in October 1803 from parts of Colchester, Glaston-bury, and Hebron.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">3</emph><emph render="italic">Laton Porter v. Edward Luther</emph>, Mar. 12, 1781, Box 1, folder 1.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">4</emph><emph render="italic">Elias Worthington v. Edward Luther</emph>, July 17, 1781, Box 1, folder 1.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">5</emph><emph render="italic">Elihu Marvin v. Eliphalet Davenport</emph>, Mar. 2, 1797. Joel Foote filled out the writ.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">6</emph><emph render="italic">Aaron Foote v. Nathaniel Bailey</emph>, Aug. 12, 1815, Box 1, folder 22. Israel Foote completed the writ.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">7</emph><emph render="italic">Complaint of Joseph Isham, Roger Bulkley, and David Yeomans</emph>, Jan. 5, 1801, Box 1, folder 5.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">8</emph><emph render="italic">Andrew Warner v. John Blackman and John H. Chappel</emph>, Oct. 6, 1812, Box 1, folder 21.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">9</emph><emph render="italic">William Buel, Jr. v. Ruel Brown and Amasa Brown</emph>, May 3, 1815, Box 1, folder 22.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">10</emph><emph render="italic">State v. Henry Freeman</emph>, Mar. 14, 1814, Box 1, folder 21. Freeman was fined $3.00, required to pay costs of prosecution of $4.37, and jailed until the judgment was satisfied.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">11</emph><emph render="italic">State v. John Button, George Button, and James Finley</emph>, Jan. 5, 1824, Box 1, folder 25.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">12</emph><emph render="italic">State v. Jonathan Palmer and Roxanna Bogue</emph>, Sep. 11, 1839, Box 2, folder 4.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">13</emph><emph render="italic">State v. William G. Huxford</emph>, Jan. 9, 1845, Box 2, folder 6.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">14</emph>Lord of East Haddam was a wealthy man. The inventory of his estate included hundreds of books and he owned 20,000 acres of land in Ohio<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">15</emph>Box 3, folder 27.<lb/></item>
<item><emph render="super">16</emph>Sale document, Oct 1, 1771, Box 3, folder 29.<lb/></item>
</list>

</scopecontent>

<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
	<head>Related Material</head>
	<p>None.</p>
</relatedmaterial>


<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->

<!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->

<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>

	<controlaccess>
		<head>Persons:</head>
			<persname encodinganalog="600" rules="dacs">Foote, Asa</persname>
			<persname encodinganalog="600" source="dacs">Foote, Joel</persname>
	</controlaccess>

	<controlaccess>
		<head>Families:</head>
			<persname encodinganalog="600" rules="dacs">Foote Family</persname>
	</controlaccess>


	<controlaccess>
		<head>Places:</head>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">Marlborough (Conn.) -- History -- Sources</geogname>
	</controlaccess>

	<controlaccess>
		<head>Occupations:</head>
			<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Clothiers</occupation>
			<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Justices of the peace -- Connecticut -- Marlborough</occupation>
			<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Merchants</occupation>
	</controlaccess>


	<controlaccess>
		<head>Document Types:</head>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Account books</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Daybooks</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Deeds</genreform>			
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Indentures</genreform>			
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Wills</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Writs</genreform>
 	</controlaccess>

</controlaccess>


<!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->

<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->


<accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
	<head>Restrictions on Access</head>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="http://libguides.ctstatelibrary.org/hg/using-archival-records" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Rules and Procedures for Researchers Using Archival Records and Secured Collections"/> policy. 
</p>
</accessrestrict>


<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
	<head>Restrictions on Use</head>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="https://ctstatelibrary.org/reproduction-publication/" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title=" Reproduction and Publications of State Library Collections"/> policy. 
</p>
</userestrict>

<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
	<head>Provenance</head>
	<p>The Foote Family Papers were donated to the Connecticut State Library in 2002.</p>

</acqinfo>



<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->


<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Container List</head>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 1. Justice of the Peace Records</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1781/1849">1781-1849</unitdate>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead> 
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-31</container>
	<unittitle>Justice of the Peace</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1781-1831</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-7</container>
	<unittitle>Justice of the Peace</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1832-1849</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">8-9</container>
	<unittitle>Justice of the Peace, record books</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1794-1811</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 2. Family Papers</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1728/1867">1728-1867</unitdate>
 </did>	
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">10</container>
	<unittitle>Account book</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1781</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<unittitle>Bills and receipts</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>Asa Foote</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1813-1818</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Joel Foote</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1816-1819</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">13</container>
	<unittitle>Edward Luther</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1749-1782, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">14</container>
	<unittitle>Sarah Miller</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1806-1832</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<unittitle>Business records</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">15-18</container>
	<unittitle>Bingham, Cyrus</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1814-1849</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">19-20</container>
	<unittitle>Johnson, H. A.</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1836</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Contracts</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1811</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">22-23</container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1783-1834, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">24-26</container>
	<unittitle>Deeds</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1750-1840</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<unittitle>Estate papers</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">27</container>
	<unittitle>Abigail Buel</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">28</container>
	<unittitle>Dan Bulkeley</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1806, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">29</container>
	<unittitle>Eleazer Carter</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1818-1839, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">30</container>
	<unittitle>Philip Caverly</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1778, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">31</container>
	<unittitle>Asa Foote</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1797-1811, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">32</container>
	<unittitle>Joel Foote</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1845-1848, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Dr. Royal Kingsbury</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1830-1840, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">2-17</container>
	<unittitle>Samuel P. Lord</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1793-1829</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">18-21</container>
	<unittitle>Sarah Miller</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1828-1834</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">22</container>
	<unittitle>Mary Owen</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1783-1785, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">23-24</container>
	<unittitle>Lawrence Powers</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1753-1776</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">25</container>
	<unittitle>Nathaniel Root</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1779</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">26</container>
	<unittitle>Genealogical papers</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">27</container>
	<unittitle>Indentures</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1787-1822</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">28</container>
	<unittitle>Marlborough Society papers</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1747-1808</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">29-31</container>
	<unittitle>Papers, miscellaneous</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1728-1845, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">32</container>
	<unittitle>Papers, Noah Bulkeley</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1819-1825</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<unittitle>Printed works</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">33</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Catalogue of Amherst Academy 1842</emph></unittitle>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">34</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">Annals of a Western Missionary</emph></unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1866-1867</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">35</container>
	<unittitle><emph render="italic">On Doing Good</emph></unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1856</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">36</container>
	<unittitle>Recipes</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<unittitle>School papers</unittitle>
 </did>	
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">37</container>
	<unittitle>Cyrus Bingham</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1806</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">1-2</container>
	<unittitle>Cyrus Bingham</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1806-1807</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">3-5</container>
	<unittitle>Edward Bingham</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1832-1840, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle>William Bingham</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1835, undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">7</container>
	<unittitle>Edwin Foote</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1814</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">8</container>
	<unittitle>Law school</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">9-10</container>
	<unittitle>Unidentified</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1830-1837</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>Wills: William Buell, Samuel Brown</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1805, 1822</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Writings: poetry</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>


</dsc>












<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->

</archdesc>
</ead>
