<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">

<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">


<eadid mainagencycode="US-ct" url="http://www.ctstatelibrary.org/RG074_003.html" countrycode="us">RG074_003</eadid>

<filedesc>
	<titlestmt>
		<titleproper>RG 074:003, David N. Gaines Genealogical Papers</titleproper>
		<subtitle>Inventory</subtitle>
		<author>Finding aid prepared by Damon M. Munz.</author>
	</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
	<publisher>Connecticut State Library</publisher>
	<date type="publication">June 16, 2008</date>

	<address><addressline>231 Capitol Avenue</addressline><addressline>Hartford, Connecticut, 06106-1537</addressline></address>
	<p>Copyright © <date>2009</date> by the Connecticut State Library</p>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>

<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by Damon M. Munz on
<date>June 16, 2008</date>
</creation>
<langusage><language></language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
	<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
	<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
		<corpname>Connecticut State Library</corpname>
		<address><addressline></addressline><addressline></addressline></address>
	</repository>

	<origination label="Creator:">
		<persname encodinganalog="100">Gaines, David N., 1854-1941</persname>
	</origination>

	<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">David N. Gaines genealogical papers</unittitle>

	<unitdate label="Dates:" datechar="creation" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1891/1940">1891-1940</unitdate>

	<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">3 cubic feet</physdesc>

	<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">David N. Gaines (1854-1941) served as the town clerk, judge of probate, postmaster, and secretary and treasurer of the First Ecclesiastical Society in Hartland. His genealogical papers consist of notes on old houses, vital statistics, East Hartland Cemetery and various Hartland families.</abstract>

	<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" 
		repositorycode="US-ct">RG074_003</unitid>
		<unitid label="Accession: ">1941-003</unitid>
	<langmaterial>The records are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.
	</langmaterial>
</did>


<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->
<bioghist altrender="biography" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
	<head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>
David Gaines was born in Hartland, Conn. in 1854 and lived there until his death in 1941. Gaines served the community in several capacities: postmaster for the east section (East Hartland) for over thirty-five years; town clerk; judge of probate; secretary and treasurer of the First Ecclesiastical Society for sixty years; and sexton of the East Hartland Cemetery for more that fifty years, being responsible for much of the rebuilding and beautification of the grounds. A lifelong Republican, Gaines served as a representative in the General Assembly in 1899 and in 1921.
</p>
<p>
While town clerk, Gaines became interested in land records and genealogies of the early settlers of Hartland. He also gathered data on the First Ecclesiastical Society, its earliest ministers and various changes made to the church building. He spent many years researching the connections of Hartland men who served in the Revolutionary War and other wars.
</p>
<p>
Gaines compiled a map in 1916 of all the homes still standing, as well as abandoned homes. He marked bridle paths and discontinued roads. This map along with the map compiled by Cornell Tiffany of West Hartland helped explain the land divisions and lots drawn up in the early 1700s and given to the early proprietors
</p>
<p>
Known as the "Sage of East Hartland", Gaines was considered a living legend in the town. A recording of his voice has been preserved as an outstanding example of typical New England speech.
</p>


<p>
<lb/><emph render="bold">Sources</emph>
</p>
<p>
Bartlett, Sally. "Residents Can Consult 'Gaines Notes'." <emph render="italic">Hartford Courant, </emph> 1976 August 27, 27C.
</p>
<p>
"David Gaines 'Seer,' Dies in Hartland." <emph render="italic">Hartford Courant, </emph>1941 September 27, 4.
</p>
<p>
"History and Map of Hartland Homes." <emph render="italic">Hartford Courant, </emph> 1917 February 13, 5.
</p>
<p>
"The Sage of East Hartland." <emph render="italic">Hartford Courant, </emph> 1941 September 28, A2.
</p>
<p>
"Sage of East Hartland." <emph render="italic">Hartford Courant, </emph>1940 January 28, SM3.
</p>
<p>
"The Sage of East Mountain." <emph render="italic">Hartford Courant, </emph>1932 January 31, E3.
</p>
</bioghist>


<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
	<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>
The bulk of the papers consist of photostatic copies of Gaines' notebooks. The house survey notes trace the ownership of Hartland area homes from 1749 to 1916. The container list indicates the names identified in the key to each "set" as provided by Gaines. Vital statistics notes include information on births, marriages and deaths in Hartland. Other notes cover the East Hartland Cemetery and a number of Hartland families. Also present is one of Gaines' original notebooks containing news clippings and vital statistics, along with a photostatic copy. Finally, name and address cards are arranged by town. Respondents were asked to indicated if they had any Hartland ancestors.
</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351$b" id="a5">
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>
Arranged into eight series as follows: House survey notes, Vital statistics notes, East Hartland Cemetery notes, Notes on families, Notebook, News clippings, Miscellaneous, and Name and address cards.
The majority of the notes are arranged by set: A-Z, AA-ZZ, AAA-DDD, followed by unlettered sets.
</p>
</arrangement>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
<head>Related Material</head>
<p>
Gaines, David N., compiler. Birth, marriage, death records, 1850-1933, taken from Hartland town records; Cemetery records from East Hartland Cemetery, 1770-1933; Genealogical notes of Bushnell, Gaines &amp; Tillotson Families, 1617-1927 [CSL call number StLib Archives 920 G12].
</p>
<p>
Gaines, David N., compiler. Hartland church records. Photostat of manuscript copy [CSL call number StLib Archives 974.62 fH261c J].
</p>
<p>
Gaines, David N., compiler. Key to East Hartland homesteads [CSL call number StLib Archives 974.62 J26:Eg K].
</p>
<p>
Gaines, David N., compiler. Key numbers to old house places in East Hartland [as per map drawn by C.H. Tiffany and D.N. Gaines] [CSL call number StLib Archives 974.62 H26:Eg KE].
</p>
<p>
Gaines, David H. and Correl H. Tiffany. Map of Hartland, both East Hartland and West Hartland, showing location of homesteads, mills, highways, etc. from earliest times to 1911. Photostat of original loaned by David N. Gaines [CSL call number StLib Archives 912.7462 H26t map case].
</p>
<p>
Record made by David N. Gaines to record his voice [CSL Call Number StLib Archives 920 G12].
</p>
<p>
Tiffany, Correll H., compiler. Key to West Hartland Homesteads [CSL call number 974.62 fH26:Wti K].
</p>
<p>
Tiffany, Correll H., compiler. West Hartland Homesteads, circa 1913-1914 [CSL call number 974.62 H26:Wti d].
</p>


</relatedmaterial>
<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->

<!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->


<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>


 <controlaccess>
 <head>Persons:</head>
			<persname encodinganalog="700" source="lcnaf">Gaines, David N., 1854-1941</persname>
	</controlaccess>

	<controlaccess>
		<head>Places:</head>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Hartland (Conn.) -- Genealogy</geogname>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Connecticut -- Genealogy</geogname>
	</controlaccess>


	<controlaccess>
		<head>Subjects:</head>

 			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Historic buildings -- Connecticut -- Hartland</subject> 
	</controlaccess>


	<controlaccess>
		<head>Document Types:</head>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">News clippings</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Notebooks</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Postal cards</genreform>
	</controlaccess>

</controlaccess>


<!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->

<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->

<accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
	<head>Restrictions on Access</head>

	<p>These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.</p>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="http://libguides.ctstatelibrary.org/hg/using-archival-records" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title="Rules and Procedures for Researchers Using Archival Records and Secured Collections"/> policy. 
</p>
</accessrestrict>


<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
	<head>Restrictions on Use</head>

<p>See the <extptr linktype="simple" href="https://ctstatelibrary.org/reproduction-publication/" show="replace" actuate="onrequest" title=" Reproduction and Publications of State Library Collections"/> policy. 
</p>

</userestrict>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
	<head>Provenance</head>
	<p>David Gaines' diary along with Barkhamsted Church record were received from David N. Gaines on May 14, 1941.</p>

</acqinfo>
<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->


<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Container List</head>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 1. House survey notes</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1910/1916">circa 1910-1916</unitdate>
	<physdesc><physfacet>negative photostat</physfacet></physdesc>
 </did>	
 <thead>
 <row>
 <entry>Box</entry>
 <entry>Folder</entry>
 </row>
 </thead>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Set A</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>1. Jonathan Bogue; 2. Abram Osborn; 21. Daniel Frazier; 25. John Andrus (Andrew); 24. Nehemiah Andrus (Andrew); 241. Abram Osborn cider mill; 23. Hezekiah Ackly; 22. Jonathan Couch.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Set B</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>Hartland Green 1. Joel Meacham, Henry Gates; Hartland Green 3. John Gates; Hartland Green 4. Burying ground; 73. First school house, stone school house; Hartland Green 5. William Chapman, Lewis Emmons, William L. Hayes; 128. Solomon Toby.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Set C</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>3. Miron Miller, Thomas Beeman; 3a. Thomas Beeman potash works; 4. Reuben Beeman; 7. Reuben Miller; 7a. Daniel Rathborn, Attenbury Smith blacksmith shop; 241. Abram Osborn cider mill distillery; 6. Stone school house.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Set D</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>All Hartland Green: 9. Parsonage, Nelson Scott; 10. Dr. Homer G. Bell; 11. Watson Gibbons; 14. Jared Newel, Benjamin Gidding; 13. Hotel now owned by George W. Carr, E.C. Emmons; 14a. Cooper shop; 15. Mary A. Hurlburt cottage.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Set E</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>11. Willis Wright; 10. Solomon E. Miller; 12. Silas Giddings; 9. Harry Miller; 8. Peter Holcomb; 14. John Atwood; 13. Ezra Miller; 15. Caleb Moses, House place on east side of road; 237. Private cemetery; 201. Ichabod Fuller; 214. Moosehorn Brook, 251. Willis Wright distillery, 80. Peter Holcomb old house, 252. Edwin Frazier cider mill, 10a. Stanley K. Dimock.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Set F</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>East Hartland Green 12. Meeting House; East Hartland Green 6. Uriel Holimes; East Hartland Green 7. Milo J. Giddings, David N. Gaines; East Hartland Green 8. M.E. Church; 9a. Eli Andrus (Andrew) ; X. Mrs. Leslie Dutton - F.C. Gould; Y. Flossie Vibbits; Z. F.C. Gould.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Set G</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>19. Orson Gates, Lester Cowdry (Cowdery); 17. Amos Seward; 16. Samuel Skinner; 5. Daniel Beman; 18. E.H. Miller; 16a. Cider mill; 15. Caleb Moses; 16. Unwin Gates; 15a. Martin Moses.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Set H</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>20. John Sweet; 26. Absalom Graham; 27. Deacon Thomas Giddings; 28. Aaron Cowles; 205. First saw mill Thomas Gidding; Hartland Green 16. William Smilly; Hartland Green 17. Harold Smith; Hartland Green 18. P. Kingsbury; 189. Jonathan Shipman; 19. Brewster Highway; 224. U. Holmes or T. Gidding saw mill; 205. U. Holmes or T. Gidding dam; 116. S. Beech, E. Palmer, U. Holmes.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle>Set I</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>29. Joseph Foote; 30-31. John Borden; 47. Jeffery O. Phelps; 45. Roswell Elmore; 46. Eliphalet Parker; 247. Charles Wright; 247a. Benjamin Parker; 45b. Ben Hoadley.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle>Set J</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>32. Benjamin Place; 248. East of Benjamin Place; No key west of Benjamin Place 45a; 33. Levi P. Case; 34. Henry Carmer; 35. A.B. Gaines spring house; No key number east of no. 33-34 in pasture; 2-- [not legible]. L.P. Case steam mill; 43. The old Jaris Case house; William Chapman no key no. 33a; Benjamin Parker no 247a; 75a. Joel Minor south of Enos Lane blacksmith shop; 43a. Hiram Bushman; 202. Tolson House; 248. Elisha Cowles; 45a. Joel Minor west of Benjamin Place)); 44. Strong Sanford.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle>Set K</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>48. Thomas Fuller, George D. Cornish; 49. John Giddings; 50. Edward Brockway; No key number 50a. Moses Brockway; No 48a. Joshua Giddings; XBD. bear den; 50a. Moses Brockway; 50b. Edward Brockway Jr.; Vol. 3-352. Survey of road north of Brockway.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle>Set L</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>52. Enos Lane Jr.; 53. Charles Kellogg; 54. West wood schoolhouse; 55. Jonathan Rathborn; 188. Adna Gillett; 56. Jonathan Herrick; 56a. Obediah Gildersleve, the survey of Brockway road; 57. Phineas Meacham; 55a. Old Taylor house; 51a. Moses Holcomb; A. old house place in Chase lot; B. Chase summer cottage.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">7</container>
	<unittitle>Set M</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>58. Dr. Emmons pest house; 59. Reuben B. Mowrey; 60. Samuel Banning; 61A, 61. Asahel Brainard; 64. William Selby; 63. Simeon Baxter; No key no. northeast 63a. Joseph and Mary Church; 60a. Charles Coombs; 61b. Porter.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">7</container>
	<unittitle>Set N</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>67. Alexander Bushnell; 263. Jonathan Bill, S.G. Bushnell; 140. Elihu Remmington; 139. David Banning; 265. Thomas Bushnell; 264. Charles Coe distillery; 141. Phineas Coe; 167a. Coplin Lake; 220. Bush Brook, Ichabod Grimes; 262. Samuel Banning.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">8</container>
	<unittitle>Set O</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>68, 70. Samuel Skinner; 62. Asa Haines, also blacksmith shop; 69. Brewer and Clement; 71. Rev. Starling Graves; 72. Town pound; 73. First schoolhouse; 65. Aaron Bush; 66. Charles Phelps; 133. Eperiam French; 245. B. Gidding sheep barn; Hartland Green 128. S. Toby, H.E. Bowers; 245a. Attenbury Smith blacksmith shop; 68a. William W. Clark barn.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">8</container>
	<unittitle>Set P</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>74. Asa Andrus, Joshua Giddings; 75. Phineas Perkins, Enos Lane, Myron Searles; 76. Benjamin Hutchens; 79. Rev. Aaron Church; 77. William Bowers; 75a. Joel Minor blacksmith shop; 78. Schoolhouse; X. Dutton cottage; Y. Vibbits cottage; Z. Gould cottage; 46 AB.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle>Set Q</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>81. Dr. Philander Humphrey; 80. Horace Emmons; 233. Humphrey store; 18a. A. Church.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle>Set R</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>89. Isaac Meacham; 88. Isaac Meacham log house; 84. Gideon Perkins; 85. Uriah Church; 88. Joseph Taylor, Isaac Meacham; 84a. Ranno Cossett; 82. Amos Perkins; 85a. Micah Scovell; 186. Timothy Brockway; 186. southwest of Welsh place on top of hill; 82a. Fred Crane; 88a. Roger Wadworth; B. Clemans mill; 84a. north side of Welsh lot; 84b. Waters house east of Welsh; 82. Phineas Perkins, Abel Moses.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">10</container>
	<unittitle>Set S</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>91. Jonathan Shipman, David Shipman; 90. Stephan Hosmer; 93. Benjamin Reed, William Roberts; 92. Pelatiah Daniels Jr.; 92a. Stephan Hosmer; 93a. Ambrose Cowdry Jr.; 93B. Timothy Gibbons, Asa Cowdry; 94. Hiram Gibbons; 95. William Seymour.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">10</container>
	<unittitle>Set T</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>102. Thomas Wadworth lot no. 26-221a; 102 Jaben Clark; 107. John Jones; 195. Charles Jones log house; 98-99. William Phillips, Benjamin Meacham; 256. Timothy Gibbons; 97. Micah Scovell; 100. Abijah Buttles; 216. Tom Gillett; 196. Dr. John Jones.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>Set U</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>11a. Lewis Emmons; 111. John Daniels; 96. Amherst Daniels; 112. Jaben Clark, Elmar Clark; 117. Ambrose Cowdry; 124. Jesse Gates, Benajah Bill; 127. Theophilus Gates; 126=125. Clay pits; 125a. schoolhouse; 125. Nathan Gates; 196. Dr. John Jones; 256. Timothy Gibbons; 116. Lester Jones distillery; 92a. Stephen Hosmer; 97a. Aaron Warner.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>Set V</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>122. John Church 2<emph render="super">nd</emph>; 122a. Jesse Gates; 86. Margret Card; 87. Uriah Church; 115. Alman Cowdry; 114. John F. Cowdry, Simeon Clark; 109. Reuben Daniels; 109a. Daniel Jones; 113. Schoolhouse; 110. Roderick Jones; 86a. Card's dam; 106. Hiram Jones; 216. Thomas Gillett.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Set W</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>123. Calvin Fuller, Silas Holcomb; 123a. Reubin Daniels; 122. John Church 2<emph render="super">nd</emph>; 121. Moses Cowdry Jr.; 118. Asa Cowdry; 116. Abijah Church; 120. Moses Cowdry Sr.; 119. James N. Cowdry.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">1</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Set X</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>132. Willis Clemans; 130. 3<emph render="super">rd</emph> schoolhouse; 131. 2<emph render="super">nd</emph> schoolhouse; 129. Eperiam Selby, O.C. Gates; 134. Aaron Gates; 191. Ira Goodsell; 136. Abner Banning distillery; 131a. Ebenezer Belden; 244. Town pound, O.C. Gates; 132. Asher French monument hill; 192. Asa Scranton.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Set Y</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>135. Abner Banning; 137. Daniel Bushnell; 142. Samuel Banning, J.D. Emmons; 146. Jonathan Bill; 147/147a. Jonathan Bill Jr., Daniel Bill; 143. Hutchens lot; 140a. William Bushnell; 139a. Daniel Bill; 149a. Jonathan Bill Jr.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Set Z</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>144. Adna Gillett; 145. Warren Emmons; 145a. Eperiam Wright; 150. Old house foot of Enoch hill; 165a. Alfred Cables; 165b. Samuel Miller; 166. Giles Lawton; 166a. Elijah Clark; 166b. Cobbs sawmill; 240a. Judson Spelman; A. Benoni Evins; 219ab. Spencer Loomis.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Set AA</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>165. Sawyer; 164a. John Hayes; 164. Judah Twining; 156. Titus Hayes; 157. Reuben Burnham; 200. Schoolhouse; 200a. Old schoolhouse; 26. Sawmill; C. Creamery ; 219. Stephen Hibbard.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Set BB</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>168. Cornwall Clark, T.T. Banning; 168a. Jonathan Couch; 169. Holcomb; 170. Richardson; 171. Asariah Stebbins; 219. David Couch, Phineas Perkins.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Set CC</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>172. Homer Fuller; No key no. John Kendall; 223. Capt. Oliver Bates; Charles Trankett; 182. Seth Roberts; 235. Hartland cemetery.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Set DD</unittitle>
 </did>
<scopecontent><p>174. Virgil Stebbins; 175. Town house; 176. Asa Smith; 177. Nathan Hatch; 59. Reuben Mowrey; 177a. Daniel Ensign; 259. Toll gate.</p></scopecontent>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Set EE</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>219. Abner Bushnell.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Set FF</unittitle>
 </did>	
<scopecontent><p>266. Holmes mill; 159. Richard Hayes = Luther Burham; 159a. Samuel Benjamin; 152. Elijah Clark = vis Coe; 158a. A. Smith cloth mill; A. Ely Andrus house; 1a. Edward Smith blacksmith shop; 2a. Burham distillery.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle>Set GG, Key numbers sent to State Library care of George S. Goddard; Key numbers to East Hartland part of map.</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle>Set HH, Survey of the division</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle>Set II, Survey by Bethuel Beman</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle>Set JJ, Untitled surveying notes</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">7-8</container>
	<unittitle>West Hartland houses compiled by Correll H. Tiffany</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">circa 1911</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle>Duplicates</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02></c01>

<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 2. Vital statistics notes</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1910/1915">circa 1910-1915</unitdate>
	<physdesc><physfacet>negative photostat</physfacet></physdesc>
 </did>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">10</container>
	<unittitle>Set KK, Vol. 1, Births-marriages-deaths from 1784-1867</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">10</container>
	<unittitle>Set LL, Vol. 2, Records of births in town of Hartland from 1852-1869</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>Set MM, Vol. 2, Deaths in town of Hartland from 1852-1869</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>Set NN, Vol. 2, Marriages in town of Hartland from 1852-1869, and to 1916</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Set OO, Births from 1869 in town of Hartland</unittitle>
 </did>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Set PP, Vol. 3, Records of deaths in Hartland from 1869-1915</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">13</container>
	<unittitle>Set QQ, Marriages in town of Hartland from 1869-1915</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">13</container>
	<unittitle>Set RR, Births-marriages-deaths, 1888-1899</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">13</container>
	<unittitle>Set SS, Deaths commencing January 1917</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">2</container>
	<container type="Folder">13</container>
	<unittitle>Set TT, Deaths and burials in Hartland from 1918 to</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 3. East Hartland Cemetery notes</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
	<physdesc><physfacet>negative photostat</physfacet></physdesc>
 </did>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Set UU, East of gate</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1920 May 10</unitdate>
	<origination label="Creator: ">O.P. Cowdery</origination>
 </did>
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Set VV, West of gate</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1920 May 11</unitdate>
	<origination label="Creator: ">O.P. Cowdery</origination>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 4. Notes on families</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1910/1920">circa 1910-1920</unitdate>
	<physdesc><physfacet>negative photostat</physfacet></physdesc>
 </did>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Set WW, Nehemiah Andrus</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Set XX, Capt. Alexander Bushnell family</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Set YY, George Coltan</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Set ZZ, Giddings family, what part is connected to Hartland Conn from 1754 to 1900 by Minot S. Giddins</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Set AAA, McCloud; Roger Veites record; Osborn; Bogue; Frazier; Miner; Rowe</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Set BBB, Joel Tiffany and Hannah Wilder; Rufus French; Daniel Huxford; Benjamin H. Banning children-g-children copy from family bible</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">1920</unitdate>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Set CCC, Wilder families</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Set DDD, Untitled</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle>Duplicates of lettered sets</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">6</container>
	<unittitle>Richard Hayes, Micah Scovell, William Roberts, Benjamin Reed; Coult family, Eli Strong, David Gidding, Capt. Jaben Clark, Rev. Aaron Church, Rowland Stebbins; Lieut. John Andrews</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">7</container>
	<unittitle>Bushnell; Samuel Banning, Phineas Coe; Dr. Dennis, James Carnick</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">8</container>
	<unittitle>Edwin P. Jones family, Obed Crosby; Northway and Gaines; Granville Mass. earlier settlers</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">9</container>
	<unittitle>Jonathan Shipman, Hezekiah Ackley, Strong, David Kellogg; Votes from Hartland town book; Johnson, Pyam Baillett, John Coreys, Aaron Cook</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">10</container>
	<unittitle>William Cowdery, Henry A. Brown; Loomis, Mead, Seward, Gates, Samuel Twining; Review of Beman - Ackley evidence</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">3</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>Grand Jury complaints and court Hartland, Dr. O.W. Kellogg, Joseph Carrier, Dr. Jeremiah Emmons, Hezekiah Ackley; Parts of letters received from different persons, T.A. Bushnell, Ruben Hale, Joseph Dewolf, Peter Gibbons, Horace Roberts, Daniel King; William Beman, Stephen Gates, William Shipman, William Baillett</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Genealogy and biography of the first settlers of Hartford; Divisions of the town of Hartford about 1640, no. 2</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Genealogy and biography of the first settlers of Harford, no. 3; Genealogy and biography of the first settlers of Harford, no. 4</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">3</container>
	<unittitle>Dr. Jeremiah Emmons children, Thomas Burham, Litchfield county Emmons, Beman Gates, Thomas Emmons; Granville, Samuel Blakeslee</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">4</container>
	<unittitle>Miscellaneous and duplicates</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 5. Notebook</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="circa 1891/1917">circa 1891-1917</unitdate>
 </did>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">5</container>
	<unittitle>Notebook with news clippings and vital statistics</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder">6-10</container>
	<unittitle>Copy of notebook</unittitle>
	<physdesc><physfacet>negative photostat</physfacet></physdesc>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 6. News clippings</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1925/1939">1925-1939</unitdate>
 </did>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">11</container>
	<unittitle>News clippings</unittitle>
 </did>	
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 7. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1906/1940">1906, 1937-1940, undated</unitdate>
 </did>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder">12</container>
	<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
 </did>	
	<scopecontent><p>Includes the East Hartland Cemetery Association, Inc. treasurer's report, 1938.</p></scopecontent>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
 <did>
	<unittitle>Series 8. Name and address cards</unittitle>
	<unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate>
 </did>
<c02 level="item">
 <did>
	<container type="Box">6</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Name and address cards</unittitle>
 </did>
<arrangement><p>Arranged by alphabetically by town. States other than Connecticut are at the end.</p></arrangement>
<note><p>Question on cards ask if the respondent has any Hartland ancestors.</p></note>	
</c02>
</c01>		
</dsc>
<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->

</archdesc>
</ead>
