<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="https://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860134674">1969.0004</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">President's Office Records (UConn)</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the University of Connecticut, President's Office Records <num>1969.0004</num></titleproper><author>Archives &amp; Special Collections staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library</publisher><p><date>2005 July</date></p><address><addressline>University of Connecticut Library</addressline><addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline><addressline>Storrs, Connecticut 06269-1205</addressline><addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://lib.uconn.edu/libraries/asc/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://lib.uconn.edu/libraries/asc/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-07-23 08:45:45 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 October</date><item>Revised for consistency.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>University of Connecticut, President's Office Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>1969.0004</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">333.25 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1881/1881">undated, 1881-</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ebd605a31fceca850af2c531760ccb50">Records of the chief administrative officer of the University of Connecticut and its predecessor institutions. The records are subdivided by administration and identified and described by the name/tenure of the individual serving as president.  In more recent years, the records are identified by date of transfer.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_10318dac0b50422f929ac79f2444e033">
    <head>History</head>
<p>In April 1881, the Connecticut General Assembly established the Storrs Agricultural School after accepting a gift of 170 acres of land, several frame buildings, and money from Charles and Augustus Storrs. The School opened on 28 September 1881, with twelve students in the first class. Before the turn of the century there were two name changes (Storrs Agricultural College 1893, Connecticut Agricultural College 1899). In 1933, two years after the institution celebrated its fiftieth anniversary, it became Connecticut State College, a name more in keeping with its steady advances and broadened mission. Six years later, in 1939, the General Assembly designated the institution the University of Connecticut, an acknowledgment of the institution's developing importance to the State in graduate and professional education, research and public service.</p><p>The University of Connecticut is recognized as the state's flagship institution of higher learning. Since its establishment, the University has grown to include 13 Schools and Colleges at its main campus in Storrs, separate Schools of Law and Social Work in Hartford, four regional campuses throughout the state and Schools of Medicine and Dentistry at the UConn Health Center in Farmington.</p><p>UConn is a Land Grant and Sea Grant College and a Space Grant Consortium institution. The University spans 4,104 acres at its main campus and four regional campuses, and an additional 162 acres at the UConn Health Center in Farmington.</p><p>Designated a Carnegie Foundation Research University-Extensive, UConn has more than 70 focused research centers where faculty, graduate students and undergraduates explore everything from improving human health to enhancing public education and protecting the country's natural resources.</p><p>The office of the President was established in 1893 when the state of Connecticut established Storrs Agricultural College as Connecticut's land-grant institution of higher education. At that time the title of its chief administrative officer, Benjamin F. Koons, was changed from Principal of the former Storrs Agricultural School to President of the new college.</p><p>In the early days of Storrs and, from 1899, Connecticut Agricultural College, the President, aided by a few faculty committees, attended to virtually every detail of the administration of the college. At the time of the appointment of President Charles Lewis Beach in 1908, the Laws and By-laws of the College specified that the President, subject to the direction of the trustees, had "the immediate direction of all departments, and direction of all matters pertaining to the welfare of the college," including the appointment and dismissal of staff members and the designation of their duties. They also provided for his participation in all meetings of the Board of Trustees. As the College expanded its enrollment and its programs, an increasing amount of the President's responsibilities were delegated to other administrative officers. The 1921 catalog states that, under the supervision of the President, "the three branches of the administration are managed by the Faculty, the Director of the Experiment Station and the Director of the Extension Service." During President Beach's administration in 1921-1922, the College was divided into five academic divisions, each headed by a dean. The establishment of the office of the Dean of Women in 1928, Dean of Men in 1929, and Director of the Division of Resident Instruction, which later became Dean of the University, in 1931, were other important steps in the evolution of the Office of the President, as each more clearly defined the duties of the college's chief administrator. By the time Charles C. McCracken assumed the office in 1930, the President was concerned mainly with long-range policy-making, major campus issues, high-level appointments, and relations with the state and federal governments. The latter became more important during President Albert N. Jorgensen's tenure, when the various programs of the New Deal made many new kinds of federal funding available to land-grant colleges and universities.</p><p>When Connecticut State College became the University of Connecticut in 1939, the new laws and By-laws stated that, "the President of the University is the executive and administrative officer of the Board [of Trustees]. In this capacity he is responsible for the operations of the University and is given authority requisite to that end." This is the mandate under which President Jorgensen worked throughout his long service as President of the University. The President was also designated as "chairman of the University Senate and of the several schools and colleges." "The administrative reorganization authorized by President Jorgensen for the University in 1939 placed direct responsibility for the schools and colleges. President Jorgensen was thus able to devote all his energies chiefly to the fulfillment of his plans for the overall development of the University.</p><p>The names and terms of the Presidents of the University can be found <extref xlink:href="http://president.uconn.edu/home/history/">here.</extref>.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_aeb2fa148fa06ea606e4281b69b321a4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p><emph render="bold">Series I: Solomon Mead</emph> (1881-1882) contains a copy of the course of study for 1882.</p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860119953">Series I: Solomon Mead</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series II: Benjamin Franklin Koons</emph> (1885-1898) contains photocopies of newspaper clippings, correspondence, articles concerning the school and a copy of a report. </p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860120251">Series II: Benjamin F. Koons</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series III: George Washington Flint</emph> (1900) contains newspaper clippings highlighting the controversies of Flint's tenure (1898-1901).</p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860119954">Series III: George W. Flint</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series IV: Rufus Whitaker Stimson</emph> (undated, 1899-1908) includes correspondence, publications, programs, an article written by Stimson and newspaper clippings. </p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127636">Series IV: Rufus W. Stimson</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series V: Edwin Oscar Smith</emph> (1956-1958) served as acting President from April - September of 1908. The series includes one folder of correspondence between Smith and Mrs. Katharine Lusk regarding the dual job amendment.</p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860115769"></extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series VI: Charles Lewis Beach</emph> (undated, 1906-1929) contains correspondence, reports, studies and administrative records documenting the influence of Mr. Beach (1908-1928) while President of Connecticut Agricultural College.</p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860133449">Series VI: Charles L. Beach</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series VII: Charles Burt Gentry</emph> (undated, 1928-1969) consist of the general correspondence of the President of the College. It is the only extant collection of the papers of the president for this period. The correspondence is concerned with internal administrative matters, major policy issues at the college, with the college's relations with state and federal governments, and with other educational agencies and institutions. Also included is a collection of correspondence presented to Mr. Gentry on the event of his retirement from the University and a small folder of correspondence with the Gentry family pertaining to the naming of the Gentry Building. </p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860124532">Series VII: Charles B. Gentry</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series VIII: George Alan Works</emph> (undated, 1926-1930) The records consist of the general correspondence of the President of the College. The correspondence is concerned with internal administrative matters, major policy issues at the college, with the college's relations with state and federal governments, and with other educational agencies and institutions. </p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127984">Series VIII: George A. Works</extref> </p><p><emph render="bold">Series IX: Charles Chester McCracken</emph> (undated, 1926-1935) contains incoming and copies of outgoing correspondence documenting the activities of the administration and interests of the President of the institution. Materials pre-dating McCracken's tenure can be found in multiple folders, particularly in the 1930-1931 section, and have been noted in brackets in the folder listing.</p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002860123325">Series IX: Charles C. McCracken</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series X: Albert Nels Jorgensen</emph> (1935-1962) includes general correspondence from 1935 to 1962. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by topic within each academic year in one series. Because some of the Jorgensen papers were apparently inadvertently destroyed before they reached the University Archives, there is correspondence missing for the years 1942-1943, 1943-1944, 1945-1946, 1946-1947, and 1951-1952.</p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127983">Series X: Albert N. Jorgensen</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series XI: Homer Daniels Babbidge, Jr.</emph> (1962-1972) documents his tenure as President of the University of Connecticut from 1962 through 1972. Included in the collection is correspondence, reports, minutes, memoranda, newspaper clippings, reports and publications, as well as materials documenting campus unrest and the files of his assistant, Wallace Moreland.</p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127952">Series XI: Homer D. Babbidge, Jr.</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series XII: Edward Victor Gant</emph> (1969 July - October; 1972-1973; 1978-1979) </p><p><emph render="bold">Series XIII: Glenn Walker Ferguson</emph> (undated, 1915-2005) documents his tenure as President of the University of Connecticut from 1973 through 1983. Included in the collection is correspondence, reports, minutes, memoranda, newspaper clippings, reports and publications, as well as materials documenting campus and state fiscal issues and the files of his assistant, Paul Capra and subsequent interim President Edward V. Gant. Also included are personal documents, correspondence, photographs, diaries, and emphemera from Ferguson's childhood through his careers as a diplomat, administrator of the Peace Corps/VISTA, academic administrator, and head of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty and Lincoln Center. </p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127871">Series XIII: Glenn W. Ferguson</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series XIV: John A. DiBiaggio</emph> (undated, 1952-1986) documents his tenure as President of the University of Connecticut from 1979 through 1985. Included in the collection is correspondence, reports, minutes, memoranda, newspaper clippings, reports and publications. </p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860133784">Series XIV: John A. DiBiaggio</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series XVI: Harry J. Hartley</emph> (undated, 1990-2000) collection contains the transcript of an interview between Dr. Hartley and Dr. Bruce Stave of the Center for Oral History and published materials documenting Dr. Hartley's activities while serving as the President of the University of Connecticut. </p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860123276">Series XVI: Harry J. Hartley</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series XVII: John T. Casteen</emph> (undated, 1981-1990) The records in this collection are the files of the President's office during John T. Casteen's administration from 1985-1990. The documents include correspondence, reports, financial and administrative records, as well as materials pertaining to his inauguration and plaques and mementos accumulated during his tenure as president.</p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127829">Series XVI: John T. Casteen, III</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series XVIII: Philip E. Austin</emph> (1996-2007) </p><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860115458">Series XVIII: Philip E. Austin</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Series XIX: Michael J. Hogan</emph> (<date>2007-2010</date>) </p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_09fa13fe10d214f076c857d96d0f8e3f">
    <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_54d2c3a99aa6f3566be06472fe03860f">
    <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
<p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6c90a922ea4b0b4059cc9c259a3aadcd">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item description, #:#], University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [President's Name]. Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_eb42b16685e16730eb9fcb6ab9411e00">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The records are periodically transferred to Archives &amp; Special Collections by the University President's Office for permanent retention.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/867876" source="fast">College presidents</subject>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027200" source="aat">Notes</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027433" source="aat">bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027457" source="aat">Resolutions (administrative records)</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300026877" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <geogname authfilenumber="7007159" source="tgn">Connecticut (state)</geogname>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300111999" source="aat">Publications (documents)</genreform>
    <subject authfilenumber="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh85061212" source="lcsh">History</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/903005" source="fast">Education, Higher</subject>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300264354" source="aat">Notebooks</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027425" source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300026437" source="aat">Press releases</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300046300" source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027440" source="aat">Minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027473" source="aat">Financial Records</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300136847" source="aat">Photocopies</genreform>
    <corpname authfilenumber="https://lccn.loc.gov/n79056688" rules="dacs" source="naf">University of Connecticut</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">University of Connecticut. President's Office</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref11_7xy" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Solomon Mead</unittitle><unitdate normal="1882/1882">1882</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref12_dee" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860119953">Solomon Mead</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref13_63b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Benjamin F. Koons</unittitle><unitdate normal="1885/1898" type="inclusive">1885-1898</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref14_adi" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860120251">Benjamin F. Koons</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref15_s1o" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: George W. Flint</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1900">1900</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref16_k1c" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860119954">George W. Flint</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref17_32f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Rufus W. Stimson</unittitle><unitdate normal="1899/1908" type="inclusive">undated, 1899-1908</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref18_x7x" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hydl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127636">Rufus W. Stimson</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref19_rro" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V: Edwin O. Smith</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956/1958" type="inclusive">1956-1958</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref20_yt7" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:86011769">Edwin O. Smith</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref21_brl" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI: Charles L. Beach</unittitle><unitdate normal="1906/1929" type="inclusive">undated, 1906-1929</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref22_e6t" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860133449">Charles L. Beach</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref23_fyd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VII: Charles B. Gentry</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928/1969" type="inclusive">undated, 1928-1969</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref24_a7f" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860124532">Charles B. Gentry</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref25_2lk" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VIII: George A. Works</unittitle><unitdate normal="1926/1930" type="inclusive">undated, 1926-1930</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref26_ccg" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127984">George A. Works</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref27_6f4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IX: Charles C. McCracken</unittitle><unitdate normal="1926/1935" type="inclusive">undated, 1926-1935</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref28_hf4" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860123325">Charles C. McCracken</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref29_4df" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series X: Albert Nels Jorgensen</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1962" type="inclusive">1935-1962</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref30_15b" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127983">Albert N. Jorgensen</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref31_cmz" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XI: Homer D. Babbidge, Jr.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962/1972" type="inclusive">undated, 1962-1972</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref32_qtw" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127952">Homer D. Babbidge, Jr.</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref33_c93" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIII: Glenn W. Ferguson</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1983" type="inclusive">undated, 1973-1983</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref34_jew" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127871">Glenn W. Ferguson</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref35_v38" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIV: John A. DiBiaggio</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1986" type="inclusive">undated, 1952-1986</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref36_0nn" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860133784">John DiBiaggio</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref37_f7v" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVI: Harry J. Hartley</unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/2000" type="inclusive">undated, 1990-2000</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref38_i0z" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860123276">Harry J. Hartley</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref39_s4a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVII: John T. Casteen, III</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1990" type="inclusive">undated, 1981-1990</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref40_hjn" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127829">John T. Casteen, III</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref69_ieh" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVIII: Philip E. Austin</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997/2007" type="inclusive">1997-2007</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref70_fry" level="file"><did><unittitle><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860115458" xlink:show="new">Philip E. Austin</extref></unittitle></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref71_bcn" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIX: Michael Hogan</unittitle><unitdate normal="2007/2010" type="inclusive">2007-2010</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_ref53_b8t" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XXI: 2009 Transfers,</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref59_hip" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_9aec5fc2fa589edcbb5027814aca1443" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_4c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_51579ca4834971d728d0ab90e9ec6256" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref61_6qm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_1a2860e07a96f5b4a6c32b07549a2363" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref62_kh1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_b9f3300904fa36cb76314877b17d2f4e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63_z7i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_232060be62fc43c5e6d6e2a28fbf5196" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64_o1z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_0db1ad56b87b7e77846e803bb0d5feea" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref65_ty8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_140b6be7d89c5d24738ba54e0d375add" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref66_yk1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_0d96c532900efa6ddfceeb68f6a010f8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref67_5m3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_a3d0e40cd744e87e175914d869b0883c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref68_84y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><container id="aspace_a8902818d2c71cbb2878f7e241586849" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2009_14</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref51_d4c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XXII: 2012 Transfers,</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref52_rcd" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-Z,</unittitle><unitdate normal="2008/2008" type="inclusive">2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_2da8b70f0393e3311a59101591a4556c" label="Text" type="box">2012_4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref73_5md" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sweatshop Labor notebooks,</unittitle><unitdate normal="2006/2006" type="inclusive">2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac75c9dc464aeb58a6dc1a4a9b086662" label="Text" type="box">2012_1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref74_9q9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sweatship Labor files,</unittitle><unitdate normal="2006/2006" type="inclusive">2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2b4dd13ce1a8264f5a40d1eddb920a3" label="Text" type="box">2012_2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref75_lep" level="file"><did><unittitle>Committee on Corporate Social Responsibility (formerly Sweatshop Labor),</unittitle><unitdate normal="2006/2009" type="inclusive">2006-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc9e8266bf77068806883a791721d7d6" label="Text" type="box">2012_3</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref76_dkt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XXIII: 2013 Transfers</unittitle><unitdate normal="2007/2010" type="inclusive">2007-2010</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref82_p6h" level="file"><did><unittitle>A - N,</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2010" type="inclusive">2009-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_99d20f7b626178c03a91445e97cb096e" label="Text" type="box">2013_1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_92951d2e73618cc7a10b1934fa27ba2a"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>BOX 2013-1 (Files from 2009-2010)					
Title	Color	Years			
A	black	2009			
A	yellow	2010			
ACE	yellow	2009-10			
Administrative Services, Dept of	blue	2009			
Affirmative Action Plan	red	2009-10			
Agriculture	red	2009-10			
Alcohol/Drugs	red	2009			
Alumni Assoc	red	2009-10			
Animal Care	red	2010			
Asian American Cultural Center	red	2009			
Asian American Studies	red	2009			
Athletics	red	2009-10			
Athletics-Basketball	red	2009-10			
Athletics-Big East	red	2010			
Athletics-Football	red	2009-10			
Athletics:NCAA	red	2009-10			
Athletics:NCAA Graduation Rates	red	2009-10			
Attorney	red	2009-10			
Attorney General	blue	2009-10			
Auditors	blue	2009-10			
Audit, Compliance &amp; Ethics	red	2009-10			
Awards	red	2009-10			
B	black	2009-10			
B 	purple	2009			
Biology	red	2009			
Board of Trustees	red	2009-10			
Branding	red	2009			
Budget-Biennial	red	2010			
Business, School of	red	2009-10			
C	black	2009-10			
C	red	2009-10			
C	yellow	2009-10			
C	purple	2009			
Campus Safety	red	2009			
CBIA	black	2009			
Centers and Institutes	red	2009-10			
Chemistry	red	2009			
Chief Financial Officer, VP and	red	2009-10			
Chief Operations Officer, VP and	red	2009-10			
Commencement	red	2009-10			
Communication Sciences, Dept of	red	2009			
Congressional/ Senate Inquiries	green	2009-10			
Congress: Washington Trips	green	2009			
CT Academy of Science and Engineering	yellow	2009			
Convocation	red	2009-10			
CT State University	blue	2009-10			
Correspondence	red	2009-10			
D	red	2010			
Dental Medicine	red	2009-10			
DHE	blue	2009-10			
DHE: ConnCAP	blue	2009-10			
DHE: ConnCAS	blue	2009-10			
Diversity &amp; Equity, Office of	red	2009			
Dodd Archives &amp; Research Center	red	2009			
Economics, Dept of	red	2009			
Education, Dept of 	green	2009-10			
Education, Neag School of	red	2009-10			
Engineering, School of 	red	2009-10			
English, Dept of	red	2009-10			
Enrollment Management	red	2009-10			
Environmental Policy/ Issues	red	2009-10			
Environmental Sciences &amp; Engineering, Center for	red	2009			
Facilities	red	2009			
Finance, Revenue, Bonding	blue	2009			
Fine Arts	red	2009-10			
Fine Arts: Drama	red	2009			
Fraternities and Sororities	red	2009			
General Assembly	blue	2009			
Governmental Relations	red	2009-10			
Governor's Office	blue	2009-10			
H	purple	2009-10			
H 	yellow	2009-10			
Hartford Hospital	black	2010			
History, Dept of	red	2009-10			
Homeland Security	green	2009			
Honors Program	red	2009			
Human Development &amp; Family Studies	red	2009			
Human Resources	red	2009-10			
Human Rights Institute	red	2009			
I	green	2009			
I	yellow	2009			
IACUC	red	2009-10			
Information Technology, Dept of	blue	2009			
Information Technology Services	red	2010			
Institute for Materials Science	red	2009			
Institutional Advancement	red	2009-10			
International Programs	red	2009-10			
Jewish Matters (General)	red	2009			
L	black	2010			
Law School	red	2009-10			
Legislative Inquiries (alpha)	blue	2009-10			
Legislative Internship Program	red	2009-10			
Legislative Program Review	blue	2009			
Legislative Thank Yous	blue	2009			
Legislative--Misc.	blue	2009-10			
Liberal Arts &amp; Sciences, College of	red	2009			
Library, Homer Babbidge	red	2009-10			
M	black	2009-10			
M	purple	2009			
Mansfield, Town of	red	2009-10			
Math Dept	red	2009			
Medicine, School of	red	2009			
Metro Hartford Alliance	black	2009-10			
Minority, Center for Academic Programs	red	2009			
Modern and Classical Languages	red	2009			
Molecular &amp; Cell Biology	red	2009			
Museum of Art, Benton	red	2009-10			
Music, Dept of	red	2009-10			
N	yellow	2009-10			
NEASC	yellow	2009-10			
NEBHE	yellow	2009			
New England Council	yellow	2009-10			
NSF	green	2009-10			
Nursing, Scool of	red	2009-10</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref77_srj" level="file"><did><unittitle>O - Z, Archival files</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2010" type="inclusive">2009-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_b52190096a894c278688be7512eb79f9" label="Text" type="box">2013_2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9273e10a76739a42d09d4e4793a15410"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>O	yellow	2009
OPM	blue	2009-10
Outreach	red	2009-10
P	yellow	2009
Parking	red	2009
Pharmacy	red	2009
Physics	red	2009
Political Science	red	2010
Provost	red	2009-10
Public Health, Dept of	blue	2009
Public Safety, Dept of	blue	2009
Public Safety, Division of	red	2009-10
Purchasing	red	2009-10
Regional Campuses	red	2009-10
Research Issues	red	2010
Scholarships--Misc	red	2009-10
Senate	red	2009
Social Work, School of	red	2009
Sponsored Programs, Office of	red	2009-10
Stem Cell	red	2009-10
Student Affairs and Services	red	2009-10
Student Affairs and Services: Food	red	2009-10
Student Organizations: ConnPIRG	red	2009
Student Organizations: Daily Campus	red	2009
Student Organizations: SUBOG	red	2009-10
Sympathy	red	2009
T	blue	2009
Tuition/Fees	red	2009-10
U	black	2009-10
University Relations	red	2009
Urban League of Greater Hartford	black	2009
USG	red	2009
University Communications	red	2009
Veterans Affairs	blue	2010
W	black	2010
W	blue	2009
W	yellow	2009</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref84_evl" level="series"><did><unittitle>2014 Transfer</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1970" type="inclusive">1934-1970</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref85_2zj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Administrative Records, Correspondence, Financial Records, Notes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1970" type="inclusive">1934-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_73fb25e8691ebeac7b6dee2848df8ef2" label="Text" type="box">2014-0149_1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ff5ee9f8e8dfb291dab9409bb680ff1b"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>President's Comm. on Equal Employment Opportunity, Student organizations, research corporation, refund of fees.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref87_al5" level="series"><did><unittitle>2015 Transfer</unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/2009" type="inclusive">1993-2009</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref88_gqm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Administrative records, Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/2009" type="inclusive">1993-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed32ad9276a0bfd004e430e2b60d80f8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2015-0046_1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5aad8a06b10a73b92712bd4525b70960"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Administrative records including:</p><p>UCONN Institution-Wide Administrative Assessment Final Report, February 1, 1999
Various BOT Committee meeting materials
     Correspondence
     Review of audit, June 25th, 2003
     Audit subcommmitte meeting documents
     Committee on Instutional advancement
     Student Life committee documents
UCONN Health Center review committee
Health Affairs Committee meeting minutes September 30, 2000, March 30, 2001
Helath Affairs Committee, Fiscal year 1, Cost Improvement Opportunity Register</p></scopecontent></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
