<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="https://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860134069">1983.0006</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Lamson (George H.) Collection    </titleproper><titleproper>George H. Lamson, Jr. Collection <num>1983.0006</num></titleproper><author>Archives &amp; Special Collections staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library</publisher><p><date>2004 February</date></p><address><addressline>University of Connecticut Library</addressline><addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline><addressline>Storrs, Connecticut 06269-1205</addressline><addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://lib.uconn.edu/libraries/asc/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://lib.uconn.edu/libraries/asc/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-07-25 12:23:33 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2018 April</date><item>Revised for consistency.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>George H. Lamson, Jr. Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>1983.0006</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate certainty="approximate" normal="1920/1935" type="inclusive">circa 1920-1935</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3d4c10dd37700bbe179a25e8038e07c2">Mr. George H. Lamson, Jr. was a faculty member at Connecticut Agricultural College for over twenty-five years. Professor of Zoology and Entomology, Lamson became the Dean of the Division of Arts and Sciences until his death in 1931. He is best known for his research on parasitic insects.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6e40b7dc4b39bbc691321626c0311063">
    <head>Biography</head>
<p>George Herbert Lamson, Jr. was born in Malden, Massachusetts, on 8 April 1882. He was the son of George Herbert and Sarah (Liscombe) Lamson. He received a Bachelors degree in Agriculture from Connecticut Agricultural Colleg in 1902. The following year he earned a Bachelor of Science degree at Massachusetts Agricultural College. He went on to receive a Masters of Science at Yale University in 1905. Mr. Lamson married Miss Kate Arroll of Bridgeport, Connecticut, on 27 July 1909. The couple had one child, a son, Arroll born in 1912. In 1906, Mr. Lamson became a faculty member at Connecticut Agricultural College and would spend the next quarter century there as a professor of Zoology and Entomology, eventually rising to the position of Dean of the Division of Arts and Sciences. </p><p>His contributions to science were impressive, having resulted from his work as a Zoologist for the Storrs Experiment Station. The detailed records of his discoveries are written in the Station's <title render="italic">Bulletins</title>. Included in his many notable contributions to science, was his part in World War I as an Entomologist, working with the National Research Council on the control of parasitic insects and the soldiers inflicted with them. He did extensive work on the fumigation of soldiers clothing against those parasites such as body lice. Mr. Lamson was chosen as the scientist to write the American work on Incubation for the Hague International Conference, in 1921. His work went far beyond mere academic value. Great economic value was attributed to his research on the life cycle and methods of control of parasitic diseases in the cattle, sheep and poultry industries. Professor Lamson was also well known for his investigation in to the incubation and preservation of eggs. Before his untimely death from heart failure in December of 1931, Lamson was working on a study of snakes native to the Connecticut region in hopes of publishing his findings on the misconceptions that existed about the reptile family. </p><p>On a more personal note, he was known as a true family man of deep religious faith. He was an active member of the Storrs Methodist Church, and an ardent supporter of righteousness and virtue. He was known for his happy philosophy of life and worked to enrich the lives of others, whether they were his students, colleagues, or friends. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ecf4b17b7307f0b1cdd240f8318a2822">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>This collection contains the correspondence, both professional and personal of Professor George H. Lamson, Jr. Included are letters of condolence pertaining to his death, primarily from professional associates. Only two of these letters were addressed to his widow. There are newspaper articles briefly covering his most memorable scientific achievements and his career at Connecticut Agricultural College>. Brief references to his family life and an album of photographs of Lamson, his family and colleagues is also included. Two small books written by him have been separated from the collection and cataloged.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_93c45cb3af3d9158f24b4a6a0efe22b4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Collection has been arranged in one alphabetic series containing three folders. The contents of the folders are topical in nature.</p>  </arrangement>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_db79a5fe349daf09ff8a6bdeb7984465">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p><title render="italic">Book of Views. Connecticut Agricultural College.</title> Dodd XA I.10 # 89</p><p><title render="italic">The Reptiles of Connecticut.</title> Dodd WQH 7</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e1f1e1776683316737b868c0760e15cb">
    <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
<p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_adcb8706166811aba34e923e5fc0e02e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item description, #:#], George H. Lamson, Jr. Collection. Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3688a65b38699e1e82341dd86f38727c">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The Collection was donated by Mr. Lamson's son and daughter-in-law, Arroll and Marguerite Lamson, in August 1995.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7bf80a9063e753b752c14e972f2d63cf">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300026656" source="aat">Newspapers</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300046300" source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300136847" source="aat">Photocopies</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300026877" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300111999" source="aat">Publications (documents)</genreform>
    <persname role="cre" rules="dacs" source="local">Lamson, Marguerite</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref12_1hk" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Collection</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" normal="1920/1935" type="inclusive">circa 1920-1935</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref13_da4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Biographical information</unittitle><unitdate normal="1922/1931" type="inclusive">undated, 1922-1923, 1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c66cd80f8bb07df60e04085c5bca576" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d6433ae50b837a34556ecc507ff484a5" parent="aspace_5c66cd80f8bb07df60e04085c5bca576" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14_0as" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1931/1935" type="inclusive">1931, 1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0f3e35270f7fc7cece1e8fb79d8d104" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_48398f9655beb5f43443f65fbcd45359" parent="aspace_c0f3e35270f7fc7cece1e8fb79d8d104" type="folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15_dse" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence--Condolences</unittitle><unitdate normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_d072501fbe58c8a1b64931192515ecc2" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4f2a7db77c671df3c382aee17444a77e" parent="aspace_d072501fbe58c8a1b64931192515ecc2" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16_093" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photograph album</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" normal="1920/1930" type="inclusive">circa 1920 - circa 1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e0bb0a2c42366d87244a0cd6c0610b8" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
