<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860129773">1997.0101</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>A Guide to the Connecticut Soldiers Collection <num>1997.0101</num></titleproper><author>Archives &amp; Special Collections staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library</publisher><p><date>2002 January, revised regularly</date></p><address><addressline>University of Connecticut Library</addressline><addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline><addressline>Storrs, Connecticut 06269-1205</addressline><addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://lib.uconn.edu/libraries/asc/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://lib.uconn.edu/libraries/asc/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-10-31 15:49:09 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>October 2017</date><item>updated for consistency and inclusion of new content</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Connecticut Soldiers Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">University of Connecticut. Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1997.0101</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1809/2000" type="inclusive">undated, 1809-2000</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a97d9bb1ec22f9a25150b74944f57e30">An artificial collection, the Connecticut Soldiers Collection was created to provide a starting point for research concerning the experiences of Connecticut servicemen from the Civil War through the Vietnam War. The sources for the materials are provided in the collection.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4bcd72c6c066690f681f960701387774">
    <head>History</head>
<p>The Connecticut Soldiers collection contains letters and papers documenting the experience of Connecticut servicemen active in the American Civil War through the Vietnam Wart. An artificial collection, additional materials are actively acquired and incorporated. The sources from which the papers were acquired are listed in the folders.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e659502d1249000d18694e72d92bb115">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The collection, at present, contains several diaries and the papers of multiple servicemen active in the American Civil War, World War I, World War II, the Korean Conflict and the war in Vietnam.</p><p><emph render="bold">American Civil War</emph></p><p>Lt. <persname>George William Allen</persname>, a member of the 15th <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> Volunteers, writes home from <geogname>Virginia</geogname> between 1862-1863.</p><p><persname>Christopher Boon</persname>, of <geogname>Westbrook, Connecticut</geogname>, initially documents his activities in a Connecticut Regiment but after being wounded in May 1863 his diary recounts his days in the VR Corps Hospital in <geogname>New Haven, Connecticut</geogname>, in two diaries covering April 1863 through 1864. Also includes receipts and manuscript documents from after the War.</p><p><persname>Gurdon Robins, Jr.</persname>, of <geogname>Hartford, Connecticu</geogname>, documents battle and camplife in 1863, followed by his experiences as a prisoner of war in Libby Prison. The diary also contains "My Own Common Place Book" with entries from 1835.</p><p>Captain <persname>Harlan P. Rugg</persname> of <geogname>Winchester Center, Connecticut</geogname>, maintained a lengthy diary account of his activities from 1861 through 1864, describing many of the major battles of the conflict.</p><p><persname>John L. Sage</persname> from <geogname>Cromwell, Connecticut</geogname> served with Company D, 24th Connecticut Regiment. His diary includes entries from <geogname>Louisiana</geogname> and <geogname>Mississippi</geogname> dating from September 1862 through September 1863.</p><p><persname>Charles H. Sears</persname> of Company C, 10th Connecticut Regiment, was born and raised in <geogname>New Haven, CT</geogname>. A carriage maker, <persname>Sears</persname> was present and involved in several major battles: Deep Bottom, Strawberry Plains, and others.</p><p><persname>D. Alonzo Smith</persname> of Company C, 19th Connecticut Regiment. His diary begins with his enlistment in 1862 in <geogname>Torrington, Connecticut</geogname>, through 1864. He served, for at least a time, as a prison guard at Fort Ellsworth, Virginia.</p><p><emph render="bold">World War I</emph></p><p>Disability claim papers submitted by <persname>Nicola Fortunato</persname> and a records of a 1922 cruise of the light cruiser “U.S.S. New Orleans” provide some insight into the years after the war.</p><p>Ccorrespondence, notes and postcards document the activities of Pfc. <persname>George W. Hanford</persname> of <geogname>Kensington, CT</geogname>, a soldier in the medical corps of the 306th Field Artillery.</p><p><emph render="bold">World War II</emph></p><p>Linwood and <persname>Esther Aldrich</persname> lived in <geogname>Norwich, Connecticut</geogname>. Married in September 1942, <persname>Linwood Aldrich</persname> worked for the <corpname>Thermos Bottle Company</corpname> as a sealer and Esther was employed at the <corpname>Lee and Osgood Company</corpname> as a stenographer. At the time the correspondence begins in July 1943, Linwood (882nd Signal Co.) is based in <geogname>New Orleans, Louisiana</geogname>. In August, he transfers to the HQ Detachment, also in New Orleans. The Detachment is shipped out to <geogname>England</geogname> in November, only days before he was scheduled to have his first leave to visit home since entering the service. The last two months of the correspondence in the collection indicates that Aldrich was transferred to <geogname>France</geogname> in November 1944. The correspondence ends a month later. </p><p>Lil and <persname>Carl Davis</persname> lived in <geogname>Hartford, CT</geogname>, during World War II, and the collection consists of the letters they received from their sons, Rodney O. and Dewey, who were in the armed forces during the war. More is known of Rod, who enlisted in 1942 in the Navy, and served in the Atlantic and Pacific until he was discharged in 1945. He was a radio operator on the USS Hermitage. The collection also contains letters from nephews and friends serving in the war.</p><p>Yeoman 3rd Class <persname>Phillip C. Edwards</persname> of <geogname>Norwich, CT</geogname> served on the submarine “U.S.S. Sand Lance” during World War II. His papers consist of a scrapbook compiled by his wife, Virginia, plus a transcript of a 3 September 1945 letter describing the last cruise of the “Sand Lance” and memorabilia.</p><p>Philip and <persname>Hazel Greene</persname>, residents of <geogname>Winsted, Connecticut</geogname>, were married in circa 1940. Philip was employed by a local firm while Hazel worked for the town hall. During World War II, Philip was drafted into service and was awarded the Purple Heart. During the same time period Hazel served on the town's rationing board. The collection contains letters written to them between 1941 and 1947.</p><p>Memoir of <persname>Andrew John Robert Guttay</persname> and brief summary of the 104th Infantry Regiment, 26th Division, <corpname>United States Army</corpname>, tour of <geogname>Europe</geogname> in 1994 with an accompanying video recording (VHS).</p><p>Corporal <persname>Burton Ingraham</persname> served in the 3580th QM Company, U.S. Army and was stationed at Camp Polk, <geogname>Louisiana</geogname> before being shipped out to <geogname>England</geogname> and later <geogname>France</geogname>. The correspondence is primarly from Cpl. Ingraham to his wife, <persname>Gladys Forbes Ingraham</persname> ("Butch"), although there are also letters from Gladys' brother, <persname>Gerald Forbes</persname> and several other acquaintances. A small portion of the collection contains information about the Colt Plant in Hartford where Gladys was employed.</p><p>Materials pertaining to the <emph render="italic">Jamaica Ginger</emph> a B17G bomber of the 563rd Bomb Squadron, 388th Bomb Group, 8th Air Force, which concluded its final flight at <geogname>Bradley Field</geogname> on 29 June 1945 are also included.</p><p>Memoir of <persname>Donald M. Kinsman</persname>, Professor Emeritus at the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>, entitled "Marine Corps Days: The World War II Experience." The document is dated November 1995.</p><p>Oral History of <persname>Robert D. Leavenworth</persname>. The document discusses Sgt. <persname>Robert D. Leavenworth</persname>'s military service experience - between November 1943 and May 1945 - as a top turret gunner and engineer on a B-24 bomber during WW II. It includes his one year German Prison Camp experience at Stalag Luft IV near the <geogname>Baltic Sea</geogname> after his plane was shot down on a bombing raid over marshalling yards near <geogname>Budapest, Hungary</geogname>. A substantial portion of the document is devoted to the 600 mile Black Death March which started at the end of January 1945 when the German Prison Camp Commander ordered the prisoners to march West when the Russian troops were nearing the camp from the East. Included also are Bob's strong attitudes toward patriotism and the American flag. Bob died on Good Friday 2007 in <geogname>Arizona</geogname>.</p><p>The papers of <persname>Peter Lukoff</persname>, Company C, 48th Armor Infantry Battalion, of <geogname>Norwich, Connecticut</geogname>, date from April 1944 through June 1945. The bulk of the collection documents Lukoff's experiences from training in the <geogname>United States</geogname> (<geogname>South Carolina</geogname>) and his activities in <geogname>France</geogname>, <geogname>Belgium</geogname>, <geogname>Germany</geogname> and <geogname>England</geogname>. Also included are letters and cards from his wife, Alma, and two children, Philip and Barbara. Lukoff was wounded in action at the Battle of the Bulge and separated from his unit for a short period of time. Prior to his war service he was employed by the <corpname>Hartford-Connecticut Trust Company</corpname>, Thames Branch.</p><p>Staff Sergeant <persname>Bernard C. Masopust</persname> of Southington and <geogname>Thomston, Connecticut</geogname>, served in the Marines and was stationed in Japan. The correspondence is dated 1945-1946 and covers the period after basic training and through his deployment and is primarily from "Barney" to his wife. In a unique tie to the University, Mr; Masopust's twin brother (mentioned in the letters) was a faculty member in the Horticulture Department for many years.</p><p>Corporal <persname>Filias J. Plourd</persname> of <geogname>Hartford, CT</geogname>, served primarily in the post office of the 260th Infantry. A noncombatant over the age of thirty-five, his letters were sent primarily to his brother, Launce.</p><p>The correspondence of Pvt. Robert N. Purcell to his wife (Jane) was a donation from Smith College to the collection. At the time of donation, it was not known where in (presumably) New England Purcell resided. The one address included in the correspondence (1943-1944), all from Robert to his wife, is directed to an address in <geogname>Bronx, NY</geogname>. Pvt. Purcell received his basic training for the Army at <geogname>Ft. Dix</geogname>, before being moved to Forts Shelby and McCain (<geogname>Mississippi</geogname>) before being shipped out to <geogname>England</geogname> and then <geogname>France</geogname>.</p><p>The most comprehensive portion of the collection to date is the correspondence of four brothers, <persname>Bernard J. Ward</persname>, <persname>Edward J. Ward</persname>, <persname>Robert F. Ward</persname> and <persname>Thomas P. Ward</persname> of <geogname>Newington, Connecticut</geogname>. All the correspondence is directed to Bernard “Bernie” or his wife, Louise. Of the four brothers, Bernie was the last to join the service during World War II and the only one to remain stateside for the duration. Bernie, who when writing to his wife signed his letters “Joe Joe”, joined the Navy in 1943, trained at the Naval Training Station in <geogname>Sampson, New York</geogname>, as was then stationed at <corpname>Yale University</corpname> in <geogname>New Haven, Connecticut</geogname>. Eddie joined the Army in 1942 and received his basic training at Ft. McKinley (<geogname>Maine</geogname>). From there, the correspondence follows his experiences at the <corpname>Fort Williams Radar School</corpname>, continued training at Fort Monroe (<geogname>Virginia</geogname>) and his service in <geogname>Australia</geogname> and <geogname>New Guinea</geogname>. Robert was also in the Army, but his correspondence follows his service beginning at Fort Jackson (<geogname>South Carolina</geogname>), Camp Pickett in <geogname>Virginia</geogname>, by way of <geogname>Louisiana</geogname> and <geogname>California</geogname>, before shipping out to active duty in the <geogname>Philippines</geogname>. There are references in the letters to his wife, Ann and daughter, Pat who was born in 1944. <persname>Thomas Ward</persname> trained at the Naval Training Station in <geogname>Rhode Island</geogname> before he served in the <geogname>Philippines</geogname> on the U.S.S. Lovelace. The majority of the letters were written between 1943 and 1944.</p><p><persname>Dexter Wilcomb</persname> served as  Technician Third Grade and documents his time in Europe during WWII. Also in the collection are clippings from Army publications and war maps</p><p><persname>Carl Viggiani</persname> was a member of a "Spearhead Military Government Team" attached to the 83rd Infantry Division during World War II. As the 83rd moved down toward the Elbe in April 1945, Viggiani's unit took over a Nazi official's home in Braunschweig for a night. Viggiani left Dachau two months after its liberation and never returned, although the memories of what he saw there have remained with him, as demonstrated by the article published in the <geogname>Haddam, CT</geogname>, paper (also included in the collection). </p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_da077d425add33e27d041c417798cf8d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The materials as part of this collection were originally maintained as a single collection. Acquisitions and donations to the collection of substantial collections that could support research independently have resulted in the reorganization and subdivision of this artificial collection. Although all the materials associated with this collection are described here, some of the series listed below are links to individual collections with their own finding aids.</p><p>The series numbers have not been assigned in any particluar order. Materials associated with the American Civil War include: Allen, Boon, Robins, Rugg, Sage, and Sears. World War I materials include: Fortunato and Hanford. World War II activities are included in: Aldrich, Antonucci, Edwards, Gambino, Guttay, Ingraham, Jamaica Ginger, Kinsman, Leavenworth, Lukoff, Plourd, Viggiani, and Ward. The Korean Conflict is documented in the Gambino Family Papers.  The war in Vietnam is represented by the Lyons Collection.</p>  </arrangement>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_b4d49b9c880ce17fb428c470f9e79bcd">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:</p><p>104th Infantry Regiment, 26th Division. 50th Anniversary European Tour 1997-0101.vr1 </p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_df8a6a0c7a716f0ce6996cdafa7405d9">
    <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
<p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <custodhist id="aspace_2502b24cb927c2c8ecbd81063f7b3b9a">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The materials have been acquired by purchase and gift.</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_aa9d927356b6f8f49de1641628343981">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item description, #:#], Connecticut Soldiers Collection. Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_162fed5138eed847122cf2a2efecb25f">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The materials have been acquired by purchase and gift.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_138e6c29fac8cec201c07f9c2a24be9f">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname authfilenumber="2016742" source="tgn">Cromwell (inhabited place)</geogname>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300026877" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <geogname authfilenumber="2016812" source="tgn">Hartford (inhabited place)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="7014246" source="tgn">Norwich (inhabited place)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="7007159" source="tgn">Connecticut (state)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="2017019" source="tgn">Kensington (inhabited place)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="2017180" source="tgn">Newington (inhabited place)</geogname>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/1180746" source="fast">World War (1914-1918)</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/1180924" source="fast">World War (1939-1945)</subject>
    <genreform authfilenumber="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/1423843" source="fast">Personal narratives</genreform>
    <subject source="aat">Family papers</subject>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027112" source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027221" source="aat">Posters</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027341" source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300027200" source="aat">Notes</genreform>
    <geogname authfilenumber="2017609" source="tgn">Winchester Center (inhabited place)</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref13_ul3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Charles H. Sears</unittitle><unitdate normal="1864/1864" type="inclusive">undated, 1864</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref14_xzu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sears Diary and loose pages</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box1:1</unitid><unitdate normal="1864/1864" type="inclusive">undated, 1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b59fb42665bec9c5fbf9a0583d21ae7" label="Text (39153019689704)" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f52847536e620947eb5a33369c32f668" parent="aspace_7b59fb42665bec9c5fbf9a0583d21ae7" type="folder">1</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref15_wvq" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: George W. Hanford</unittitle><unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_edff46a0136a2b238067bf5a106dcd4d"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:20050140">George Hanford Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref17_r3c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Phillip C. Edwards</unittitle><unitdate normal="1938/1945" type="inclusive">undated, 1938-1945</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_0a7526ee5c52d25bc98b30a216db417c"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127528">Phillip C. Edwards Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref19_nlc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Filias J. Plourd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1946" type="inclusive">1943-1946</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_2d447a26661e726620bdcce0f992ca39"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860116501">Filias J. Plourd Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref21_gpg" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V: Ward Family</unittitle><unitdate normal="1942/1945" type="inclusive">undated, 1942-1945</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_f4d0d2d7d16e48e3d2583b9a2634d7e6"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:20010014">Ward Family Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref23_7jd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI: Peter Lukoff</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1945" type="inclusive">1944-1945</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_7bfff308a39351b2699f78a34d307e39"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:20050143">Peter Lukoff Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref25_l4h" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VII: Burton Ingraham</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1945" type="inclusive">undated, 1941-1945</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_7af9105e69d013df12afb1e970d63458"><head>General note</head></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref27_try" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VIII: Linwood Aldrich</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1944" type="inclusive">undated, 1943-1944</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_30c8faf6800a9ed388d0ac9e160e90d1"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860119516">Linwood Aldrich Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref29_5hb" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IX: Carl A. Viggiani</unittitle><unitdate normal="1938/1996" type="inclusive">undated, 1938-1996</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_4c8ed8048cde73a4d916b5b105327af8"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860120299">Carl A. Viggiani Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref31_4v3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series X: <emph render="italic">Jamaica Ginger</emph></unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2000" type="inclusive">2000</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref32_xpc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Information</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box1:3</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_0287adf5fb406e8583bfa3c6fb676e5a" label="Mixed Materials (39153019689704)" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_e97a148c0260eccf40026462a1250373" parent="aspace_0287adf5fb406e8583bfa3c6fb676e5a" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33_ncf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2000" type="inclusive">2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_df1758b9e555b7d2db99ed89faa650b6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">OS</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref34_9ie" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XI: Nicola Fortunato</unittitle><unitdate normal="1921/1922" type="inclusive">1921-1922</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref35_mlt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Disability claim</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box1:2</unitid><unitdate normal="1921/1922" type="inclusive">1921-1922</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe002463437ccdd448e4bd41478efe5c" label="Text (39153019689704)" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d61a1b70adfa865abefa59ad83346a58" parent="aspace_fe002463437ccdd448e4bd41478efe5c" type="folder">2</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref36_q4w" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XII: Gurdon Robins, Jr.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1835/1863" type="inclusive">1835, 1863</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref37_ub1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diary</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box1:4</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">1835, 1863</unitdate><container id="aspace_d32828b8c500b8749f0d1e140c87df7e" label="digitized (39153019689670)" type="box-folder">1:4</container><container id="aspace_a74c1b3c1e84c6cb903ccb531fb034a1" label="Mixed Materials (39153019689704)" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7c803d64cc8fac3fe48809caa136ab01" parent="aspace_a74c1b3c1e84c6cb903ccb531fb034a1" type="folder">4</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref38_dy2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIII: Harlan P. Rugg</unittitle><unitdate normal="1861/1864" type="inclusive">1861-1864</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_56511a16e8661d1e0aa0e253a8c72066"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860118339">Harlan P. Rugg Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref40_1qq" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIV: John L. Sage</unittitle><unitdate normal="1862/1863" type="inclusive">1862-1863</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref41_v27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diary</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box1:5</unitid><unitdate normal="1862/1863" type="inclusive">1862-1863</unitdate><container id="aspace_733ac63aedbe3cb99f1cecba0e9ac6ed" label="Text (39153019689704)" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_9d8d0f26931a745dbcb9e64ad3e79817" parent="aspace_733ac63aedbe3cb99f1cecba0e9ac6ed" type="folder">5</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860039626" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="John L. Sage Diary"><daodesc><p>John L. Sage Diary</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref42_nx8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XV: George William Allen</unittitle><unitdate normal="1862/1863" type="inclusive">1862-1863</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref43_ta4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box1:6</unitid><unitdate normal="1862/1863" type="inclusive">1862-1863</unitdate><container id="aspace_a366dd328182a07b1623cafc99ce3117" label="Text (39153019689704)" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_39790b7c804176573ffb2a0c63f5f12e" parent="aspace_a366dd328182a07b1623cafc99ce3117" type="folder">6</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860039544" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Letters"><daodesc><p>Letters</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref44_wmu" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVI: Robert N. Purcell</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1944" type="inclusive">1943-1944</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref45_t43" level="file"><did><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_7dfa6b7653f17a3f210faf902adeb838" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_aec121a76cc24871dd89e5bdd68c2ddc" parent="aspace_7dfa6b7653f17a3f210faf902adeb838" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46_9th" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1943-06/1943-06" type="inclusive">1943 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_169eb299308c2307045bfe513c95979d" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_516fb6677a0d64f79773a56f784a95b4" parent="aspace_169eb299308c2307045bfe513c95979d" type="folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref47_may" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1943-07/1943-07" type="inclusive">1943 July</unitdate><container id="aspace_27b5913a4bf1645823450937533a5146" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_873d2df8d79895c38485823c923a76c0" parent="aspace_27b5913a4bf1645823450937533a5146" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref48_wdw" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1943-08/1943-08" type="inclusive">1943 August</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a720e30327fc851af56986d2f0a7d08" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_9c358d31f36f0b05742bf6137c476abc" parent="aspace_6a720e30327fc851af56986d2f0a7d08" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref49_3rr" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1943-09/1943-09" type="inclusive">1943 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_e860dac049374f87c48ef2c1f1543fbf" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_059a736b92cfba2cd1da829e4944c0a5" parent="aspace_e860dac049374f87c48ef2c1f1543fbf" type="folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50_87n" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1943-10/1943-10" type="inclusive">1943 October</unitdate><container id="aspace_b213980921f26aa432bfd5055f440f67" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_2084fadf434991c22fccd2d92d83ead7" parent="aspace_b213980921f26aa432bfd5055f440f67" type="folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51_aoy" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1943-11/1943-11" type="inclusive">1943 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f4362f038b64e8bc8710719f3d8dc28" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_757cb3c480e529ef345e4071cb9de5d5" parent="aspace_3f4362f038b64e8bc8710719f3d8dc28" type="folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52_vr0" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1943-12/1943-12" type="inclusive">1943 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4aeb98d42734134f5231e4ea22f4808" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_bbeca7afd204e1b142e4258a618d72d0" parent="aspace_d4aeb98d42734134f5231e4ea22f4808" type="folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref53_48r" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1944-01/1944-01" type="inclusive">1944 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_699dd6ecb3df09153d865c7cad190269" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_5f86d777dff72761c4911bc5a84963c3" parent="aspace_699dd6ecb3df09153d865c7cad190269" type="folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref54_zz1" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1944-06/1944-06" type="inclusive">1944 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8d84d0bad056faf2da3adc17b5b91a2" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_e9577ed715f2edf8939df8133012a8d5" parent="aspace_a8d84d0bad056faf2da3adc17b5b91a2" type="folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref55_m4s" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1944-07/1944-07" type="inclusive">1944 July</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d339d4c02f96bc1dce745653e9c8a21" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_42107657f982c25b8a3ef914080e4f0f" parent="aspace_4d339d4c02f96bc1dce745653e9c8a21" type="folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref56_02o" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1944-08/1944-08" type="inclusive">1944 August</unitdate><container id="aspace_b882938909825974b9907e0b335965f3" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_899a46c56c0a3f848805addcd019260e" parent="aspace_b882938909825974b9907e0b335965f3" type="folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57_dqt" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1944-09/1944-09" type="inclusive">1944 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_4307e0ae045dac3a3736b57b97b32763" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_5bdd1b313427e05badaa3635e0f91449" parent="aspace_4307e0ae045dac3a3736b57b97b32763" type="folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref58_nun" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1944-10/1944-10" type="inclusive">1944 October</unitdate><container id="aspace_4812f60dee6b5f54dd6195dd43ac01b9" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_43ac9390c57ab6e5df7b0bbc92e8772a" parent="aspace_4812f60dee6b5f54dd6195dd43ac01b9" type="folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref59_lu6" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1944-11/1944-11" type="inclusive">1944 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_16c4f662789856ad22a04cf33d60d35b" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_79102ab7d5d1c0210e41c0ca2a06a9ad" parent="aspace_16c4f662789856ad22a04cf33d60d35b" type="folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_oi3" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1944-12/1944-12" type="inclusive">1944 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_aaffb34ad8d1fec8f1ff787711b7b7f1" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f5740c306f069bdc6c4b314583d6ee3b" parent="aspace_aaffb34ad8d1fec8f1ff787711b7b7f1" type="folder">22</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref61_9px" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVII: D. Alonzo Smith</unittitle><unitdate normal="1862/1865" type="inclusive">1862-1865</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref62_4s5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diary</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box2:23</unitid><unitdate normal="1862/1864" type="inclusive">1862-1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_f015f3829e11ab93fd4708b2aa4796e9" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_c37d0c4667ecffca1d35bb1c71d4fcb8" parent="aspace_f015f3829e11ab93fd4708b2aa4796e9" type="folder">23</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860040010" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Diary"><daodesc><p>Diary</p></daodesc></dao></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63_o35" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pass (photocopy)</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box2:24</unitid><unitdate normal="1865-06-09/1865-06-09" type="inclusive">1865 June 9</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2cc92a7df40d63178eec0a0cb9bf6ed" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_24446091f4eb9cbea5fcf06d6efd1ce0" parent="aspace_d2cc92a7df40d63178eec0a0cb9bf6ed" type="folder">24</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:86004010100" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="D. Alonzo Smith pass (photocopy)"><daodesc><p>D. Alonzo Smith pass (photocopy)</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref64_e5g" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVIII: Philip and Hazel Greene Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1947" type="inclusive">1941-1947</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_c437fd468afaa83432ebafdcc0b9503c"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860127529">Greene Correspondence Collection</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref66_isp" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIV: Robert D. Leavenworth Oral History</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2004" type="inclusive">2004</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_b6cf110c8c86bbc31c67542b470ac378"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860118336">Robert Leavenworth Oral History</extref> (Leavenworth Family Papers, Series I, Box 34).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref68_t5h" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XX: A. J. Robert Guttay</unittitle><unitdate normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">undated, 1994</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref69_6ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memoir [documents 1943-1945]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d9d4dc4a1f87feae7115c2b38017078" label="Text" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_ce7f0ef4fcbafc0f871c4a499ca27e41" parent="aspace_1d9d4dc4a1f87feae7115c2b38017078" type="folder">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref70_qog" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summary of 104th Infantry tour of Europe</unittitle><unitdate normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_f92eedef439ea54a4263e8e44fdf098b" label="Text" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_c6dfd1572a20894e3ee740b6727e0aea" parent="aspace_f92eedef439ea54a4263e8e44fdf098b" type="folder">26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref71_dld" level="file"><did><unittitle>104th Infantry Reg., 26th Div., 50th Anniversary European Tour</unittitle><unitdate normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_5cf30b1f9012df42eb88f0d5be45663d" label="Moving Images" type="other">Video</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref72_dq6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XXI: Donald M. Kinsman</unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">1995</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref73_lnz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memoir [documents 1942-1946]</unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_3251025388d4266f3bc38f174254f89f" label="Text" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_018e81716fab0b4cc923a0c30a241b20" parent="aspace_3251025388d4266f3bc38f174254f89f" type="folder">27</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref74_gr6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XXII: Davis Family</unittitle><unitdate normal="1938/1945" type="inclusive">1938-1945</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_30c1f73b7b9bb7110395b8ffedf3d2d3"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860115783">Davis Family Correspondence</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref76_1g2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XXIII: Christopher Boon</unittitle><unitdate normal="1863/1888" type="inclusive">undated, 1863-1888</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref77_kfm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diaries (2)</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box3:28</unitid><unitdate normal="1863/1864" type="inclusive">1863-1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce278e414e85a48f952566061d90750c" label="Text" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_47a904e1df264df84d97f6660c693bf7" parent="aspace_ce278e414e85a48f952566061d90750c" type="folder">28</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860039745" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Diaries"><daodesc><p>Diaries</p></daodesc></dao></did></c><c id="aspace_ref78_ayp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents</unittitle><unitid>1997-0101/Box3:29</unitid><unitdate normal="1865/1888" type="inclusive">undated, 1865-1888</unitdate><container id="aspace_05b6a5988b5538dd3ec434178131078f" label="Text" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_89ba5ea3f3c26ca42cb63f180dc46c1e" parent="aspace_05b6a5988b5538dd3ec434178131078f" type="folder">29</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860073928" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Documents"><daodesc><p>Documents</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref79_9tt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XXIV: Bernard C. Masopust</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1946" type="inclusive">undated, 1945-1946</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_f5f0832d15e830be10807f7b27141acf"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860114649">Bernard C. Masopust Papers</extref></p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref81_1m6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XXV: Dexter Wilcomb Papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1945" type="inclusive">undated, 1943-1945</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_181d2539ca1182a85b94e6d256d41683"><head>General note</head><p><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/11134/20002:860131250" xlink:show="new">Dexter Wilcomb Papers</extref></p></odd></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
