<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Ready_for_export" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/MSS19910009.html">MSS19910009</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad Records
                    <num>1991.0009</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad Records</titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by The finding aid was created by Archives &amp; Special Collections staff.</author>
                <sponsor>This project was funded by a grant from the  , with additional funding from the University of Connecticut Libraries and matching gift funds from the   and several individuals.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-06-02T12:40-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>The finding aid is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>May 2012</date>
                <item></item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>1991.0009</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3050.0 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1760/1980" type="inclusive">undated, 1760-1980</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="ref13" label="Physical description">1,305 boxes and 2,199 bound volumes.</physdesc>
            <langmaterial id="ref11" label="Language(s) of Materials">English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref43" label="Abstract">The corporate records of the New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad document the history and impact of the system that dominated railroad transportation in southern New England from 1872 to 1969.</abstract>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>History</head>
            <p>During the centennial celebration of the 
                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> in 1926, President 
                <persname>E. J. Pearson</persname> boasted that the "...history of the New Haven system was a history of transportation in this country." Had he limited his claim to the New York - Boston corridor, Pearson would have been substantially correct. For almost one hundred years the 
                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname>, better known as the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>, was the primary means of passenger and freight transportation in Southern New England. Chartered in 1872, this merger between the New York &amp; New Haven and Hartford &amp; New Haven railroads later included the long desired rail link between Boston and New York. Approximately one hundred small independent railroads were built in southern New England between 1826 and the 1880s. By 1904 the majority were absorbed into the vast New Haven system. At its peak in 1929, the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> owned and operated 2,131 miles of track throughout New York, Connecticut, Massachusetts, and Rhode Island.</p>
            <p>The local railroad lines that eventually became part of the New Haven system developed in response to local business and transportation needs. Unlike the Western states, where railroads preceded and shaped settlement, in the Northeast they served primarily to link existing towns, businesses, and markets. The New Haven system thus developed as a result of numerous consolidations and mergers. The New Haven traced its founding to 1826, when one of its predecessor companies originated, but the 
                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> was not chartered until 1872. The company followed the pattern of consolidation established by the 
                <corpname>Pennsylvania Railroad</corpname> and other companies, particularly after 1889, when major lines in Connecticut, Rhode Island, and southern Massachusetts provided a strong network linking New York and Boston. By 1890, company revenue exceeded $100,000,000 per year, and the New Haven employed 4,000 people to serve twelve million passengers annually.</p>
            <p>This success led a wealthy group of New York investors, headed by 
                <persname>J. P. Morgan</persname>, to seek and gain control of the New Haven's board. In 1903, Morgan installed 
                <persname>Charles Mellen</persname> as president of the railroad. Together Morgan and Mellen set out to achieve a complete monopoly of transportation in New England. Substantial improvements to the system were made during the Mellen years, including electrification of rail lines between 
                <geogname>Woodlawn, New York</geogname>, and 
                <geogname>New Haven, Connecticut</geogname>, and construction of a power generating plant in 
                <geogname>Cos Cob, Connecticut</geogname>. These accomplishments, however, were overshadowed by Morgan's ambitious schemes to dominate all modes of transportation in New England. Steamboat lines, trolley companies, and other railroad lines were purchased regardless of price and incorporated into the New Haven system.</p>
            <p>An investigation of the New Haven's activities by 
                <persname>Louis Brandeis</persname> in 1907 revealed the overextended railroad was on the verge of financial collapse. Morgan's death in 1913 and Mellen's subsequent resignation brought to a close a stormy period in the New Haven's history.</p>
            <p>During the First World War all of the railroads in the United States, including the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>, were operated by the federal government. After the war, under 
                <persname>Edward Pearson</persname>, President through 1928, the railroad was able to recover partially, despite increasing competition from automobiles, by sharing in the national economic growth of the 1920s. The company tried to meet this transportation competition by forming the 
                <corpname>New England Transportation Company</corpname>, which operated a fleet of trucks and buses. Recovery of the New Haven, however, was cut short by the Depression of the 1930s, and in 1935 the New Haven plunged into bankruptcy. The company remained in trusteeship until 1947, when it returned to private ownership.</p>
            <p>A series of struggles for control of the company in the post World War II period severely weakened the management of the company and its ability to adapt to changes in the transportation industry. The completion of the 
                <corpname>Connecticut Turnpike</corpname> and other superhighways and the start of air shuttle service between Boston and New York intensified competition. The company's historic liability as a railroad overburdened with many short, costly branch lines further accelerated its decline.</p>
            <p>On July 2, 1961, the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> once again went into receivership. A seven year trusteeship period followed, culminating in the absorption of the New Haven in the 
                <corpname>Penn Central</corpname> system on January 1, 1969. Three years later the Penn Central itself collapsed into bankruptcy. The former components of the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> were divided among several entities. Freight service was assumed by Conrail when it was formed in 1976, although the 
                <corpname>Providence &amp; Worcester Railroad</corpname> also provided freight service on portions of the former New Haven, as did a few other operators. Passenger commuter service was funded by the 
                <corpname>New York Metropolitan Transit Authority</corpname> and the 
                <corpname>Connecticut Department of Transportation</corpname>. Long-haul passenger service was provided by 
                <corpname>Amtrak</corpname> beginning in 1971. After 1976 passenger commuter service was operated by 
                <corpname>Conrail</corpname>. In 1982 the 
                <corpname>United States Congress</corpname> passed legislation that forced 
                <corpname>Conrail</corpname> to divest itself of its commuter rail lines. On January 1, 1983, 
                <corpname>Metro-North Commuter Railroad</corpname>, under joint ownership of the states of New York and Connecticut, took over all commuter passenger service. Amtrak continued to handle all long-haul passenger service.</p>
            <p>The history of the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> reveals a company formed by one of the classic merger and consolidation patterns of the late 19th century, which was later unable to respond effectively to major changes in the transportation industry. The company's rapid growth, collapse, temporary recovery, and final dissolution offer a dramatic story, with government regulation, internal management decisions, and market competition playing important roles in the company's history.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>This collection of 
                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> records contains central administrative and financial records of the New Haven Railroad and approximately 300 predecessor and subsidiary companies. The records are dated from 1831 to 1980, with the bulk of material dated 1935 to 1968.</p>
            <p>These records constitute the official records of the company, primarily from the central administrative offices. In particular, they document activities of the Board of Directors and Comptroller. Operational, engineering, and personnel activities are less fully covered, and there are major gaps in coverage of many aspects of the company's history. This collection does not include: personnel or employee records; operational records regarding equipment, schedules, etc.; maps, engineering drawings, or mechanical records; or detailed information about financial and operational activities on a daily basis. There are few administrative files for the Mellen-Morgan years, and gaps exist in several record groups and series for various time periods. Some of these gaps apparently exist because records were lost or destroyed. In some cases, records were scattered and some of these records were found and preserved by collectors and historical groups. Several other collections at the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> and other repositories thus supplement or fill in some of these gaps.</p>
            <p>The collection is organized in seven record groups: Secretary's Office; Trustees; Annual Reports; Comptroller's Office; Accounting Department; Legal Department Claims; and Bound Volumes.</p>
            <p>The SECRETARY'S OFFICE record group contains central administrative files for the New Haven Railroad and many of its subsidiary companies. As the official record-keeping officer for the company, the Corporate Secretary maintained minutes of meetings, reports, administrative files, agreements, real estate records, stocks and stockholder records, legal records, and records of subsidiary companies. This record group is thus important for many issues pertaining to administrative and legal activities, particularly those under purview of the Board of Directors.</p>
            <p>The TRUSTEES record group contains files relating to the company's activities during reorganization under court-appointed Trustees. The major concentration of records covers the second reorganization, from 1961 to its merger with Penn Central in 1968. These records include publications, reports, administrative files, legal and court records, financial records, and related materials.</p>
            <p>The ANNUAL REPORTS record group was created by combining annual reports prepared by the Secretary and the Accounting Department. These records include annual reports to stockholders, the Interstate Commerce Commission, and various state governments, as well as annual reports by other railroad companies.</p>
            <p>The COMPTROLLERS record group consists of records from the Comptroller's Office. These relate primarily to financial and administrative concerns, including employee relations, strikes, passenger fares, revenue forecasts, government relations, audits, freight operations, abandonment of rail lines, and subsidiary companies.</p>
            <p>The ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT record group contains additional financial and reporting records, relating to financial transactions. This includes Securities and Exchange Commission reports, stock portfolios, rate structure studies, claims, journal entries, vouchers, and subsidiary company records.</p>
            <p>The LEGAL DEPARTMENT CLAIMS record group contains claim files and cases handled by the Legal Department.</p>
            <p>The BOUND VALUES record group was created for convenience in organizing and handling oversize bound volumes from a variety of offices and companies. These include bound volumes from the New Haven Railroad's Secretary's Office, Accounting Department, and Comptroller's Office. There are also bound volumes from approximately 300 predecessor and subsidiary companies.</p>
            <p>This collection of 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> records is the largest archival collection for the company and its predecessors and subsidiaries. The University of Connecticut also holds several major collections of materials from the New Haven Railroad, received from other sources or donors.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref3">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#], 
                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> Records. 
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Restrictions on Use and Copyright Information</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Records must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <odd id="ref9">
            <head>General note for researchers</head>
            <p>This guide to the 
                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> Records is an archival finding aid prepared to assist researchers in using the collection. Due to the size and complexity of this collection, which contains more than 3,000 linear feet of documents, a brief explanation of how to use this guide is in order.</p>
            <p>Two basic archival principles guided us in arranging and describing the records in this collection. The records have been maintained according to their office of origin and their original order. The documents are organized in record groups, each of which contains the files created by a particular department (e.g., Secretary, Trustees). Only two record groups, Annual Reports and Bound Volumes, are based on type of material rather than office of origin.</p>
            <p>Within each record group, documents are filed in sub-categories called series. Each series contains records which were generated by a specific office within a department, created as a result of a particular type of activity, or related to a specific topic. The arrangement of files in each series reflects, to the extent possible, the original filing system under which the records were created and maintained by each office.</p>
            <p>Although this finding aid can be used profitably before visiting the Archives, please remember that it was developed specifically for use in consultation with a reference archivist. There is no substitute for discussing your research query directly with the reference archivist, who will assist you in locating information and in avoiding some of the many potential wrong turns and dead-ends which frequently make archival research both challenging and, sometimes, frustrating.</p>
            <p>This finding aid will not enable you to identify individual items, or to locate in one place all the material on a given subject. Nor can the Archives staff provide photocopies of individual pieces or specific information on a topic. With a collection of more than 2,000 linear feet of documents, it is impossible to list or catalog each item or topic. In most cases, only a general listing of filing categories is available. The finding aid is merely an aid to research, not a substitute for it.</p>
            <p>This guide can, however, assist you in narrowing your search and in identifying which series or boxes are likely to contain useful information. The first step is to determine which of the major offices within the company was likely to have dealt with the issue or topic you are researching. This will guide you to one or more of the record groups. The narrative description of the records should be read carefully for an overview of the filing systems and the types of records in each record group and series.</p>
            <p>After identifying which series might contain useful information, you should scan the contents list for each appropriate series. The contents lists for some series only identify the numerical or alphabetical grouping of files in each box. In some cases, they provide a listing of the file folder titles in the boxes. The only listing which is more detailed than this is provided for the record group Bound Volumes, which lists each type of record book for the various companies. For some series, a card file index prepared by the office of origin provides more detailed access to names, places, and topics (see Appendix A). The contents list will lead you to the box numbers which should be requested for research use (include both record group number and box number, since boxes in each record group are numbered separately).</p>
            <p>Because of the size and complexity of this collection, researchers investigating most topics should carefully examine the listings for each of the record groups and series. Information about a particular railroad company or a local station, for example, might be located in two or three different record groups. A large number of files and individual documents refer to numerous railroad companies, stations, or topics; however, the size of the collection made it impossible to list each such reference. Thus, some information about the Naugatuck Railroad, for example, may be located in Secretary's Office Legal Records, even though the company's name does not appear in the contents list for this series. Other clues, such as dates of major events, topics of special importance to the company, or secondary subjects related to the main topic of inquiry, will need to be followed in order to locate such information.</p>
            <p>It should be noted that this collection contains only the core group of New Haven Railroad records in the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center . Many of the company's historically valuable records have been destroyed or scattered among other archival repositories and private collectors. The Railroad Archives already has acquired several other groups of New Haven Railroad records, and welcomes information about other railroad records which might be donated for preservation and research use.</p>
        </odd>
        <odd id="ref12">
            <head>Acknowledgements</head>
            <p>This project was funded by a grant from the 
                <corpname>National Endowment for the Humanities</corpname>, with additional funding from the University of Connecticut Libraries and matching gift funds from the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad Historical and Technical Association</corpname> and several individuals. For their many contributions to the project, we wish to thank Advisory Board members Fred V. Carstensen, L. Peter Cornwall, William G. Dulmaine, Jr., Charles B. Gunn, Alan M. Levitt, Karl Schlachter, Karl Stieg, and Gregg M. Turner.</p>
            <p>The staff members who completed this undertaking include: project archivists Marguerite Giguere-Davis, Peter Latincsics, Heather Smith, and Cheryl Turkington; project assistants Jill Padelford, Aldo Salerno, and John Wraight; students assistants Peter Cote, Laura Ebert, Brian Fitzgerald, Christine Klimek, Elise Orringer, and Jeffrey Wilson; and project director Randall Jimerson.</p>
        </odd>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Provenance and Acquisition</head>
            <p>The history of the 
                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> records and the records of its predecessor and subsidiary companies is almost as complex as the organization itself.</p>
            <p>In 1952, approximately 1,945 bound volumes, mostly financial ledgers of the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> and its predecessor and subsidiary companies, were placed on "permanent deposit" at 
                <corpname>Yale University Library</corpname> by the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>. Within ten years, space shortages forced Yale to consider transferring the volumes to other repositories. In 1962, the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> authorized 
                <corpname>Yale University</corpname> to destroy the material on permanent deposit that could not be transferred elsewhere. The volumes were then transferred to Baker Library at 
                <corpname>Harvard University</corpname>, the Marine Historical Society in Mystic, Connecticut, and the 
                <corpname>Connecticut Electric Railway Association</corpname> at 
                <geogname>Warehouse Point, Connecticut</geogname>. There is no record that any documents were destroyed.</p>
            <p>In February 1969, 
                <persname>William E. Wood</persname>, Director of the 
                <corpname>National Railway Historical Society</corpname> transferred over 500 bound volumes and several cartons of timetables, vouchers, and stock certificates to the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Library</corpname> from their storage location at 
                <geogname>Warehouse Point, Connecticut</geogname>. The bulk of the New Haven's 20th century records remained in a records center at 
                <geogname>Cedar Hill, Connecticut</geogname>.</p>
            <p>In June 1978, the Trustees of 
                <corpname>Penn Central</corpname>, the New Haven's successor, designated the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> the official repository for records of the 
                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname>. Later that year, the first group of records from the Cedar Hill records center were transferred to the University. The records included approximately 1,150 cartons (over 1,200 linear feet) of Accounting Department and Comptroller records, personal injury claims, and legal case files.</p>
            <p>
                <corpname>American Financial Enterprises, Inc.</corpname>, successor to the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>, signed a formal Deed of Gift, donating additional records to the University, on October 24, 1980. This agreement renewed the designation of the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> as the official repository for historical records of the 
                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>. In 1980, the University received over 1,000 linear feet of records from the railroad's headquarters at 54 Meadow Street, New Haven. The records included approximately 1,000 bound volumes, annual reports, Secretary files, Trustee files, and claims.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref44">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the railroads of southern New England. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=4">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest">Alpert, George (1898-1988).</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">McGinnis, Patrick B.</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad Company.</corpname>
            <genreform source="local">Administrative Records.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Financial Records.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Legal Records.</genreform>
            <subject source="local">Railroads -- Connecticut.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Railroads -- Massachusetts.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Railroads -- New England -- History.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Railroads -- New York (State).</subject>
            <subject source="local">Railroads -- Rhode Island.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref8" level="recordgrp">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Record Group 1: Secretary's Records,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1760/1971" type="inclusive">undated, 1760-1971</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref14">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Note that the numbers in brackets refer to the original file numbers given to the reports and documents by the 
                        <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> and are necessary for the referencing of the documents from the index cards available in the Reading Room.</p>
                </odd>
                <c id="ref15" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series I: Old Company Secretary Files,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1945" type="bulk">Bulk, 1930-1945</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1840/1947" type="inclusive">undated, 1840-1947</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref26">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>These records concern the administrative and financial running of the company for the Trustees, the Board of Directors and the Stockholders before the 1947 reorganization. The OLD COMPANY SECRETARY FILES include (but are not limited to) the meeting minutes of the Board of Directors, Trustees and Stockholders, information about pensions, 
                            <corpname>Grand Central Terminal</corpname>, equipment, subsidiary companies, financial and statistical statements and real estate records. Document types in the OLD COMPANY SECRETARY FILES include meeting minutes, reports, agreements, and correspondence. It is speculated that these records were removed from the Secretary's files for study during the first bankruptcy and reorganization; the bulk of these records are dated prior to the reorganization of the railroad in 1947. The "A"-series numbers are given on the left margin of the listings for this series. A partial set of index cards which access the records is available.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref132" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[1] Board of Directors Meetings,</unittitle>
                            <unitdate normal="1920/1934" type="inclusive">1920-1934</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <c id="ref133" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid959003" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref134" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid959004" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref135" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid959005" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1923/1926" type="inclusive">1923-1926</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref136" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid959006" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1926/1930" type="inclusive">1926-1930</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref137" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid959007" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1930/1933" type="inclusive">1930-1933</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref140" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid960003" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref139" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[4] Executive Committee of Board of Directors Meetings: deeds, financial statements, daily cash balances and operating revenues,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid960002" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1916/1933" type="inclusive">1916-1933</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref141" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[4-4.1] Board of Directors Meetings: financial statements, income and revenue, cash balance, memoranda of cash situation,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid960001" type="Box" label="Text">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1917/1950" type="inclusive">1917-1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref142" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[4.1] Trustees' Meetings, Board of Directors Meetings: financial statements, cash balance, income revenue, memoranda of cash situation,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid960004" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1929/1942" type="inclusive">1929-1942</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref143" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[4.1] Reorganized Company and Trustees meeting, Board of Directors meetings financial and statistical statement, news releases, memoranda on cash situation,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid960005" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1941/1961" type="inclusive">1941-1961</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref144" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[4.2-4.6] Board of Directors Meetings, Trustees Meetings: memoranda of cash situation, financial statements, freight and passenger service,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid960006" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1922/1948" type="inclusive">1922-1948</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref145" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[4.6-.19] Trustees Meetings: memoranda to trustees, monthly reports to directors, monthly financial reports to employees, annual budget, estimated income and expenses, financial and statistical statements, newspaper articles,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962001" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1936/1961" type="inclusive">1936-1961</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref146" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[4.19] Information furnished to Directors, Board of Directors Meeting memoranda, financial statements, real estate sales, stock purchase plans, by-laws, revenue of car loadings, facts and figures (1922-54), passenger equipment, proposed centralized traffic control (1952-56),</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962002" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1922/1956" type="inclusive">1922-1956</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref147" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[4.19-.21] Board of Directors Meetings: deeds, financial and statistical statements; summary of revenues, expense and income; income accounts and selected statistics; digest of real estate sales; equipment summaries; photos: Stamford derailment; 
                                <corpname>Seaboard Air Line Railroad</corpname> statements; loan agreements,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962003" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1953/1959" type="inclusive">1953-1959</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref148" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[5.111-.782] Memoranda for Board of Directors: authority for expenditures; contracts; Board of estimates and apportionment (
                                <geogname>New York City</geogname>); map: proposed pipe and conduit; Proceedings for reorganizing of RR; 
                                <corpname>Boston Market Terminal Co.</corpname>; appropriations; agreements,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962004" type="Box" label="Text">15</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1928/1950" type="inclusive">1928-1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref149" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[5.783-5.840] Memoranda for Board of Directors: estimated expenditures, authority for expenditures; petition; contracts; agreements,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962005" type="Box" label="Text">16</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1947/1952" type="inclusive">1947-1952</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref150" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[5.841-7.1] Memoranda for Board of Directors: real estate sales, authority for expenditures, Income Tax return 1928: Internal Revenue: necessity certificate; stock certificates; petition; report to 
                                <corpname>Massachusetts Department of Public Utilities</corpname>; maps, news clippings; 
                                <corpname>South Bay Wharf and Terminal Company</corpname>,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962006" type="Box" label="Text">17</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1905/1967" type="inclusive">1905-1967</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref151" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[7.2-12] Meetings of committee on finance and operations: employee positions and wages, continuation of salaries and allowances for ill or deceased employees; real estate: proposed sales; statement of expenditures for road and equipment; report to Finance Committee,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962007" type="Box" label="Text">18</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1918/1946" type="inclusive">1918-1946</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref152" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[13-13.5] Board of Directors memoranda: income account and selected statistics; financial information; income and revenue; maps: railroad lines; photos of coaches (exterior); newspaper articles; article: "McClellon Water-Tube Boiler Test",</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962008" type="Box" label="Text">19</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1917/1952" type="inclusive">1917-1952</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref153" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[13.6-13.16] Trustees Meetings: memoranda to and from Board of Directors, railroad accidents and fatalities; passenger and freight service; revenue and statistics; airline travel: rates and routes; company's coal situation; 
                                <corpname>Springfield Street Railroad Co.</corpname>: revenue,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962009" type="Box" label="Text">20</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1920/1952" type="inclusive">1920-1952</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref154" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[13.17-13.35] Trustees Meetings: memoranda from Trustees; timetable changes; equipment situation; fire damage on Cos Cob bridge (1939); overnight freight service (Speed Witch); probable effect of the war in Europe on railroad business (1939); operation of daily coach service between Washington D.C. and Maine (train named "East Wind"); flood and hurricane destruction (1938, 1944, 1950); freight traffic; ticket sales to travel groups; low and nonpaying passenger trains; limited train statistics; bus vs. train service; passenger service in various cities; maps: 
                                <corpname>Old Colony Railroad</corpname> lines,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962010" type="Box" label="Text">21</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1931/1951" type="inclusive">1931-1951</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref155" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[13.36-13.68] Memoranda from Trustees, Board of Directors, Stockholders, Special Committee on pensions; pensions; payroll; rail failures; revocable permit, authority for expenditure, operating and traffic statistics; proposed new train service, automobile travel, various railroad companies, information on Freedom Train,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid962011" type="Box" label="Text">22</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1902/1949" type="inclusive">1902-1949</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref156" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[15.58-.60] Letters authorizing pensions and dollar amounts; statements of authorized pension payroll,</unittitle>
                        </did>
                        <c id="ref157" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid963002" type="Box" label="Text">23</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1902/1935" type="inclusive">1902-1935</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref158" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid963003" type="Box" label="Text">24</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1918/1946" type="inclusive">1918-1946</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref159" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid963004" type="Box" label="Text">25</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1917/1947" type="inclusive">1917-1947</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref160" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[37-37.8] Memoranda to and from Board of Directors, Stockholders: Stockholder meeting ballots Federal decree: complaint; petitions, news releases; By-laws, charters; 
                                <corpname>Boston and Maine Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Boston Holding Co.</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Eastern Steamship Corp.</corpname>,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid963001" type="Box" label="Text">26</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1907/1935" type="inclusive">1907-1935</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref161" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[37.8-37.40] Memoranda from Board of Directors, Stockholders, Committees; Federal decree: US v. NYNH&amp;H; Bill of complaints; petitions, bus and railway revenue; news releases; releases; 
                                <corpname>Connecticut Company</corpname>: sale; income account,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid963005" type="Box" label="Text">27</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1905/1933" type="inclusive">1905-1933</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref162" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[41-44] Memoranda from Trustees, Stockholders, Board of Directors Meetings: real estate transactions, maps, 
                                <corpname>Public Utilities Commission</corpname> (CT) docket; Meeting memoranda: 
                                <corpname>Northern Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Pemigewasset Valley Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Wilton Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Connecticut and Passumipsic Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Peterboro Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Kansas, Oklahoma and Gulf Railwa</corpname>y, 
                                <corpname>Springfield Railway Company</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Atchinson, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Co.</corpname>,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid963006" type="Box" label="Text">28</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1914/1951" type="inclusive">1914-1951</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref163" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[44.35-83] Memoranda from meetings of Board of Directors, Trustees, Stockholders, Committee on 
                                <geogname>New Haven Station</geogname>; real estate transactions; insurance policies; blueprints, building licenses and permits; 
                                <corpname>Public Utilities Commission</corpname> dockets, annual reports of 
                                <corpname>New Haven Police Department</corpname>, 
                                <geogname>Cedar Hill Yard</geogname>,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid963007" type="Box" label="Text">29</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1911/1947" type="inclusive">1911-1947</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref164" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[102-115] Memoranda from meetings of Stockholders, Board of Directors, Special Committee on Finance; expenditures for additions and improvements; report on maintenance of railroad; contracts for construction of equipment; 
                                <corpname>Public Utilities Commission</corpname> (CT) docket; 
                                <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> Act and its Amendment; 
                                <geogname>Thames River Bridge</geogname> dedication and engineer's report; 
                                <corpname>Boston Terminal Co.</corpname>; agreement and settlement between Director General of Railroads and NYNH&amp;H,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid963008" type="Box" label="Text">30</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1903/1967" type="inclusive">1903-1967</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref165" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[115-133] Memoranda from Board of Directors: summary of net corporate income; proposed Hydro-electric development; receipts and disbursement of 
                                <corpname>Equitable Trust Company</corpname> of New York; Revenue Act collateral indentures; agreements,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid999023" type="Box" label="Text">31</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1928" type="inclusive">1901-1928</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref166" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[133-147] Memoranda from meetings of Board of Directors, stockholders; petitions, decree, Public Utilities Commission of Connecticut dockets; real estate appraisal; statement of balance sheets and income account; record showing stock; ballots; debentures; legal cases; merger agreement: 
                                <corpname>Consolidated Railway Company</corpname>; agreements,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid999024" type="Box" label="Text">32</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1948" type="inclusive">1901-1948</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref167" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[147, 181] Memoranda of Board of Directors, stockholders: bills of complaint, legal cases: 
                                <persname>Harold Norris</persname>, 
                                <persname>Edwin Adams</persname>, Bartlett; Registered Gold Bond Specimens; Reports covering destruction of cancelled European loan Franc debentures,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid999025" type="Box" label="Text">33</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1946" type="inclusive">1910-1946</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref169" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[181] European loan; memoranda from Board of Directors; Office of Treasurer; list of bondholders, Committee on Stocklist; 
                                <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> finance docket; agreements; collateral trust indentures; 
                                <geogname>Grand Central Terminal</geogname>: leases, agreements, drawings,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid999027" type="Box" label="Text">34</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1900/1947" type="inclusive">1900-1947</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref170" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[202, 247] 
                                <corpname>Grand Central Terminal</corpname>: memoranda to Board of Trustees; lease; blueprints, Clayton Act: anti-trust questionnaires, NYNH&amp;HRR and subsidiaries lines index,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001002" type="Box" label="Text">35</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1914/1963" type="inclusive">1914-1963</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref171" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[247, 279, 289.1-.4, 290-292] Clayton Act: anti-trust questionnaires, NYNH&amp;HRR and subsidiaries lines index; common and preferred stock; annual stockholders meeting, Memoranda from Board of Directors and Trustees; real estate appraisal and digests; 
                                <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> valuation dockets; Stockholders meeting, list of deeds of NYNHHRR (1840s-1900s); 
                                <corpname>Norwich and Worcester Railroad</corpname>; leases, contracts, agreements made by NYNH&amp;H (c1840-1900), Publication of 
                                <corpname>London Stock Exchange</corpname> yearbooks; memoranda from Board of Trustees; blueprints,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001001" type="Box" label="Text">36</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1840/1955" type="inclusive">1840-1955</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref172" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[294-321] Memoranda from Board of Directors, Trustees, Special and sub-committees on Finance, Stockholders; income accounts; finance dockets; Transportation Act; Railway mail payment; Corporate rent and sales of real estate; mortgages, creamation affadavit,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001003" type="Box" label="Text">37</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1914/1949" type="inclusive">1914-1949</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref173" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[321] Memoranda from Board of Directors; petitions and court orders; By-laws of NYNH&amp;H; Reorganization proceedings, ICC finance dockets mortgages; mortgage supplements and releases,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001004" type="Box" label="Text">38</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1920/1951" type="inclusive">1920-1951</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref174" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[399.1-426] Memoranda from Stockholders and Board of Directors; repairs to cars; blueprints; 
                                <corpname>New England Navigation Company</corpname>,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001005" type="Box" label="Text">39</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1893/1945" type="inclusive">1893-1945</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref175" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[595.38-595.70] Memoranda from Board of Directors; trucking, agreements and contracts, ICC finance dockets; insurance; blueprints; reports on old freight equipment; condemnation of equipment; leases; mortgages; [595.58] 
                                <corpname>American Locomotive Company</corpname> conditional sale agreement; 
                                <corpname>Lina-Hamilton</corpname> conditional sale agreement; 
                                <corpname>Fairbanks, Morse &amp; Company</corpname> agreement; retirement of box cars; [595.61-.70] Retirement of box cars and locomotives,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001006" type="Box" label="Text">40</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1889/1950" type="inclusive">1889-1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref176" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[595] Memoranda from Trustees; condition and condemnation of equipment; report on freight equipment,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001007" type="Box" label="Text">41</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1947" type="inclusive">1942-1947</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref177" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[643.1-.19] Memoranda from Trustees, Board of Directors; United States Bankruptcy Act; ICC finance dockets; petitions: reorganization proceedings; maps,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001008" type="Box" label="Text">42</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1935/1947" type="inclusive">1935-1947</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref178" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[643.20-.38] Memoranda from Trustees, Board of Directors; report to Trustees regarding contracts; study of contracts, agreements, leases; disbursement and purchasing contracts; real estate department revenue reports; [643.31] Intercorporate relations: report on costs of storing and serving motor vehicles, intercorporate billing, proposed billing against 
                                <corpname>Springfield Street Railroad</corpname>; material purchased for maintaining motor coaches; 
                                <corpname>Berkshire Street Railway Company</corpname>; [643.32] Reorganization lists of parties of records and interviews; [643.33] Treatment of securities under plan of reorganization; [643.34-.38] Memoranda from Trustees and Board of Directors; contracts; analysis of real estate; petitions: reorganization proceedings; list of road and equipment items retired,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001009" type="Box" label="Text">43</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1935/1949" type="inclusive">1935-1949</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref179" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[643.39] Memoranda from Trustees meeting: severance study, estimated revenues and expenses, petition: reorganization proceedings; maps; analysis of LCL traffic; materials and supplies; passenger terminal for Boston; recapitulating studies; abandonment study of Boston group of the 
                                <corpname>Old Colony Railroad</corpname>;[[643.44] Memoranda of meeting and appointment of Trustees; list of meetings for Board of Directors, stockholders, committee on preparing plan of reorganization; statements of fees and expenses; claims for compensation for services during reorganization proceedings; ICC finance dockets; income account,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001010" type="Box" label="Text">44</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1935/1953" type="inclusive">1935-1953</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref180" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[644] Trustees meetings: memoranda, dockets, land deeds,</unittitle>
                        </did>
                        <c id="ref181" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid1001011" type="Box" label="Text">45</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref182" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid1001012" type="Box" label="Text">46</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref183" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid1001013" type="Box" label="Text">47</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref184" level="file">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle></unittitle>
                                <container id="cid1001014" type="Box" label="Text">48</container>
                                <unitdate normal="1940/1943" type="inclusive">1940-1943</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref185" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[644] Trustees meetings: memoranda, dockets, reports on new legal business,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001015" type="Box" label="Text">49</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1944" type="inclusive">1943-1944</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref186" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[644] Trustees meetings: memoranda, dockets,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001016" type="Box" label="Text">50</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1944/1945" type="inclusive">1944-1945</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref187" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[644] Trustees meetings: memoranda, dockets, petitions,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001017" type="Box" label="Text">51</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1945/1947" type="inclusive">1945-1947</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref188" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[645-645.12] Companies and Subsidiaries: 
                                <corpname>Providence and Worcester Railroad Company</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Norwich and Worcester Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Chatham Railroad Company</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Holyoke and Westfield Railroad Company</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Boston and Providence Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Naugatuck Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Providence, Warren and Bristol Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Housatonic Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Dutchess County Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>New Haven and Northampton Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Harlem River and Portchester Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Boston and New York Air Line</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Wood River Branch Narragansett Pier Railroad</corpname>; memoranda; payment of income taxes and rentals under lease; analysis of earnings; reorganization proceedings; blueprints; ICC finance dockets; summary of accounts; [645.12] Yardmasters, Assistant Yardmasters, and Stationmasters: increase in wages,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001018" type="Box" label="Text">52</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1905/1947" type="inclusive">1905-1947</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref189" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[658] Companies and subsidiaries: memoranda from Trustees meetings; construction of sidetracks; blueprints; supplies; real estate transactions; equipment rental; authority for expenditures; 
                                <corpname>Public Utilities Commission</corpname> (CT) docket; 
                                <corpname>Manufacturers Realty Company</corpname>,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001019" type="Box" label="Text">53</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1938/1947" type="inclusive">1938-1947</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref190" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>[658, 833, 966, 1006] Memoranda from Trustees meetings: companies and subsidiaries; authority of expenditures; 
                                <corpname>Public Utilities Commission</corpname> (CT) docket; installation of sidetracks, General railroad situation: memoranda from Trustees meetings; President 
                                <persname>Patrick McGinnis</persname>' reports, gross operating revenue and other financial information; 
                                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> Management semina; Seminar material on President 
                                <persname>Dwight D. Eisenhower</persname>'s Cabinet Committee report on Transportation; Eastern railroad policies,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001020" type="Box" label="Text">54</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1961" type="inclusive">1942-1961</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref191" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Various histories: 
                                <corpname>Hotel Barclay</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Berkshire Street Railway Company</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Hotel Biltmore</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Hotel Commodore</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Hotel Parklane</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Providence Produce Warehouse Company</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Hotel Roosevelt</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>Hotel Waldorf Astoria</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>, 
                                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname>; Origin and nature of NHRR certificates of interest,</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1001021" type="Box" label="Text">55</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series II: New Company Secretary Files,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1947/1961" type="bulk">Bulk, 1947-1961</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1935/1971" type="inclusive">undated, 1935-1971</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref27">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>These are files of the Corporate Secretary during the "New Company" period following the 1947 reorganization. This series is organized and indexed in the same structure as the OLD COMPANY SECRETARY FILES. It, too, contains the meeting minutes of the Stockholders, Trustees, and Directors, information on employee relations and labor practices, real estate, insurance and finance. This series also contains information on wartime employment, the second reorganization and bankruptcy. Of particular interest are the "Historical Files"--reference files of the early days of the New Haven and its predecessors. This series, like the OLD COMPANY SECRETARY FILES, was retained in the original order used by the Secretary's office; the A numbers are similar to but do not mirror the Old Company A numbers. The series is best accessed by the index cards in conjunction with the listings.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series II: New Company Secretary Files" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg1_series2.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series II: New Company Secretary Files, undated, 1935-1971 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series III: Agreements,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1870/1971" type="inclusive">1870-1971</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref28">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>These are the legal agreements and other legally binding papers between the New Haven and other companies for the use of realty. The AGREEMENTS are arranged in chronological order and are numbered sequentially from 260 to 19520. A partial card index is available to access these agreements. The index is arranged alphabetically by name of the city or town of the property, the name of the property (where one exists), and the company with whom the agreement exists. Additional agreements concerning 
                            <corpname>Grand Central Terminal</corpname> (1848-1959), Mail, Baggage and Carriage (1889-1964), and Park Square property (1895-1959) are arranged at the end of this series. These agreements are not indexed in the card index.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series III: Agreements" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg1_series3.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series III: Agreements, 1870-1971 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series IV: Appropriations,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1916/1948" type="inclusive">1916-1948</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref29">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>These records document the expenditures and acquisitions which improved the railroad. This series contains information on purchases, repairs to and extensions of rails, retirement of equipment, and agreements with other companies. Examples include increasing ton rating for electric locomotives (1917), the purchase of 20 Russian locomotives (1920) and eliminating rail crossings. These are numbered A-5. to 5.719. Listed with the APPROPRIATIONS are script agreements, agreements- equipment trust, and listings of the New Haven's securities. For documents on land acquisition see Series VI, REAL ESTATE; see also records from the COMPTROLLER'S DEPARTMENT and the ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT for documents relating to the day-to-day financial expenditures.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series IV: Appropriations" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg1_series4.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series IV: Appropriations, 1916-1948 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series V: Legal Records,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1840/1940" type="bulk">Bulk, 1840-1940</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1760/1961" type="inclusive">1760-1961</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref30">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series is divided into three subseries: Charters and By-Laws, Legal Agreements and Mortgages and Leases. These records are apparently duplicates of documents found in other series and include documents that do not fit the "A" number scheme. The Charters and By-Laws, 1846-1953, contain materials relating to the incorporation and history of the New Haven and some of its subsidiary companies. The majority of charters and by-laws are from the late 19th and early 20th centuries only. The New Haven charters are listed first, followed by subsidiary companies, listed in alphabetical order by name of the company. The corporate histories, also in this subseries, are arranged separately from the corporate charters and by-laws. The Legal Agreements are mostly nineteenth century documents; these are arranged by type of document. The Mortgages and Leases document the leasing of track and facilities by and from other railroad companies such as the 
                            <corpname>Berkshire Street Railway Company</corpname>, 
                            <corpname>New York Connecting Railway</corpname> and the 
                            <corpname>Stamford Railway Company</corpname>. Documents include leases, agreements and indentures. In addition to the leases, there are records relating to various mortgage bonds and securities issued. The Mortgages and Leases are arranged alphabetically by name of the company.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series V: Legal Records" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg1_series5.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series V: Legal Records, 1760-1961 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series VI: Real Estate,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1917/1968" type="inclusive">1917-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref32">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains documents on real estate holdings and transactions of the New Haven. Included in this series are maps, property descriptions, deeds, valuations, easements (rights to use crossings), and some title claims. The REAL ESTATE documents are filed chronologically by date of transaction. Each document was assigned an "A-12" number by the Secretary's office, A-12. to 12.7675. The documents are accessed by a card index which is arranged alphabetically by location; the card index is not complete.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series VI: Real Estate" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg1_series6.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series VI: Real Estate, 1917-1968 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series VII: First Reorganization,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1935/1947" type="inclusive">1935-1947</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref34">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains documents on real estate holdings and transactions of the New Haven. Included in this series are maps, property descriptions, deeds, valuations, easements (rights to use crossings), and some title claims. The REAL ESTATE documents are filed chronologically by date of transaction. Each document was assigned an "A-12" number by the Secretary's office, A-12. to 12.7675. The documents are accessed by a card index which is arranged alphabetically by location; the card index is not complete.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series VII: First Reorganization" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg1_series7.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series VII: First Reorganization, 1935-1947 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series VIII: Stocks,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1872/1951" type="inclusive">1872-1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref36">
                        <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                        <p>These records concern the company's stock and debentures before and during the first bankruptcy and reorganization. The series is divided into three subseries: Stockholders, New England Stockholders, and Ledger Cards of Stockholders. Stockholders contains correspondence, lists of stockholders, and vouchers about the company stock; these are numbered A-79 to 79.2. New England Stockholders is listings of individuals who held either Preferred Stock, Common Stock, Convertible Indentures and General Mortgage Income Bonds; the listing covers only the New England area. Ledger Cards contains information on who owned Preferred Stock, Convertible Debentures, and Common Stock; brokers are also listed. The cards document when stocks were bought, their value, and when due. Most of the Ledger Cards date 1943-48 and were due in either 1947 or 1948.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series VIII: Stocks" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg1_series8.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series VIII: Stocks, 1872-1951 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series IX: Subsidiary Companies,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1943/1947" type="bulk">Bulk, 1943-1947</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1872/1951" type="inclusive">1872-1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref38">
                        <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                        <p>This series contains documents relating to subsidiary companies of the New Haven. The records are for the following companies:</p>
                        <p>Railroads: 
                            <corpname>Central New England Railway</corpname>
                            <corpname>Hartford Connecticut Western Railroad</corpname>
                            <corpname>New York Connecting Railroad</corpname>
                            <corpname>Providence, Warren Bristol Railroad</corpname>
                            <corpname>Western Shore Railway</corpname></p>
                        <p>Street Railways/Motor Coach Lines: 
                            <corpname>Berkshire Motor Coach Company</corpname>
                            <corpname>Berkshire Street Railway Company</corpname>
                            <corpname>Connecticut Company</corpname>
                            <corpname>Connecticut Railway Lighting Company</corpname>
                            <corpname>County Transportation Company</corpname>
                            <corpname>Interstate Limited Motor Coach</corpname>
                            <corpname>New York Stamford Railway Company</corpname>
                            <corpname>Soundview Transportation Company</corpname></p>
                        <p>Other Companies: 
                            <corpname>New England Steamship Company</corpname>
                            <corpname>New England Airlines Inc.</corpname></p>
                        <p>These represent only a few of the subsidiaries owned by the New Haven. The SUBSIDIARY COMPANIES series contains the organization records of those companies listed. The documents include: bylaws, meeting minutes, legal papers, reorganization plans, reports to the 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> (ICC), and other types of documents. The records are arranged by type of operation (railroad, street railway/motor coaches, marine and airline), and within that, alphabetically by company name. See Appendix C for a detailed listing of this series. See also the BOUND VOLUMES (RG 7) and the ANNUAL REPORTS (RG 3) for additional records of 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> subsidiary, predecessor and successor companies, as well as Series VII, SUBSIDIARY COMPANIES, in the ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT (RG 5).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series IX: Subsidiary Companies" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg1_series9.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series IX: Subsidiary Companies, 1872-1951 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref39" level="recordgrp">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Record Group 2: Trustee's Records,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1920/1980" type="inclusive">1920-1980</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref40">
                    <head>Scope and Content</head>
                    <p>This record group documents the responsibilities and activities of the court-appointed Trustees, especially during the second reorganization period of the 
                        <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>. After a period of financial difficulties in the late 1950's, the New Haven filed a petition for reorganization under Section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act. The petition was granted on 7 July 1961. The 
                        <corpname>United States District Court, District of Connecticut</corpname>, appointed three trustees: 
                        <persname>Richard Joyce Smith</persname>, 
                        <persname>William Johnson Kirk</persname> (appointed in July) and 
                        <persname>Harry William Dorrigan</persname> (appointed in August). Dorrigan served until his death in 1966. Smith and Kirk continued to serve as co-Trustees until 1969. In appointing the Trustees the court stated:</p>
                    <p>"The case does not have as its sole or chief purpose the modification of the debt structure, but the actual survival of the 
                        <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> as a system of transportation for passengers and freight. It will be the task of these men to develop and put into execution a formula designed to achieve this." (Memorandum of Decision on Appointment of Trustees. 26 July 1961.)</p>
                    <p>The records in the TRUSTEES record group reflect the tasks assigned by the Court, that of overseeing financial matters, continuing daily operations, and dealing with state and federal agencies involved in reorganizing the Railroad. The records fall into four broad categories: information gathering, District Court proceedings, 
                        <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> (ICC) hearings on reorganization, and the Pennsylvannia and New York Central Merger.</p>
                    <p>While some records from the first reorganization, 1935-48, do exist in this record group, it seems likely they were maintained as a reference source by the second reorganization's trustees. Records for the first reorganization are located in the SECRETARY and ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT record groups. Note that the container lists provided do not include every file heading found in a particular box; the lists provide only a selected sampling of topics.</p>
                    <p>The detailed description lists the contents for all of the boxes in Record Group 2, Series 1-5.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Record Group 2: Trustee's Records" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg2.pdf">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Record Group 2: Trustee's Records, 1920-1980 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <c id="ref41" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series I: Publications and Reports,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1935/1968" type="bulk">Bulk, 1935-1968</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1920/1980" type="inclusive">1920-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref42">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains records of both the first and second reorganizations. The series is divided into two subseries: Studies and Reports and Bound Volumes. Studies and Reports contains financial and operational information, most of it from the period of the first reorganization. Bound Volumes consists of the printed reorganization proceedings before the U.S. District Court for both periods of reorganization; ICC hearing minutes concerning the Penn Central merger; and the transcripts of hearings before the 
                            <corpname>United States District Court</corpname>.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series II: Trustees Files,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1960/1970" type="bulk">Bulk, 1960-1970</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1920/1972" type="inclusive">1920-1972</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref46">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series is further divided into three subseries: Numerical Files, General Reference Files, and Six Month Claims Files.</p>
                        <p>Numerical Files, 1920-72, contain correspondence, memos, studies and reports, arranged in numerical order, which cover a variety of subjects from abandonments to the ICC and reorganization. Included here is a numerical sequence identified as 
                            <persname>Richard Joyce Smith</persname> files (RJS-O). There is a card index available only for the first section of numerical files.</p>
                        <p>The General Reference Files 1953-70, were used as a basic source of information on technical matters, public opinion, government intervention in the reorganization, and the impact on local service and stations. Many of these files are identified with Trustee 
                            <persname>Harry W. Dorrigan</persname>.</p>
                        <p>Six Month Claims, 1953-68, deals with those claims presented for debts incurred within six months of reorganization. These files contain memos, correspondence and legal records (exhibits and affidavits).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref47" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series III: 
                            <corpname>Penn Central</corpname> Merger,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1962/1975" type="inclusive">1962-1975</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref48">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains correspondence, memoranda, court records, statistical reports, studies and newspaper clippings dealing with the merger of the New Haven Railroad with the 
                            <corpname>Penn Central</corpname>. This material covers proceedings before the 
                            <corpname>U.S. District Court</corpname> and the 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname>. In March of 1962, the 
                            <corpname>Pennsylvania Railroad</corpname> and 
                            <corpname>New York Central Railroad</corpname> filed with the ICC for permission to merge. In June, the Trustees of the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> filed a petition with the ICC for inclusion in that merger. The final Pennsylvania and New York Central merger was granted only on the condition that it include the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>. The merger was approved in April 1966 and executed in 1968. Penn Central Merger material is also available in other series of the TRUSTEES record group.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref49" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series IV: General Counsel,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1961/1982" type="inclusive">1961-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref50">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains the office files of the General Counsel, who reported to the Trustees. It is divided into three subseries: Subject Files, Merger Records, and 
                            <persname>J. W. Moore</persname> Records.</p>
                        <p>The Subject Files, 1961-77, are alphabetically arranged general reference files on a variety of topics.</p>
                        <p>The Merger Records, 1961-73, consist mainly of legal records, hearings and transcripts relating to the reorganization and merger.</p>
                        <p>The final subseries, 
                            <persname>J.W. Moore</persname> Records, 1962-82, contains records maintained by Professor Moore of 
                            <corpname>Yale Law School</corpname>, who served as Counsel to the Trustees. Some material deals with the 
                            <corpname>Penn Central</corpname>'s bankruptcy and the subsequent formation of 
                            <corpname>Conrail</corpname>.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref51" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series V: Treasurer's files,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1960/1975" type="inclusive">1960-1975</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref52">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>Like other series in the TRUSTEES record group, the Treasurer's files deals principally with the New Haven reorganization and merger with the 
                            <corpname>Penn Central</corpname>. Most of the series consists of court transcripts and ICC hearing reports. A significant amount of material deals with the incorporation of the 
                            <corpname>Penn Central</corpname> and other northeastern railroads into 
                            <corpname>Conrail</corpname>.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref53" level="recordgrp">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Record Group 3: Annual Reports,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1835/1976" type="inclusive">1835-1976</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref54">
                    <head>Scope and Content</head>
                    <p>The Annual Reports Record Group contains reports from the Accounting Department to the 
                        <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname>, state regulatory agencies, and public utility commissions, as well as stockholder reports from the Secretary's Department. The annual reports to the ICC and state agencies were the overall responsibility of the Comptroller, who was in charge of the Accounting Department. The intrinsic importance of the records, however, warranted their separate treatment from the Accounting and Secretary departments' records.</p>
                    <p>This record group contains annual reports to the stockholders, to the ICC, and to state regulatory agencies, as well as working papers and appraisal reports. The stockholders annual reports were compiled by the Board of Directors for the stockholders, usually in conjunction with the company's annual meeting. Annual reports filed with the public utility commissions in Connecticut, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, and New York contain information very similar to that submitted to the ICC; in cases where the carrier was not an interstate operator, these state reports are the only reports available.</p>
                    <p>The detailed description lists the contents for all of the boxes in Record Group 3, Series 1-6.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Record Group 3: Annual Reports" ns2:role="Image-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg3.pdf">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Record Group 3: Annual Reports, 1835-1976 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <c id="ref55" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series I: Annual Reports to the Stockholders,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1835/1972" type="inclusive">1835-1972</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref56">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series is divided into two subseries: 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>, 1873-1972, and Subsidiary Companies, 1835-1968. The series contains annual reports to the stockholders, state legislatures, or to courts during periods of trusteeship. The reports contain financial and operating statistics of a more general nature than that of the ICC reports (Series II). The purpose of the reports was to inform stockholders of the financial status and well-being of the company. The reports list the Board members and officers as well as provide information on income and expenses, investments, and operating statistics. In addition, the reports contain a brief narrative summary of the company's activities for the year in question. Reports issued by the NHRR will sometimes contain information on subsidiary operations. Some annual reports contain maps, while later versions include photographs. The reports are printed, bound volumes in most cases; some of them, however, are handwritten or are photocopies. The ANNUAL REPORTS TO THE STOCKHOLDERS are organized by railroad, with the NHRR preceding the subsidiaries. The subsidiaries are arranged alphabetically by company name. Within each company, the reports are arranged chronologically.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref57" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series II: Annual Reports to the 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname>,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1888/1968" type="inclusive">1888-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref58">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series is divided into two subseries: 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> and Subsidiary Companies. The series is composed of reports filed by the NHRR and its subsidiaries in compliance with ICC regulations. The reports contain essential financial, statistical, and operating information of a detailed nature. Included are expenses and income, investments, mileage data, fuel consumption, passenger statistics, employee information, and accidents. One box of reports from the ICC appears at the end of the series. These include reports on NHRR financial transactions, rate investigations and ICC finance docket 21989, 
                            <corpname>Pennsylvannia Railroad</corpname> and 
                            <corpname>New York Central Railroad</corpname> merger. The reports are bound, printed volumes. The 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>, 1888-1968, is arranged in chronological order. The Subsidiary Companies, 1888-1966, is alphabetically arranged by company name, then in chronological order; gaps within the span dates are not indicated.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref59" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series III: Annual Reports to the States,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1874/1957" type="inclusive">1874-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref60">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains reports filed by the NHRR and its subsidiary companies with various state regulatory agencies as required by law. These states include Connecticut, Massachusetts, New York, and Rhode Island. The reports contain financial, statistical, and operating information pertaining to intrastate commerce in the state to which the report was submitted. The reports are bound, printed volumes. The 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>, 1888-1914, reports are in chronological order. The Subsidiary Companies, 1874-1957, reports are arranged alphabetically by company name and then filed in chronological order; gaps within the span dates are not indicated.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref61" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series IV: Annual Reports to the 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname>: Foreign Roads,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1948/1963" type="inclusive">1948-1963</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref62">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains reports to the ICC and to stockholders from "foreign roads." "Foreign roads" are defined as any operation (railroad) not directly affiliated with the NHRR. Although the exact reason why the records were maintained is unclear, it is likely they were used as a reference source on railroads that did per diem (rental fee for use of tracks) business with the NHRR. The reports are printed, bound volumes. Reports are arranged in a rough chronological order, with each box in alphabetical order by company. Gaps within the span dates are not indicated.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref64" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series V: Annual Reports: Working Records,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1931/1959" type="inclusive">1931-1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref65">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains the supporting files related to the preparation of the annual reports required by the ICC, various state regulatory agencies, and stockholder reports. The records include corrections submitted, amendments, requisitions, correspondence, and filing fees. Included are records of both the NHRR and its subsidiaries. The files contain information pertinent to both the annual and quarterly reports to the ICC. The WORKING RECORDS are arranged alphabetically by company name, but preceded by NHRR records. Within each company, the records are in reverse chronological order.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref66" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series VI: Appraisal Reports,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1909/1976" type="inclusive">1909-1976</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref67">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains a small number of appraisal and valuation reports made of the land and physical property directly owned by the NHRR or the land and physical property of NHRR subsidiary companies. Most of these reports were issued by the accounting firm of Price Waterhouse. Information in the valuation and appraisal reports includes right-of-ways, rails, structures and land. NHRR reports are listed first, followed by an alphabetical list of subsidiary company reports. The dates of the actual appraisal and of the report are listed.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref68" level="recordgrp">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Record Group 4: Comptroller's Records,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1905/1969" type="inclusive">1905-1969</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref69">
                    <head>Scope and Content</head>
                    <p>The Comptroller was an elected officer of the 
                        <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> in charge of the Accounting Department. The Comptroller's Department supervised and directed all accounts relating to receipts and disbursements. The Comptroller had custody of the general books and accounts, vouchers, drafts, payrolls, invoices, interest coupons, bonds, and other evidence of payment; he also maintained the bonds, interest coupons and other evidence of cancelled debt. The office was responsible for preparing annual reports, which evaluated the financial situation of the company, and submitting the reports to the 
                        <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> (ICC), various state utility regulatory agencies and the stockholders. For ease of access, the ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT records and ANNUAL REPORTS are maintained as distinct record groups.</p>
                    <p>The records of the COMPTROLLER provide the researcher with a better look at company administration and policy-making than the related ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT records. Few of these records contain routine finance and operation details.</p>
                    <p>This record group is divided into three series: I COMPTROLLER II DEPUTY COMPTROLLER III ASSISTANT COMPTROLLER</p>
                    <p>Each series is arranged numerically by a number assigned by the company; no topical index to the numbers was found in the records. The box lists that follow are sample topics included in the files rather than a list of each folder in the box.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref70" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series I: Comptroller,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1944/1964" type="bulk">Bulk, 1944-1964</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1905/1968" type="inclusive">1905-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref71">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series documents the activities of the Comptroller. The series shows employee relations in some detail. There are files on employee agreements, payroll and benefits, working conditions and strikes. The series also contains extensive information on passenger fares and relations, including claims. Located here are financial statistics, revenue forecasts, revenue reports, costs studies and audit reports. Apparently, the Comptroller acted as one of the major information distributors in the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>. Information was sent to publications and associations, such as the 
                            <corpname>Association of American Railroads</corpname> (AAR). The department maintained files on meetings, membership associations, and charities. There is also a substantial amount of information on government relations and tax issues.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series I: Comptroller" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg4_series1-2.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series I: Comptroller, 1905-1968 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref72" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series II: Deputy Comptroller,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1953/1967" type="bulk">Bulk, 1953-1967</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1915/1969" type="inclusive">1915-1969</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref73">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains the records of this office which acted as a direct assistant to the Comptroller; most of the files in this series are associated with Deputy Comptroller 
                            <persname>A. J. Beauton</persname>. The DEPUTY COMPTROLLER files do not differ greatly from those of the Comptroller; they include information on subsidiary companies, audits, insurance, expenditures, and agreements. The records in Series I more completely document employee relations and passenger service and relations than does Series II. This series has been combined with Series I for the web presentation of the finding aid.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series II: Deputy Comptroller" ns2:role="Image-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg4_series1-2.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series II: Deputy Comptroller, 1915-1969 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref74" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series III: Assistant Comptroller,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1945/1955" type="bulk">Bulk, 1945-1955</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1921/1965" type="inclusive">1921-1965</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref75">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series overlaps in content with Series I and II. More than the previous two series, this series contains records similar to those found in the ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT record group. This series also includes an important subseries of Abandonment Files, which document the last years of operation of branches. These are arranged by rail line within each state. There is also a significant amount of material on the subsidiary companies, including the 
                            <corpname>New York Connecting Railroad</corpname>, the 
                            <corpname>Connecticut Company</corpname> and 
                            <corpname>New England Transportation Company</corpname>. Information on hotel properties, the 
                            <corpname>Grand Central Terminal</corpname> building, and freight operations is available in this series.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series III: Assistant Comptroller" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg4_series3.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series III: Assistant Comptroller, 1921-1965 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref76" level="recordgrp">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Record Group 5: Accounting Department,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1890/1970" type="inclusive">1890-1970</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref77">
                    <head>Scope and Content</head>
                    <p>The Accounting Department served three basic functions:</p>
                    <p>l. to receive revenues for rail services 2. to ensure proper payment of bills and salaries 3. to maintain a record of financial and operating statistics for use in annual reports.</p>
                    <p>Company by-laws (l953) state that "the Comptroller shall have general charge of the Accounting Department. . . . He shall prepare and submit an annual statement of the financial condition of the company . . ." The Accounting office answered to the Comptroller and was responsible for preparing balance sheets and income statements for the NHRR as well as furnishing federal and state regulatory agencies with monthly, quarterly and annual reports. For ease of access, the ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT, ANNUAL REPORTS, and COMPTROLLERS RECORDS are maintained as distinct record groups.</p>
                    <p>The Accounting Department was responsible for contract payments, such as equipment installments, obligations, bond interest and dividends. It collected mortgage installments and interest receivable. The budget was assembled by the Accounting Office. It controlled accounting activities at 
                        <corpname>Grand Central Terminal</corpname> and oversaw company operation in the terminal area. In addition to its financial responsibilities, the Accounting Department compiled extensive files of railroad operating statistics, such as hourly wage rates, operating cost per train mile/car mile/ton and passenger mile.</p>
                    <p>The Accounting Office records are far from complete. They are best used in conjunction with the SECRETARY RECORDS (RG 1), the COMPTROLLERS RECORDS (RG 4), and the BOUND VOLUMES (RG 7) for a more complete picture.</p>
                    <p>Many of the records of the Accounting Department were judged to have low informational and research value. Journal entries and vouchers were sampled and heavily weeded, as described below. In addition, the following files were discarded: 
                        <corpname>Grand Central Terminal</corpname> bills collectable,13 linear feet; Per Diem files, 6 linear feet; and baggage claims, 1 linear foot.</p>
                    <p>The detailed description lists the contents for all of the boxes in Record Group 5, Series 1-10.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Record Group 5: Accounting Department" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg5.pdf">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Record Group 5: Accounting Department, 1890-1970 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <c id="ref78" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series I: General Subject Files,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1940/1960" type="bulk">Bulk, 1940-1960</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1895/1968" type="inclusive">1895-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref79">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains a wealth of information on subjects ranging from the history of the 
                            <corpname>Connecticut Company</corpname> to board meeting data. This catch-all series includes press releases, operating statistics and some 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Committee</corpname> and 
                            <corpname>Securities and Exchange Commission</corpname> investigation files. The accompanying container list is not a complete folder listing and researchers are advised to use it only as a general guide to the 36 boxes. The series is arranged in a random fashion by subject heading, and includes material on both the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> and subsidiary companies.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref80" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series II: Closed Subject Files,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1920/1970" type="inclusive">1920-1970</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref81">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains inactive files on matters that were closed. Like the GENERAL SUBJECT FILES above, the series is a mix of completed contracts and agreements as well as noncurrent subsidiary, 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> and investment files. Here also are some Abandonments hearings files, l962-69, before the ICC.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref82" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series III: 
                            <corpname>Securities and Exchange Commission</corpname>,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1935/1950" type="inclusive">1910-1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref83">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains reports to the 
                            <corpname>Securities and Exchange Commission</corpname> (SEC) filed by the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> and many of its subsidiary lines. These reports, filed in accordance with the Securities and Exchange Act of l934, give information on securities registered by corporations, companies in bankruptcy and receivership, and those that did not file reports with the 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname>. The series includes the proofs and working papers for the SEC reports, as well as reports on gross earnings and taxes to 
                            <geogname>New York State</geogname>.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref84" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series IV: Portfolios,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1933/1948" type="bulk">Bulk, 1933-1948</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1904/1952" type="inclusive">1904-1952</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref85">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains bound portfolios listing the stocks and bonds owned by the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> and its subsidiary lines. In addition to lists of stocks and bonds, the volumes also contain general statements of income, expenditures, and accounts. Some of the information for the NHRR is presented in an alternate accounting system. The series is arranged in chronological order by year with the NHRR portfolios preceeding the subsidiary lines.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref86" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series V: Rate Structure Studies and Cases,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1950/1953" type="bulk">Bulk, 1950-1953</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1936/1953" type="inclusive">1936-1953</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref87">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series provides the researcher with material which documents, in part, the relationship between the 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> and the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>. This series includes reports, testimony transcripts, and printed reports resulting from hearings held by the ICC concerning rate increases. Most of the material presented is financial and statistical data in support of the New Haven's argument. There is also a record of the testimony by those rail users who opposed the rate increase. The records are arranged by case number, then chronologically.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref88" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series VI: First Reorganization,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1945" type="inclusive">1937-1945</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref89">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series documents, during 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> hearings, the impact of the first court ordered reorganization on the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> and its subsidiary lines. These essential accounting records contain a wealth of financial and statistical information within the various reporter's and stenographer's minutes, exhibits, and reports filed with the ICC. The material is arranged either by exhibit number or in a very rough chronological order. First Reorganization records are also located in the SECRETARY RECORDS. Information on the Second Reorganization is located in the TRUSTEES RECORDS.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref90" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series VII: Subsidiary Companies,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1938/1962" type="inclusive">1938-1962</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref91">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series is composed of records pertaining to a number of 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> subsidiaries companies. The 
                            <corpname>Connecticut Company</corpname>, l948-62, consists of financial statements and reports, contracts, and audit reports. The 
                            <corpname>New England Transportation</corpname> records deal with 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> investigations and quarterly reports, l938-1967. Trial balances, company history, income accounts, and journal entries, l928-196l, are available for the 
                            <corpname>Providence Produce Warehouse</corpname>. The records from 
                            <corpname>County Transportation</corpname> pertain to hearings before the 
                            <corpname>New York Public Service Commission</corpname>; the hearings dockets and minutes cover the period l946-48. Correspondence regarding the sale of the 
                            <corpname>Soundview Transportation Company</corpname>, l946-48, is contained in this series. Also see Series IX, SUBSIDIARY COMPANIES, in the SECRETARY RECORDS (RG 1).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref92" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series VIII: Claims,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1940" type="inclusive">1930-1940</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref93">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series deals with death, injury, tax, and property damage claims filed by individuals and corporations with the 
                            <corpname>Federal District Court</corpname> during reorganization proceedings. These claims were submitted as proof that the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> was in debt to the party involved before it declared bankruptcy. They are arranged in numerical order by file number. An index, including a summary of each claim, is available in the first box of this series. See also the LEGAL DEPARTMENT CLAIMS record group.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref94" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series IX: Budget,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1946/1957" type="inclusive">1946-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref95">
                        <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                        <p>This series contains the working papers, income accounts, estimates, and forecasts used to prepare the company's budget. This series contains the working papers for the budget. The final operating figures are not in this series.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref96" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series X: Journal Entries and Vouchers,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1890/1967" type="inclusive">1890-1967</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref97">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains a sample of journal entries and vouchers for different periods of time for both the 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> and its subsidiary lines. The series also contains microfilmed journal entries, 1920-1940. The information contained in the journal entries and vouchers is available in summary form in the BOUND VOLUMES (RG 7). Within the record type, the materials are arranged by company, then chronologically.</p>
                        <p>The journal entries and vouchers were sampled to provide a physical example of these record types. Sampling reduced the journal entries from 154 linear feet to one linear foot, and reduced the vouchers from 90 linear feet to one linear foot. The sampling procedure used for the journal entries was to retain one inch of these folded documents from each of approximately 30 randomly-selected boxes, including at least one box from each company represented in the files. A similar procedure was used in sampling the vouchers. Neither sample is statistically reliable.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref98" level="recordgrp">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Record Group 6: Legal Department Claims,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1915/1975" type="inclusive">1915-1975</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref99">
                    <head>Scope and Content</head>
                    <p>The Claims Department reported to the General Attorney's office in the Legal Department. Headed by the General Claim Agent, the Claims Department was divided along state lines with district offices in New Haven, Boston, New York City, and Providence. (This record group contains no claims from the Providence district office.)</p>
                    <p>The Claims Department was responsible for investigating personal injury and accident claims of passengers and employees, as well as property damage and fire claims. District claims agents, with the assistance of special representatives, were responsible for investigating the claims and for obtaining all relevant information, including claimant interviews, photographs, medical records, etc. Most claims were settled out of court, but in some cases the claims were eventually brought to civil court, either on the federal or state level. This record group contains files from both out of court settlements and actual court cases. These claims have been sampled from a much larger group of records. The various sampling procedures for each series of claims are explained in the series descriptions below. Photographs have been removed from the discarded records and are located in the New Haven Railroad Photographs Collection. Note that additional claims are located in Series VIII of the ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT record group.</p>
                    <p>The detailed description lists the contents for all of the boxes in Record Group 6, Series 1-3.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Record Group 6: Legal Department Claims" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg6.pdf">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Record Group 6: Legal Department Claims, 1915-1975 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <c id="ref100" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series I: Personal Injury Accident Out-of-Court Settlements,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1944/1970" type="inclusive">1944-1970</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref101">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains completed claim report forms, correspondence, newspaper clippings and photographs. The series is further divided into three subseries: New Haven District, 1944-70, Boston District, 1964-68, and 
                            <corpname>New England Transportation Company</corpname>, 1944-60. Within each series, the files are arranged numerically by claim file number; the file numbers listed are not inclusive numbers due to the sampling procedures applied to the records.</p>
                        <p>New Haven District subseries originally included over 400 linear feet of files. After appraisal it was decided to retain only a 5% representative sample. The first and last box and every 22nd box in between were retained, representing the types of claims files maintained by the company during this 26-year period. The sample is not statistically reliable. The Boston District files originally consisted of 67 linear feet of records, in 27 transfile boxes; one inch of files was retained from each box. 
                            <corpname>New England Transportation Company</corpname> claim records originally included 20 linear feet and were sampled as follows: 3 inches of files were taken from the first and last boxes and from every 5th box in between.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref102" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series II: Personal Injury Accident Court Cases,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1960/1975" type="inclusive">1960-1975</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref103">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains records of cases heard in 
                            <corpname>Federal District Court</corpname>, 
                            <corpname>State Supreme Court</corpname> and 
                            <corpname>Superior Court</corpname>. The records include completed claims forms, correspondence, hearing transcripts, newspaper clippings and photographs. Series II is divided into three subseries: Connecticut Court Cases, 1960-75, Boston Court Cases, 1960-75, and New York Court Cases, 1960-75.</p>
                        <p>Series II was sampled using a "fat file" sampling method in which files one inch thick or more were retained. The New York Court Cases originally contained nine linear feet and was reduced to six linear feet. The Connecticut Court Cases originally contained 14 linear feet and was reduced to six linear feet. The Boston Court Cases contained 50 linear feet and was reduced to 21 linear feet.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref104" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series III: Fire and Livestock Claims,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1915/1945" type="inclusive">1915-1945</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref105">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains claims for damages from fires and to livestock caused by locomotives. All the claims in this series were settled out of court. The record types in this series include completed claims forms, correspondence, and photographs. This subseries was retained intact, with no sampling.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref106" level="recordgrp">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Record Group 7: Bound Volumes,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1802/1980" type="inclusive">1802-1980</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref107">
                    <head>Scope and Content</head>
                    <p>This record group consists of bound volumes which require special shelving because of their format, size, and bulk. In general, the volumes are in poor or fragile condition and should be handled with care. These records were originally created by offices represented in other record groups, or by other companies. The BOUND VOLUMES include records of both the 
                        <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> and its subsidiary and predecessor companies. The subsidiary and predecessor companies are primarily New England transportation companies: railroads, railways, coach lines, and steamship lines; there are also a few companies of other types, such as real estate and coal companies.</p>
                    <p>The type of information found within the bound volumes varies widely with each company and may include one or more of the following: organizational, incorporation and termination information; minutes of board of directors' and stockholders' meetings; reorganization proceedings and related trusteeships; acquisitions of other companies; daily financial transactions arranged by date (journal entries) and by account (ledger entries); cash transactions (cash books); balance sheets; annual reports to the 
                        <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname>; stock certificates, registers, journals, ledgers and dividends; bonds and mortgages; and letter books. This record group contains approximately 850 linear feet of material.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref108" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series I: 
                            <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname>,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1872/1980" type="inclusive">1872-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref109">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains those volumes generated by the 
                            <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> and is divided into five subseries: Secretary's Office, Accounting Department, Comptroller's Office, Securities, and 
                            <persname>L. S. Miller</persname>.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series I: New Haven Railroad" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg7_series1.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series I: New Haven Railroad, 1872-1980 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                    <c id="ref111" level="subseries">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Subseries A: Secretary's Office,</unittitle>
                            <unitdate normal="1872/1963" type="inclusive">1872-1963</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref112">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This subseries is comprised of the minutes of the Board of Directors (BOD) and its committees, minutes of stockholders meetings, minutes of trustees meetings during the first reorganization (1935-47), and reorganization proceedings. There are two sets of the BOD minutes. The first set of minutes has an index for each volume, with volumes 31 to 33 each having an additional copy. These indices are placed in front of the appropriate volume, beginning with volume 3. The exception is volume 14, which is partially indexed with volume 13 and does not have a unique index. The index for volume one is separate from its volume due to its physical size. The index for volume 2 (No. 2), which is interfiled with the index for the minutes of the standing committee (S. com.), is located on index cards. The second set of minutes has an index which is located in the front of each volume. It is strongly recommended that the researcher use the typescript minutes located in Series I and II in the SECRETARY record group. The Secretary's Office subseries also contains charters and legislation pertaining to the 
                                <corpname>New Haven Railroad</corpname> and its predecessors and subsidiaries, and an index to Rhode Island railroad legislation to 1901.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref113" level="subseries">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Subseries B: Accounting Department,</unittitle>
                            <unitdate normal="1872/1969" type="inclusive">1872-1969</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref114">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>These volumes include journals, ledgers, balances, the 
                                <corpname>Grand Central Terminal</corpname> Capital Account, accounting procedures, other financial accounts, and registers and records of bonds, debentures, mortgages, warrants and stocks. The journals and ledgers are organized by type, i.e. Chief Clerks, General, Federal Control, and Materials and Supplies, and then by date. Between 1914 and 1918, even-number General Journal entries were entered into one volume and odd- numbered entries into the next volume. This division of even and odd entries also occurred in the Federal Control and 
                                <corpname>U. S. Railroad Administration</corpname> journals between 1918 and 1922. Most of the General Ledgers are indexed. These indexes are generally separate volumes but are placed in the front of their respective volumes. Many of the other journals are also indexed, usually on the inside front cover or the first few pages of the volume.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref118" level="subseries">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Subseries C: Comptroller's Office,</unittitle>
                            <unitdate normal="1902/1950" type="inclusive">1902-1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref119">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This subseries contains statistics on passengers and freight, reports on other companies, and the financial records of insurance funds (accident and casualty, coal, and general) overseen by trustees of the 
                                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname>. (These trustees are unrelated to those that oversaw the reorganization periods of 1935-48 and 1962-80.)</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref120" level="subseries">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Subseries D: Securities,</unittitle>
                            <unitdate normal="1899/1968" type="inclusive">1899-1968</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref121">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This subseries contains minutes of the custodians of securities and histories of securities. See the ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT record group for portfolios.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref122" level="subseries">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Subseries E: 
                                <persname>L. S. Miller</persname>,</unittitle>
                            <unitdate normal="1911/1930" type="inclusive">1911-1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref123">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This subseries contains the files of 
                                <persname>L. S. Miller</persname>, who was an agent of the 
                                <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> and of the 
                                <corpname>National Bank of Commerce</corpname>. This subseries contains his journals, ledgers, mortgage records and other financial materials.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref110" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series II: Predecessor and Subsidiary Companies,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1802/1964" type="inclusive">1802-1964</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref115">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series also includes leased lines, and is arranged alphabetically by company name. Within each company, volumes are arranged by type: minutes; journals; cash books; ledgers; pay roll and voucher records; balance and trial balance sheets; bond and stock certificates, transfers and ledgers; letter books; and miscellaneous records (e.g., reorganization proceedings, passenger train records, contract books). Not all companies have all of these types of volumes. Preceding the listing of volumes, the name of the company is often followed by a brief history of the company and may include some or all of the following types of information: date of incorporation, date of organization, name changes, mergers, foreclosures, consolidation with other companies, names of predecessor and successor companies, and date of termination of corporate existance. The material for these histories is drawn from the 1915 chart of lines owned by the 
                            <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> Company, Charters of the 
                            <corpname>New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Railroad</corpname> Company and certain of its subsidiary lines together with the special legislation relating to the same (New Haven, 1906) and its supplements, and records of the companies themselves. These histories are intended only as a guide for cross-referencing. Additional cross-referencing is provided.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series II: Predecessor and Subsidiary Companies" ns2:role="Image-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg7_series2.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series II: Predecessor and Subsidiary Companies, 1802-1964 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref116" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series III: Multiple-Company volumes,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1831/1953" type="inclusive">1831-1953</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref117">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>This series contains volumes that were either used by or contain the records of two or more companies. Typically, the companies are related by mergers and consolidations as in the case of the joint volumes of the 
                            <corpname>New York and Stamford Railway Company</corpname> and the 
                            <corpname>Greenwich Tramway Company</corpname>, which predate the acquisition of both companies by the Consolidated Railway in 1905. The MULTIPLE-COMPANY VOLUMES are arranged alphabetically by the name of the first company listed. (This series does not include volumes that were used by a company and its immediate predecessor or successor. Volumes of that type are located in Series II.)</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Series III: Multiple-Company volumes" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_rg7_series3.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Series III: Multiple-Company volumes, 1831-1953 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref124" level="series">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Series IV: Unidentified volumes,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref125">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>These are volumes whose generating company could not be determined. They are arranged by type (e.g., journal, ledger), and then by date. Possible originating company identification is included, when the information could be determined, in bracketed notes on the type of company (e.g., trolley, steamship), the location of head or regional office, or the names of vessels and stations. Most of these volumes are in extremely poor or fragile physical condition. NOTE: Researchers who are able to identify any of these volumes should notify the Archives staff.</p>
                        <p>There is no detailed description of the volumes in this series.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref126" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Appendices,</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref127" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Appendix A: Secretary Records: Index Card Files,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Appendix A: Secretary Records: Index Card Files" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_appendix_a.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Appendix A: Secretary Records: Index Card Files, undated </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref128" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Appendix B: Historical Files,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1920/1965" type="inclusive">undated, 1920-1965</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref129">
                        <head>Scope and Content</head>
                        <p>These files are contained in Boxes 159 and 160 of RG1, Series I.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Appendix B: Historical Files" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_appendix_b.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Appendix B: Historical Files, undated, 1920-1965 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref130" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Appendix C: Record Group 1: Series IX: Subsidiary Companies,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1958" type="inclusive">1893-1958</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Appendix C: Record Group 1: Series IX: Subsidiary Companies" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_appendix_c.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Appendix C: Record Group 1: Series IX: Subsidiary Companies, 1893-1958 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
                <c id="ref131" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Appendix D: 
                            <corpname>Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname> Finance Docket/Ex Parte Docket Numbers/
                            <corpname>Public Utilities Commission</corpname> Docket Numbers,</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1940/1973" type="inclusive">1940-1973</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Appendix D: Interstate Commerce Commission Finance Docket/Ex Parte Docket Numbers/Public Utilities Commission Docket Numbers" ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/NHRR/1991-0009_appendix_d.pdf">
                        <daodesc>
                            <p>Appendix D: Interstate Commerce Commission Finance Docket/Ex Parte Docket Numbers/Public Utilities Commission Docket Numbers, 1940-1973 </p>
                        </daodesc>
                    </dao>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
