<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">
<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
<eadid mainagencycode="US-CtU" countrycode="US">MSS19980339</eadid>
<filedesc>
    <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>University of Connecticut, Agricultural Economics Department Records</titleproper>
            <subtitle/>
            <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicola Shayer.</author><sponsor>This finding aid was prepared with generous support from Amy Albert.</sponsor>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>&#x00A9; 2010  University of Connecticut</publisher>
            <date type="publication">July 2010</date>
            <address>
               <addressline>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center</addressline>
               <addressline>405 Babbidge Road, Unit 1205</addressline>
               <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut  06269-1205</addressline>
		<addressline> URL: http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/ </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Finding aid encoded by Betsy Pittman in December 2010.</creation>
         <langusage>
            <language>English</language>
         </langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date normal="20040323">July 30, 2010</date>
            <item>MSS19980339 converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02.xsl (sy2003-10-15).</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" type="Inventory">
      <did id="a1">
         <head>Overview of the Records</head>
         <repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
            <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center</corpname>.</repository>
         <origination label="Creator:">
            <corpname encodinganalog="110">University of Connecticut, Agricultural Economics Department</corpname>.</origination>
         <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">University of Connecticut, Agricultural Economics Department Records.</unittitle>
         <unitdate label="Dates:">undated, 1840-1951.</unitdate>
         <physdesc label="Extent:" encodinganalog="300$a">83  linear feet. </physdesc>
         <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">The collection reflects the many bureaucratic permutations of the Department of Agricultural Economics from the late 1910s until after World War II. The collection spans many institutional name changes and reorganizations.  The bulk of the collection is documentation from the Extension Service, which was headed by one of three Directors of the school, then known as Connecticut Agricultural College, with the President as the Executive head of the College. Under him were three Directors, the two others being the Faculty and the Director of Instruction, and the Director of the Experimental Station.</abstract>
         <unitid encodinganalog="090" label="Record Series:" countrycode="US" repositorycode="UCW">MSS19980339</unitid>
         <langmaterial label="Language">
            <language langcode="eng">English.</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did><!-- COLLECTION METADATA GO HERE: -->
      <bioghist altrender="biography" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
         <head>History</head>
         <p>This Collection reflects the many bureaucratic permutations of the Agricultural Economics Department at the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> from the late 1910s until after World War II. The Collection spans many institutional name changes and reorganizations. The University itself underwent three during this time period.  In 1899, the institution was chartered as the <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> until 1933, when the name was changed to <corpname>Connecticut State College</corpname>. In 1939, the name was changed to the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>.  The documents reflect these name  changes.</p>
         <p>The bulk of the collection is documentation from the Extension Service, which was headed by one of three Directors of the school, then known as <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname>, with the President as the Executive head of the College.  Under him were three Directors, the two others being the Faculty and the Director of  Instruction, and the Director of the Experimental Station.</p>
         <p>The Extension Service, described in the College <title render="italic">Bulletin</title>  as, "...the division of the college that carries on all of the non-resident educational work of the institution. Extension teaching is done through personal and circular letters,  farm and home visits, bulletins, news and special articles, radio, meetings, classes, and in other ways" , was formalized in 1914.  The Extension Service served the state, in the words of the State College <title render="italic">Biennial Report</title>: "As our agriculture becomes more intensive and competition becomes keener, the simple practices of the past must give place to highly technical methods of production and marketing. If <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>'s farming is to continue prosperous, (sic) it will demand more and more research, and will not be satisfied with superficial work." </p>
         <p>This quote is a reference to the early 20th century trend toward the industrialization of agriculture, as well as the application of scientific methodology in order to maximize the economic benefits of farming.  Farming had been a local economy that simultaneously sustained local families and brought in small local profits. When the war intervened, the Federal government found ways to turn local products into commodities that people could profit from, even when the commodity was not yet considered a staple of family life. For example, during World War I, an extension economist noted that,  "Milk was the one surplus food in <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> and a campaign to induce children to drink more milk was instituted." </p>
         <p>The combination of Federal, State and County funding for the University Extension Service eventually resulted in a Cooperative Organization between the four groups. Initially, the <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> was given State and Federal funding to provide agricultural training to local farmers before and during World  War I. These training networks were expanded upon during the war, and were firmly in place  by the time of the Depression.</p>
         <p>According to the book, <title render="italic">Connecticut Agricultural College - A History</title> by Walter Stemmons, the combination of Federal and State funding helped to   "extend...the college campus to the boundary of the state."   The Extension service began as an  outgrowth of the Cooperative orchard demonstrations held jointly by the College and the <corpname>Connecticut Pomological Service</corpname>. By 1915, Professor <persname>I.G. Davis</persname> became the Assistant State Leader of Extension Services,  which was organized by county. Their marketing materials began with the <title render="italic">Farm Bureau News</title>, which became the <title render="italic">Extension Service News</title>, and was  finally entitled the <title render="italic">Connecticut Agricultural College (CAC) Review</title>, with <persname>I.G. Davis</persname> serving as editor. </p>
         <p>The pre-World War I years saw the Extension Service set goals to professionalize agriculture.  They began by chronicling markets, which were previously not monitored or quantified, "[I]n 1917 the Extension service, in cooperation with the United States Bureau of Markets and the Bridgeport fruit and vegetable association, established a daily reporting service on the Bridgeport market. These records are in the non-processed portion of the collection. The success of this plan led to its extension the following summer to Hartford, New Haven and Waterbury. Later the egg market was included in the reports. From this beginning developed a state-wide market reporting service." </p>
         <p>The Extension Service was responsible for other areas, such as field crops, sheep, animal husbandry, and bee-keeping. Records for these endeavors are not included in this collection, nor is farm/home engineering or forestry. However, fruit and vegetable surveys are included. In addition, there are Home Demonstration surveys, which have quantified the financial aspects of running a domestic economy. However, this Collection also includes handwritten notes from the surveyors themselves. These field agent notebooks give background information on some of the women surveyed, especially those reluctant to participate, "[s]he seems to delight in being pernicious." These records are in the non-processed portion of the collection.</p>
         <p>The First World War contributed to growth of the Extension Service, financially speaking, "What the war did was to speed up the machinery tremendously and to make available financial resources far beyond the expectancy of natural growth. It also provided contacts and elements of cooperation little short of impossible in peace time."  Surveys were the method used to quantify agricultural production, as well poultry farms.   In addition, farm management surveys were implemented,  "During the first two years of the extension service about one thousand farm management records were taken in each of seven counties as a basis for the new county movement."  Although the survey covers acres tilled, and livestock owned, there is, in addition,  personal information such as nationality, education, and standard of living survey information which provides a revealing indication of how government judged quality of life.</p>
         <p>By 1925, the Director of the Extension Service, Mr. Ellis, described the interconnections between the then <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> (CAC), the local  farming population, and the Federal government, "The Extension service is the division of the CAC which is extending information on improved methods in agriculture and home making to the rural population of the state. The extension service in Connecticut is a part of a  National system of agricultural education established by federal laws."  This seemingly  altruistic desire to help rural populations would change as the Extension Service and the County agents who worked for the Extension Service used their local ties to help the  Federal Government recruit farm labor during World War II in order to help large  agricultural industries in Connecticut stay economically viable.</p>
         <p>By the pre-World War II years, according to the <title render="italic">Connecticut Agricultural Bulletin</title>,  for the year 1932-1933, the Connecticut Agricultural College's  Division of Agriculture was one of five Divisions of the school. The other four included the  Division of Arts and Sciences, the Division of Home economics, the Division of Mechanical  Engineering, and the Division of Teacher Training.  The Directory of Courses at this time was organized by subject heading, alphabetically,  and includes Agricultural Engineering, Agronomy, Animal Husbandry, Bacteriology and Animal Disease, Botany, Chemistry, Dairy Industry,  Economics, Education, English, Farm Management, French, Forestry, Geography, History, Home  Economics, Textiles, Food and Nutrition, Home Administration, Horticulture, Mathematics,  Mechanical Engineering, Military Science, Physical Education, Physics, Poultry Husbandry,  Religious Education, Sociology, and Zoology.</p>
         <p>It is under the Subject Heading 'Economics' in the Directory of Courses where Agricultural Economics, and Agricultural Marketing, and Cooperative Association Marketing are found.   The Professors listed, among others, Professor <persname>I.G. Davis</persname>, and Extension Economist <persname>E. Perregaux</persname>, who have extensive correspondence in the unprocessed portion of the collection.</p>
         <p>This was the organization in place before World War II's labor shortages, and the statement below is an illustration of the overlap between College teachers, Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station staff, the Extension Service and local farm bureaus, and their creation by State and Federal legislation: </p>
         <p>"In addition to the 57 men and women formally engaged for this work, the members of the resident teaching staff of the College and the staff of the Connecticut agricultural experiment station make valuable contributions to extension teaching. Of those regularly appointed to the Extension staff, twenty-six have their headquarters at the College and work throughout the State, primarily as specialist in particular fields, and thirty-one are engaged as county agents in agriculture, home making or boys and girls' club work and have their headquarters in the offices of the Farm Bureau of their respective counties. Extension teaching deals principally with agriculture and home making, but its field is gradually broadening. It now includes at least modest beginnings in economics, the physical and biological sciences, music, dramatics and recreation. The Extension Service in Connecticut is a unit of a national system of education established by State and Federal laws. The work is centered at the College under the Director of Extension, who is responsible to the President and through him to the Trustees of the College and to the Secretary of the <corpname>United States Department of Agriculture</corpname>."</p>
         <p>The institutional lines between the Extension Service and the Agricultural Division are also blurry, "[b]esides their regular teaching duties at the college, the members of the staff of the Agriculture Division have delivered numerous addresses to agricultural societies and other farm organizations both within and without the state. Residential instruction is integrated with the Experimental Station and the Extension services. A number of instructors belong to both the residential instruction faculty and the extension service faculty" . </p>
         <p>In his 1934 report as Director of the Extension Service, Mr. Ellis describes the beginnings of the connection between the Extension service and local markets, which would be broadened during World War II.  This time period is when emergency projects were implemented, presumably due to the Depression. Ellis writes, "[t]he Extension service was called upon by the Agricultural Adjustment Administration to administer the adjustment programs that affect Connecticut. The Extension Service helped with such problems as the tobacco acreage reduction program, dairy marketing problem, the economic ramifications of chain stores who did not use local goods."   The marketing specialists also worked with county agents and state bureau markets to improve marketing methods by creating uniform packaging of fruits and vegetables.  They also assisted vegetable farmers in keeping account books, and poultry farm management extension workers aided farmers with problems of farm organization such as helping farmers refinance their debts.</p>
         <p>By 1942, and during World War II, bureaucratic changes included the appropriation of the name the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>, and the establishment of the <corpname>College of Agriculture</corpname> which incorporated the Extension Service into one of its three branches, including Resident Instruction, <corpname>Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station</corpname>, and Extension Service. It is this period of the collection that is represented in this finding aid. </p>
         <p>Although the Extension service continued to describe itself as "...mak[ing] available to the people of the State information regarding the results of scientific research in agriculture and homemaking, and through a definitely planned program endeavors to interest them in putting improved methods in to practice in order that there may be a profitable agricultural industry and satisfying home and community life in the country".  What this statement omits is that during World War II, the University of Connecticut Extension service, through its <corpname>Emergency Farm Labor Program</corpname>, in cooperation with State and Federal  governments and local businesses, played a key role in making the people of the state available  as laborers to the agricultural industry.  A quote from one of the documents is helpful to bridge this gap, "The Agricultural Extension Service of the College of Agriculture of the University of Connecticut is the agency responsible for the recruiting, training and placement of agricultural workers. Farm Labor offices are centrally located in each of the eight counties in the state.  County Agricultural Agents are in charge of the Farm Labor Program in their  counties and trained personnel in placement work, called Farm Labor Assistants, work under  their direction."</p>
         <p>During World War II, this agricultural training shifted in focus from helping farmers to improve their private land to providing Industrial Agriculture with newly trained Farm Labor. Essentially, the training of non-farmers, referred to during the war as Emergency Farm Labor - helped to fill the gap the Selective Service opened. For example, former female secretaries were taught dairy farming and high school students were taught how to help with the tobacco harvest. The latter training was the result of the State's need to help one of the larger agricultural economies of Connecticut get its product to market.</p>
         <p>By 1945, the organization of the University became even more complex. The establishment of both the Ratcliffe Hicks School of Agriculture, within the College of Agriculture, and a Department of Agricultural Economics and Farm Management makes it difficult to trace the Extension Service, and determine differences between the two.   The School of Agriculture had lower requirements for admission, "graduation from an approved secondary school and agricultural experience such as 4-H Club work, vocational agriculture, agricultural industry, or experience on a farm."  On the other hand, the College of Agriculture required "Graduation from, or completion of 16 units in, an approved secondary school; Rank in top fourth of high school graduating class, or a satisfactory score on an aptitude test administered by the University; Applicants are urged to acquire general ed, English fluency (written and oral), acquaintance with English and American literature, basic mathematics including algebra and geometry; and introductory sciences. Foreign language ability is highly desirable." </p>
         <p>At this time the faculty of the College of Agriculture included Mr. Clapp, as the Acting Director of Agricultural Extension, so it is assumed that the Extension Service remained under the College of Agriculture.  There is correspondence from Mr. Clapp in the processed portion of the collection for the years 1945-1947.</p>
         <p/>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
         <head>Scope and Content</head>
         <p>Transferred to Archives &#x0026; Special Collections in 1982, the collection contains 83 linear feet of documentation including newspaper clippings, correspondence, schematics of the institutional hierarchy, financial documentation, marketing pamphlets and brochures, surveys, maps, press releases, photographs, and glass plate negatives.  The scope of the collection begins with news clippings about the Emergency Farm Labor Department's organization of farm labor during World War II.  The result of the Selective Service draft meant many farmers left their land, creating a shortage of laborers during harvest. In response to this shortage, the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> and the <corpname>State of Connecticut</corpname> cooperated to create the <corpname>Emergency Farm Labor Department</corpname>, which established the <corpname>Women's Land Army</corpname>, as well as  farm labor camps for <geogname>Jamaica</geogname>n laborers, conscientious objectors, prisoners, migrant labor from <geogname>Newfoundland</geogname>, and high school students from <geogname>Florida</geogname>, <geogname>Pennsylvania</geogname>, <geogname>Massachusetts</geogname> and <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>.  Some of this student labor was as young as (and sometimes under) 14 years of age. The clippings document the role that Mr. Paul (schematic indicates "State Farm Labor Supervisor" under the Extension Emergency Farm Labor Program from the University of Connecticut, as Director of State Farm Labor), played in defeating the Child Labor Bill, effectively making it legal for tobacco growers to hire children under 14 years of age. </p>
         <p>In addition, there is correspondence from the <corpname>USDA</corpname> about the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>'s Agriculture Department and their growing  responsibility as part of the Emergency Farm Labor Committee to provide training for newly  recruited farm laborers. This correspondence includes the actual work schedules, descriptions  of farm labor work, child labor abuses.  In contrast, as part of a state and nationwide  marketing campaign, there are pamphlets and brochures published by the UConn Extension service, of these farm labor camps that show students advertising "Vacation Work" as being fun. The brochures and pamphlets include photos of youngsters playing tennis, softball, and swimming, as well winners of the Tobacco Beauty Queen contest.  </p>
         <p>The balance of the collection includes Farm Surveys from the early 1910s for Dairy, Apple, Tobacco and Poultry farms. These surveys span the time frame of World War I, the Depression, and World War II, chronicling the Agricultural Economics Department's participation in maximizing the <corpname>State of Connecticut</corpname>'s agricultural resources during  difficult economic times. The Farm Business Surveys record information such as acres tilled and  livestock owned, and also contain personal information such as nationalities of farmers,  education levels, and standard of living statistics. There is documentation on the coursework for the Home Economics department, as well as surveys, reports and photos on soil conservation.  </p>
         <p>Large portions of the collection remain unprocessed, although the proposed arrangment for the collection is reflected in the Series descriptions listed below.  For information regarding the accessibility of information in the unprocessed portions of the collection, please contact the curator.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a" id="a4">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series I: Emergency Farm Labor Correspondence</emph> (<date>1942-1948</date>).  The EFL correspondence to State Directors of Extension 1942-1948 touches on themes of Labor supply and Administration of the program. Labor supply documentation includes information on deferments, training and service, interstate employment and recruiting.  This includes restricted transfer of workers, unemployed laborers being referred to other state-run food programs, and acquiring war prisoners for farm labor. There is a memo detailing Mexican Workers (25,00 imported for work), Bahamians (3,000 imported), Jamaicans (9,000), War Prisoners (of 40,000 possibly 15,000 available for work), Japanese from relocation centers (2,000), U.S. Soldiers (civilians should be used instead).  These are separate from domestic migratory workers (non-existent). There is documentation on future employment estimates,  Updates on workers (Mexican Nationals), certification of need timelines, Request for Farm Labor forms, Victory Farm Volunteer and Women's Land Army membership card updates, farm labor 'crisis' letters, labor recruiting instructions, foreign and out-of-state labor certification requirements (cannot hire out of state labor without formal quantification of need), work agreement contracts, housing, prisoner of war used as farm labor, and VFV certificates.</p>
         <p>The Administration correspondence includes specific instructions to directors.  A copy of the Labor Bill of 1943, budget requirements, wage rates, office supplies, farm equipment lists, bureaucratic changes from the Federal government, housing guidelines, instructions on using labor properly, committees to improve the EFL program, budget updates, "release of information" regulations and hierarchy, requests for increased production, Selective Service and deferment of agricultural workers. There is also information on the impact of Legislative Resolution 209 on recruitment, placement, labor usage, Selective Service and State administration/supervision, Victory Farm Volunteers, Woman's Land Army, transportation and housing for intrastate farm workers. Labor documentation includes agricultural deferment regulations, ramifications of county extension workers being drafted, establishment of monthly report requirements, stabilization and adjustments in wages, Legislative updates on the 1944 Farm Labor Appropriations Bill, memoranda regarding working relationships between field employees of the Office of labor and the State Extension Service, memoranda regarding the simultaneous loss of farm labor and crop-harvesting needs, bureaucratic changes, possible funding and responsibility changes for Extension Service per Farm Labor Program possible legislative update/change, leasing property, staff and employment requirements, allocation of funds/reimbursement clarifications, insurance requirements, work requirements of farm workers transported with farm labor funds and whether they can work in food processing, cooperative proposal, farm labor housing requirements, farm fund expenditures, memo re: distribution of poster "Pitch In and Help" - with specific instructions to post where woman will see it (with copy of poster).  There is documentation on farm workers health and medical services, recruiting publications for Woman's Land Army, training publications for Work Leaders, VFV on the Farm Front, proper allocation of farm labor supply centers, Labor Manual updates, cooperative arrangement between Price Administration and Extension Service re: gas vouchers, allocation of farm labor funds, equipment, accounting of receipts, and transportation regulations for farm workers. For advertising, there is information on a motion picture and outdoor posters. Incentives include State exemptions from Federal Excise Taxes re: transportation of farm workers, Annual Reports, continuance of farm labor program, medical injury claims/who will pay for injured workers, budget draft, updates on legislation, egg price supports, cotton hearings, G.I. farm loans, rural electrification, veterans agricultural advisory board, the 1945 agricultural census, and appropriation approvals.</p>
         <p>Telegrams span the years of 1943-1946 and document communication between the Federal government and those connected with implementing the Emergency Farm Labor program at the local level.  Correspondence includes that between the Federal Government and Mr. Woodward, Director of Extension under the Extension Emergency Farm Labor Program, 1942-1944. Mr. Clapp, Acting Director of Extension under the Extension Emergency Farm Labor Program, took over for Mr. Woodward the correspondence from 1945-1947 is directed to him.  The Federal War Office Memoranda (1942-1951) includes instructions on all administrative organization of the programs. Also included are changes in bureaucracy that affect funding for programs. The <title render="italic">Emergency Farm Labor Circular</title> (1945) is an information bulletin meant to be for the wider employment audience.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series II:  Emergency Farm Labor Financial Records</emph> (<date>undated, 1941-1948</date>) includes annual reports, budget requests, budget statements, financial statements, financial reports for the Agricultural Extension Division. There is information on the Extension Farm labor budget, memoranda on budget requests, receipts for 1942-1948. Also included are work contracts, including interstate workers, project agreements, voluntary agreement on standards of employment, recruiting labor memorandum agreements, termination of work agreement for Newfoundlanders, a supplement agreement for extension work, memoranda of agreement for Negro College workers, and extension agreements for extension workers. Memoranda of agreements and farm labor contracts for the Cooperative, statement of employment need, personnel files, personnel expense account lists, auditors certificates, accounting records of the Extension farm labor, account information for farm labor and farm labor accounting records as well as financial documentation, application for emergency purchases, wage information and wage hearing minutes, monthly state farm labor work camps, and wage rate hearings are also included in this Series.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series III: Legislation</emph> (<date>undated, 1942-1947</date>) includes all legislative action materials that would have had an effect on the State labor situation including a Senate Report on Farm Labor, Selective Service, and child labor. Minutes from Senate Appropriations committee hearings, printed Acts and Bills, House of Representative reports, Joint resolutions, and regulations are also included.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series IV: Emergency Farm Labor Conferences</emph> (<date>1942-1947</date>) documents regional conference programs, and a State agricultural defense labor committee program.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series V: Emergency Farm Labor Schematics</emph> (<date>undated, 1943</date>) clearly show the complicated institutional hierarchy of the following organizations: the <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> organization for agricultural labor, Wartime activities, the organization of Extension Emergency Farm Labor Program and the <corpname>USDA War Food Administration</corpname>.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series VI:  Emergency Farm Labor Marketing Material</emph> (<date>undated, 1942-1949</date>) includes newspaper clippings, bulletins, brochures, certification/merit badges, and magazine articles on <corpname>Connecticut's Land Army</corpname>.  There is a publicity report by <persname>Paul Putnam</persname>, and a radio address script.  There is a poem by <persname>James Young</persname>, a <geogname>New London County</geogname> Farm  labor assistant and documentation on the <corpname>War Food Administration</corpname> movie to recruit Emergency Farm Labor with script, called "Victory Harvest." There are marketing posters from <corpname>U.S. Crop Corps</corpname> "Harvest War Crops" and "Crop emergency" (1944). Also included information regarding a Newfoundlanders supper and meeting, menu and attendees, plus <geogname>Newfoundland</geogname> motion pictures.   Regarding <corpname>Connecticut Light &#x0026; Power Company</corpname>, there is the text of an address made to the <corpname>American Society of Agricultural Engineers</corpname>  regarding the farm labor problem. The purpose of the address was to as if electrically  operated farm equipment could help production. Some obstacles to rural electrical service  were noted. Also, a determination needed to be made regarding which jobs could have been  made more efficient with electrical power equipment. For example, were there electrically operated machines for specific jobs? The address delineated three proposed phases: 1) determining the available electrical equipment; 2) encouraging farm invented and developed equipment; and 3) additional new devices.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series VII:  Reports</emph> (<date>1943-1948</date>) includes Emergency farm labor summary of accomplishments for 1945-1948, statistical summaries of the Agricultural Conservation program, and an Emergency Farm Labor statistical summary of worker placement.   There are statistics on farm workers by ethnicity, a statistical report on agricultural marketing and farm transportation.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series VIII: Farm Labor</emph> (<date>undated, 1939-1947</date>) includes <corpname>USDA</corpname> surveys on outside agricultural labor requirements for 1947, <corpname>USDA</corpname> farm labor requirements for 1939, 1944, a <corpname>USDA</corpname> co-op work guide, a <corpname>USDA</corpname> migrant workers guide for 1947 and a <corpname>USDA</corpname> farm labor newsletter and committee report for 1943-1044.  There is information on the Civilian War Service, the War Manpower Commission, and War Food Administration memoranda. Documentation on the Extension Services and the farm work camps, as well as the <corpname>Connecticut Labor Department</corpname>  standards for tobacco workers is also included.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series IX: Farm Labor Camp</emph> (<date>undated, 1943-1947</date>) includes Emergency farm labor statistical summaries from 1943-1947, a Farm Labor Program fact sheet for 1946-1947 and a Plan of Work for 1947. There is a State Farm Labor Report and a Farm Labor Employment report as well as documents regarding work simplification.  There is information on the Connecticut Agricultural Wartime production capacity and the War manpower Commission.  This series includes county agent reports on Farm labor, a conference address on farm labor and a Department of Labor tobacco Inspection Report.  There are also analyses of Questionnaires by Tobacco supervisor, a training manual and reports on the Connecticut Farm Labor Program as well as the Out-of-State Farm Labor Programs. </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series X: Youth Labor Camps</emph> (<date>undated, 1943-1947</date>) includes reports on the Robinson farm labor camp (undated), the farm work camps, the farm labor camp summary by town. There are handwritten Farm labor camp notebooks from <persname>Paul Putnam</persname>, as well as oversized charts on farm labor camps reports and stats by town, including:  tobacco work camp - Girls (1945), Tobacco work camp - Boys (1945), Fruit and vegetable work camps (1944-1945); County reports (1945-1947); Camps by town (1946-1947); County monthly reports (1947); Annual report material (1947);
Federal Rural Land Use by County; Inventory of State Owned Land; Staff and Salaries for the Florida Farm Labor Camp (undated); and Selective service camp data. Finally there is information on the farm labor camps  from the <corpname>Connecticut Department of Health</corpname>. The farm work camps reports include information on Bolton, poultry, and  a class report with a good description of camps, including a bibliography. There are  brochures on the camps and employee vital statistics. There is advertising claiming that  Youth Labor camps "Help American Farmers save the world from Starvation."</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series XI: Women's Land Army</emph> (<date>1942-1945</date>) includes a WLA news bulletin, a report with employee information such as weight, height, ethnicity, and religion. There is a report on training personnel recruitment brochure. There blank certificates of completion and an transportation card. There are meeting minutes of the advisory board, Victory Farm Volunteers newsletter and a Report on the Victory Farm Volunteers dairy course and pickle program. </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series XII: Extension Services</emph> (<date>1943</date>) series includes information about the Cooperative extension work between the Agricultural and Home Economics department and the government. </p>
         <p/>
                <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series XIII: USDA Farm Survey Notes</emph> (<date>undated, 1914-1917, 1921-1943</date>):  Quantification of farms as a business, including information such as farm size, acres tilled, crops harvested, and livestock owned, as well as family size, age of workers (invariably children of farmer) and number of years as a farmer.  These surveys also include qualitative information such as level of education of the farmer, his wife and children; the family's nationality and race, and their standard of living. These are organized first by County, then by farmer. </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series XIV: State of Connecticut farm economics agricultural survey</emph> (<date/>) includes the surveys as well as workers association part time farming surveys. </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series XV: Federal and State marketing surveys</emph> (<date/>) including dairy, cold storage poultry, fruits and vegetables. There are farmers' exchange feed prices, and market reports. There is information on the <corpname>Eastern Connecticut Poultry Producers</corpname> (<corpname>ECPP</corpname>), the <corpname>USDA</corpname> fluid milk report, and the Southern New England Telephone business conditions survey report. This series includes marketing papers, marketing of fruits and vegetables by motor truck.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Series XVI: Connecticut Agricultural College</emph> (<date/>). Department files from the 1930s Agricultural school including an extension service milk marketing survey; questionnaires, and farm management reports. Conference information and Cooperative associations;  and correspondence from the office of <persname>I.G. Davis</persname>, Professor of Agricultural Economics in the  Extension Office, in Charge of Extension Work in Marketing. Agricultural department  employee information and records, including the home economics administration  and  employee information. From the I.G. Davis/Department of Economics Administration, there is a secretary rolodex from 1930s. Press releases, and <geogname>Scantic County, Massachusetts</geogname> tree farms soil conservation service. Financial Records of the <corpname>Connecticut Valley Tobacco Association</corpname>.</p>
               </arrangement>
      <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University's history.  See also <extref href="http://www.lib.uconn.edu/online/research/speclib/ASC/SNET/snetmain.htm">Southern New England Telephone Company Records</extref> for information similar to that found in Series VI and XV and <extref href="http://www.lib.uconn.edu/online/research/speclib/ASC/findaids/CTVTG/MSS19790005.html">Connecticut Valley Tobacco Growers Association Records</extref> for materials similar to that found in Series XVI.  For detailed information not available in this finding aid, please contact the <extref href="http://www.lib.uconn.edu/online/research/speclib/ASC/collections/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorid=3">curator</extref> or ask at the reference desk.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <bibliography id="a10">
         <head>Bibliography</head>
         <p/>
         <p>
            <bibref>
               <title render="italic">Connecticut Agricultural College Bulletin</title>, Vol 27, No. 4. <imprint>Storrs, CT: <publisher>Connecticut Agricultural College</publisher>, <date type="publication">February 1932</date>.</imprint>
            </bibref>
         </p>
         <p>
            <bibref>
               <title render="italic">University of Connecticut Bulletin</title>, Vol. 37, No. 4. <imprint>Storrs, CT: <publisher>University of Connecticut</publisher>, <date type="publication">1942-1943</date>.</imprint>
            </bibref>
         </p>
         <p>
            <bibref>
               <title render="italic">Connecticut State College Biennial reports </title>. <imprint>Storrs, CT: <publisher>Connecticut State College</publisher>, <date type="publication">1926 - 1934</date>.</imprint>
            </bibref>
         </p>
         <p>
            <bibref>
               <persname>Stemmons, Walter</persname>.  <title render="italic">Connecticut Agricultural College - A History</title>, <imprint>Storrs:, CT: <publisher>Connecticut Agricultural College</publisher>, <date type="publication">1931</date>.</imprint>
            </bibref>
         </p>
      </bibliography>
<!-- END COLLECTION METADATA --><!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->
      <controlaccess id="a12">
         <head>Index Terms</head>
         <p>This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
</p>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Persons:</head>
            <persname encodinganalog="700" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Organizations:</head>
            <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Family Names:</head>
            <famname encodinganalog="600" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Places:</head>
            <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Document Types:</head>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Publications.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Blueprints.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Maps.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Administrative Records.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Financial Records.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Minutes.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Press releases.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Audio visual materials.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Fliers. [printed matter]</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Photocopies.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Notes.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Drawings.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Sound recordings.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Lantern slides.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Microfilm.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Filmstrips.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Histories.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Abstracts. </genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Examinations.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Broadsides.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Organizational charts.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Questionnaires.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Surveys.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local"/>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local"/>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Occupations:</head>
            <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Functions:</head>
            <function encodinganalog="657" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Titles:</head>
            <title encodinganalog="630" source="local"/>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess><!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS --><!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->
      <accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
         <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
         <p>There are no access restrictions on this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
         <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
         <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite encodinganalog="510" id="a18">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Item description, #:#], <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>, <corpname>Agricultural Economics Department</corpname> Records.  <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
         </p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
         <head>Acquisition Information</head>
         <p>The Department of Agricultural Economics transferred the papers in 1982.</p>
      </acqinfo>
<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
      <dsc type="combined" id="a23">
         <head>Detailed Description</head>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series I: Emergency Farm Labor Correspondence, <unitdate>1942-1948</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>USDA</corpname> Letters to State Directors of Extension, <unitdate>1942-1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>USDA</corpname> Letters to State Farm Labor Supervisors, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Telegrams, <unitdate>1943-1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Mr. Woodward, Director of Extension, <unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Mr. Clapp, Acting Director of Extension <unitdate>1945-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Federal War Office Memoranda, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>War Food Administration</corpname> circular, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Selective Service, <unitdate>1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series II: Emergency Farm Labor Financial Records, <unitdate>undated, 1941-1948</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Annual Reports, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Budget Requests, <unitdate>1944-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Budget statements, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Financial statements, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Financial report - Agricultural Extension Division, <unitdate>1945-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Extension Farm Labor Budget, <unitdate>1944-1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Memoranda on budget requests, <unitdate>1942-1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Receipts, <unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Receipts, <unitdate>1945-1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Interstate workers contract, <unitdate>1946-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Sample Farm Labor Project Agreement, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Voluntary agreement "standards of employment", <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Recruiting labor memorandum agreement, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Termination of work agreement - Newfoundlanders, <unitdate>1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Supplemental Agreement for Extension work, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Memorandum of Agreement for Negro College workers, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Extension of Agreement for Extension workers, <unitdate>1945-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Memorandum of Agreement - Cooperative, <unitdate>1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm Labor Contract - Cooperative, <unitdate>1943-1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Employment needs, <unitdate>1941, 1943, 1946-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Personnel files, <unitdate>1942-1943, 1944-1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Personnel expense account lists, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Auditors certificate, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Extension Farm Labor Accounting Records, <unitdate>1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm labor accounts, <unitdate>1945-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm labor camps accounting records, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm labor financial documentation, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Application for Emergency purchases, <unitdate>1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm labor wages, <unitdate>1943-1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Wage hearing minutes, <unitdate>1945, 1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series III: Legislation, <unitdate>undated, 1942-1947</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Senate Report on Farm Labor, <unitdate>1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Selective Service, <unitdate>1942</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Policy on War Manpower Commission child labor, <unitdate>1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Hearings Senate Appropriations Committee, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Joint resolution, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>House of Representatives report, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Regulations - Labor and Transportation, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Acts, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Minutes, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Bills--Federal and State, <unitdate>1944, 1946-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series IV: Emergency Farm Labor Conferences, <unitdate>1942-1947</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Regional conference programs, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>State agriculture defense labor committee , <unitdate>1942-1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series V: Emergency Farm Labor Schematics, <unitdate>undated, 1943</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Schematics, <unitdate>undated, 1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series VI:  Emergency Farm Labor Marketing Material, <unitdate>undated, 1942-1949</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p>The subject of the clippings concerns the Farm Labor situation during World War II in <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>, and the University Extension Service's attempts to  recruit and train Farm Labor during the War. Mr. <persname>Paul Putnam</persname>, State  Farm Labor Director through the Extension Service under the Emergency Farm Labor  organization, is the subject of many of these articles. The clippings tell a story of a  State desperate to fill the labor gap left by the Selective Service. Many different groups  were suggested as replacement labor, including prison labor (those arrested for public  drunkenness). This method of supplying labor was considered unfeasible, and so new labor  supplies were pursued. </p>
               <p>The second method of finding labor was to suggest the use of <geogname>Massachusetts</geogname> teenagers as farm labor. This proposal was attacked and  defeated by Employment Department officials from Boston.  The search for labor shifted to  conscientious objectors, Japanese evacuees, and Southern (i.e. Afro-American) migrant  laborers. These alternatives provided labor, however a new housing problem was created.  Complaints from the white community surrounding the Labor Camps objected to having Afro- American migrant labor living in their community, although they were not quite so  explicit. Various reasons were used to couch their protests in practical reasons, however  one official is quoted in the clippings on the record as being of the opinion these were  thinly veiled racist arguments. </p>
               <p>This problem was solved in part by the creation of Farm Labor Camps for various newly minted organizations: <corpname>Victory Farm Volunteers</corpname>, the <corpname>Women's Land Army</corpname>, high school boys and girls (all white).  In addition, recruiting  Newfoundlanders from <geogname>Canada</geogname> through an arrangement with their  government proved mutually beneficial. </p>
               <p>
                  <geogname>Jamaica</geogname>n farm laborers were also recruited for seasonal labor and  there are many photographs in the newspaper clippings that show these men in the typical 1940s formal attire for train travel: hats, suits and ties; presumably to calm racial fears. There are additional photos of the Jamaican men's choir, and celebrations of their National Holiday. One revealing photo shows a racially mixed audience listening to the men's choir, a marketing attempt to show the community there would be no negative repercussions of having Afro-American and Jamaican men in their neighborhoods. In addition, there is an article written by a Jamaican farm worker, which gives a different  perspective on the farm labor experience, and reveals culture differences between Jamaicans and Americans. This man describes his trip by boat from the <geogname>West Indies</geogname> in April and covers all of the impressions of this trip from the cold  temperatures to his being unaccustomed to farm work, (he was an artisan at home). He  writes that although the pay is high, the food is bad: only bacon and eggs served  everyday. The Jamaicans were given a Field Day in honor of their National Holiday, which  included soccer, cricket, boxing, racing, and dancing with the Nelson Orchestra. Finally,  there is an article short on information and raises questions about how Jamaicans were treated. Describing the departure of some Jamaicans due to fear of winter, but also due to "bad treatment" one wonders exactly what their experience was like, and is a foreshadowing  of the rioting mentioned below.</p>
               <p>The <corpname>Woman's Land Army</corpname> is the subject of articles that include photographs, many showing young women extolling the virtues of dairy farming over secretarial work. These ladies are quoted as describing dairying "fun" compared to "depressing" secretarial work, despite their self-described "handicap" of being weaker than men. </p>
               <p>Ultimately, the shortage of farm labor was solved by the recruitment of high school students from <geogname>Florida</geogname>, hired for "Vacation Work". There are many  articles and photographs that chronicle this endeavor.  There were glitches in the <corpname>Farm Labor Camps</corpname>, among the fewdocumented: sewage problems for Jamaican workers, the electrocution of female farm laborers trying to take a shower, and an incident of poor communication between young local workers and the transportation authorities which resulted in nine little girls (all around 14 years old) walking 21 miles home to Hartford. This incident was widely reported, and many of the articles are included here. </p>
               <p>The marketing campaign is evident in the articles on radio addresses by the Extension Service, many of which are described in these articles. In addition, there are editorials interspersed which weigh in on almost all of these topics. </p>
               <p>There is extensive documentation of the child labor issue; the debate over whether it should be illegal to hire children under 14 for farm labor. Mr. <persname>Paul Putnam</persname>, State Farm Labor Supervisor under the Extension Service's Emergency Farm Labor Program of the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>, was key in  defeating this child labor legislation, essentially making it legal to hire children under  14, with no consequences for the company if being found doing so. As an appeasement, Mr.  Putnam brokered a "voluntary agreement" for the tobacco industry to agree to not hire those 14 and under.  It should not come as a surprise to find that there continued to be  documentation of children as young as 11 years old working 8 hour days, 6 days a week with  no consequences for their employers.</p>
               <p>One of the interesting facts that come from the articles is the land-ownership distribution in <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>. The Extension Service was no longer  necessarily helping the individual farmer when the statistics are published that,  "Queen  Wilhelmina of Holland was declared to be one of the largest owners of tobacco land in the Enfield section of <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>, she visits to inspect her holdings". That the Extension Service was working to provide labor for tobacco companies leasing from Queen Wilhelmina illustrates the difference between their stated goals in the <title render="italic">Bulletins</title> and the practical realities of their endeavors. </p>
               <p>There are eye-catching photographs from the coverage of the last day of work for Floridian high school students who have a Field Day to celebrate the end of their working summer. Headlines proclaim the Floridian Winner of the Shade Tobacco Queen beauty contest, for which <persname>Paul Putnam</persname> was a judge. However, even the beauty contest  was subject to the political and economic ties between the Extension Service and industry, "Ann Flora was disqualified for first place because she was not an employee of the <corpname>Connecticut Shade Tobacco Growers Association</corpname>". The field day also had softball games, swimming, worker prizes, and dancing in the evening.  Interestingly, this article makes it clear that the brochures found in the Marketing series of this collection shows these activities as part of the Vacation Work experience, in reality is only recording one day of these recreations per summer. These brochures clearly exclude references to and photographs of the daily grind of work. For the non-white laborers, a "Field Day" was held on a different day, segregated from the white Floridian workers. These events included winners in a seven-event contest held Sunday evening at Hartman farm specifically for Jamaican and southern "Negro" [sic] tobacco workers to play checkers, dominoes, and have contests such as basket foul shooting and a sprint.  There are no photographs from this event.</p>
               <p>The abuses on farm labor camps follow a specific pattern in this collection. First, there are reports of abuse, and in response there are articles that describe the official reaction: invariably, a tour of the offending facility for the benefit of various religious and legislative leaders. For example, there is a single article about Bahamian and Jamaican workers who rioted, although the article fails to indicate what conditions they were living in. In reaction to this bad press, a Farm labor camp held an "Open House" for 12 local community leaders who visited with campers, stayed for dinner, and had entertainment and a tour.  Quotes about how well-run the labor camp was give no indication the situation of the Bahamian and Jamaican workers was resolved.</p>
               <p>Articles clearly serving as marketing tools include headlines such as, "Life on state tobacco farm not all hard labor" and are accompanied by photos of kids eating, playing badminton, playing softball, and swimmers curiously have hair which is both dry and styled. Another article headline advertises, "High school lassies work and play. Summer work on a tobacco farm is like a vacation, except you get paid". </p>
               <p>Pay is an interesting subject, this article indicates high school students earn 45 cents and hour, which adds up to $100 for the whole summer after room and board is deducted. This total is achieved by working 8 hour days, 6 days a week, which hardly includes swimming, badminton or softball. Comparing these articles to the Farm Labor Camp reports in this collection that describe daily schedules beginning at 5 a.m. gives insight into the discrepancies between the actual program and the marketing campaign the public saw. </p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Emergency Farm Labor Newspaper Clippings , <unitdate>1942, 1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Food for Freedom survey, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Marketing Bulletins, <unitdate>1949</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Brochures, <unitdate>undated, 1943-1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Extension Service Marketing Brochure "Vacation Work", <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Articles on Connecticut's Land Army, <unitdate>1942-1943, 1945-1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Putnam publicity report, <unitdate>1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Radio Script, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Poem, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Press releases, <unitdate>1943, 1946, 1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>War Food Admininstration movie, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Posters, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Newfoundlanders Supper and Meeting, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>Connecticut Light &#x0026; Power Company</corpname>, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series VII:  Reports, <unitdate>1943-1948</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">3</container>
                  <unittitle>EFL Summary of accomplishments, <unitdate>1945-1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Statistical summary of the agricultural conservation program, <unitdate>1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>EFL stat summary of worker placement, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Statistics on farm workers by ethnicity, <unitdate>1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Statistical report on agricultural marketing, <unitdate>1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm Transportation, <unitdate>1945-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02><c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">4</container>
                  <unittitle>Statistical summaries, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02><c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Committees, <unitdate>1939-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series VIII: Farm Labor, <unitdate>undated, 1939-1947</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">3</container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>USDA</corpname> survey on outside agricultural labor req, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>USDA</corpname> farm labor requirements, <unitdate>1939, 1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>USDA</corpname> co-op work guide, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>USDA</corpname> migrant workers guide, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>USDA</corpname> farm labor newsletter/committee report, <unitdate>1943-1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Civilian War Service, <unitdate>1943-1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>War Manpower, <unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>War Food Administration</corpname> memoranda, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Extension Services, <unitdate>1944-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Report on farm work camps, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Report on farm work camps, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>
                     <corpname>Connecticut Labor Department</corpname> standards for tobacco  workers, <unitdate>1942</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series IX: Farm Labor Camp, <unitdate>undated, 1943-1947</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">3</container>
                  <unittitle>EFL farm labor statistical summary, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm Labor Program fact sheet, <unitdate>1946-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Plan of Work, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>State Farm Labor Report, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm Labor Employment report, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Work simplification, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Connecticut Agricultural Wartime Production Capacity, <unitdate>1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>War Manpower Commission, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>County agent reports on Farm labor, <unitdate>1944-1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Conference address on farm labor, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Department of Labor - Tobacco Inspection Report, <unitdate>1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Analysis of Questionnaires - Tobacco supervisors, <unitdate>1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Training Manual, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Connecticut Farm Labor Program, <unitdate>1943-1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Out-of-State Farm Labor Programs, <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series X:  Youth Labor Camps, <unitdate>undated, 1943-1947</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">3</container>
                  <unittitle>Robinson farm labor camp, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm work camps reports , <unitdate>1943-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm labor camp summary by town, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm labor camp notebooks, <unitdate>1946-1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm labor camps reports and statistics by town, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Farm Labor Camps - <corpname>Connecticut Department of Health</corpname>, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series XI: Women's Land Army, <unitdate>1942-1945</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">3</container>
                  <unittitle>Recruitment brochure, <unitdate>1942-1943, 1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Victory Farm Volunteers News letter, <unitdate>1945</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box"></container>
                  <unittitle>Report on VFV dairy course and pickle program, <unitdate>1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">12</container>
	</did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">13</container>
	</did>	
</c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series XII: Extension Services, <unitdate>1943</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">3</container>
                  <unittitle>Cooperative Extension Work for Agricultural and Home Economics, <unitdate>1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series XIII:  USDA Farm Survey Notes, <unitdate>undated, 1914-1943</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
          
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries A: Record of a Year's business Survey (Geographic), <unitdate>undated, 1914-1936</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Part time farming information Farm size, acres tilled, crops, stock. Including personal info Number in family, Number on farm age year's farmer. Education: nationality and race, standard of living with Maps. New London County undated, no farm name 18 folders  - specific names of farmers Factors to calculate include:  Tabulation form Labor Efficiency CT</unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">6</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Current expenses notes, capital, receipts from stock products, misc. receipts, livestock summary efficiency factors, value of buildings, depreciation charges, Milk rec'd, working capital labor, crops, acres, labor income, man work units, profits, personal info: (education) CAC Operator, Capital, General expenses, receipts from stock purchases, misc. receipts efficiency factors; Summary crops, stock, crops, yield operator sales, landlord sales, operator livestock, landlord livestock, machinery, receipts, education, crop rotation; Map - Lebanon, daily time record home management studies, census, typewritten tables, bulletin, value per acre, agriculture instruction</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1914-17, 1924</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries B: Apple Marketing, <unitdate>1931-1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">17</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">43</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">48</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">50</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
</c02>

            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries C: Egg Marketing, <unitdate/>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">43</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle></unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">44</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries D: County agent reports, <unitdate>1916-1930</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">20</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle></unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">21</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">27</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
 </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries E: Farm Administration Survey, <unitdate>1927-1929</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">21</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Agricultural economics farm management county agent report; photo, farm fair pamphlet, "The farm home maker" agricultural report, photos quantitative and narrative photos, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1927-1929</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries F: Tobacco Survey, <unitdate>1926-1930</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">15</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">24</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
     <c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">25</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>  
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">53</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>        
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series XIV: State of Connecticut Farm Economics Agricultural Survey</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries A: Farm Economics Agricultural Survey, <unitdate>1913-1922</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">8</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Values: dairy productions, eggs, crops, receipts, expenses (plus) personal info: CT ag econ nationality, occupation, family, age standard of living; Chesnutt Hill, Colchester, Lenanon, Bozrahville, Leonard's Bridge, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1922</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
      <c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">9</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>New London, North Franklin, Willimantic, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1913-1916</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03> <c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">59-60</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Hours of manual labor, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1927</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03><c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">62-63</container>
	<unitdate>1934</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
                 </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries B: Workers Association Part-time farming survey, <unitdate>1923-1935</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>

<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">9</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series XV: Federal and State marketing surveys </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries A: Dairy, Eastern Connecticut Poultry Producers (ECPP), <unitdate>undated, 1921-1941</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
                  <did>
               	<container type="Box">7</container>
                   </did>	
               </c03>

<c03 level="file">
                  <did>
               	<container type="Box">18</container>
                   </did>	
               </c03><c03 level="file">
                  <did>
               	<container type="Box">35-36</container>
               <note><p> Box 35 includes SNET report on business conditions </p> </note> </did>	
               </c03>
               <c03 level="file">
                  <did>
               	<container type="Box">38-41</container><unittitle>Dairy Study</unittitle>
                   </did>	
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries B: Fruits and Vegetables, <unitdate>1919-1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">18</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03><c03 level="file">
                  <did>
               	<container type="Box">37</container>
                   </did>	
               </c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">51-52</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">65-66</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle> </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries C: Farmers' Exchange Feed Prices, <unitdate>1919-1930</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">33-34</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Newspaper clippings, "Roadside stand disapproved for farm produce"</unittitle>
	<unitdate>1919, 1927, 1930</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
     </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries D: USDA Fluid Milk report, <unitdate>1921-1943</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did><c03 level="file">
                  <did>
               	<container type="Box">35</container>
               	<container type="Folder"></container>
               	<unittitle></unittitle>
               	<unitdate></unitdate>
                   </did>	
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series XVI: Connecticut Agricultural College, <unitdate>undated, 1920-1959</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries A: Questionnaires, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <note>
                  <p>egg laying contest, tariffs, dairy, poultry, census; Newspaper clipping  - Davis Newspaper clipping,  Davis 1925 Foreigners on farms: "Need Americanizing" agriculturally, socially, politically, Storrs Bulletin State AG. Ext</p></note>
                <c03 level="file">
                   <did>
                	<container type="Box">Index card box</container>
                	<container type="Folder"></container>
                	<unittitle>Department files, 1930s; ag school fino Small red BOX "data on the Lebanon SURVEY Ag Econ "Inside: index cards age, percent of area, income (labor / family) rec'd hens, horses Results are recorded quantitatively mathematically</unittitle>
                	<unitdate>1920</unitdate>
                    </did>	
                </c03>
                 </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries B: Farm Management report, <unitdate>1926-1944</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            <c03 level="file">
                  <did>
               	<container type="Box">7</container>
               <unittitle> Corn belt</unittitle> </did>	
               </c03> 
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">8</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unitdate>1920s</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">9</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unitdate>1930s</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03><c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">10-11</container>	<unittitle>Wholesale Specialized farms, </unittitle><unitdate>1933-1935</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">13</container><unitdate>1927-1950</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">14</container><unitdate>1924-1943</unitdate>
	   </did>	
</c03><c03 level="file">
                  <did>
               	<container type="Box">16</container>
              <unittitle> Includes farm income and expenses, earnings and performance</unittitle> </did>	
               </c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">19</container><unitdate>1927-1951</unitdate>
	   </did>	
</c03><c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">22-23</container><unittitle> Suffield county, </unittitle><unitdate>1926</unitdate>
	   </did>	
</c03><c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">26</container><unitdate>1936</unitdate>
	   </did>	
</c03><c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">27</container><unittitle>Tolland, Hartford and New London counties</unittitle>
	   </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">28-32</container><unitdate>1924-50</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">42</container><unitdate>1936-1940</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">45</container><unitdate>1940s</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">49</container><unitdate>1931</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">54-55</container><unitdate>1937-1950</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">61</container><unitdate>1937-1950</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">64</container><unitdate>1937-1950</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">67</container><unitdate>1937-1950</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">71</container><unitdate>1937-1950</unitdate>
	    </did>	
</c03>
</c02>
                <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries C: Record Keeping, <unitdate>1918-1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">37</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Farm Survey Data Reports, Documentation, farm census, maps blueprints, surveys, GLASS PLATES 1918-1938 farm data photo plates, women canning, children in garden (to show height of corn?), picnic, chicks, pigs, four children on porch, sheep club, sweaters made from yarn, baseball game, demonstration by ct. club members, 4H club women, state sewing club corset cover, apron, cap hem stitched towels, Boston poultry show, class photo, junior short course class photo, junior food army, Goshen fair, banquet, News clippings market men plan war on parking, blue prints, Reports, 1946 New Haven, fruits trees by town, census, commodities stats, veggie prices, price studies, surveys, athletic council college fundraising, recording of digging potatoes, cost of growing potatoes, account books.</unittitle>
    </did>	
</c03>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries D: Home Economics Administration, <unitdate/>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">69-70</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Supervisor weekly and monthly reports, 1948-50, committee on 4H history, conference notes, rural youth committee, itineraries, child nutrition, education materials, interview notes, recording of method demonstrations given, circulations, training local leaders, food preparation narrative reports.</unittitle>
    </did>	
</c03>  </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries E: <persname>I. G. Davis</persname>, <unitdate>1920s</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
<!-- <c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">old box number:46</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Employee file, job application, correspondence, Ct. agricultural experimental station, Davis' school transcripts from Bates college and Harvard, financial records (budget), news clipping with photo of Davis, Bulletin, Social research re: Purnell act, 1925-6, curriculum information for home economics (foundation of the family, functions of the family, reproduction, education, economics, civic, social, "the family s a repository of the mores of the race", Problems of the modern family, indications of pathology Homeless men nd women, widowhood, divorce, desertion, the illegitimate family, difficult children, old age, poverty, illness and accidents, child labor, mental deficiency , crime, women in industry, inadequate standards and facilities for recreations , inadequate education for worthy home members, lack of vital religious and moral education, education for vocational home marketing, education of women for the development of personality considering such questions as: "combining a 'career' with home making, provision for vocational pursuits, faced in such questions as raised by the 'feminist movement" the home a cooperative institute), New England research council, salary information from other ag. Departments, Fed. Emergency relief admin., dept. of commerce correspondence, Davis personal information, travel vouchers, WPA info, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1920</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03> <c03 level="file">
                     <did>
                  	<container type="Box">old box number:15</container>
                  	<container type="Folder"></container>
                  	<unittitle>an report 1930; File: Jewish agricultural society Inside 1 folded, typed agronomy 4 b S. Kostolefky; Bibliography of farm manure references S. Kostolosky exam Problem 7 graded A; Handwritten chart Kirkpatrick USDA letter to IG Davis 1924ScheduleTrip to NY; Correspondence 1927IG Davis correspondence 1924Perregaux, ext economist Connecticut agricultural College 1927IG Davis, Correspondence (Prof of ag econ 1924
Egg laying contest Correspondence Coop extension workers Agricultural and home economics 1926 Frederick Waugh, extension economist Telegrams 1927 agricultural economics, correspondence Davis 1923Applicants for Ag economist position 1923Correspondence Davis 1923 alpha kappa phi fraternity American College bureau 1923 listing of grad salaries Harvard U Dept of Economics 1923To Davis re: hiring "is he a married man? If not, he'd be a good candidate"1921 Prof Davis correspondence Con ag.</unittitle>
                  </did>	
                  </c03> -->
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">29</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence, </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>

            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subseries F: Department of Economics Administration, <unitdate>1923-1930s</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>

<!-- <c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">old box number:47</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Econ dept organization through the 1930s, committee info on honors degrees guidelines, student list, plan of grad study, correspondence recommendation, curriculum, class list, major requirements, assignment sheets, book requirements, student enrollment 1923-31, meeting reports, blueprints, Census committee info, tobacco, dairy, info on farm taxation, salary information. </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03> -->
 
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">68</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Press releases, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1956-1962</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c03>  
<c03 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">56-58</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle><geogname>Scantic County, MA</geogname>, tree farms soil conservation service, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1931-1940</unitdate>
    </did>	<note><p>Bulletin, surveys, financial statements, lists of farms, services data, blueprints, data, plan of conservation operations, directions for working schedules, summary sheets, Land ownership data, photos (tobacco leaf, potatoes, soil depletion, farm wreckage from hurricane, tobacco shed, seminars, charts, code sheet, directions for summary sheet, data, tax, outline (Intro: "studies in the econ of soil conservation have been in progress in ct since 1938 originally, I.G. Davis personally supervised the project since his death in early 1939), newspaper clippings, correspondence  Surveys, (Family living information: human resources and living age stopped going to school; Grade, nationality; parent living standard as shown by number of rooms; Number in household; Electric lights; Running water; Bath complete; Sewage disposal; Screen; Radio, auto, refrigerator, Outside appearance 1, 2,3 4, Health of farmer. </p></note> 
</c03>
<c03>
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Financial Records, <corpname>Connecticut Valley Tobacco Association</corpname>, <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                     </unittitle>
                  </did>
                  <note>
                     <p>Trial balances of expense accounts; Account ledger books, charts. </p>
                  </note>
               </c03>
          <!-- <c03 level="file">
             <did>
          	<container type="Box">old box number: 25</container>
          	<container type="Folder"></container>
          	<unittitle>Administrative Papers, <corpname>Connecticut Valley Tobacco Association</corpname></unittitle>
          	<unitdate>1920s</unitdate>
<note>
                     <p>Members, Bulletins, statistics, pamphlets, studies, article reprints, experiment, statistics, history of tobacco culture, maps, charts, statements, news clippings, correspondence, price lists, reports, meeting minutes, questionnaires, surveys.</p>
                </note>
              </did>	
          </c03> -->
           </c02>
         </c01>
       </dsc>
<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
   </archdesc>
</ead>