<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">
<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
<eadid mainagencycode="US-CtU" countrycode="US">MSS19980297</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Davis and Geck Company Records</titleproper>
<author>Inventory prepared by James W. Scannell.</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>&#x00A9; 2005 University of Connecticut</publisher>
<date type="publication">July 1998</date>
<date type="revision">2008</date>
<address><addressline>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</addressline><addressline>405 Babbidge Road, Unit 1205</addressline><addressline>Storrs, Connecticut 06269-1205</addressline> <addressline> URL: http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/ </addressline></address>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>Text converted and initial EAD encoding provided by Apex CoVantage, April 2005</date></creation>
<langusage><language>English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a"><corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>.</repository>
<origination label="Creator:">
<corpname encodinganalog="110">Davis and Geck Company.</corpname>
</origination>
<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Davis and Geck Company Records.</unittitle>
<unitdate label="Dates:">undated, 1909-1997.</unitdate>
<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">14.5 linear feet.</physdesc>
<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" repositorycode="UCW">MSS19980297</unitid>
<langmaterial><language>English</language>.</langmaterial>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">The Davis and Geck Company was founded in 1909 by Charles T. Davis and Fred A. Geck. The company specialized in surgical sutures, beginning with catgut and moving on to kangaroo tendons and later to advanced synthetic materials. For much of its history, Davis and Geck was the world's second largest producer of surgical sutures. The company became part of American Cyanamid in 1930. After subsequent sales, the company was renamed Sherwood, Davis and Geck. Though the D+G offices were initially located in Brooklyn, N.Y., the company purchased a factory in Danbury, Conn., in the early 1950s. This factory was scheduled for closure in 1998 following the sale of Sherwood, Davis and Geck to the Tyco Corporation and the transfer of plant operations to Mexico.</abstract>
</did>
<bioghist altrender="history" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
<head>History</head>
<p>The <corpname>Davis and Geck Company</corpname> was founded in 1909 by <persname>Charles T. Davis</persname> and <persname>Fred A. Geck.</persname> Geck was experienced in the marketing of sutures from his experience with another company, <corpname>Van Horn and Sawtell</corpname>. <persname>Charles Davis</persname> already owned his own medical supply company. The company's two other founders were <persname>Frank C. Bradeen</persname>, Vice President, and <persname>Benjamin F. Hirsch</persname>, as secretary. After only a few months, <persname>Fred Geck</persname> withdrew from the company as he did not have the requisite knowledge to assist in suture manufacture. Bradeen left the company after only two years. <persname>Benjamin Hirsch</persname> remained with the company up until the 1950s, and was responsible for much of the company's marketing strategy and for securing several patents. It should be noted that the company's first production facility was in the back room of a livery stable located on Carleton Avenue in <geogname>Brooklyn, NY</geogname>.</p>
<p>In 1909, the year that the <corpname>Davis and Geck Company</corpname> was founded, most hospitals were sterilizing their own catgut sutures, frequently through the use of a chemical solution. The process was imperfect, and frequently resulted in infections or operative delays. In 1913 the <corpname>Davis and Geck Company</corpname> introduced the Calustro-thermal process for the heat sterilization of suture tubes after the sutures were sealed inside. This provided hospitals with a reliable product, and saved time in the operating room as well.</p>
<p>The <corpname>Davis and Geck Company</corpname> was extremely busy filling contracts during the first World War. In 1922, Davis and Geck began to market Atraumatic needles, which were eyeless needles that had the sutures directly attached to the needle. However, by this time the founder of the company had become involved in a murder investigation. On 17 February 1921, <persname>Charles T. Davis</persname> shot and killed a police detective who had come to his office to clarify an insurance claim filed by Davis. Davis' mental health came into question - apparently he was convinced that <persname>Kaiser Wilhelm</persname> was trying to assassinate him. Davis was confined to a mental institution for a few years, but faced a formal criminal trial in 1925 after his mental state had considerably improved. He was found guilty and sentenced to 10-20 years in prison.</p>
<p>By 1930, with <persname>Charles T. Davis</persname> scheduled for a parole hearing, a battle was brewing for control of the company between Davis and his wife. Mrs. Davis claimed to have improved the company during her husband's incarceration, and had also installed her paramour, a Polish nobleman named <persname>Cornelius Tuczynski</persname>, as vice president of the company. The Davises settled the ownership dispute by selling Davis and Geck to the <corpname>American Cyanamid Corporation</corpname> for three million dollars.</p>
<p>Beginning in 1928, the <corpname>Davis and Geck Company</corpname> also began to produce surgical films as a way to document new procedures and to assist in the training of doctors and nurses. This program continued into the 1980s as the Clin&#x00E9; Clinic Films Program. The company also gained prestige from 1927 through 1950 through a series of dramtic print advertisements entitled &#x201C;Sutures in Ancient Surgery,&#x201D; all of which featured prints by noted artist and photographer <persname>Lejaren &#x00E0; Hiller</persname>. The original photos from this series have been donated to the <corpname>Art Institute of Chicago</corpname>.</p>
<p>Nylon sutures were introduced in 1941. Just prior to Word War II, Davis and Geck held appproximately 70% of the domestic market for sutures, and during the war provided 75% of the sutures required by the U.S. military. However, after the war the company began to lose market share to <corpname>Ethicon</corpname>, a division of <corpname>Johnson and Johnson</corpname>. Failure to respond to improved packaging introduced by <corpname>Ethicon</corpname> led to a reduced market share of 40% by 1952.</p>
<p>In 1951, Davis and Geck acquired a factory in <geogname>Danbury, Connecticut</geogname>, formerly owned by the <corpname>Mutual Rough Hat Company</corpname>. Production began at this plant in 1953, and it remained the company's primary production facility up until the 1990s. At its peak, over 2000 different surgical products were produced at this one location. Towards the latter 1950s, Cyanamid chose to drop the Davis and Geck name, renaming the company as the <corpname>Surgical Products Division of American Cyanamid</corpname>, though retaining the D&#x0026;G trademark. The Davis and Geck name resurfaced by the 1970s, by which time the company had introduced sutures based on an organic material called polyglycolic acid. These sutures were strong and easy to tie in knots, but could also be completely absorbed by the body's own tissue over time. This generation of sutures provided the backbone for the company's renewed presence in the global marketplace, continuing to the present day.</p>
<p>By the middle 1990s, Davis and Geck was no longer a subsidiary of <corpname>American Cyanamid</corpname>. The company was known as <corpname>Sherwood, Davis and Geck</corpname> through 1997. The Danbury factory was scheduled for closure in 1998 following the sale of <corpname>Sherwood, Davis and Geck</corpname> to the <corpname>Tyco Corporation</corpname> and the transfer of plant operations to <geogname>Mexico</geogname>.</p>
<p>(The above history was compiled through the use of documents found in the collection, including accounts written by <persname>Ben Hirsch</persname> and <persname>Charles Riall.</persname>)</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>Collection highlights include several typescript histories of the company prepared at various times by members of the Davis and Geck administration, including <persname>Ben Hirsch</persname> and <persname>Charles T. Riall</persname>. Other materials include promotional literature describing Davis and Geck products from the 1910s through the 1980s. Some intra-company literature is also present, including newsletters, customer service guidelines, and a plant supervisor's manual. The map case contains floorplans of the Danbury factory, detailing a proposed 1995 renovation. Artifacts obtained from the factory have been donated to the <corpname>Menczer Museum of Medecine and Dentistry</corpname> in <geogname>Hartford, Conn.</geogname> The <corpname>Eli Whitney Museum</corpname> has also received materials from the Davis and Geck plant.</p>
<p>Materials have been placed in a rough order that puts historical documents first, followed by advertisements and product literature, and moving on to company publications and Cyanamid annual reports.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351$b" id="a5">
	<head>Arrangement</head>
	<p></p>
<p><emph render="bold">Series I: Records</emph> (<date>undated, 1909-1997</date>) includes all the materials in the collection.</p>
</arrangement>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
	<head>Related Material</head>
	<p>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut business records.  For detailed information on these collections please contact the <extref href="http://www.lib.uconn.edu/online/research/speclib/ASC/collections/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorid=4">curator</extref> or ask at the reference desk.</p>
</relatedmaterial>
<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>
<p>This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.</p>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects:</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Medical supplies industry--United States.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Connecticut--Business, industries, and trades--Sutures.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Danbury (Conn.)--Business, industries, and trades--Sutures.</subject>
              
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Document Types:</head>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Correspondence.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Manuscripts.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Publications.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Photographs.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Floor Plans.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Memorabilia.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Administrative Records.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Slides.</genreform>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506" id="a14">
<head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>There are no access restrictions on this collection.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
<head>Restrictions on Use</head>
<p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
</userestrict>

<prefercite encodinganalog="510" id="a18">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item description, #:#], <corpname>Davis and Geck Company</corpname> Records. <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Materials donated by Davis and Geck and <persname>Charles T. Riall</persname> in June 1998.   The patent materials were donated in 2008 by the <corpname>Hartford Medical Society</corpname>, which also holds <corpname>Davis and Geck Company</corpname> materials.</p>
</acqinfo>
<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Detailed Description</head>
<c01 level="series">
   <did>
	<unittitle> Series I: Records, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated, 1909-1997</unitdate>
    </did>	

<c02>
<did>
<container type="Box">1</container>
<unittitle>Correspondence from <persname>Charles T. Riall</persname> to <persname>Ian Lawson</persname>, </unittitle>
<unitdate>circa 1997</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Three typed manuscripts - overview of Davis and Geck history, </unittitle>
<unitdate>circa 1972-1979</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Davis and Geck historical articles, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1953-1986</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Historical articles in bound folder, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Miscellaneous historical documents, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1951-1992</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>&#x201C;The Science of Bow-Strings,&#x201D; historical manuscript, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1953</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Documents relating to trial of <persname>Charles T. Davis</persname>, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1921-1930, 1986</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Manuscript drafts of historical articles by <persname>Charles T. Riall</persname>, </unittitle>
<unitdate>circa 1985</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Drafts of Davis and Geck biography for Danbury historical book, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1984-1986</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Davis and Geck Patent Records, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1934-1965</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Customer complaint form and special products order form, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1984-1985</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>'Literature of D+G Sutures' folder cover, </unittitle>
<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Davis and Geck Publications - 3 pamphlets, </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>circa 1916-1923</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Davis and Geck Publications - 6 pamphlets, </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>circa 1916-1929</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Davis and Geck Publications - 5 pamphlets, </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>circa 1913-1929</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Davis and Geck Publications - 4 pamphlets, </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>circa 1920-23</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Print advertisements (photocopies), </unittitle>
<unitdate>1913-1922</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Print advertisements, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1931-1935</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Documents pertaining to <persname>L. Hiller</persname> and the &#x201C;Sutures in Ancient Surgery&#x201D; photo series, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1927-1997</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Ordering info. and price lists - <geogname>U.S.</geogname>, <geogname>Canada</geogname>, and <geogname>England</geogname>, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1937-1949</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Cyanamid Surgical Products Direct-Purchase Plan, </unittitle>
<unitdate>circa 1958</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Patent materials, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1953, 1957-1958</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Promotional materials (9 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1957-1989</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Promotional materials not related to products (7 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1927, 1970, 1989</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Publications: <title render="italic">Lifelines</title> and <title render="italic">Diamond Glitters</title> (9 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1953-1968, 1984</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Publication: 'Strings and Things' (1 item), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1978</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Cyanamid UK supplier's manual, </unittitle>
<unitdate>circa 1990</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle><corpname>American Cyanamid</corpname> Annual Reports (4 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1957-1969</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle><corpname>American Cyanamid</corpname> Annual Reports (4 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1974-1978</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle><corpname>American Cyanamid</corpname> Annual Reports (3 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1980-1987</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle><corpname>American Cyanamid</corpname> Annual Reports (3 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1988-1993</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle><corpname>Sherwood Davis and Geck</corpname> Service Awards (1 item), </unittitle> 
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1997</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="Box">2</container>
<unittitle>Memorabilia (D&#x0026;G logos, 4 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>circa 1970s?</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>'Initial Sales Training' folder, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>'Needle Plant Prospectus' folder, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1982</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>'Supervisor's Manual - Danbury Plant' folder, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1958-1977</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Product catalog folder, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1976-1977</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Product catalog folder, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1986-1987</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Package of lecture slides belonging to Dr. Lawson, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1998?</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Publications--<title render="italic">Diamond Glimmers</title> and <title render="italic">LifeLines</title> [incomplete], </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1959-1985</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>"Primary Nursing Care Workshop," featuring Dr. <persname>Joan O'Leary</persname>, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Gold Cup (permanent file), </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1975, 1977</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Clippings, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="Box">3</container>
<unittitle>5 promotional posters, mounted on styrofoam backing, </unittitle>
<unitdate>circa 1980s?</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>3 safety award plaques, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1957, 1980, 1987</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>1 lab coat with company logo, </unittitle>
<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">4</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Research &#x0026; Development award (Silver bowl), </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Thermal mug, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1994</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02><c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Water bottle, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1991</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Highlighters, Buttons, pins and related promotional materials, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Coverlet&#x00AE; adhesive dressing (1 box), </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Trivia questionnaire, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Text for slide show, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle><corpname>Davis and Geck</corpname> tie, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>circa 1980</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">5</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Photographs, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Slides, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Movie film (surgeon using D&#x0026;G products), </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Audio Cassette (training tape), </unittitle>
	<unitdate>circa 1994</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">6</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>16mm film of James Affleck, CEO of American Cyanamid entitled, "Changes and Challenges", </unittitle>
	<unitdate>circa 1970</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Album of an open house, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1980</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Life Lines, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1989-1995</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Safety data sheets, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1980</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Written materials concerning manufacturing processes, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence to and from the war department, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1917-1918</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Instruction manual and telephone directory, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1994</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Atraumatic needles, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>6 slides, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>ID badge of Dr. Ian Lawson, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1987</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Photo of 'Joe' Judy, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>2 rolls of film, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Make up kit, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">AS</container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Framed memorandum recording the absorption of polglycolic ester (PGA) in laboratory animals, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1963</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="Box">OS</container>
<unittitle>'Commitment to Danbury' floor plans (4 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1995</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Photo enlargements of D&#x0026;G products (4 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1985</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>'Sutures in Ancient Surgery' prints - 2 items, plus `Best Wishes Class of 1959' - photo of Danbury factory (1 item), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc><unitdate>1928-1930, 1959</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>2 photos - picture of a livery stable, and photo of site of former D&#x0026;G offices in Manhattan, </unittitle>
<unitdate>1983</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="Box"></container>
<unittitle>Photo enlargements of D&#x0026;G products (2 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Safety certificates (3 items), </unittitle>
<physdesc></physdesc>
<unitdate>1962, 1981, 1987</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Enlargement of company roster photo, </unittitle>
<unitdate>circa 1920s</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Folder containing oversized photocopies of safety awards and patent certificates, </unittitle>
<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box"></container>
	<container type="Folder"></container>
	<unittitle>Safety Award placques, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1965, 1969, 1981, 1984</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
