<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Ready_for_export" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/hyman/MSS19910050.html">MSS19910050</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Trina Schart Hyman Papers
                    <num>1991.0050</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">Hyman (Trina Schart) Papers</titleproper>
                <subtitle>An Inventory</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Terri J. Goldich</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269-1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-09-06T07:52-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>
                <language>English</language></langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Trina Schart Hyman Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1991.0050</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1985/1994" type="inclusive">1985-1994.</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">Collection of children's book author and illustrator Triana Schart Hyman. The collection contains correspondence, illustrations, manuscripts, and notes related to her and other authors' works.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Hyman, Trina Schart.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biography</head>
            <p>
                <persname>Trina Schart Hyman</persname> was born in 
                <geogname>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</geogname>, in 1939. She spent her youth and early adulthood exploring various forms of art. After attending the 
                <corpname>Philadelphia Museum College of Art</corpname>, 
                <corpname>Boston Museum School of the Arts</corpname>, and 
                <corpname>Konstfackskolan</corpname> (a Swedish state art school), she became the art director for 
                <title render="italic">Cricket</title>, a children's literary magazine. Hyman's works are unique in that they portray her "fantastical" imagination. Before her death in 2004, Hyman was the illustrator of more than 150 books. She won the Caldecott Award for her illustrations in 
                <title render="italic">Saint George and the Dragon</title>. Other illustrations from books such as 
                <title render="italic">Little Red Riding Hood</title>, 
                <title render="italic">Herschel and the Hanukkah Goblins</title>, and 
                <title render="italic">A Child's Calendar</title>, have also received high recognition.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The collection contains correspondence, illustrations, manuscripts, notes, and publications by children's book author and illustrator Trina Schart Hyman. The collection contains materials related to other American illustrators, children's literature, and fairytales.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref5">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p></p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Series I: Inventory</emph> (
                <date>1985-1994</date>)</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#], 
                <persname>Trina Schart Hyman</persname> Papers. 
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Acquisition Information</head>
            <p>The papers were donated to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center by Trina Schart Hyman in 1991.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bibliography id="ref15">
            <head>Bibliography</head>
            <p>Wrote/Adapted and Illustrated: How Six Found Christmas, 1969. (Reteller) The Sleeping Beauty, from the Brothers Grimm, 1977. A Little Alphabet, 1980. Self-Portrait: Trina Schart Hyman, 1981. (Reteller) Little Red Riding Hood, from the Brothers Grimm, 1983. The Enchanted Forest, 1984. Illustrated: Hertha Von Gebhardt, Toffe och den lilla bilen, 1961. Carl Memling, Riddles, Riddles, from A to Z, 1963. Melanie Bellah, Bow Wow! Meow!, 1963. Sandol S. Warburg, Curl Up Small, 1964. Eileen O'Faolain, Children of the Salmon, 1965. All Kinds of Signs, 1965. Ruth Sawyer, Joy to the World: Christmas Legends, 1966. Joyce Varney, The Magic Maker, 1966. Virginia Haviland, reteller, Favourite Fairy Tales Told in Czechoslovakia, 1966. Edna Butler Trickey, Billy Finds Out, 1966. E. B. Trickey, Billy Celebrates, 1966. Jacob D. Townsend, The Five Trials of the Pansy Bed, 1967. Elizabeth Johnson, Stuck with Luck, 1967. Josephine Poole, Moon Eyes, 1967. John T. Moore, Cinnamon Seed, 1967. Paul Tripp, The Little Red Flower, 1968. Eve Merriam, reteller, Epaminondas, 1972. J. Varney, The Half-Time Gypsy, 1968. E. Johnson, All in Free but Janey, 1968. Norah Smaridge, I Do My Best, 1968. Betty M. Owen and Mary MacEwen, editors, Wreath of Carols, 1968. Tom McGowen, Dragon Stew, 1969. Susan Meyers, The Cabin on the Fjord, 1969. Peter Hunter Blair, The Coming of Pout, 1969. Clyde R. Bulla, The Moon Singer, 1969. Ruth Nichols, A Walk Out of the World, 1969. Claudia Paley, Benjamin the True, 1969. P. Tripp, The Vi-Daylin Book of Minnie the Mump, 1970. Donald J. Sobol, Greta the Strong, 1970. Blanche Luria Serwer, reteller, Let's Steal the Moon: Jewish Tales, Ancient and Recent, 1970. Mollie Hunter, The Walking Stones: A Story of Suspense, 1970. Tom McGowen, Sir MacHinery, 1970. Phyllis Krasilovsky, The Shy Little Girl, 1970. The Pumpkin Giant, retold by Ellin Greene, 1970. Wylly Folk St. John, The Ghost Next Door, 1971. Osmond Molarsky, The Bigger They Come, 1971. O. Molarsky, Take It or Leave It, 1971. Carolyn Meyer, The Bread Book: All about Bread and How to Make It, 1971. E. Johnson, Break a Magic Circle, 1971. E. Greene, reteller, Princess Rosetta and the Popcorn Man, 1971. Eleanor Cameron, A Room Made of Windows, 1971. Eleanor Clymer, How I Went Shopping and What I Got, 1972. Dori White, Sarah and Katie, 1972. Ruth Nichols, The Marrow of the World, 1972. Eva Moore, The Fairy Tale Life of Hans Christian Andersen, 1972. Jan Wahl, Magic Heart, 1972. P. Krasilovsky, The Popular Girls Club, 1972. Paula Hendrich, Who Says So?, 1972. Myra Cohn Livingston, editor, Listen, Children, Listen: An Anthology of Poems for the Very Young, 1972. Carol Ryrie Brink, The Bad Times of Irma Baumlein, 1972. Howard Pyle, King Stork, 1973. Hans Christian Andersen, The Ugly Duckling and Two Other Stories, edited by Lillian Moore, 1973. Phyllis La Farge, Joanna Runs Away, 1973. E. Greene, compiler, Clever Cooks: A Concoction of Stories, Recipes and Riddles, 1973. C. R. Brink, Caddie Woodlawn, revised edition, 1973. Elizabeth Coatsworth, The Wanderers, 1973. Eleanor G. Vance, The Everything Book, 1974. Doris Gates, Two Queens of Heaven: Aphrodite and Demeter, 1974. Dorothy S. Carter, editor, Greedy Mariani and Other Folktales of the Antilles, 1974. Charles Causley, Figgie Hobbin, 1974. Charlotte Herman, You've Come a Long Way, Sybil McIntosh: A Book of Manners and Grooming for Girls, 1974. J. Grimm and W. Grimm, Snow White, translated from the German by Paul Heins, 1974. Jean Fritz, Why Don't You Get a Horse, Sam Adams?, 1974. March Wiesbauer, The Big Green Bean, 1974. Tobi Tobias, The Quitting Deal, 1975. Margaret Kimmel, Magic in the Mist, 1975. Jane Curry, The Watchers, 1975. Louise Moeri, Star Mother's Youngest Child, 1975. Jean Fritz, Will You Sign Here, John Hancock?, 1976. Daisy Wallace, editor, Witch Poems, 1976. William Sleator, Among the Dolls, 1976. Tobi Tobias, Jane, Wishing, 1977. Spiridon Vangheli, Meet Guguze, 1977. Norma Farber, Six Impossible Things before Breakfast, 1977. Betsy Hearne, South Star, 1977. Patricia Gauch, On to Widecombe Fair, 1978. Betsy Hearne, Home, 1979. Norma Farber, How Does It Feel to Be Old?, 1979. Pamela Stearns, The Mechanical Doll, 1979. Barbara S. Hazen, Tight Times, 1979. Daisy Wallace, editor, Fairy Poems, 1980. J. M. Barrie, Peter Pan, 1980. Elizabeth G. Jones, editor, Ranger Rick's Holiday Book, 1980. Kathryn Lasky, The Night Journey, 1981. Jean Fritz, The Man Who Loved Books, 1981. J. Grimm and W. Grimm, Rapunzel, retold by Barbara Rogasky, 1982. Margaret Mary Kimmel and Elizabeth Segel, For Reading Out Loud! A Guide to Sharing Books with Children, 1983. Mary Calhoun, Big Sixteen, 1983. Astrid Lindgren, Ronia the Robber's Daughter, 1983. Charles Dickens, A Christmas Carol: In Prose, Being a Ghost Story of Christmas, 1983. M. C. Livingston, Christmas Poems, 1984. (With Hilary Knight and others) Pamela Espeland and Marilyn Waniek, The Cat Walked through the Casserole: And Other Poems for Children, 1984. Margaret Hodges, Saint George and the Dragon: A Golden Legend Adapted from Edmund Spenser's Faerie Queen, 1984. Elizabeth Winthrop, The Castle in the Attic, 1985. Dylan Thomas, A Child's Christmas in Wales, 1985. J. Grimm and W. Grimm, The Water of Life, retold by B. Rogasky, 1986. Vivian Vande Velde, A Hidden Magic, 1986. Myra Cohn Livingston, compiler, Cat Poems, 1987. Mark Twain, A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court, 1988. Geoffrey Chaucer, Canterbury Tales, adapted by Barbara Cohen, 1988. (With Marcia Brown and others) Beatrice Schenk de Regniers, compiler, Sing a Song of Popcorn, 1988. Swan Lake, retold by Margot Fonteyn, 1989. Eric Kimmel, Hershel and the Hanukkah Goblins, 1989. Margaret Hodges, The Kitchen Knight: A Tale from King Arthur, 1990. B. Rogasky, compiler and editor, Winter Poems, 1991. Lloyd Alexander, The Fortune-Tellers, 1992. Marion Dane Bauer, Ghost Eye, 1992. Eric A. Kimmel, reteller, Iron John, 1994. Kimmel, reteller, The Adventures of Hershel of Ostropol, 1995. Barbara Rogasky, The Golem: A Version, 1996. Margaret Hodges, adapter, Comus, 1996. Angela Shelf Medearis, Haunts: Five Hair-Raising Tales, 1996. Howard Pyle, Bearskin, 1997. John Updike, A Child's Calendar, 1999. Katrin Tchana, reteller, The Serpent Slayer and Other Stories of Strong Women, 2000. Sherry Garland, Children of the Dragon: Selected Tales from Vietnam, 2001. Katrin Tchana, Sense Pass King: A Tale from Cameroon, 2002. Dean Whitlock, "Sky Carver", 2005 Contributor of illustrations to textbooks and Cricket magazine. Katrin Tchana, Changing Woman and Her Sisters: Goddesses from Around the World, 2006. Adaptations: Dragon Stew was adapted as a filmstrip with record, BFA Educational Media, 1975; Tight Times was filmed as a "Reading Rainbow" special, PBS-TV, 1983; Little Red Riding Hood was adapted as a filmstrip with cassette, Listening Library, 1984.</p>
        </bibliography>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref16">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=1">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest"></persname>
            <genreform source="local">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Illustrations (visual works).</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Manuscripts.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Notes.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Publications.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Inventory,</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid763001" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1985/1994" type="inclusive">1985-1994</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, illustrations, manuscripts, notes, publications,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid762001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1985/1994" type="inclusive">1985-1988, 1990-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref14">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: American illustrators, Children's literature, fairytales.]</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
