<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://lcweb2.loc.gov/xmlcommon/dtds/ead2002/ead.dtd">
<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
<eadid url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/Chatham/MSS19800001.html" mainagencycode="US-CtU" countrycode="US">MSS19800001</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Chatham Quarry Records</titleproper>
<author>Finding aid prepared by Aldo E. Salerno.</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>&#x00A9; 2004 University of Connecticut</publisher>
<date type="publication">June 1991</date>
<address><addressline1>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</addressline1><addressline2>405 Babbidge Road, Unit 1205</addressline2><addressline3>Storrs, Connecticut 06269-1205</addressline3></address>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation><date>Text converted and initial EAD encoding provided by Apex CoVantage, April 2005.</date></creation>
<langusage><language>English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a"><corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center</corpname>.</repository>
<origination label="Creator:">
<corpname encodinganalog="110">Chatham Quarry (Portland, Conn.).</corpname>
</origination>
<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Chatham Quarry Records.</unittitle>
<unitdate label="Dates:">1818-1842</unitdate>
<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">.5 linear feet.</physdesc>
<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" repositorycode="UCW">MSS19800001</unitid>
<langmaterial><language>English</language>.</langmaterial>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">The Chatham Quarry, or Town Quarry, was a small part of the extensive brownstone quarries located on the banks of the Connecticut River near the towns of Portland and Middletown, Connecticut. The Chatham Quarry, which took in about two acres, remained under municipal control for the use of the inhabitants of the towns of Chatham and Middletown throughout its existence. In 1824, the town of Middletown leased the quarry to John Lawrence Lewis for five years in order to extract stones for the building of a scientific and military academy. The quarry was bought from the town by Brainerd Quarry Company and the Middlesex Quarry Company for $20,000. The office of the town quarry agent closed in 1884.</abstract>
</did>
<bioghist altrender="history" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
<head>History</head>
<p>The <corpname>Chatham Quarry</corpname>, or <corpname>Town Quarry</corpname>, was a small part of the extensive brownstone quarries located on the banks of the <geogname>Connecticut River</geogname> near the towns of Portland and <geogname>Middletown, Connecticut</geogname>. As early as the 1650s, settlers used small  pieces of the brownstone for building materials. When the townspeople of Middletown  realized the value of these enormous deposits, they hired caretakers to manage them. After  the Revolutionary War, the town was forced to sell off the quarries to private interests  to pay their war debt. By the 1849s, control of the quarries rested mainly with three  companies&#x2014;<corpname>Shaler and Hall, Middlesex Quarry Company</corpname> and <corpname>Brainerd Brothers</corpname>.</p>
<p>The brownstone was of excellent quality and was in demand in practically every part of the country. The stone was used extensively for gravestones and monuments throughout New England. One block of the Washington Monument was built with Portland brownstone. Other prominent buildings constructed with this stone were the old Hancock House in Boston, the <corpname>Copper Institute</corpname> and the <corpname>Astor Library</corpname> in New York City, and the mansions of such influential industrialists as <persname>William H. Vanderbilt</persname> and <persname>Fractured Gallatin</persname> in New York City, <persname>George Pullman</persname> in Chicago, and <persname>George Corliss</persname> in <geogname>Providence, Rhode Island</geogname>.</p>
<p>The <corpname>Chatham Quarry</corpname>, which took in about two acres, remained under municipal control for the use of the inhabitants of the towns of Chatham and Middletown throughout its existence. For almost two hundred years the residents had the right to use the stone to build cellars, steps, walks and more. In 1824, the town of Middletown leased the quarry to <persname>John Lawrence Lewis</persname> for five years in order to extract stones for the building of a scientific and military academy, although the academy was never built. In 1883, the town offered use of the quarry as an inducement to <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname> to locate in Middletown. For the sum of $10,000, <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname> enjoyed the usage of the quarry for almost forty years, and many of the university's finest buildings were constructed from <corpname>Chatham Quarry</corpname> stone.</p>
<p>The quarry was controlled and managed by the town until August 1884, when it was bought by <corpname>Brainerd Quarry Company</corpname> and the <corpname>Middlesex Quarry Company</corpname> for $20,000. The sum was divided among the towns of Middletown, Portland, Cromwell, and Chatham. The quarry had already been exhausted, and the town had been leasing it to the <corpname>Brainerd Company</corpname> for quite some time as a storage area for scrap and stone. The office of the town quarry agent closed in 1884. The last person to hold this office was <persname>William H. Beebe</persname>.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
<head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The records of the <corpname>Chatham Quarry</corpname> detail the daily financial transactions of one of the oldest brownstone quarries in the <geogname>United States</geogname>. All of the records are handwritten ledger sheets or financial documents. Records of an administrative or personnel nature are not available. The records are composed of sales and expense statements for the quarry for the years 1818-1839 and 1832-1841. It also includes one folder of statements, account balances and receipts for the years 1833-1842.</p>
</scopecontent>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
	<head>Related Material</head>
	<p>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut businesses.  For detailed information on these collections please contact the <extref href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=4">curator</extref> or ask at the reference desk.</p>
</relatedmaterial>

<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>
<p>This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.</p>
<controlaccess>
<head>Organizations:</head>
<corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Brainerd Quarry Company.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Middlesex Quarry Company.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Brownstone industry.</corpname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects:</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Quarries and quarrying&#x2014;Connecticut.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Connecticut&#x2014;Mines, mining, and mineral resources&#x2014;Brownstone.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Portland (Conn.)&#x2014;Mines, mining, and mineral resources&#x2014;Brownstone.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Middlesex County (Conn.)&#x2014;Business, industries, and trades&#x2014;Quarrying.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Middletown (Conn.)&#x2014;Business, industries, and trades&#x2014;Quarrying.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Middlesex County (Conn.)&#x2014;Mines, mining, and mineral resources&#x2014;Brownstone.</subject>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Document Types:</head>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Financial Records.</genreform>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Occupations:</head>
<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="local">Quarry.</occupation>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506" id="a14">
<head>Restrictions on Access</head>
<p>There are no access restrictions on this collection.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
<head>Restrictions on Use</head>
<p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
</userestrict>
<custodhist encodinganalog="561" id="a16">
<head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The <corpname>Chatham Quarry</corpname> Records were donated to <corpname>Yale University</corpname> by <corpname>Harvard Business School</corpname> in 1942. The Yale Library Manuscripts and Archives donated the records to the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> Libraries in January, 1980.</p>
</custodhist>
<prefercite encodinganalog="510" id="a18">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item description, #:#], Chatham Quarry Records. <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The Yale Library Manuscripts and Archives donated the records to the <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname> in January, 1980.</p>
</acqinfo>
<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Detailed Description</head>
<c01 level="series">
   <did>
	<unittitle> Series I: Records, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1818-1842</unitdate>
    </did>	

<c02>
<did>
<container type="Box">1:</container>
<container type="Folder">1-23</container>
<unittitle>Sales and expenses, <unitdate>1818-1841</unitdate></unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="Box">1:</container>
<container type="Folder">24</container>
<unittitle>Statements, Account balances and receipts, <unitdate>1833-1842</unitdate></unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
