<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">

<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">


<eadid url="http://chpc.lib.uconn.edu/" mainagencycode="US-CtU" countrycode="US">MSS19840028</eadid>

<filedesc>
	<titlestmt>
		<titleproper>Connecticut Historic Preservation Collection</titleproper>
		<subtitle></subtitle>
		<author>Finding aid prepared by Laura Katz Smith.</author>

</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
	<publisher> &#x00A9; 2010  University of Connecticut</publisher>
	<date type="publication">April 2010</date>

	<address><addressline>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</addressline><addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline><addressline>405 Babbidge Road, Unit 1205</addressline><addressline>Storrs, Connecticut  06269-1205</addressline><addressline>URL: http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/</addressline></address>

</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>

<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by Laura Katz Smith in April 2010.</creation>
<langusage><language>English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
	<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
	<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a"><corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. 
Dodd Research Center</corpname>
		</repository>

	<origination label="Creator:">
		<corpname encodinganalog="110">Connecticut Historical Commission.</corpname>
	</origination>

	<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Connecticut Historic Preservation Collection.</unittitle>

	<unitdate label="Dates:">1975-2010.</unitdate>

	<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">200 linear feet.</physdesc>

		<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" 
		repositorycode="US-UCW">MSS19840028</unitid>

	<langmaterial><language>English</language>.
	</langmaterial>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">The Connecticut Commission on Culture and Tourism’s State Historic 
Preservation Office (SHPO) and the Office of Connecticut State Archaeology are the lead agencies for the preservation of the state's archaeological and architectural historic heritage. This guide provides references to documentary, architectural 
and archaeological survey reports conducted in accordance with federal, state, and local regulations regarding cultural 
resource protection, provided by SHPO, and is intended to provide researchers with an overview of the 
available literature and completed surveys. The surveys are organized by the 169 Connecticut towns, as well as sections for 
Statewide, Regional or Thematic surveys, and  thereunder within four catagories of types of surveys 
-- Historical and Architectural, Archaeological, Documentation Studies, and Maps.  Other materials include books, CDs, 
posters, and pamphlets.</abstract>


</did>


<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->


<bioghist altrender="biography" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
	<head>Organizational History</head>
	<p>The <corpname>Connecticut Historical Commission</corpname> was established in 1955 as a state agency, and was mandated when the National Historic Preservation Act required every state to appoint a State Historic Preservation Officer and establish a State Historic Preservation Office.  In 2003 <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> established the Division on Culture and Tourism which combined the state's historical commission, the Commission on the Arts, the Film Office and the Tourism Office.  The division administers the State Register of Historic Places as well as federally funded National Register-based programs designed to identify, register, and protect the buildings, sites, structures, districts, and objects that comprise and define <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>'s cultural heritage. The CHC also possesses regulatory authority for all archaeological studies undertaken on state lands or within state-administered waters. </p>
</bioghist>

<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
	<head>Scope and Content</head>
	<p>The collection consists of archaeological surveys, historical and architectural surveys, documentation studies of 
properties, and maps, produced for the <corpname>Connecticut Historical Commission</corpname> by archaeologists and 
historians.  Other materials include books, CDs, posters, and pamphlets.  </p>

<p>Architectural Surveys:</p>

<p>Most of the historical and architectural surveys were completed by selected towns in the state to inventory properties they 
deemed historical and noteworthy. These surveys often determined which properties would be eligible for submission to the 
National Register of Historic Places.  Please note that the forms for the NRHP submissions are not kept with the CHPC; they 
are kept at Connecticut's Division of Culture and Tourism, in Hartford.   </p>



<p>Archaeological Surveys:</p>

<p>The <corpname>Connecticut State Historic Preservation Office</corpname> (SHPO) describes the archaeological survey process in this manner: </p>

<p>The National Historic Preservation Act mandates that all federally funded, assisted, licensed and/or permitted projects be 
reviewed by the <corpname>Connecticut State Historic Preservation Office</corpname>. As such, they review 1,200 to 1,500 
proposed projects annually and, depending upon specific project location, will require the federal agency (or permit 
applicant) to employ a professional archaeological consultant to conduct appropriate historic and archaeological studies. 
Approximately seventy percent of the archaeological reports are generated from the federal review process.</p>

<p>The <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> Environmental Policy Act (CEPA) mandates that state agencies coordinate with SHPO regarding the consideration of historic and archaeological resources as part of project planning and development. Unlike the federal process, state agency assisted, permitted or licensed projects are exempt from the historical 
commission's  review.  It is only when the state agency proposes an action (such as, for example, a new campus building, changes in a state park, construction of a new prison) that SHPO has an opportunity to review and comment.  Also, any proposed archaeological investigation on state lands (whether CEPA-related or academic research) requires a permit from the office. About ten percent of the CHPC archaeological reports are generated in this manner.</p>

<p>About thirty town governments have enacted Planning and Zoning regulations that require developers to consult with 
the State Archaeologist regarding archaeological sensitivity of proposed subdivisions. In turn, the State Archaeologist 
may require the developer to hire an archaeological consultant.  Also, towns have chosen to require archaeological surveys, 
irrespective of its regulations, for especially complex or controversial projects as an important way to gather additional 
information about a proposed development area. This generates about ten percent of CHPC reports.</p>

<p>The last ten percent represents projects that tribal governments, town governments, and/or private property owners have 
commissioned to acquire baseline data about their respective properties.  Other surveys may be generated as academic research 
projects (thesis-related).</p>

<p>[Thanks to <persname>David Poirier</persname>, former Staff Archeologist of the <corpname>Connecticut Historical 
Commission</corpname>, for the above description of the survey process.]</p>

<p>Documentation Studies:</p>
<p>Documentation studies are generated when a federal or <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>-funded project has to take into account its affects on historical archeaological resources.  The studies document the "before" structure or when changes in the structure mitigate adverse effects of changing or destroying the building.  If the building is considered irreplaceable or very important historically then the <corpname>State Historic Preservation Office</corpname> decides whether or not to allow the project to proceed.</p>

</scopecontent>

<arrangement encodinganalog="351$b" id="a5">
	<head>Arrangement</head>
	<p>The surveys and studies are arranged alphabetically by <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> town and thereunder by historic and architectural survey, archaeological survey, documentation study, and maps.  Cities in the state of <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> are considered dependent municipalities, meaning they are located within and subordinate to a town. All but one -- <geogname>Groton, Connecticut</geogname> -- of the currently existing cities in Connecticut are consolidated with their parent town.  Winsted is an incorporated city but administered within the town of Winchester.  Former cities include South Norwalk, which is consolidated in the town of Norwalk; Rockville, which is a census-designated place and a village in the town of Vernon; and Willimantic, a census-designated place in the town of Windham. Information about villages within towns (ex. Storrs is a village of the town of Mansfield) can be found within the literature about the town.</p>

<p>Historical and Architectural Surveys and Documentation Studies should be requested by town and title of survey or study, 
or title only.  Archaeological surveys are each given an item number (ex. CHPC no. 756).  Maps are organized by town.</p>


</arrangement>

<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
	<head>Related Material</head>
	<p>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various 
aspects of Connecticut history, flora, fauna and environment.  For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
<extref href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=4">curator</extref> or ask at the reference desk.</p>
</relatedmaterial> 


<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->

<!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->

<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>
<p>This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.</p>		
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Organizations:</head>
			<corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Connecticut Commission on Arts, Culture, History and Film.</corpname>
		   <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Connecticut Historical Commission : State Preservation Office.</corpname>
		</controlaccess>
							
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Subjects:</head>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Archaeology -- Connecticut.</subject>
	      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Connecticut -- History.</subject>
 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Historic buildings -- Connecticut.</subject>
		</controlaccess>
		
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Document Types:</head>

<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Publications.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Photographs.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Blueprints.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Maps.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Photocopies.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Books.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Drawings.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Posters.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Histories.</genreform>

		</controlaccess>
		
		</controlaccess>


<!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->

<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->


<accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
	<head>Restrictions on Access</head>
	<p>There are no access restrictions on this collection.</p>
</accessrestrict>

<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
	<head>Restrictions on Use</head>
	<p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the 
University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
</userestrict><prefercite encodinganalog="510" id="a18">
	<head>Preferred Citation</head>
	<p>[Item description, CHPC no.],  Connecticut Historic Preservation Collection.  <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special 
Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
	<head>Acquisition Information</head>
	<p>The surveys, studies, books, and other materials, were initially donated by the Connecticut Historical Commission in 
1984.  Additions to the surveys are made on a continuing basis, as they are generated by the archeaologists and historians who 
provide them for the State Historic Preservation Office.</p>

</acqinfo>



<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->

<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Detailed Description</head>

<c01 level="series">
   <did>
	<unittitle>Architectural and Archaeological Surveys, Documentation Studies and Maps, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>1975-2010</unitdate>
    </did>	

<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<unittitle>Materials are listed in a database: <extref href="http://chpc.lib.uconn.edu/">http://chpc.lib.uconn.edu/</extref>.  The surveys and studies are available at 
 <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, <corpname>University of 
Connecticut Libraries</corpname>. </unittitle>
	<unitdate></unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

</c01>

</dsc>

</archdesc>
</ead>
