<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Ready_for_export" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/good/MSS19970047.html">MSS19970047</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Peter Good Papers
                    <num>1997.0047</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">Good (Peter) Papers</titleproper>
                <subtitle>An Inventory</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Kristen DeBona and Ashley Norris.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269-1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>March 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2013-02-07T10:55-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 2013</date>
                <item></item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Peter Good Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1997.0047</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>12.25 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1990/2013" type="inclusive">1990-2013</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The collection contains calendars, posters and realia associated with the work of Cummings and Good Graphic Designs.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Good, Peter</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biography</head>
            <p>Peter Good, born in the south end of Hartford, CT, is an internationally recognized graphic designer and illustrator who is well-known in Connecticut for the powerful images he has created for countless corporations, small businesses, museums, and art organizations. Raised on Franklin Avenue by a housepainter father and a homemaker mother, Peter Good first became involved in the art world while at the University of Connecticut where he began his academic career in psychology and ended up in graphic design after taking a studio design course. Good graduated from the University of Connecticut School of Fine Arts with a B.F.A. in Graphic Design after working under professor Paul Zelanski in 1965. After graduation, Good worked for a small design agency in his hometown of Hartford, CT that served mostly industrial clients. In 1967, Good went to New York City and spent six months at Chermayeff and Geismar, and then went to Appelbaum and Curtis. After two years, Good took a job in Middletown, CT working with Xerox Education Publications.</p>
            <p>It was not until 1971, that Good established his own studio called Peter Good Graphic Design in Chester, Connecticut where he worked on various design assignments for companies and institutions such as United Technologies Corporation, Mystic Seaport, Hartford Symphony Orchestra, The National Theatre of the Deaf, and the Connecticut Humanities Council. While Good's work has run the gamut from corporate logos to book covers to calendars, he is perhaps best know for his work with posters, which since 1984 have been included in each of the Warsaw Poster Biennial Exhibitions, in every Lahti Poster Biennial Exhibition in Finland, and in all of the International Poster Triennials in Toyama, Japan. Good's posters are represented in the collections of the Library of Congress, the Cooper-Hewitt Museum, the Museum of Modern Art in Toyama, Japan, and the Die Neue Sammlung Museum in Munich, Germany.</p>
            <p>Today Good, with his wife Jan Cummings Good, owns and runs Cummings&amp;Good Graphic Design Studio at their renovated 1809 studio in Chester, Connecticut. Good and his wife create identities, posters, books, and brochures for Fortune 500 companies, creative entrepreneurs, and artful non-profits. Recently, Cummings&amp;Good have completed works for the new Connecticut Science Center in Hartford, a 2009 comprehensive brochure for Connecticut Landmarks, material for the Paris Air Show for United Technologies, a poster for the Manchester String Quartet 2009 concert series at the National Institutes of Health in Washington DC, the 2009 season brochure for Musical Masterworks in Old Lyme, and an invitation for Goodspeed Musicals’ 2009 Gala.</p>
            <p>In addition to the design studio, Cummings&amp;Good also serves as a store called C&amp;G located on the first floor of Peter and Jan’s landmark 1809 studio in the heart of Chester Center. The 200 year old space has been renovated and returned to its 19th century origins when it was known as Chester’s Stone Storesell. C&amp;G offers note cards, art prints, and signature themed calendars, but the emphasis is on high-quality clothing and accessories.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The collection contains the posters, calendars, memorabilia, and original artwork of Peter Good.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#] 
                <corpname>Peter Good</corpname> Papers. 
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Acquisition Information</head>
            <p>Materials in the collection have been donated periodically by 
                <persname>Peter Good</persname> beginning in 1997.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref21">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=3">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <genreform source="aat">Advertisements.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Fliers. [printed matter]</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Illustrations (layout features).</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Posters.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Press releases.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Publications.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Works of Art.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Inventory,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/2010" type="inclusive">1990-2012</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Publications,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid952001" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1991" type="inclusive">1990-1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref15">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: 
                            <title render="italic">The Japan Idea</title>, 
                            <title render="italic">Connecticut Masters</title>, 
                            <title render="italic">Wadsworth Atheneum</title>, (3) "25 Good Posters."]</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Calendars,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid952004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1998/1999" type="inclusive">1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Calendars,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid952002" type="Item" label="Graphic materials">1-10</container>
                        <container id="cid1428001" type="Item" label="Graphic materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1998/2013" type="inclusive">1998-2001, 2003-2006, 2007, 2009-2010, 2013</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref17">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Calendars in tins.]</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Realia, Publications, Fliers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid952003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1996/1997" type="inclusive">1996-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref19">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: (1) Tee Shirt, (2) Pins, Annual Reports, "
                            <corpname>Cummings and Good Graphic Designs</corpname>."]</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
