<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Exported" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/nacla/MSS19990119.html">MSS19990119</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) Archive of Latin Americana
                    <num>1999.0119</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Finding aid prepared by Betsy Pittman.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 2007</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-01-11T14:24-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) Archive of Latin Americana</unittitle>
            <unitid>1999.0119</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="spa"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>135.0 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1985" type="bulk">Bulk, 1965-1985</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1950/1990" type="inclusive">1950s-1990s</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref6" label="Languages">English. Spanish.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref11" label="Abstract">The NACLA Archive brings together publications from and about all Latin American countries. Predominant throughout are primary sources, with secondary sources consisting mainly of research institutes' working papers and other similar types of scholarship. A large portion of the archive was microfilmed in 1998 by Scholarly Resources, Inc.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="local" source="local">North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>History</head>
            <p>The North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) was founded in response to the April 1965 U.S. invasion of the Dominican Republic. This armed intervention by the United States against a popular uprising -- classic gunboat diplomacy -- preempted the restoration to power of freely elected president Juan Bosch. It also paved the way for the thirty year dictatorship of caudillo Joaquin Balaguer. NACLA's founders were especially struck by the Johnson administration's ability to disseminate its version of events virtually unchallenged, while mainstream opinion makers set the tone of a limited public debate. Moreover, as the U.S. intervention in Vietnam began in ernest, progressive critics and opponents of U.S. policy, both abroad and at home, began seriously to consider questions about the nature of public education, the role of independent media, and how to make critical analysis of the U.S. power structure accessible to a broad and interested public.</p>
            <p>NACLA, which took shape from these questions, was founded in October and November of 1966 in a series of meetings of Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, the University Christian Movement, and returned Peace Corps volunteers, along with assorted other individuals and organizations. According to its articles of incorporation, NACLA's role was "to encourage, produce and distribute information designed to identify and explain those elements and relationships of forces in the United States and Latin America which inhibit and frustrate urgently needed profound social and economic change." The "congress" in NACLA's name was suggested by the "Congress of Unrepresented People," a contemporary group of civil rights, antinuclear, and labor activists who came together to challenge elite conceptions of the national interest as fundamentally opposed to the real interests of the majority of the American people.</p>
            <p>[See the preface of the attached PDF file (7.9 MB), linked under Detailed Description, for further details.]</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The NACLA Archive is the largest and most extensive collection of its type. The Archive brings together publications from and about all Latin American countries. Predominant throughout are primary sources, with secondary sources consisting mainly of research institutes' working papers and other similar types of scholarship. The Archive represents the ideas and concerns of various interest groups about the conditions within a particular country. A large portion of the archive was microfilmed in 1998 by Scholarly Resources, Inc.</p>
            <p>[See the Scope and Contents of the attached PDF file (7.9MB), linked under Detailed Description, for further details.]</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref3">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The materials have been arranged by the creator alphabetically by country of origin.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
            <p>There are no access restrictions on this collection.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref7">
            <head>Related material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Latin America. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#], North American Congress on Latin America Archive of Latin Americana. Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <altformavail id="ref9">
            <head>Alternative Form Available</head>
            <p>The Archive was microfilmed in 1998 by Scholarly Resources, Inc.</p>
        </altformavail>
        <controlaccess>
            <genreform source="local">Photocopies.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Publications.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref10" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Finding aid</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1999/1999">1999</unitdate>
                </did>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Finding aid " ns2:role="Text-Service" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/nacla/nacla.pdf">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Finding aid , 1999 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
