<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Ready_for_export" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/storrsexperiment/MSS19720001.html">MSS19720001</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Records
                    <num>1972.0001</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Records</titleproper>
                <subtitle>An inventory</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Laureen Riley, Aldo E. Salerno,Betsy Pittman and Daniel Allie.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269-1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-09-06T07:28-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>The finding aid is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>February 1991</date>
                <item></item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>1972.0001</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>28.0 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1888/1920" type="bulk">Bulk, 1888-1920</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1882/1950" type="inclusive">1882-1950</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">The records of the Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station provide information on one of the oldest agricultural experiment and research stations in the United States. The records provide substantial information on the early years of the Experiment Station from 1888 to 1920. The majority of the records consist of correspondence to and from the executive and administrative staff of the station and local farmers and business organizations interested in obtaining information about the station's experiments and research findings.</abstract>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The records of the 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural Experiement Station</corpname> provide information on one of the oldest agricultural experiment and research stations in the 
                <corpname>United States</corpname>. The records provide substantial information on the early years of the Experiment Station from 1888 to 1920.</p>
            <p>The records provide valuable insight into the relations between the station and the farming communities in 
                <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>, the interactions between agricultural stations and the relationship of the station to the state and federal government. The records also describe the agricultural problems of the times, the solutions and suggestions that were offered, and many of the farming implements and methods that were used in Connecticut during the period covered by the materials.</p>
            <p>The records span the first sixty years of the experiment station's history (1888-1950), but the bulk of the records cover the period from 1888-1920. The majority of the records consist of correspondence to and from the executive and administrative staff of the station and local farmers and business organizations interested in obtaining information about the station's experiments and research findings. Significant correspondents include: 
                <persname>W. O. Atwater</persname>, 
                <persname>W. H. Leslie</persname>, 
                <persname>F. E. Singleton</persname>, 
                <persname>Clarence Atkins</persname>, 
                <persname>Fred Chadwick</persname>, 
                <persname>C. S. Phelps</persname> and 
                <persname>W. B. Young</persname>. The records also contain detailed records of the station's financial condition from 1888 to 1899. The records do not contain the actual research findings or publications and bulletins of the Experiment Station.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>History</head>
            <p>The creation of an agricultural experiment station in 
                <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> was first suggested by Professor 
                <persname>Wilbur Olin Atwater</persname> of 
                <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname> in an address before the State Board of Agriculture in December 1873. Due to Atwater's persuasive powers, the 
                <corpname>Connecticut General Assembly</corpname> appropriated $5,600 for the establishment of a temporary, two-year experiment station at 
                <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname>. The station, the first of its kind in America, was started in 1875 with Atwater as its director.</p>
            <p>In March 1877, the General Assembly granted $5,000 annually for the creation of a permanent agricultural experiment station at 
                <corpname>Yale University</corpname>, then the land grant college of 
                <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>. The station was established at the 
                <corpname>Sheffield Scientific School</corpname> of Yale in New Haven. Its first director was Professor 
                <persname>Samuel Johnson</persname> of Yale.</p>
            <p>In March 1877, Congress passed the Hatch Act which authorized to each state a grant of $15,000 for the creation of agricultural experiment stations in connection with the land grant colleges. Both 
                <corpname>Yale University</corpname> and the 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural School</corpname>, created in 1881, claimed the grant as the legitimate land grant college in 
                <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>. The 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural School</corpname>'s claim was supported by the 
                <corpname>Connecticut State Grange</corpname>. The 
                <corpname>Connecticut General Assembly</corpname> settled the dispute by splitting the grant between the two claimants.</p>
            <p>The 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station</corpname> was formally established in April 1888, with Professor 
                <persname>W. O. Atwater</persname> of 
                <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname> (Class of 1865) as its director. The purpose of the station was to conduct research and experiments to further agricultural progress. The results of investigations were published in the bulletins which were made available to 
                <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> residents upon request. The station was directed from 
                <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname>. Field experiements were conducted at the 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural School</corpname>, while laboratory experiements were conducted at the chemistry lab at 
                <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname>.</p>
            <p>The General Assembly finally granted an annual appropriation of $1,800 for the 
                <corpname>Storrs Experiment Station</corpname> in 1895. Professor Atwater remained the director until 1903 when he resigned and the station was reorganized under the sole control of the 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural College</corpname>, completely severing its ties with 
                <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname>.</p>
            <p>In 1912, the 
                <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural School</corpname> at Yale and the Storrs Experiment Station were joined under the direction of Dr. 
                <persname>E. H. Jenkins</persname> of Yale. The purpose of this joint directorship was to ensure harmony of purpose and to prevent duplication of effort. Professor Jenkins remained the director of the station until 1922, when he was replaced by Professor 
                <persname>William L. Slate, Jr.</persname>, a Professor of Agronomy at the Connecticut Agricultural School. Professor Slate served as director until 1949. Members of the Station staff devoted the majority of their time to research while others taught and conducted research depending upon the needs of the Station, In 1925, Congress passed the Purnell Act which granted to 
                <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> an annual sum of $60,000 in support of its two experiment stations. The Connecticut Agricultural School specialized primarily in plant work, while the Storrs Experiment Station focused on animal industry.</p>
            <p>The achievements of the 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station</corpname> during its first fifty years of existence were notable. Investigations were conducted in numerous areas such as poultry disease and breeding, animal parasites, calf-feeding, pasture management and other subjects. The station was the first to describe and classify the bacteria of milk and milk products. It contributed greatly to the knowledge of the role of legumes in soil fertility, helped to establish practices for the feeding and management of dairy cattle and it worked out the correct practices for the incubation of eggs. Measures for controlling stomach worm in sheep were also developed at the Station.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref8">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=3">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#], 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station</corpname> Records. 
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <custodhist id="ref6">
            <head>Custodial History</head>
            <p>The records of the Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station were given to the Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station by the Olin Library of 
                <corpname>Wesleyan University</corpname> on 28 June 1966. The records were then transferred to the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> Library Special Collections Department. In 1973, the records were removed from Special Collections due to lack of storage space and placed in the College of Agriculture vault.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Provenance and Acquisition</head>
            <p>The records were transferred from the College of Agriculture to the University Archives in 1981.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Restrictions on Use and Copyright Information</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest" role="Donor (dnr)">Storrs Agricultural College.</corpname>
            <subject source="aat">Archives.</subject>
            <genreform source="local">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Manuscripts.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Publications.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Reports.</genreform>
            <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref10" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: An Inventory</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>22.05 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1882/1947" type="inclusive">1882, 1888-1920, 1924, 1933-1947</unitdate>
                </did>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                    <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                    <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                    <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                    <subject source="local">Agriculture—Connecticut.</subject>
                    <subject source="local">Connecticut—Agriculture.</subject>
                    <genreform source="local">Financial Records.</genreform>
                    <genreform source="local">Ledgers.</genreform>
                    <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                    <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.</geogname>
                    <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.</geogname>
                    <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                    <geogname source="local">Storrs, Conn.</geogname>
                    <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, ephemera, fliers, notes, administrative records, transcripts, financial records, manuscripts,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1161001" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized A-B</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1897/1920" type="inclusive">1897, 1901-1905, 1907-1909, 1911, 1913, 1914, 1916, 1917, 1919, 1920,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref12">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from companies and organizations: A.B. Ansbacher and Co.; Ansbacher Insecticide Co, Inc.; American Association for the Advancement of Science; American Coal Products Company; American Cooperative Creameries Association; American Express Company; American Farm-Management Association; American Flax Fibre &amp; Linen Corp.; American Milling Company; American Hardware Corporation.</p>
                        <p>Correspondence to and from individuals: Pres. Charles Lewis Beach, Charles M. Jarvis, Pres. Rufus W. Stimson, L.A. Prof. Clinton, Francis G. Benedict, James S. Judd, Frank Avery, Prof. H.J. Baker, Prof. William L. Slate, E.H. Jenkins, Dir. H.J. Baker.</p>
                        <p>Correspondence with farms and experiment stations: Middletown, Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station; Vermont Agricultural Experiment Station (Burlington, VT.); Valentine Farm; Snow Farm; Whitney Farm.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural subjects discussed in correspondence: sulfate of ammonia as pesticide; camembert cheese (Charles M. Jarvis); shropshire sheep; winter vetch; alfalfa hay; poultry testing; crop planting; pigs; white pine blister; model farms.</p>
                        <p>Fliers, publications, and Ephemera on: "The Fourth Annual Meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Agricultural Teaching, November 11, 1913" (schedule of events); "Potato Scab and its Prevention" (flier); "Farm Estimate for quarter July-Sept. 1908;" "Practical Agriculture."</p>
                        <p>General Subjects, Storrs, Connecticut, University of Connecticut, University of Connecticut History, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural School.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Middletown (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, notes, postcards,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1161002" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized B-C</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1920" type="inclusive">1893, 1896-1903, 1905, 1907-1913, 1916, 1918-1920</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref14">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: A.L. Benedict, inventor of "Benedict's Celebrated Rolling Window Screens for the Exclusion of Insects;" Prof. L.A. Clinton; Fred L. Belden; Peaceful Nook Farm, Huckleberry Hills (New Canaan, CT); Dr. F.G. Benedict; Prof. W.O. Atwater; A.P. Bryant; Davol Rubber Co.; Melvin Brandow; Title Insurance Company; Fred Koenig; H.C. Burrington; A.I. Bush, Attorney at Law; Greenwich High School; Ontario Agricultural College (Guelph, Canada); Ontario Veterinary College; Dominion of Canada Department of Agriculture; "The Canadian Horticulturalist" (publication); United States Department of Agriculture, Washington, D.C.; U.S. Senate Committee on Agriculture and Forestry; Middletown, CT, Experiment Station.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural Subjects in correspondence: pesticide use; San Jose Scale insects; metabolism experiments--carbon content; alcohol experimentation; fertilizers; cultivation of soy beans; Bordeaux Mixture (for fighting Blight); Chestnut Blight; leaf-miners; soil testing; alfalfa cultivation.</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Middletown Experiment Station, Storrs, CT, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, financial records, publications, legal documents, ephemera,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1161003" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, Alphabetized C-D</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1889/1924" type="inclusive">1889, 1894, 1896-1901, 1904-1914, 1917-1918, 1920, 1924,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref16">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Professor W.L. Slate; Alfred Cochran; Thomas M. Cochrane; The Core Brass Manufacturing Company; The Coe Mortimer Company, Importers of Genuine Peruvian Guano, Manufacturers of E. Frank Coe's High Grade Fertilizers; Connecticut Board of Agriculture; Prof. L.A. Clinton; State Comptroller's Office (Thompson S. Grant, Comptroller; T.D. Bradstreet, Comptroller); "Corn" Magazine; Correspondence Insititute of America; Irving G. Davis; Corbin Screw Corporation.</p>
                        <p>Publications: "Legislative Bulletin," Friday, March 3, 1899, and Tuesday, March 7, 1899; "An Act Concerning the State Board of Agriculture;" "Prospectus: Farmers' Institutes by the Connecticut State Board of Agriculture, in Cooperation with the State and Storres Experiment Stations for 1898-1899; Farmers' Convention Program (ephemera); "Handbook of Fairs and Dates: Issued by the State Board of Agriculture July 1, 1917."</p>
                        <p>Agricultural subjects in correspondence: plant fertilization, pigeons, tobacco cultivation, bacteria for fertilization of crops, potato cultivation, manure application to crops, white leghorns, denatured alcohol, dairy bacteriology, decorative grasses, orchard cultivation, San Jose Scale insects.</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, postcards, posters, notes, financial records, legal documents,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1164001" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized E-G </extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1897/1920" type="inclusive">1897-1898, 1903, 1906-1911, 1913-1918, 1920</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref18">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: The E.C. Brown Company, Manufacturers of Pumps; E.D. Chittenden Company; E.D. Cummings; E.L. Freeman &amp; Sons, Stationers, Printers, Binders; Meadow Brook Farm; Echo Farm, Litchfield, Connecticut; Electric Boat Company, Groton, CT; Edison Manufacturing Company; Eimer and Amend, Manufacturers and Importers of Chemicals and Chemical Apparatus; Du Pont; Federal Chemical Company; Federation of Jewish Farmers of America; Travelers Insurance Company; Maple Shade Farm; Pres. Charles Lewis Beach; Gardner Advertising Company, Essex, CT; James Gould Company.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural and experimental subjects discussed in correspondence include: seed oats, seed potatoes, onion seed, suitable and unsuitable crops for cow pastures, weevils, Rhode Island Red eggs, potato beetles, Kjeldahl Flasks, thermometers, preparing soil with dynamite (for tree stump removal), barometers, ether, ground phosphate rock, alfalfa cultivation.</p>
                        <p>Items regarding events: "New England Farm and Business Conference: Under the Auspices the Eastern States Agricultural and Industrial Exposition, Inc.: Held in Springfield, Mass., Sept. 15 and 16, 1916" (Poster); "Eastern States Exposition and Dairy Show, 1913."</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural School, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, postcards, notes, ephemera,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1164002" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized G-H</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1896/1915" type="inclusive">1896-1902, 1904, 1907-1913, 1915,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref21">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Grasselli Chemical Company; Prof. L.A. Clinton; Dr. Charles B. Graves, M.D.; F.W. Gray; C.D. Jarvis; W.O. Atwater; Great Britain Royal Agricultural Society; Yorkshire College; Cardiff Public Libraries; Board of Agriculture and Fisheries; Board of Agriculture for Scotland; J. Stillwell Grover; Hammond, Knowlton &amp; Co., Silk Manufacturers; Pope Manufacturing Company, automobile manufacturer of Hartford, Conn.; Pres. R.W. Stimson; Holstein-Friesian Association of America; Russell Manufacturing Co.; L.D. Huff; D.Y. Hallock &amp; Sons; Harder Manufacturing Company; Hoffmann, Ahlers &amp; Co.; Hall Camera Co.; Pennsylvania Department of Agriculture; Hammond Typewriter Company; Pequot Poultry Farm; Melrose Castle Farm.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural subjects in correspondence include: sulphuric acid, arsenate of lead (as insecticide), San Jose Scale insects, "Miscible oil for Spraying Purposes" (pesticide), treating peach trees and cherry trees against pests, Bordeaux Mixture (pesticide), production of Camembert Cheese, soluble oil (pesticide), poison content of carrots, peas and beans, Oyster Shell Scale (pest), milk-producing goats, dairy bacteria.</p>
                        <p>Items related to Agricultural Events: "Horticultural Society of New York International Conference on Plant Hardiness and Acclimatization" schedule of events (ephemera).</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Connecticut Agricultural College.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, legal documents, notes,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1164003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized I-P</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1920" type="inclusive">1893, 1895-1897, 1903-1904, 1908-1909, 1911-1912, 1915-1918, 1920,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref23">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: University of Illinois; Iowa State University, Division of Veterinary Medicine (Ames, Iowa); Prof. L.A. Clinton; Second Congregational Church of Mansfield; Odd Fellows' Home of Connecticut; Central Vermont Railway Company; Prof. W.L. Slate; Hampden County (Mass.) Improvement League; State of Connecticut Board of Agriculture; Pres. Charles Lewis Beach; C.D. Jarvis; State Normal School of California; Leeds &amp; Northrop Company; H.F. Judkins; Kentucky Tobacco Product Co.; Col. Charles Maples Jarvis; Herbert K. Job, State Ornithologist of Connecticut; R. Hart Geer; Horner's Zoological Arena: Wild Animal Importers; John B. Doolin, State Game and Fish Warden, Oklahoma; Chemical Laboratory, Wesleyan University; Benjamin Franklin Koons.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural topics discussed in correspondence include: nitrate of soda, plant fertilizer, leaf blight, potato blight, creation of cheese, soluble oil (pesticide), arsenate of lead (pesticide), electrical measuring instruments, poultry manure, millet, fertilizing potatoes, quail disease.</p>
                        <p>Publications and Manuscripts: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin no. 27, December, 1903 (fragment); "Problems in Fruit Growing" (Manuscript).</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, University of Connecticut History, Storrs, Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, financial records, ephemera, publications, postcards,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1164004" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized L-M</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1895/1920" type="inclusive">1895-1896, 1902-1920,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref25">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Prof. L.A. Clinton; Fairlea Farm, Orange, CT; Maple Ridge Farm; U.S. House of Representatives, Washington, D.C.; American Witch-Hazel Company, Charles C. Dickinson, Pres.; Town of Southington, CT; Loyal Protective Insurance Co.; Crescent Farm; Lowell Farms; New London County Improvement League; Prof. W.L. Slate; Curtis Publishing Company; Prof. A.G. Gulley; Illinois Metals Co.; Hatch Experiment Station, Massachusetts; Massachusetts Board of Agriculture; Michigan Agricultural College; Minnesota Agricultural Experiment Station; Dr. Conn; City of St. Louis Health Department; Montana State Board of Horticulture; Ohio State University; North Carolina Agricultural Experiment Station; Ohio Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Pennsylvania; Chester D. Jarvis; Moss Bros. Roller Coasters; Charles H. Moss; Morris European and American Express Co.; Litchfield Electric Light Corp.; Maryland Agricultural College; Massachusetts Institute of Technology; Prof. W.L. Slate.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural Subjects discussed in correspondence include: raising cattle, crop rotation, crop fertilization and cultivation, fruit cultivation, harvesting corn and alfalfa, dairy cows, Canada peas, Army Worms, tobacco cultivation, cow peas, potatoes, San Jose scale insects, Maltese goats, dodder (parasitic plant), bacteria.</p>
                        <p>Publications and ephemera: "Home Nature-Study Course, Cornell University," December 1903, discussing chickadees, snowstorms and egg production (correspondence course publication); Schedule for "Second Annual New England Conference on Rural Progress--Massachusetts State Board of Agriculture, March 5, 6, 1908" (ephemera).</p>
                        <p>General Subjects include: Storrs Agricultural School, Agricultural Colleges and Schools, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Agricultural Experiment Stations, United States, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, financial records, publications, photographs, ephemera,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1164005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized M-P</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1888/1920" type="inclusive">1888, 1895-1898, 1902, 1904-1920</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref27">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Maine Agricultural Experiment Station; Journal of Agricultural Research; A.W. Buchanan; Prof. W.O. Atwater; Pres. B.F. Koons; Henry C. Miles; George K. Nason, Dealer in Lumber, Coal, Lime, Cement, Windows, Doors, Blinds, Mouldings, and Builders' Supplies, Est. 1862; Prof. L.A. Clinton; Prof. W.A. Stocking, Cornell University; Prof. C.L. Beach; Cornell Experiment Station; New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station; Syracuse University; Natchaug Grange; New England Corn Exposition; Massachusetts Agricultural College; Prof. W.D. Hurd; American Breeders' Association; New Zealand Department of Agriculture, Commerce, and Tourists, Wellington, NZ; Gladys F. Ogden, Fortland Farm, Stamford, CT; Huntsville Improvement Club, Huntsville, Utah; Ohio State University; Ohio Agricultural Experiment Station; Prof. W.L. Slate; Wing and Evans, Inc., Agent for the Solvay Process Co., Manufacturer of Soda, Detroit, Michigan; Oregon Agricultural Experiment Station; Greene County Farm Bureau, Xenia, Ohio; James B. Olcott; Prof. C.A. Zavitz; Ontario Department of Agriculture, Guelph; Pennsylvania State College; Pelton &amp; King, Printers and Binders; Central Vermont Railroad; Rhode Island Agricultural Experiment Station.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural topics discussed in correspondence include: miscible oil, soluble oil, scalecide, poultry husbandry, pomology, potato culture, potato grubs, corn cribs, sulphuric acid as herbicide, grass culture.</p>
                        <p>Publications and ephemera: "New York State Fruit Growers' Association" newsletter, Jan. 26, 1906; program for the "Twenty-fourth Annual Meeting of the Ontario Agricultural and Experimental Union, Dec. 8,9, 1902" (ephemera).</p>
                        <p>General Subjects include: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Agricultural Experiment Stations, United States, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Study and teaching.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Connecticut--Agriculture.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Education--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, notes, photographs, financial records, preliminary sketches, postcards,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1164006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized P-V</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1888/1920" type="inclusive">1888-1890, 1892-1907, 1910-1914, 1916, 1918, 1920 </unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref29">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Prof. L.A. Clinton; The Agricultural Experts Association; George T. Powell; Plimpton Manufacturing Co., Envelope and Blank Book Manufacturers; Frank S. Platt Co., Growers and Dealers in Lima Beans, Garden, Field, and Flower Seeds; U.S. Envelope Co.; Q and C Co.; Prof. W.O. Atwater; Wesleyan University; Prof. C.S. Phelps; W.H. Latham &amp; Co., Builders; Peter Hendersen Seed Co.; Norwich, Conn. School; Bridgeport Deoxidized Bronze and Metal Co.; O.H. Platt, Senator; Pound-a-Minute Churn Company; Maple Grove Farm; Lucien Sanderson, Importer of Agricultural Chemicals; Connecticut Dairymen's Association; The Evening Post Editorial Department; James S. Ray, Manufacturer of Casket Hardware; Forbes Diastase Company; The Electrominus Company; New Jersey State Board of Agriculture; Republic of Hawaii (1899); "Porto Rico"; B.B. Noyes &amp; Co.; University of Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station; Dr. Conn; Rhode Island Agricultural Experiment Station; Peck, Stow, and Wilcox Co., Tinners, Machines, and Tools; Escuela Nacional De Agricultura y Veterinaria (Peru); Arthur W. Dox.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural subjects addressed in correspondence: alfalfa cultivation, entomology, seed corn ("leaning" and "pride of the north"); dairy; bovine tuberculosis; bacteria.</p>
                        <p>Assorted non-correspondence items: Photographs (Storrs Agricultural School barns); Preliminary sketches for planning a newly-invented butter churn.</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges--Photographs.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Study and teaching.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Education Universities and Colleges.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Science and scientific affairs--Research institutes.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Buildings, structures, etc.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, clippings, ephemera, postcards, financial records,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1164007" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized O-S</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1894/1920" type="inclusive">1894, 1902, 1904-1920,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref32">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Orange Judd Co., Publishers and Importers of all Standard Books Pertaining to Rural Affairs; The Canadian Horticulturalist; The Rural New Yorker; The Hartford Evening Post; Iowa Experiment Station; Ginn &amp; Co., Publishers of School and College Text-books; The Technical World Magazine, Chicago; C.D. Jarvis; Prof. L.A. Clinton; The London Times, American Office; Success Magazine: A Periodical of American Life; Purdue University Agricultural Experiment Station; Central Vermont Railroad; Quinebaug Pomona Grange; The Riggs School, Inc.; The Rugg &amp; Faber Co.; The Shaw-Walker Co., Muskegon, Michigan; Columbia University, Department of Chemistry; Prof. W.O. Atwater; Stanley and Patterson, Inc., Manufacturer of General Electrical Equipment Supplies; R.W. Stimson; W.O. Stocking, Jr.; Russ Bro's [sic] Co., Farm Machinery and Fertilizers; Remington Typewriter Co.; Richardson Manufacturing Co.; Roethlisberger &amp; Co.; H.G. Rampsberger &amp; Co.; The Springfield Republican.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural subjects addressed in correspondence include: production of camembert and roquefort cheese.</p>
                        <p>Publications and ephemera: clipping of article "Common Weed Pests," by Dr. L.H. Pammel, Iowa Experiment Station; schedule of events for the "Second Annual Meeting of the National Association of Dairy Instructors and Investigators, Chicago, October 11, 12, 1907 (ephemera).</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, University of Connecticut History, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Business.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, financial records, notes, ephemera, legal documents,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1167001" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized R-V</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1888/1944" type="inclusive">1888, 1894-1895, 1897, 1901-1902, 1904, 1906-1908, 1910-1920, 1941-1944,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref35">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Russian Department of Agriculture; W.A. Stocking, Jr.; E.A. Strout Farm Agency, Inc.; The Old Homestead Dairy and Poultry Farm; C.L. Beach; Edwin O. Smith; W.L. Slate; Duzer Du, Dramatic Fraternity, Defauw University, Greencastle, Indiana; Alphano Humus Company; Southern Pacific Railroad; Central Vermont Railroad; Samuel Cupples Envelope Co.; Sanderson Fertilizer Co.; Skinner Chuck Co.; Sturgis &amp; Walton Co., Publishers; Tirrill Gas Machine Lighting Co.; Brown-Howland Co., Inc. of Connecticut; Underwood Typewriter Co.; U.S. Smelting Co.; S.L. Allen &amp; Co; S.R. Feil Co.; W.O. Atwater; W.L. Slate; Dean E.G. Woodward; Big Y Laboratory; Dean W.B. Young; Pres. A.N. Jorgensen; State College of Washington, College of Agriculture and Agricultural Experiment Station; Smithsonian Institution; Society of Educational Extension; South African Government Laboratory; R.W. Stimson; Underwood Travel System; L.A. Clinton; Virginia State Crop Pest Commission; War Manpower Commission.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural Subjects discussed in correspondence include: plight of Russian peasantry (pre-revolution); Soil testing and crop fertilization; potato culture; swamp draining (to create farmland); Planet Jr. 12-toothed harrow (agricultural product produced by S.L. Allen &amp; Co.); Sheep parasites (to be treated with medicated salt); Shropshire sheep; Lime-tree winter-moth; Bordeaux mixture (pesticide); bean weevil.</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural College, Connecticut Agricultural College, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Education—Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, legal documents, notes, postcards, publications,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1167002" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, alphabetized V-Z</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1889/1920" type="inclusive">1889-1890, 1892-1920</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref37">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute; Van Ogden Voght; John H. Voorhees; North Jersey Society for the Promotion of Agriculture; United States Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations; Farmers' Institute Movement; C.F. Doane; Arthur W. Dox; Dr. D.E. Salmon; E.H. Webster; Charles M. Jarvis; C.B. Lane; L.A. Clinton; G.M. Rommel, Animal Husbandman; War Department, Surgeon General's Office, U.S. Army Medical Museum and Library (1889); Prof. W.O. Atwater; Signal Service, U.S. Army; Smithsonian Institution; United States Department of Agriculture Weather Bureau; World's Columbian Exposition (1892); Dir. A.W. Harris, Office of Experiment Stations, USDA; E.W. Allen, Office of Experiment Stations, USDA; Department of Labor; Department of the Interior, Department of Pensions (1902); Hon. N.D. Sperry, House of Representatives; United States Department of Agriculture, division of Agrostology; Hon. O.H. Platt; Gov. O. Vincent Coffin; Dir. A.C. True; Hon. Watson C. Squire, Senator; Hon. Martin A. Knapp; Sen. E.S. Henry; Hon. Joseph R. Hawley; University of Chicago; Susan B. Sipe; Earl Bixby Ferson; University of Florida, Florida Experiment Station; Pres. Andrew Sledd, University of Illinois College of Agriculture Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Maine, Prof. W.D. Hurd; University of Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station; Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station; Wesleyan University; Worcester County Horticultural Society.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural subjects discussed in correspondence include: Poultry farming; Camembert and Rocquefort cheese; Dairy goats (known as "Milch Goats"); Maltese Goats; Maltese (or Malta) Fever; Cultivation of plants in sand and water (plant cultivation exhibit for World's Fair); law against oleomargarine; army worms (pests); alfalfa cultivation; San Jose scale insects (pests); Bordeaux Mixture (pesticide); asparagus cultivation; Oyster Shell Scale insects (pests).</p>
                        <p>Publications and other non-correspondence items: "Bulletin of the New England Weather Service, November 1895, No. 45" (Publication); USDA Office of the Secretary: Regulations Governing Appointments to Positions of Expert and Agent in the Department of Agriculture (legal documents).</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: United States Deparment of Agriculture; Storrs Agricultural School; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Study and teaching.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Connecticut—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, financial records, ephemera,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1167003" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders, Alphabetized W-Z</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1888/1947" type="inclusive">1888-1889, 1891-1903, 1905, 1908, 1913-1915, 1919-1920, 1933-1947,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref39">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Prof. W.L. Slate; New England Corn Exposition; H.C. Wells; H.R. Watts; Pres. C.L. Beach; Winship Teachers' Agency; The Vermont Farm Machine Co., Manufacturers the Improved U.S. Cream Separators and Dairy Specialties; Nathan G. Williams; C.D. Jarvis; M.H. Williams, Grower and Breeder of Yellow Dent Seed Corn, "The Kind that Matures;" Albida Farm, A.A. Wigand, Niantic, Connecticut; West Virginia University; Wyoming State Board of Agriculture; Williams Patent Crusher and Pulverizer, Inc.; Atlanta Milling Co.; White Adding Machine Co.; Charles Warner Co.; Dean W.B. Young; United States Department of Agriculture; A.N. Jorgensen; Dir. C.E.F. Goterman, Cornell Agricultural Experiment Station; J.H. Washburn, Wemanesa Grange no. 170; Weston Electrical Instrument Co.; Prof. Francis G. Benedict; C.D. Woods; W.O. Atwater; Wesleyan University Chemical Laboratory; New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station; Prof. E.B. Voorhees; American Cereal Co.; Pennsylvania State College; University of Vermont; H.C. Humphrey, American Glucose Co.; New York Agricultural Experiment Station; Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station.</p>
                        <p>Agricultural Subjects discussed in correspondence: potato grubs; field plowing; alfalfa cultivation; Bordeaux Mixture (pesticide); Potato Blight; sowing hay; ground moles (and how to trap them); crushed lime vs. caustic lime (fertilizers); usage of the "bomb calorimeter" for digestion and metabolic experiments; 1892 Cholera scare in Storrs; Sheep feeding experiments; dietary research; respiraton calorimeter.</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Correspondence, United States Deparment of Agriculture, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                        <p></p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Connecticut—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, notes, publications, administrative records, legal documents,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1167004" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1888/1941" type="inclusive">1888, 1892-1899, 1901-1902, 1937-1941,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref41">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: State of Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station; Oklahoma Department of Agriculture; Rural Publishing Co.; Rhode Island Board of Agriculture; New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station; Dr. C.D. Woods; Pennsylvania State College; Association of American Agricultural Colleges and Experiment Stations; Hon. Edward Atkinson; Pratt Institute, Brooklyn; New England Homestead / The New York Homestead; New Hampshire College of Agriculture and the Mechanic Arts; West Virginia University and Agricultural Experiment Station; Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Minnesota Agricultural Experiment Station; Maine State College Agricultural Experiment Station; H.P. Armsby, Committee on Agricultural Experiment Station Exhibit at World's Fair; Agricultural Department, State of Florida; F.G. Benedict; State Library of Massachusetts; A.O. Bryant; Iowa Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station; Michigan Agricultural College; St. Louis &amp; Hannibal Railway, Missouri; W.O. Atwater; Maine State College Agricultural Experiment Station; American Jersey Cattle Club; J.J. Hemingway; Alabama Agricultural College; Wesleyan University Chemical Laboratory; Leuthi Bros., Gnadenhutten, Ohio; Florida Agricultural Department; The Rural New Yorker; New Hampshire College; World's Columbian Commission; C.D. Woods; Harry C. Flood; Schuyler Electric Co.; Pennsylvania State College Agricultural Experiment Station; Rhode Island State Board of Agriculture; Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station; Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station; North Carolina Agricultural Experiment Station; Vermont Experiment Station; University of Arizona Agricultural Experiment Station; W.L. Slate; United States Department of Agriculture; C.B. Gentry.</p>
                        <p>Non-correspondence documents include: "The Logarty Gas &amp; Chemical Co.: Ammonia from the Nitrogen of the Air, November 1894 (publication);" Personal Affadavits (legal declarations of anti-communist, anti-fascist, and anti-Nazi affiliation).</p>
                        <p>General subjects: Agricultural Experiment Stations, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural College, University of Connecticut History, University of Connecticut in World War II.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, financial records, notes,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1167005" type="Box" label="Text">15</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1882/1905" type="inclusive">1882, 1886-1889, 1895-1896, 1898-1901, 1903-1905</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref43">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Bills and Receipts from assorted businesses: Lucius R. Hazen, Bookseller, Stationer, and Newsdealer; Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co.; Wesleyan University Chemical Laboratory; Scribner and Welford, Importers of Books; Educational Supply Co.; Eimer &amp; Amend, importers of Chemicals and Chemical Apparatus; Remington Standard Typewriter; J.P. Barstow &amp; Co.; N.A. Stearns &amp; Son, Manufacturers and Dealers in Harness, Robes, Blankets, Brushes, Whips, etc.; Mapes Formula and Peruvian Guano Co.; Southern New England Telephone Co.; Aero Distilled Water Co.; American Electrical Works; Baker &amp; Adamson Chemical Co; Beach &amp; Co.; A. Brazos &amp; Sons; Bugbee Bros.; Baker &amp; Co.; F.B. Fargo &amp; Co.; Hall &amp; Bill Printing Co.; S.S. White Dental Manufacturing Co.</p>
                        <p>Payment to, and bills from, individuals: W.E. Foster, C.S. Phelps (charging for travel expenses), W.O. Atwater, A.W. Stocking, F.G. Benedict, H.E. Bidwell, Albert Bingham, C.S. Blakeslee, Revella Bognini, Oscar Bowers, John Bowman, James H. Bunce, G.R. Burdick, M.A. Bates, Arthur F. Green, W.N. Hill, William F. House, G.H. Hulbert, Jr, R.E. Turner, F.A. Bagnoll.</p>
                        <p>Correspondence from W.O. Atwater.</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural College, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Financial Records, University of Connecticut History.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs, Conn.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, publications, postcards, legal documents, financial records</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1167006" type="Box" label="Text">16</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1888/1901" type="inclusive">1888, 1892-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref45">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: W.O. Atwater; Remington Standard Typewriter; Eimer &amp; Amend, Importers of Chemicals and Chemical Apparatus; Pelton &amp; King; Lucius R. Hazen, Bookseller and Stationer; Gustav E. Stechert, Importer of Books and Periodicals; John P. Barstow &amp; Co., Dealers in Stoves, Furnaces, Ranges, Farming Implements, Seeds, and Fertilizers; New York City Custom House; Case Lockwood &amp; Brainard Co.; Mapes Formula and Peruvian Guano Co.; Peabody Museum of American Archaeology and Ethnology (Harvard); Gustav E. Stechert, Importer of Books and Periodicals; The German Kali Works; Gilbert &amp; Barnes Manufacturing Co.; Fairbanks, Brown, &amp; Co. Standard Scales; Middletown Gas Light Co.; Bailey Manufacturing Co., Manufacturer of Bailey's Letter-copying Machine; C.D. Woods, Wesleyan University; Felt &amp; Tarrant Manufacturing Co.; Aero Distilled Water Co.; G.W. Sheldon &amp; Co.</p>
                        <p>Non-correspondence documents include: "Schedules for Financial Reports of the Agricultural Experiment Stations as prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture" (periodically published books intended for use in recording financial records; mostly unused, from years 1896 and 1897); "Illustrated Price List of Hoskins' Patent Hydro-Carbon Blow-Pipe and Furnaces" (publication or flier--intended as advertising).</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station financial records and corresponence, Storrs Agricultural College, University of Connecticut history.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agriculture--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs, Conn.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Books (3) (ledgers), financial records, notes,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1167007" type="Box" label="Text">17</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Books (ledgers), numbered 56-58</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1889/1899" type="inclusive">1889-1892, 1893-1894, 1897-1899</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref47">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Ledgers numbered 56, 57, and 58, covering monetary exchanges over the dates April-December 1889, January-December 1890, January-December 1892, January-December 1893, January-June 1897, July-December 1897, January-December 1898, January-June 1899.</p>
                        <p>Names included in ledger notes: W.O. Atwater, C.S. Phelps, C.L. Beach, B.F. Koons.</p>
                        <p>General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural College, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Financial Records.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <genreform source="local">Financial Records.</genreform>
                        <genreform source="local">Ledgers.</genreform>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Books (4) (ledgers), financial records,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1167008" type="Box" label="Text">18</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Books (ledgers), numbered 53-55, 59</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1896/1904" type="inclusive">1896-1904</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref49">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Ledgers, numbered 53, 54, 55 and 59, covering monetary transactions over the dates June-December 1896, January-June 1897, July-December 1897, January-December 1898, January-June 1899 and the years 1899-1904.</p>
                        <p>Names included in ledgers: W.O. Atwater (Erroneously called "O.W. Atwater"), Charles Lewis Beach.</p>
                        <p>General subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Financial Records.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <genreform source="local">Financial Records.</genreform>
                        <genreform source="local">Ledgers.</genreform>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname>
                        <geogname source="local">Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.</geogname>
                        <subject source="local">Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--History.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
