<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Exported" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/">MSS19980082</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>University of Connecticut, Institutue of Cooperative Marketing Records
                    <num>1998.0082</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">Institute of Cooperative Marketing Records</titleproper>
                <subtitle>An Inventory</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by The inventory was created by Tanya Rose Lane.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-12-28T08:13-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>The finding aid is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>University of Connecticut, Institute of Cooperative Marketing Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>1998.0082</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref4" label="Abstract">The collection contains papers given on various topics associated with the Institute in 1927.</abstract>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref5">
            <head>History</head>
            <p>In April 1881, the 
                <corpname>Connecticut General Assembly</corpname> established the 
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural School</corpname> after accepting a gift of 170 acres of land, several frame buildings, and money from Charles and 
                <persname>Augustus Storrs</persname>. The School opened on 28 September 1881, with twelve students in the first class. Before the turn of the century there were two name changes (
                <corpname>Storrs Agricultural College</corpname> 1893, 
                <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> 1899). In 1933, two years after the institution celebrated its fiftieth anniversary, it became 
                <corpname>Connecticut State College</corpname>, a name more in keeping with its steady advances and broadened mission. Six years later, in 1939, the General Assembly designated the institution the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>, an acknowledgment of the institution's developing importance to the State in graduate and professional education, research and public service.</p>
            <p>The 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> is recognized as the state's flagship institution of higher learning. Since its establishment, the University has grown to include 13 Schools and Colleges at its main campus in Storrs, separate Schools of Law and Social Work in Hartford, five regional campuses throughout the state and Schools of Medicine and Dentistry at the UConn Health Center in Farmington.</p>
            <p>UConn is a Land Grant and Sea Grant College and a Space Grant Consortium institution. The University spans 4,104 acres at its main campus and five regional campuses, and an additional 162 acres at the UConn Health Center in Farmington.</p>
            <p>Designated a Carnegie Foundation Research University-Extensive, UConn has more than 70 focused research centers where faculty, graduate students and undergraduates explore everything from improving human health to enhancing public education and protecting the country’s natural resources.</p>
            <p>At this time there is no specific information about the Institute of Cooperative Marketing.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Restrictions on Use and Copyright Information</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Provenance and Acquisition</head>
            <p>Unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#], University of Connecticut, Institute of Cooperative Marketing Records. 
                <corpname>Archives &amp;#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp;#x0026; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://www.lib.uconn.edu/online/research/speclib/ASC/collections/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorid=3">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref11">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The collection contains photocopies of papers presented on topics of interest to the Institute.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest">University of Connecticut</corpname>
            <subject source="local">University Archives</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref1" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Inventory</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>1927</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref2" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle></unittitle>
                        <container type="Box">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1927</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref3">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Administrative records [Subjects include: Agricultural Economics, 
                            <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname>, dairy industry, local produce market.]</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
