<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">

<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
<eadid url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/findaids/masopust/MSS20100074.html"  mainagencycode="US-CtU" countrycode="US">MSS20100074</eadid>

<filedesc>
	<titlestmt>
		<titleproper>Connecticut Soldiers Collection</titleproper>
		<subtitle>Bernard C. Masopust Papers</subtitle>
		<author>Finding aid prepared by Betsy Pittman.</author>
	
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
	<publisher> &#x00A9; 2010  University of Connecticut</publisher>
	<date type="publication">September 2010</date>

	<address><addressline>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</addressline><addressline>405 Babbidge Road, Unit 1205</addressline><addressline>Storrs, Connecticut  06269-1205</addressline><addressline>URL http://doddcenter.uconn.edu</addressline></address>

</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>

<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by Betsy Pittman in September 2010.</creation>
<langusage><language>eng</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory">
<did>
	<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
	<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a"><corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>.
		</repository>

	<origination label="Creator:">
		<persname encodinganalog="100">Masopust, Bernard C.</persname>
	</origination>

	<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Bernard C. Masopust Papers.</unittitle>

	<unitdate label="Dates:">undated, 1945-1946.</unitdate>

	<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">.1  linear feet.</physdesc>

	<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">Correspondence from Staff Sergeant Bernard "Barney" Masopust, USMC, to his wife during basic training (North Carolina) and service overseas in Japan, 1945-1946.</abstract>

	<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification:" countrycode="us" 
		repositorycode="US-UCW">MSS20100074</unitid>

	<langmaterial><language>English</language>.
	</langmaterial>
</did>



<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->

<bioghist altrender="biography" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
	<head>Biography</head>
	<p><persname>Bernard C. Masopust</persname> ("Barney") was born in New York City on March 7, 1912.  His future wife, <persname>Helen Babinetz</persname>, was born on Madison Avenue, New York City, in 1916.  Bernard moved to Southington while in his twenties, having lived and been educated in New York City. Helen lived in <geogname>Southington, CT</geogname>  Masopust, who worked in trade, tool and die manufacturing,  was too old to be drafted for World War II so he enlisted.  Married in August 1944, the couple moved to Cherry Point (<geogname>Havelock, NC</geogname>) in 1945 for basic training, and lived on the base.  Helen found employment in a munitions factory working alongside other military wives.  After her husband's deployment in 1945, Helen returned to <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> to live with her parents in Southington, where she gave birth to their oldest child in 1945.  Stationed in Japan with the occupational forces, Barney worked in a machine shop working to help reestablish Japan's industry. It's believed that Barney saw some combat in the islands, but it unknown in what capacity.  His correspondence documents his acquaintance with men stationed in Okinawa as well as with men transferred to southern <geogname>Japan</geogname> for R &#x0026; R. </p>
<p>Barney's twin brother applied for a legal name change in the 1940s fearing discrimination while looking for employment.  Dr. <persname>Joseph M. Lent</persname>, as he became known, was first employed by the <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> in 1946 as an Extension agent in Hartford County.  Soon thereafter he became a professor of Plant Sciences and retired as a professor of Horticulture in 1978.  In the 1950s, Lent gained recognition for his study of boron deficiency in beets and other vegetables and later received awards for the introduction of "Black Opal" (basil, 1963) and an improved acorn squash (1971).  His wife, "Lou," was one of the first female graduates of the forestry program at UConn.</p>
<p>After the war, Masopust returned to Connecticut and he and his family lived in <geogname>Thomaston, CT</geogname> where he worked in his trade, tool and die.  Although he worked in several different shops, Masopust was employed by New Departure (Tool &#x0026; Die) in <geogname>Bristol, CT</geogname>, for forty-three years after he left the service. Bernard Masopust died March 21, 1994. </p>   

</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
	<head>Scope and Content</head>
	<p>The collection contains 2 photographs and twelve letters, primarily from Masopust to his wife Helen, dating from the period after she had left <geogname>North Carolina</geogname> to return to <geogname>Connecticut</geogname>.  The correspondence is personal in nature, discussing family and friends with little to no mention of Barney's activities in the military.  Individuals of note mentioned in the letters are <persname>David Masopust</persname> (oldest son of Bernard and Helen), Joe (<persname>Joseph M. Lent</persname>, twin brother of Bernard), Henrietta (or "Hennie," Barney and Joe's sister), <persname>Lillian Schulze</persname> (wife of a fellow Marine and friend from Cherry Point), and Helen's brother Frank who also served in the war and was stationed in <geogname>Hawaii</geogname> but returned home in 1945.  Correspondence has recently surfaced in which Barney discusses rumors he has heard about an atomic bomb and recounts his time in Okinawa and Pearl Harbor (briefly before departure to Japan).  [Note: these letters are expected, but have not yet arrived, to be placed in the collection--10/2010.]</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351$b" id="a5">
	<head>Arrangement</head>
	<p>The correspondence is arranged chronologically.</p>
<p><emph render="bold">Series I: Correspondence and photographs</emph> (<date>undated, 1945-1946</date>) </p>
</arrangement>

<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
	<head>Related Material</head>
	<p>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various aspects of Connecticut history and the experiences of Connecticut residents while in the military.  For detailed information on these collections please contact the <extref href=" http://www.lib.uconn.edu/online/research/speclib/ASC/collections/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorid=3">curator</extref> or ask at the reference desk.</p>
</relatedmaterial> 






<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->

<!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->
<controlaccess id="a12">
<head>Index Terms</head>
<p>This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
</p>
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Persons:</head>
			<persname encodinganalog="700" source="local">Masopust, Bernard C.</persname>
	
		</controlaccess>
		
			
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Places:</head>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="local"></geogname>
	
		</controlaccess>
		
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Subjects:</head>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local"></subject>
	
		</controlaccess>
		
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Document Types:</head>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Correspondence.</genreform>

		</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>

<!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->

<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->
<accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
	<head>Restrictions on Access</head>
	<p>There are no access restrictions on this collection.</p>
</accessrestrict>


<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
	<head>Restrictions on Use</head>
	<p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
</userestrict>



<custodhist encodinganalog="561" id="a16">
	<head>Custodial History</head>
	<p>The materials were kept by Mrs. Bernard C. Masopust and given to her granddaughter, <persname>Caitlin Masopust</persname>, in 2010.</p>
</custodhist>

<prefercite encodinganalog="510" id="a18">
	<head>Preferred Citation</head>
	<p>[Item description, #:#],  Connecticut Soldiers Collection, <persname>Bernard C. Masopust</persname> Papers.  <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
</prefercite>


<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
	<head>Acquisition Information</head>
	<p>The collection was donated in September 2010 by <persname>Caitlin Masopust</persname>.</p>

</acqinfo>




<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->


<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
<dsc type="combined" id="a23">
<head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>

<c01 level="series">
   <did>
	<unittitle>Series I: Correspondence and photographs, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated, 1945-1946</unitdate>
    </did>	
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">1:</container>
	<container type="Folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Correspondence, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated, 1945-1946</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
   <did>
	<container type="Box">1:</container>
	<container type="Folder">2</container>
	<unittitle>Photographs, </unittitle>
	<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    </did>	
</c02>

</c01>

</dsc>












<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
</archdesc>
</ead>

