<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Ready_for_export" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/hagedorn/MSS20020125.html">MSS20020125</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Connecticut Soldiers Collection
                    <num>2002.0125</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">Hagedorn (Raymond E.) Papers</titleproper>
                <subtitle>Raymond E. Hagedorn Papers</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by James Brundage.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269-1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>June 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-07-31T15:55-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>The finding aid is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Connecticut Soldiers Collection, 
                <persname>Raymond E. Hagedorn</persname> Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>2002.0125</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1932/1946" type="inclusive">undated, 1932-1946</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref44" label="Abstract">Personal letters between Major Raymond E. Hagedorn, his wife, and friends during the second World War. The letters describe his training at Fort Blanding, Florida and Fort Benning, Georgia in 1941, and follow him through his service in the pacific between September 1942 and April 1943. Beginning April 1943 the letters focus on his time at military hospitals both in and outside of the United States, and describe medical retirement from the Army. Also included in the collection are numerous letters between his wife, Gertrude, and her friends. These letters discuss various wartime issues including rationing, their husbands' service, and domestic issues.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Author (aut)">Hagedorn, Raymond E.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref45">
            <head>Biography</head>
            <p>
                <persname>Raymond E. Hagedorn</persname> was born on June 22, 1905, in 
                <geogname>South Windsor, Connecticut</geogname>, and spent the majority of his life in 
                <geogname>Manchester, Connecticut</geogname>. He was married to 
                <persname>Gertrude Angeli</persname> on September 7, 1929, and had three children, only one of whom, 
                <persname>Quentin Paul Hagedorn</persname>, survived past infancy. Hagedorn worked as an electrical contractor prior to 
                <subject>World War II</subject>.</p>
            <p>In addition to his job as an electrician, Hagedorn had joined the 
                <corpname>Connecticut Army National Guard</corpname> in 1922, at the age of 16, and served as a member of the 169th Infantry Regiment. He was commissioned a Second Lieutenant in June 1929 and continued to serve as an officer during World War II. Activated in February 1941, Captain Hagedorn and the 169th trained in anti-tank manuevers at 
                <geogname>Fort Blanding, Florida</geogname>. The unit combined with regiments from three other New England states to form the 43rd Infantry Division. While the unit was training at Fort Blanding, and later at Fort Shelby in 
                <geogname>Mississippi</geogname>, Hagedorn went with several other officers from the 169th to the Army's officer training camp at 
                <geogname>Fort Benning, Georgia</geogname>. Following the attack on 
                <geogname>Pearl Harbor</geogname>, Hagedorn was promoted to Major and assigned to the post of battalion executive officer. In August 1942 the division moved to 
                <geogname>Fort Ord, California</geogname> where they conducted amphibious training in preperation for their departure to the Pacific.</p>
            <p>In early October 1942 Hagedorn and the 43rd Infantry Division left 
                <geogname>San Francisco</geogname>, sailing initially to 
                <geogname>New Zealand</geogname>. In late November Hagedorn and the Division Headquarters moved once again, this time to the Island of 
                <geogname>New Caledonia</geogname>. In February 1943 Hagedorn once again moved with the 43rd to the Island of 
                <geogname>Guadalcanal</geogname>. At this point in time Hagedorn began to suffer from low blood pressure and headaches, a condition he attributed to the climate. By March 1943 Hagedorn is in and out of hospitals on 
                <geogname>Guadalcanal</geogname>, and in April 1943 he is sent back to 
                <geogname>New Zealand</geogname> to recover. However, shortly after arriving Hagedorn is sent back to the 
                <geogname>United States</geogname> to recover.</p>
            <p>After leaving the 
                <corpname>39th General Hospital</corpname> in 
                <geogname>New Zealand</geogname>, Hagedorn is sent to 
                <corpname>Sedderman General Hospital</corpname> in 
                <geogname>San Fransisco</geogname> to recover. Diagnosed shortly thereafter with a nervous disorder, he is sent to 
                <corpname>Harmon General Hospital</corpname> in 
                <geogname>Texas</geogname>. After a brief visit to 
                <geogname>Connecticut</geogname> in June, Hagedorn returned to 
                <geogname>Texas</geogname> where he is told he will be returned to duty, and sent back to the pacific. However, after consulting with numerous doctors Hagedorn's orders are overturned, and he is eventually retired from active duty in May 1944. Hagedorn remained in the 
                <corpname>Connecticut National Guard</corpname> following the war, and is eventually promoted to Lieutenant Colonel. During the 
                <subject>Korean War</subject> Hagedorn served as an intelligence officer and aide to Connecticut's Adjutant General.</p>
            <p>Following World War II Hagedorn briefly resumed his electrical business before becoming the plant engineer for the New Departure Division of 
                <corpname>General Motors</corpname> in 
                <geogname>Meriden, Connecticut</geogname>. Retiring from 
                <corpname>GM </corpname>in 1962 Raymond Hagedorn spent the rest of his life in Manchester, passing away on September 21, 1985.</p>
            <p>
                <persname>Gertrudue Angeli Hagedorn</persname> was born on October 5, 1907, in 
                <geogname>Manchester, Connecticut</geogname> and spent her entire life there. She died March 20, 2002. Their son, 
                <persname>Quentin Hagedorn</persname>, was born January 12, 1939.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content note</head>
            <p>The collection consists of the personal letters sent and received by Major 
                <persname>Raymond E. Hagedorn</persname>. Hagedorn corresponded regularly with his wife, and less frequently with friends, during the second World War. The letters provide detailed accounts of his training at 
                <geogname>Fort Blanding, Florida</geogname> and 
                <geogname>Fort Benning, Georgia</geogname> in 1941, and follow him through his service in the pacific between September 1942 and April 1943. The letters are organized into two groups. The first is comprised of materials he sent to his wife and son, and letters he received from them. The second is comprised of letters sent to him and his wife by friends and relatives, and letters he sent to friends and family.</p>
            <p>Hagedorn describes life in the army in detail, and his letters provide a fascinating account of military preparations prior to the war. While training Hagedorn discusses topics such as his living conditions on base, food in the army, other officers and their families, and the monotony of army life. He often inquires as to the nature of life in 
                <geogname>Manchester, Connecticut</geogname>, the daily affairs of those at home, and into the well-being of his wife and son. Other topics discussed in his early letters include going to the movies, the weather, the attack on 
                <geogname>Pearl Harbor</geogname>, 
                <persname>FDR</persname>, the Japanese army, 
                <corpname>Coca-Cola</corpname>, and often include intimate remarks.</p>
            <p>There is a substantial gap in the correspondence between himself and his wife during the period of February 1942 to September 1942. However, based on letters sent to his wife from friends, it appears that he was living with her in 
                <geogname>Oklahoma</geogname> during that time period. Their correspondence resumes in September 1942 when he is at 
                <geogname>Fort Ord, California</geogname>. In October he leaves the 
                <geogname>United States</geogname> for 
                <geogname>New Zealand</geogname>. These letters are very upbeat and discuss topics to include food, life in New Zealand, buying souveniers for his family, going to the movies, receiving mail (to include V mail), and the environment. Hagedorn often discusses his movements, but tells his wife where he is in code. He provides humorous details about the environments he encounters, to include squawking birds, swarms of mosquitos, varieties of fruits, and the activities of the native populations.</p>
            <p>By early 1943 the letters begin to focus more on his declining health, and the activities he engages in to stay busy. He also spends much more time inquiring about his son and his family. Beginning in February the letters are focused on his leaving the Pacific to return home. It is also around this point that letters from his wife begin to be returned to Manchester, as by the time they arrive he has been sent back to the 
                <geogname>United States</geogname>, and it is from this period that the majority of the letters from her survive. From this point forward the majority of his letters describe his time at military hospitals both in and outside of the United States, and the process of medical retirement from the Army. After returning home in June, the correspondence picks up in July and continues to October 1943 at which point it stops all together. The final letters between he and his wife are concerned primarily with his health, and whether he will be returned to duty or retired. The letters provide great detail into medical retirement from the army and life at military hospitals during the second World War.</p>
            <p>Also included in the collection are numerous letters between his wife, Gertrude, and her friends. These letters discuss various wartime issues including rationing, their husbands' service, and domestic issues. The letters are comprised primarily of those sent to Gertrude by friends and family, with a large portion being made up of letters from other officers' wives. These letters discuss the various events of the war, and provide a valuable perspective of the war. There are also letters from various doctors detailing her son's health issues.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref46">
            <head>Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref47">
            <head>Restrictions on Use and Copyright Information</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref48">
            <head>Provenance and Acquisition</head>
            <p>The papers were purchased by Archives &amp; Special Collections in 2002.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref49">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#], Connecticut Soldiers Collection, 
                <persname>Raymond E. Hagedorn</persname> Papers. 
                <corpname>Archives &amp;#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref50">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various aspects of Connecticut history and the experiences of Connecticut residents while in the military. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=3">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <genreform source="local">Personal Papers.</genreform>
            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Personal narratives—Connecticut.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref3" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Correspondence,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1932/1946" type="inclusive">undated, 1932-1946</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref6" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Family Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1068001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1932/1943" type="inclusive">undated, 1932-1943</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1938-1945--Personal narratives--Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Connecticut --Personal narratives.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Economic aspects—Connecticut.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                    <c id="ref7" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>undated, 1932, 1940, 1941 Mar</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1932/1941" type="inclusive">undated, 1932-1941</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <controlaccess>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut--Military affairs.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Connecticut --Personal narratives.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Manpower—United States.</subject>
                        </controlaccess>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref8" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1941 Jul</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068007" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1941/1941">1941 Jul</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <controlaccess>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut--Military affairs.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Connecticut --Personal narratives.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Manpower—United States.</subject>
                        </controlaccess>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref9" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1941 Aug</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068008" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1941/1941">1941 Aug</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <controlaccess>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut--Military affairs.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Manpower—United States.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Personal narratives—Connecticut.</subject>
                        </controlaccess>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref10" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1941 Sep</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068009" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1941/1941">1941 Sep</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <controlaccess>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut--Military affairs.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives--Connecticut.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Manpower—United States.</subject>
                        </controlaccess>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref11" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1941 Sep - Oct</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1941/1941">1941 Sep - Oct</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <controlaccess>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut--Military affairs.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Economic aspects—Connecticut.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Manpower—United States.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Personal narratives—Connecticut.</subject>
                        </controlaccess>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref12" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1941 Nov - Dec</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068011" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1941/1941">1941 Nov - Dec</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <controlaccess>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut--Military affairs.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Economic aspects—Connecticut.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Manpower—United States.</subject>
                            <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Personal narratives—Connecticut.</subject>
                        </controlaccess>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref13" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1942 Feb - Sep</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Feb - Sep</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref14" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1942 Oct - Nov</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068013" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Oct - Nov</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref15" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1942 Dec (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Dec</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref16" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1942 Dec (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068015" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Dec</unitdate>
                            <materialspec id="ref43" label="Newsletters">[Note: Hagedorn mentions in a December letter that the men in his unit have produced a newsletter. He says that he is including one for his wife, and in fact two newsletters were found mixed within the collection at the time of processing. These were likely the newsletters he was refering to, however, as they were not found with the letter at the time of the collection's organization they are now filed in their own file: Newsletters.]</materialspec>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref17" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Jan</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Jan</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref18" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Feb</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068017" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Feb</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref19" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Mar (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Mar</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref20" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Mar (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068019" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Mar</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref21" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Apr</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068020" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Apr</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref22" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 May - Jun</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068021" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 May - Jun</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref23" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Jul</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068022" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Jul</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref24" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Aug</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068003" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Aug</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref25" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Oct</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068023" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Oct</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Personal Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1070001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1935/1946" type="inclusive">undated, 1935-1946</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Connecticut --Personal narratives.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Economic aspects—Connecticut.</subject>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Manpower—United States.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                    <c id="ref27" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>undated, 1935, 1941 Jan - Jul</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1935/1941" type="inclusive">undated, 1935 -1941</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref28" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1941 Aug - Dec</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1941/1941">1941 Aug - Dec</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref29" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1942 Aug - Sep</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068025" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Aug - Sep</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref30" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1942 Oct</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068026" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Oct</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref31" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1942 Nov</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068027" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Nov</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref32" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1942 Dec</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068028" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Dec</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref33" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Jan</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068029" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Jan</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref34" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Feb</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068030" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Feb</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref35" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Mar</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Mar</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref36" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Apr</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068032" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Apr</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref37" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 May</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068033" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 May</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref38" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Jun - Jul</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068034" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Jun - Jul</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref39" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1943 Aug</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068035" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943 Aug</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref40" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>1946 Feb - Aug</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid1068036" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1946/1946">1946 Feb - Aug</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Greeting Cards</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1068005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <genreform source="local">Greeting cards.</genreform>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Newsletters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1068006" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1942/1942">1942 Dec</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <controlaccess>
                        <subject source="local">Connecticut—History—World War, 1939-1945.</subject>
                        <genreform source="local">Newsletters.</genreform>
                        <subject source="local">World War, 1939-1945—Manpower—United States.</subject>
                    </controlaccess>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
