<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Exported" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/AC/findaids/brownr/MSS20100096.html">MSS20100096</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Richard D. Brown Papers
                    <num>2010.0096</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">Brown (Richard D.) Papers</titleproper>
                <subtitle>An Inventory</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Daniel Allie.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269-1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-12-12T14:24-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>The inventory is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Richard D. Brown Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>2010.0096</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.8 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1968/2008" type="inclusive">undated, 1968-2008</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref12" label="Abstract">Richard D. Brown is an Emeritus professor of history at the University of Connecticut, specializing in the American Revolution. The collection contains course materials, student records and recommendations, papers and presentations, professional associations, and grant applications of UConn History professor Richard D. Brown.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="aacr" source="local" role="Author (aut)">Brown, Richard D.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The collection includes correspondence, reports, memoranda, and similar materials pertaining to Brown's career at 
                <corpname>UConn</corpname>. Also in the collection are course related materials, student records and recommendations, papers and presentations, professional associations, and grant applications. The materials relate to Brown's position as a professor in the history department and as the first director of the Humanities Institute, and span his tenure at the university from 1971 to the present.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref13">
            <head>Biography</head>
            <p>
                <persname>Richard David Brown</persname> was born in 
                <geogname>New York City</geogname> on October 31, 1939, the son of 
                <persname>Alvyn Adolph</persname> and 
                <persname>Dorothy Kruskal Brown</persname>. His preparatory education was at 
                <geogname>Devereux Manor, Devon, Pennsylvania</geogname> and the 
                <corpname>Fieldstone School</corpname>, 
                <geogname>Riverdale, New York</geogname>. In 1957 he enrolled at 
                <corpname>Oberlin College</corpname> where he was active in Musical Union and at the radio station, WOBC. He graduated in 1961 and won a Woodrow Wilson Fellowship to study at 
                <corpname>Harvard University</corpname>, where he earned an M.A. in 1962 and a Ph.D. in 1966. Professor Brown served as a Fulbright lecturer at the 
                <corpname>University of Toulouse</corpname> in France during the academic year of 1965-1966. After reeiving his Ph.D he returned to 
                <corpname>Oberlin College</corpname> where he was an assistant professor of history until 1971. In 1971 he joined the faculty at the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>, and served as an associate professor of history until 1975 when he was promoted to full professor. He served as head of the history department from 1974-80, and has also directed the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Humanities Institute</corpname>.</p>
            <p>A student of American history specializing in the American Revolution, and American social and cultural history, Professor Brown has published extensively in these fields. He is the author of several books, including 
                <title render="italic">The Strength of a People: The Idea of an Informed Citizenry in America, 1650-1870</title> (1996); 
                <title render="italic">Knowledge is Power: The Diffusion of Information in Early America, 1700-1865</title> (1989); 
                <title render="italic">Massachusetts: A Bicentennial History</title> (1978); 
                <title render="italic">Modernization: The Transformation of American Life, 1660-1865</title> (1976); 
                <title render="italic">Revolutionary Politics in Massachusetts: The Boston Committee of Correspondence and the Towns, 1772-1774</title> (1970); and 
                <title render="italic">The Hanging of Ephraim Wheeler: A Story of Rape, Incest and Justice in the Early Republic</title>, (2003). Professor Brown has also edited several anthologies, authored over 35 articles and 65 book reviews, and has delivered more than 90 papers at academic conferences.</p>
            <p>In addition to teaching, Professor Brown has acted as president of the 
                <corpname>New England Historical Association</corpname> (1990-91), and has served as a member of the Board of Trustees of 
                <corpname>Old Sturbridge Village</corpname> (1984-87). He has also served as the chair to the Editorial Board of 
                <corpname>The William and Mary Quarterly</corpname> (1996-98) and as a member of the Advisory Board of Editors to 
                <corpname>Common-Place: An Online Journal of American History</corpname>.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research with the exception of those materials restricted under FERPA.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref14">
            <head>Restrictions on Use and Copyright Information</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref17">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students, etc. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=3">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref16">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#], 
                <persname>Richard D. Brown</persname> Papers. 
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref15">
            <head>Provenance and Acquisition</head>
            <p>The records were donated by Richard D. Brown in 2010, with a subsequent donation in 2011.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="aacr" source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Brown, Richard D.</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Administrative records.</genreform>
            <subject source="aat">Archives (institutions).</subject>
            <genreform source="local">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="fast">Dept. of History.</subject>
            <subject source="fast">Faculty.</subject>
            <genreform source="local">Manuscripts.</genreform>
            <subject source="local">Personal papers</subject>
            <genreform source="local">Photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="fast">Universities and colleges.</subject>
            <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--Faculty--Professional and personal papers.</subject>
            <subject source="local">University of Connecticut--Faculty.</subject>
            <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
            <subject source="local">University of Connecticut. Dept. of History.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref4" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: An Inventory,</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <unitdate normal="1968/2008" type="inclusive">1968-2008</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative records, Correspondence, Manuscripts, notes, publications, galley proofs, transcripts, financial records, ephemera,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1155001" type="Box" label="Text">2011.0118_1</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>5.9 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1968/2008" type="inclusive">1968, 1971, 1973, 1976, 1983, 1996, 2002, 2005, 2006, 2008</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref6">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: UConn history department, Humanities Institute.]</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative records, transcripts, notes, correspondence, ephemera, manuscripts, financial records, fliers,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1155002" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1975/2002" type="inclusive">1975, 1986, 1989-1998, 2000-2002,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref18">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Courses taught by Richard D. Brown:</p>
                        <p>HIST 211: The Historian's Craft (Spring 2002; syllabi, assignment sheets, and notes);</p>
                        <p>HIST 331: American Revolution (Spring 1989, Spring and Fall 1990, Fall 1991, Spring 1994, Fall 1995, Spring 2001; documents and syllabi);</p>
                        <p>HIST 244 (1996);</p>
                        <p>Special Topic: The Wheeler Case of 1805-1806.</p>
                        <p>Articles, publications, manuscripts, transcripts and ephemera:</p>
                        <p>"Unjust Rules for Insanity" by Jennifer S. Bard (article);</p>
                        <p>"The Rape of Elizabeth Cureton: A Microhistory" (photocopied book chapter; no author listed);</p>
                        <p>program for "Fourteenth annual Meeting: Society for HIstorians of the Early American Republic;"</p>
                        <p>manuscript "Capturing the Bard: The American Publication of Shakespeare's Plays, 1822-1851" by Rosalind Remer;</p>
                        <p>manuscript "'The Female Marine' in an Era of Good Feelings: Seduction, Patriotism, and the Modern Personality" by Daniel A. Cohen;</p>
                        <p>manuscript "Political Culture and Political Behavior in a Republican Slave Society: Toward a History of Voting Behaviour in Southampton County, Virginia, 1850-1860" by Gregory Bowen;</p>
                        <p>"The Baptists of Virginia, 1714-1830," and "Politics of the Ancient Dominion in Virginia" by Hazel Strabeck;</p>
                        <p>"The Early Baptists" by Paul E. Teed;</p>
                        <p>"Reading Religion: An Eighteenth-Century Artisan Constructs His Piety" by Erik R. Seeman;</p>
                        <p>flier "Educating a Citizenry: School and Society in the World of Thomas Jefferson;"</p>
                        <p>New England Historical Association Fall Conference program, Oct. 17, 1992;</p>
                        <p>Meeting Minutes from SHEAR conference.</p>
                        <p>Correspondence topics include: Argument over peer review for article ""Deconstructing William Cushing" in William and Mary Quarterly; "Slavery in American Society," 3rd ed.; correspondence with Daniel A. Cohen.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, financial records, notes, manuscripts, transcripts, publications, galley proofs, ephemera, fliers, maps,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1155003" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1980/2002" type="inclusive">1966, 1971-1972, 1976, 1978, 1982-1984, 1986-1991, 1994, 1996-1997, 200-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref19">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Brown's trip to University of Lucknow, India (correspondence; and notes)</p>
                        <p>Correspondence pertaining to nominating Frank Costigliola for Chancellor's Research Excellence Award (2002), and manuscript of Costigliola's essay "Reading for Meaning: Theory, Language, and Metaphor;"</p>
                        <p>Documents pertaining to Brown's teaching of course History 231 (including book reserve forms from the Homer Babbidge library, syllabi, and *grading sheets*);</p>
                        <p>Transcripts of Library Committee meeting, Jan. 19, 1976;</p>
                        <p>Brown's correspondence with Clark University, University of Iowa, Whitworth College, University of California Santa Barbara, Ursinus College, Lafayette College, Toogaloo College; Correspondence with Southern Illinois University regarding Brown's book "Major Problems in the Era of the American Revolution and the Constitution" (1990);</p>
                        <p>Letters of recommendation for students, written by Brown;</p>
                        <p>Publication "An Offprint from The New England Quarterly: 'Not Only Extreme Poverty, but the Worst Kind of Orphanage:' Lemuel Haynes and the Boundaries of Racial Tolerance on the Yankee Frontier, 1770-1820" by Richard D. Brown (Vol. LXI, no. 4, Dec. 1988); also includes galley proofs and manuscripts of paper;</p>
                        <p>Research assignments for Brown's course HIST 298: Rape, Incest, and the Gallows (years 1989-1991, 1997);</p>
                        <p>Correspondence regarding project on "Soviet-American Dialogue on the American Revolution;" includes manuscript of paper "The American and French Revolutions of the 18th Century (An Essay in Comparative Description)" by A.A. Fursenko, and Richard D. Brown's paper "The Atlantic Revolutions of the 18th Century: A.A. Fursenko's Comparison of the American and French Revolutions" (including handwritten notes and drafts);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript of book chapter "Epilogue: From Cohesion to Competition" by Richard D. Brown, for book "Printing and Society in Early America" (1983), along with manuscript of preface by William L. Joyce and John B. Hench;</p>
                        <p>Syllabus for HIST 104: Healthcare in America from General Practice to General Hospital, along with papers from HIST 337: American Social History, 1600-1865 (Spring 1991; includes syllabi and teaching notes)</p>
                        <p>Flier for exhibit "The Great River: Art and Society of the Connecticut Valley, 1635-1820," Wadsworth Atheneum, 1985;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript of "Regional Culture in the Revolutionary Era: The Connecticut Valley, 1760-1820" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript of "Geographics of Value: The Exchange of Objects, People &amp; Knowledge Between Post-Colonial America and the British Empire" by Kariann Yokota, Yale (Paper Presented to the Boston Area Early American History Seminar, The Massachusetts HIstorical Society), along with Yokota's paper "A Culture of Insecurity: America as a Post-Colonial Nation;"</p>
                        <p>Drafts of "Colonial and Revoloutionary Antecedents to the Constitution" and "Spreading the Wrod: Rural Clergymen and the Communication Network of Eighteenth-Century New England" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Galley proof of Richard D. Brown's introduction to "Farm Labor in Southern New England during the Agricultural-Industrial Transition;"</p>
                        <p>Manuscript of article "The Reverend Ebenezer Parkman's Farm Workers, Westborough, Massachusetts, 1726-82" by Ross W. Beales, Jr.</p>
                        <p>Manuscript of "'Labor is the Great Thing in Farming:' The Farm Laborers of the Ward Family of Shrewsbury, Massachusetts 1787-1860" by Jack Larkin;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "'What is Done in my Absence?' Levi Lincoln's Oakham, Mass. Farm Workers 1807-20" by Richard B. Lyman, Jr.</p>
                        <p>Campus map of Tufts University;</p>
                        <p>Correspondence between Richard D. Brown and Seymour Bellin, of Tufts University;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Technology and Society in the U.S. Overview, 1789-1880" by Richard D. Brown.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, manuscripts, publications, transcripts, fliers, ephemera,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1155004" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1968/2000" type="inclusive">undated, 1968, 1972, 1974, 1976-1977, 1980-1996, 1999-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref20">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include: Richard D. Brown's application for grant for project "Family Violence and Community Justice in New England: The Wheeler Case of 1805-1806;"</p>
                        <p>Teaching notes from HIST 337, on "French and English Models;"</p>
                        <p>Clippings from newspapers and photocopied articles "Plebes and Politicians (book review)" by Lawrence Stone; "Social History in Britain" by Harold Perkin; "Social Stratification in Germany" by Hartmut Kaelble; "An Interview With E.P. Thompson" by Mike Merrill;</p>
                        <p>Correspondence to Richard D. Brown from Jane R. Pomeroy (1996);</p>
                        <p>Photocopied table of contents of "Major Problems in the Era of the American Revolution 1760-1791" ed. Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Program for event "Outdoor Historical Drama: Staged Reading, Nov. 11, 1995," historical drama project by Three Rivers Community-Technological College consulting Richard D. Brown for historical detail; includes manuscript for play "A Brave Revenge" by John Basinger (1993);</p>
                        <p>article "Building Bridges" by R. Angus Murdoch, Executive director of Antiquarian and Landmarks Society;</p>
                        <p>Transcript of "Meeting Notes: Publications Committee" Jan. 15, 1992, Antiquarian and Landmarks Society);</p>
                        <p>Publication "The Landmark" from Fall 1991, Summer 1992, and Summer 1993;</p>
                        <p>Publication "ALS newsletter" Fall 1989, Summer 1990, and Winter 1990;</p>
                        <p>Publication "The Connecticut Antiquarian" Vol. 41, no. 1 (Winter 1990);</p>
                        <p>Draft of "Connecticut Antiquarian Mission Statement" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>ALS Annual Reports, from 1990, 1993, and 1996;</p>
                        <p>Richard D. Brown's correspondence with Dr. H. Lehmann, Dr. H. Wellenreuther, and Carola Wessel of the German Historical Institue;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "A Comment on British and German Cultural Transmission, 1730-1760" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Relocating Ethnicity: Educating Pennsylvania's Germans in the 18th Century" by Anita Tien (Mar. 1992);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Benjamin Franklin, Poor Richard, and The 'Way to Wealth:' The 'Proverbial' American Created [A], Interpreted [B], and Translated [C]" by Harald Kittel;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Problem of the Butler Transatlantic Problematique and American Religious History" by A.G. Roeber (1992);</p>
                        <p>Papers pertaining to Richard D. Brown's course HIST 401, Fall 1996 [restricted];</p>
                        <p>Flier for "The University of Connecticut Presents a Lecture Series: New England Society in the 19th Century: an Interdisciplinary Approach, Spring 1974;"</p>
                        <p>Teacher Evaluations [restricted] for Richard D. Brown (1980-1982, 1984, 1986-1989);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Text and Concepts: Excerpts, 1727, from the Diary of Ebenezer Parkman, 1703-1782" by Ross Beales and Ken Lockridge, 1999;</p>
                        <p>Publication "Old Sturbridge Visitor" Fall and Winter 1994;</p>
                        <p>Publication "The Old Sturbridge Village Grasshopper" Vol. 28, no. 1 (1996);</p>
                        <p>Syllabi and Final Exam questions for Richard D. Brown's HIST 231 (1989) (portions resetricted);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Importance of Special Collections" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Publication "The University of Connecticut Libraries Harvest" (Fall 1990);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Delegates to the Mass. Convention of Towns, 1768" by Richard D. Brown (1968);</p>
                        <p>Research Grant for Richard D. Brown's project "Communication Networks in Pre-Industrial America: Selected Interpersonal Studies in the Transmission and Reception of Information, 1700-1800;"</p>
                        <p>Program for event "41st Annual Meeting: The Southern Historical Associantion, Washington D.C." (1975);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Comments on James H. Dorman's 'Aspects of Collective Behavior in the American Popular Resistance, 1765-1775: A Theoretical Prospectus,' and Robert M. Weir's 'Who Shall Rule at Home: The American Revolution as a Crisis of Legitimacy for the Colonial Elite" by James K. Martin; Manuscripts of Dorman's and Weir's papers included;</p>
                        <p>Correspondence with Bruce M. Stave;</p>
                        <p>Photocopied article "Inside Industrial Archives" by Robert Levy;</p>
                        <p>Correspondence: Richard D. Brown's proposal to create anthology series "University of Connecticut Classic Texts in American History and Culture" (1987);</p>
                        <p>Publication "Stonehill College: The Summit" Vol. 41, no. 9 (Dec. 6, 1988);</p>
                        <p>Flier for "The Colonial Experience: The Eighteenth-Century Chesapeake;"</p>
                        <p>Correspondence with the George A. and Eliza Gardner Howard Foundation (1988);</p>
                        <p>Letters of recommendation written by Richard D. Brown, 1967-1976.</p>
                        <p></p>
                        <p></p>
                        <p></p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Manuscripts, administrative records, financial records, notes, publications, transcripts, correspondence, photographs (slides),</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1155005" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1974/1990" type="inclusive">undated, 1974-1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref21">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include:</p>
                        <p>Financial Records on Richard D. Brown's project expenses (1980-1990);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Leaders and Followers in the American Revolutionary Movement" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Conservative Whigs in a Radical Whig Revolution: The Institutionalization of Conservative Thought in the Continental Congress 1774-1776" by Jerrilyn Greene Marsten (1976);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Autonomy of American History Reconsidered" by Lawrence Veysey;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Politics of the Boston Elite, 1730-1760" by Joel A. Shufro;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Ideal of the Written Constitution: A Political Legacy of the Revolution" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Report from "Committee for Review of Department Structure and Policies (History Department);"</p>
                        <p>Clipping from OAH Newsletter, Feb. 1996: "New Directions for History Doctoral Programs?" by John R. Dichtil;</p>
                        <p>Publication "Harvard University Department of HIstory Alumni Newsletter" (Spring 1996);</p>
                        <p>Publication "Recommendations of the Graduate Review Committee" (May 7, 1996);</p>
                        <p>Transcript of History Department Meeting, Feb. 1, 1996;</p>
                        <p>Publication "Chair in the History of Human Rights: Proposal for an Endowment Campaign;"</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Remarks on Presentation of 'Massachusetts: A Bicentennieal History' to Governor Michael Dukakis, Nov. 28, 1978" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Emergence of Voluntary Associations in Massachusetts, 1760-1830" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Photocopied article "Modernization and the Emergence of Volunteer Organizations" by David Horton Smith;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Healing Arts in Colonial and Revolutionary Massachusetts: The Context for Scientific Medicine" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "An Analysis of the Social, Political and Professional Impact of the Revolution upon the Boston Medical Community (1759-1789)" by Philip Cash;\</p>
                        <p>Abstract of paper "The Medical Practitioners of Massachusetts, 1630-1800: Change and Continuity" by Eric H. Christianson;</p>
                        <p>Publication "The Mind of the Colonial Physician" by Gert Wallach, M.D., Mp.H.;</p>
                        <p>Publication "Provincial Medical Practice in England 1730-1815" by Joseph F. Kett;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Boston Medical Community and Emerging Science 1780-1820" by John C. Greene;</p>
                        <p>Abstract for "Health and Mortality in the Early Massachusetts Community" by James H. Cassedy;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Medical Profesion in Colonial Boston" by G.B. Warden;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Influence of Europe on Colonial Massachusetts Medicine" by C.H. Brock;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Therapeutic Practice in Colonial New England" by J. Worth Estes, M.D.;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Proposal for Continuation of a Program in American History and Historical Museum Work" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Bibliography, Catalogues of Books, the Novel, and Cultural History" by Robert B. Winans;</p>
                        <p>Correspondence with American Antiquarian Society;</p>
                        <p>Schedule for "AAS Printing and Society in Early America Conference;"</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The World of Print and Collective Mentality in Seventeenth-Century New England" by David D. Hall;</p>
                        <p>Handwritten manuscript "Printing and Society in Early America: Epilogue: From Cohesion to Competition" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Anglo-American Book Trade Before 1776: Personnel and Strategies" by Stephen Botein;</p>
                        <p>Photographic Slides, labelled "Springfield, 1790-1840;"</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Ingenuity and Enterprise in Springfield: The Urbanization of a Country Town, 1790-1840" (1986) by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript :The Newspaper Expose and the Revolution: A Language for Facts, Ideals, and Rogues" by Thomas C. Leonard;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Media and Language in Massachusetts Before the Revolution" by Michael J. Crawford;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Social Order of the Upper South in the New Nation: An Era of Involuntary Change" by Allan Kulikoff (1980);</p>
                        <p>Correspondence regarding the formation of an American Studies minor;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Modernization as a Framework for American History" by Richard Jensen (1981);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "How the Shaysites Organized Themselves: The Cultural Constraints on Revolutionary Action" by Stephen E. Patterson;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Shame and Guilt in Early America" by John P. Demus;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "'Somnia:' The Dream Diary of William Jenks'" by Redmond J. Barnett;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Constructing the Western Railroad: The Irish Dimension" by Edward J. O'Day;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Recovering from Victory: A Post-War Perspective on the Revolution" by Paul A. Gilje;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Egalitarian Currents in the Early 1780's" by Ruth Bogan;</p>
                        <p>Program for conference "Triumph of the American Revolution Symposium;"</p>
                        <p>Publication "Treaty of Paris Bicentennial Newsletter" (1983);</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Unmet Shipping Needs: The Case for Railroads in Indiana" by Victor M. Bogle;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Canals in America: New Light on Old Towpaths" by Ronald E. Shaw;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Urban Craft Structure and Artisan Culture in Early Eighteenth-Century Boston: The Evidence from the Gold-Smithing Trade" by Ward;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Rural Artisan Culture: The Preindustrial Joiners of Newtown and Woodbury, Connecticut" by Edward S. Cooke, Jr.;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "The Craftsmen of Roxbury, Mass.: Clockmaking Community in the Early 19th Century" by Thomas Michie;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "In Gotham's Shadow: The New Jersey Press, 1850-1900" by Richard F. Hixson;</p>
                        <p>Program for conference: "Small World, Big Challenges: Putting the Pieces Together: Northeast Regional COnference on the Social Studies, Connecticut Council of Language Teachers Convention" (Oct. 26-29, 1983).</p>
                        <p></p>
                        <p></p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, notes, manuscripts, galley proofs, notes, clippings, photographs (slides),</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1155006" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.5 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1978/2001" type="inclusive">undated, 1978, 1982-1990, 1996-1997, 2001,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref22">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include:</p>
                        <p>Notes by Richard D. Brown: "Report on: 'The First Revolution: Boston Merchants and the Acts of Trade;'"</p>
                        <p>Photographic slides (photographs of old documents);</p>
                        <p>Photocopied article "Vignettes of the Past: American Historical Broadsides through the War of 1812" by Georgia B. Bumgardiner;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "NEH Public Programs Division Project Narrative" by William L. Joyce;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Spreading the Word: Rural Clergymen and the Communication Network of 18th Century New England" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Migration in 18th-Century America: A Microcosmic Approach" by John Sky;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Markets, Streets, and Stores: The Politics of Urban Space in Revolutionary Boston" by Barbara Clark Smith;</p>
                        <p>Abstract of paper "'To Apprise the People of the Time:' The Use and Distribution of Clocks and Watches in Preindustrial America" by Margaret Bohn Alexander;</p>
                        <p>Abstract and manuscript of paper "Rural Clergy and the Communication Network of 18th-Century New England" by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Galley proofs and manuscripts of book chapter "Shays's Rebellion and the Ratification of the Federal Constitution in Massachusetts" by Richard D. Brown, from book "Beyond Confederation: Origins of the Constitution and American National National Identity" ed. Richard Beeman, Stephen Botein, and Edward C. Carter;</p>
                        <p>Correspondence with book's publisher, Institute of American History and Culture (1987);</p>
                        <p>Notes on Shays's Rebellion, by Richard D. Brown;</p>
                        <p>Syllabi, [Grading Sheets-restricted], exams and correspondence from Richard D. Brown's teaching of course HIST 337 (1974-1975, 1977-1980, 1983, 1986);</p>
                        <p>Photocopied article "On the Writing of Colonial History" by Charles McLean Andrews;</p>
                        <p>Manuscript "Prospero's America: John Winthrop, Jr., Alchemy, and the Creation of New England Culture (1606-1676)" by Walt W. Woodward;</p>
                        <p>Letters of recommendation by Richard D. Brown, on behalf of Walt W. Woodward;</p>
                        <p>Richard D. Brown's lecture notes on his book "Massachusetts and the Building of a Nation."</p>
                        <p></p>
                        <p></p>
                        <p></p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, publications, legal documents, ephemera, notes, galley proofs,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1237001" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1986/1994" type="inclusive">1986-1989, 1991-1992, 1994,</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref24">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>[Subjects include:</p>
                        <p>Manuscript of Radio America program on Mercy Otis Warren, episode 1;</p>
                        <p>Richard D. Brown's correpondence with Marc Lipsitz, acting as a scholarly consultant for radio program (1986);</p>
                        <p>Article "The American Revolution as a Social Movement Revisited" by Colin Bonwick;</p>
                        <p>Richard D. Brown's correspondence with D.C. Heath &amp; Co., publishers of his book "Major Problems in the History of the American Revolution;</p>
                        <p>Legal Documents: Contract between Richard D. Brown and publisher;</p>
                        <p>Table of contents for "Major Problems in the History of the American Revolution;"</p>
                        <p>Richard D. Brown's handwritten notes on the "Major Problems" book;</p>
                        <p>Flier from D.C. Heath publishers on the "Major Problems in American History" series (1991);</p>
                        <p>Photocopied table of contents to book "Colonies to Nation, 1763-1789: A Documentary History of the American Revolution" ed. Jack P. Greene;</p>
                        <p>Photocopied article "'Ideology' and an Economic Interpretation of the Revolution" by Joseph Ernst;</p>
                        <p>Photocopied article "The American Revolution Considered as an Intellectual Movement" by Edmund S. Morgan;</p>
                        <p>Article "Social Change and the Meaning of the American Revolution" by Kenneth A. Lockridge;</p>
                        <p>Notes by Richard D. Brown on chapter 1 of "A Documentary History of the American Revolution."</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
