<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Ready_for_export" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/Schulze/MSS20020100.html">MSS20020100</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>August F. Schulze Papers
                    <num>2002.0100</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">Schulze (August F.) Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Erin K. Donovan and James Brundage.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269-1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 2002</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-07-31T15:54-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>
                <language>English</language></langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>June 2012</date>
                <item></item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>August Frederick Schulze Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>2002.0100</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.15 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1908/1920" type="inclusive">1908-1920.</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The collection contains materials associated with August Schulze's experiences as a student at Connecticut Agricultural College (B.S. 1910, M.S. 1922). The collection also contains materials associated with Doris Schulze Cox's experiences at the University of Connecticut in the late 1940s.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Schulze, August</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biography</head>
            <p>Originally from 
                <geogname>Brooklyn, New York</geogname>, 
                <persname>August Frederick Schulze, Jr.</persname> entered the 
                <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> in the fall of 1908 as a third year student in the Associate Course in Agriculture. He was active at 
                <corpname>CAC</corpname> as a color sergeant in the campus military organization, the 
                <corpname>CAC Cadet Battalion</corpname>, from 1909 through 1911. During the years 1909-1912, he was considered a special student because he took courses irregularly in the 
                <corpname>School of Mechanic Arts</corpname>. In the school year 1912-1913, he was a candidate for a Bachelor of Science degree, which he earned in 1913 in Investigation Work.</p>
            <p>After earning his degree, Mr. Schulze was hired by 
                <corpname>CAC</corpname> as an Instructor in Botany, a position he held from 1913 through 1915. He worked in this capacity along with Professor 
                <persname>A.F. Blakeslee</persname> and was able to earn $800.00 per academic year. After the spring of 1915, Mr. Schulze was was no longer on record as an employee of CAC as he took on a position as an investigational agent with the 
                <corpname>United States Bureau of Chemistry</corpname> from 1916 to 1918. Following his work for the government Mr. Schulze returned to the Agricultural College as a Field Assistant in Genetics in 1918, and became a Professor of Horticulture and the Superintendent of Grounds at the 
                <corpname>Riggs School</corpname> from 1918 to 1920. Mr Schulze's time book in the 
                <persname>August Schulze</persname> Papers reflects that he was working in labor and school service instruction from October 1918 through July 1920. At this time Mr. Schulze returned to the 
                <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> as a student, receiving his M.S. degree in 1922. After receiving his degree he began teaching as an instructor in Zoology, and from 1923 until 1949 worked at the 
                <corpname>Storrs Agriculture Experiment Station</corpname> as an Assistant Zoologist, an instructor in Zoology, and at the end of his career as an instructor of Animal Diseases.</p>
            <p>For a photograph of Mr. Schulze see the 1930 edition of 
                <title render="italic">The Nutmeg</title>. Mr. Schulze is pictured with the faculty of the Biological Sciences department.</p>
            <p>
                <persname>Doris Schulze Cox</persname> is the daughter of 
                <persname>August F. Schulze</persname>, and attended the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname> in the late 1940s, eventually graduating from 
                <corpname>Russell Sage College</corpname>. She taught fourth grade at the 
                <corpname>Albany Acadamy for Girls</corpname> following college.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The 
                <persname>August Schulze</persname> Papers contain Mr. Schulze's education and employment records for the 
                <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname>. The educational records, including term reports, account statements, and a deposit slip, span the dates September 1908 through March 1913. The term reports contain his classes and grades for each term that he attended 
                <corpname>CAC</corpname>. The account statements show for each month that he was at 
                <corpname>CAC</corpname> the amount of money he owed for items such as board, laundry, and supplies, the credit he earned for labor, and the date he paid his bill in full. The deposit slip shows that he was able to deposit money ($25.00) with the college on September 17, 1908. The employment record includes Mr. Schulze's time book from his time as a Professor of Horticulture and Superindendent of the 
                <corpname>Riggs School</corpname>, spanning the period October 1918 through July 1920. This time book reflects labor and instruction in agricultural areas, such as potatoes, beets, and wood, as well as labor and instruction in school service. The time book does not have Mr. Schulze's name on it. Recently included in the collection are Mr. Schulze's degrees, photographs from his time as an undergraduate at the college, and the cap, gown, and hood from his M.S. degree ceremony.</p>
            <p>The collection also contains materials related to his daughter's time at the University, in the late 1940s. 
                <persname>Doris Schulze Cox</persname> did not graduate from the university but retained and donated items from her time at the university to include a beanie, books, and photographs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref5">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The papers were separated by type (term reports, account records, deposit slip, and workman's time book) and placed in acid-free folders, which were in turn placed in an acid-free box. Within the box, the folders were arranged so that the school records come before the work record, with grade reports first, and financial records following. Within each folder the papers were arranged according to chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bibliography id="ref7">
            <head>Bibliography</head>
            <p>The following 
                <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> publications were used to research the biographical information given about 
                <persname>August Schulze</persname>:
                <bibref>
                    <title render="italic">The CAC Biennial Report of the Trustees</title>. 1912-1914, pg. 71; 1914-1916, pg. 74-75.</bibref>
                <bibref>
                    <title render="italic">The CAC Bulletin</title>. 1908-1909, announcements for 1909-1910, pg. 70; 1909-1910, announcements for 1910-1911, pg. 68, 74-75; 1910-1911, announcements for 1911-1912, pg. 74, 79; 1911-1912, announcements for 1912-1913, pg. 79; 1912-1913, announcements for 1913-1914, pg. 73; 1913-1914, announcements for 1914-1915, pg. 5; 1914-1915, announcements for 1915-1916, pg. 90.</bibref>
                <bibref>
                    <title render="italic">Nutmeg</title>. 1915, pg. 10.</bibref></p>
        </bibliography>
        <accessrestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref10">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item, Folder #], August Frederick Schulze Papers. Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Acquisition Information</head>
            <p>This collection was found in the "Early History Records", an artificial collection in the University Archives. In 2002, the collection was eliminated and items placed in appropriate University Archives record groups (President's Office Records, etc.). Original provenance is unknown. In 2011, Mr. Schulze's daughter donated additional materials which have been integrated into the collection.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref17">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=3">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <famname source="ingest">Schulze, August.</famname>
            <subject source="local">College students--Connecticut--Storrs.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Connecticut Agricultural College--Students.</subject>
            <genreform source="local">Financial Records.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">School Records.</genreform>
            <subject source="local">University Archives</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Personal Papers,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>1908-1920</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref13" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> Term Reports for 
                            <persname>August Schulze</persname>,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid518004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1:1</container>
                        <unitdate>1908 Dec 18 - 1913 Mar 22</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> Account Statements for 
                            <persname>August Schulze</persname>,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid518003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1:2</container>
                        <unitdate>1908 Oct 1 - 1913 Aug 1</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <corpname>Connecticut Agricultural College</corpname> Deposit Slip for 
                            <persname>August Schulze</persname>,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid518002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1:3</container>
                        <unitdate>1908 Sep 17</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Workmen's Time Book,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid518001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1:4</container>
                        <unitdate>1918 October - 1920 Jul</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
