<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Ready_for_export" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtU" url="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/President/MSS20080092">MSS20080092</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [Philip E. Austin Papers]
                    <num>2008.0092</num>
                </titleproper>
                <titleproper type="filing">President's Office Records (UConn) - Philip E. Austin (1996-2007)</titleproper>
                <subtitle>An Inventory</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tim Webb and James Brundage.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/findaids/yourlogo.jpg"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>University of Connecticut Libraries</addressline>
                    <addressline>405 Babbidge Road Unit 1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut, 06269-1205</addressline>
                    <addressline>860.486.2524</addressline>
                    <addressline>archives@uconn.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-08-01T08:29-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Inventory is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [Philip E. Austin Papers]</unittitle>
            <unitid>2008.0092</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.8 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1991/2007" type="inclusive">1991-2007</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref13" label="Abstract">The collection contains correspondence, administrative records, financial records, an honorary degree, photographs, notes, fliers, publications, and legal documents. The materials are from Austin's tenure as president of the university, as well as materials from the president's office and the university prior to his appointment.</abstract>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref14">
            <head>Biography</head>
            <p>
                <persname>Philip E. Austin</persname> was born on 
                <date>March 25, 1942</date>, and served as the thirteenth president of the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>. Austin grew up in 
                <corpname>Fargo, North Dakota</corpname> and attended 
                <corpname>North Dakota State University</corpname>, receiving a bachelor of science degree in 1964. He remained at the university receiving an M.S. in Agricultural Economics in 1966. In 1968 he received a Ph.D in Economics from 
                <corpname>Michigan State University</corpname>.</p>
            <p>Before entering the academy Austin served in the 
                <corpname>United States Army</corpname> as an economist in the office of the Deputy Chief of Staff for Economic Affairs at the U. S. Military Headquarters in 
                <geogname>Saigon, Vietnam</geogname>. Following his service in 
                <geogname>Vietnam</geogname> Austin served as an Economist in the Director’s Office of the U.S. Office of Management and Budget, from 1971 to 1974. He also served as the 
                <corpname>Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW) Department's Deputy Assistant Secretary for Education</corpname> from 1974-1977. From 1978 to 1984 Austin served as Provost and Vice President for Academic Affairs, and Professor of Economics and Finance, at 
                <corpname>Bernard Baruch College</corpname> in 
                <geogname>New York City</geogname>.</p>
            <p>In 1984 Austin was appointed President of 
                <corpname>Colorado State University</corpname>, serving in that capacity until 1989. in 1989 he began working as Chancellor of the 
                <corpname>University of Alabama</corpname> system, remaining in that postition for the next seven years. On October 1, 1996, Austin was appointed as the thirteenth president of the 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut</corpname>. Austin remained at 
                <corpname>UConn</corpname> until 2007, when he resigned his office. Upon 
                <persname>Michael Hogan</persname>'s departure as president in 2010, Austin returned to the President's Office as interim president. After 
                <persname>Susan Herbst</persname> was selected to be the next president of the University, Austin assumed the position of the Interim Vice President for Health Affairs at the University's Health Center, a position he held for the next year. Austin currently lives in 
                <geogname>West Hartford, Connecticut</geogname>.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref15">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection contains correspondence, administrative records, financial records, an honorary degree, photographs, notes, fliers, publications, and legal documents. The materials are from Austin's tenure as president of the University, as well as materials from the president's office prior to his appointment.</p>
            <p>Subjects in the collection include ethics commission, university events, exchange programs in 
                <geogname>China</geogname>, 
                <geogname>Dubai</geogname>, 
                <geogname>Germany</geogname>, 
                <geogname>Ireland</geogname>, 
                <geogname>Puerto Rico</geogname>, and 
                <geogname>Thailand</geogname>, the Fulbright Association, family studies, financial aid, fine arts, fraternaties and sororities, freedom of information, funding requests, the graduate school, greek housing, the 
                <corpname>Greek Orthodox Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Hartford</corpname>, 
                <corpname>Hartford Hospital</corpname>, 
                <corpname>John Dempsey Hospital</corpname>, human rights institute, the UConn Husky mascot, inauguration, the 
                <corpname>Department of Information Technology</corpname>, 
                <corpname>Islamic Center</corpname>, the 
                <corpname>Judaic Studies Center</corpname>, the 
                <corpname>Center for Latin American Studies</corpname>, and the law school. Also included are publications, to include the 
                <title render="italic">Journal Inquirer</title> and the 
                <title render="italic">Hartford Courant</title>.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref16">
            <head>Access</head>
            <p>The collection is open and available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref17">
            <head>Restrictions on Use and Copyright Information</head>
            <p>Permission to publish from these Papers must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref18">
            <head>Provenance and Acquisition</head>
            <p>The records were transferred in several installments beginning in 2008.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref19">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>[Item description, #:#], University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [Philip E. Austin Papers, 1996-2007]. 
                <corpname>Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, 
                <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries</corpname>.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref20">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Archives &amp; Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the 
                <extref ns2:href=" http://doddcenter.uconn.edu/asc/dodda2z/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorinfo=3">curator</extref> or ask at the Reading Room desk.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest">University of Connecticut. President's Office.</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">University of Connecticut</corpname>
            <genreform source="local">Administrative Records.</genreform>
            <subject source="aat">Archives.</subject>
            <genreform source="local">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Notes.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="local">Reports.</genreform>
            <subject source="local">University of Connecticut.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: An Inventory,</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>6.5 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1991/2007" type="inclusive">1991-2007</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref3" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Clippings, Financial Records, Administrative Records, Publications, Legal Documents,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1102001" type="Box" label="Text">2009-0005_1</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders with labeled tabs organized alphabetically.</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1997/2007" type="inclusive">1997-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref4">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Subjects Include: Ethics Commission, Events, Exchange Programs (China, Dubai, Germany, Ireland, Miscellanous, Puerto Rico, S's, Thailand), Fulbright Association, Facilities, Family Studies, Finance and Administration, Finance Revenue and Bonding, Financial Aid, Financial Planning and Management, Fine Arts, Fleet Bank, Fraternaties and Sororities,</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative Records, Clippings, Notes, Photographs, Correspondence, Financial Records, Publications, Fliers, Maps,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1102002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2009-0005_2</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders with labeled tabs organized alphabetically.</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1994/2005" type="inclusive">1994-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref6">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Subjects Include: Freedom of Information, Freedom of Information-Heidinger, Funding Requests, General Assembly, Governmental Relations, Governmental Relations-Federal Lobbyist, Governor's Commission of UConn Review and Accountability, Governor's Council on Economic Competitiveness and Technology, Governors Office, Governor's Task Force: Contracting Reform, Governor's Task Force: CT Center for Science and Exploration, Graduate School, Graduate Student Housing, Greek Housing, Greek Orthodox Center, Greetings from the President.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Administrative Records, Clippings, Publications, Photographs, Fliers, Financial Records,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1102003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2009-0005_3</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders with labeled tabs organized alphabetically.</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1991/2005" type="inclusive">1991-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref8">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Subjects Include: Hartford Arts Council, Hartford Chamber of Commerce, Hartford Club, Hartford Consortium, Hartford Courant, Hartfor-Miscellaneous, Hartford Schools Partnership, Hazardous Waste Treatment Lab, University of Hartford, Health Center, Health Center Alliance.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative Records, Correspondence, Clippings, Fliers, Financial Records, Legal Documents, Publications, Awards,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1102004" type="Box" label="Text">2009-0005_4</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders with labeled tabs organized alphabetically.</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1993/2005" type="inclusive">1993-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref10">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Subjects Include: Hartford Center Alliance (Hartford Hospital), Health Center Board of Directors, Health Center Finance Corp, Health Center-John Dempsey Hospital, Health Center-Kreutzer, Department of Health, Department of History, Honorary Degree, Honors Program, Hotel Conference Center, Human Resources, Human Rights Institute, Husky Mascot, Inauguration, Department of Information Technology, Information Technology Services, Institute for (Material Science, Puerto Rican and Latin American Studies, Public Service), Institutional Advancement, Institutional Research, International Programs, Islamic Center, Jewish Matters, Journal Inquirer, Journalism, Judaic Studies Center, Justice for Janitors, Keystone Proposal, Labor Ed Center, Labor Relations.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative Records, Correspondence, Clippings, Financial Records, Notes, Legal Documents,</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid1102005" type="Box" label="Text">2009-0005_5</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.3 Linear feet</extent>
                            <extent>Folders with labeled tabs organized alphabetically.</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1991/2005" type="inclusive">1991-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref12">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Subjects Include: Center for Latin American Studies, Law School, Law School Accreditation, Law School Foundation, Law School Library, Lawsuits and Grievances (Folders with Contents: A, Alexander, B, Baker and Levoy, C, D, Donovan, Dorsky, E, F, G).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative records,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1155009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2011_1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="2006/2007" type="inclusive">2006-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
