<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "/eadcb/shared/ead/ead.dtd">
<ead audience="external" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
<eadid mainagencycode="US-CtU" countrycode="US">MSS20030074</eadid>
<filedesc>
  <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America, Unity Lodge, Local 251 Records</titleproper>
            <subtitle/>
            <author>Finding aid prepared by Laura Katz Smith.</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>&#x00A9; 2003  University of Connecticut</publisher>
            <date type="publication">September 2003</date>
            <address>
               <addressline>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center</addressline>
               <addressline>405 Babbidge Road, Unit 1205</addressline>
               <addressline>Storrs, Connecticut  06269-1205</addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Finding aid encoded by Laura Katz Smith in October 2003.</creation>
         <langusage>
            <language>English</language>
         </langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date normal="20040323">March 23, 2004</date>
            <item>MSS20030074 converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02.xsl (sy2003-10-15).</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" type="Inventory">
      <did id="a1">
         <head>Overview of the Records</head>
         <repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
            <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center</corpname>.</repository>
         <origination label="Creator:">
            <corpname encodinganalog="110">United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America, Unity Lodge, Local 251</corpname>.</origination>
         <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America, Unity Lodge, Local 251 Records.</unittitle>
         <unitdate label="Dates:">1937-1948.</unitdate>
         <physdesc label="Extent:" encodinganalog="300$a">2 linear feet.</physdesc>
         <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract:">Materials associated with the United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America, Unity Lodge, Local 251, which represented workers at the Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Machine Tools Division of Niles-Bement-Pond in West Hartford, Connecticut, from 1938 to 1948.  Collection consists of a membership dues book, a large scrapbook of newspaper clippings and bulletins involving a strike of the union members at the West Hartford plant from March to August 1946, the local's charter, and other administrative records.</abstract>
         <unitid encodinganalog="090" label="Record Series:" countrycode="US" repositorycode="UCW">MSS20030074</unitid>
         <langmaterial label="Language">
            <language langcode="eng">English.</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did><!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->
      <bioghist altrender="biography" encodinganalog="545" id="a2">
         <head>History</head>
         <p>United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America, Unity Lodge, Local 251, represented workers at the <corpname>Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Division</corpname> of <corpname>Niles-Bement-Pond</corpname> in <geogname>West Hartford, Connecticut</geogname>.  Its predecessor union was established in 1933-1934 as the <corpname>Machine Tool and Co-workers of America</corpname>, Unity Lodge.  In March 1937 the Unity Lodge affiliated with the <corpname>United Automobile Workers of America</corpname> to become UAW Local 348.</p>
         <p>The charter for Local 251 was established on <date>October 3, 1938</date>.  Local 251  became part of the Amalgamated Local 405 of the <corpname>International Union of United Automobile,  Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America</corpname> on <date>March 19, 1948</date>.</p>
         <p>
            <corpname>Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Company</corpname> was founded in 1860 by <persname>Francis Pratt</persname> (1827-1902) and <persname>Amos Whitney</persname> (1832-1920), who met while working as machinists for the <corpname>Phoenix Iron Works</corpname>.  The first products they produced included silk winders, guns, lathes, and drills.  The company formally incorporated in 1869.  By the end of the 1800s the company branched into the production of planters, screw machines, die sinkers, wrenches, gages, weighing machines, and more.</p>
         <p>In 1879 the company hired Harvard professor <persname>William A. Rogers</persname> and <corpname>Stevens Institute of Technology</corpname> graduate <persname>George M. Bond</persname> to begin work to establish the standard inch.  This led to the important  development of the Rogers-Bond Comparator, accurate to one fifty-thousandth of an inch.  This research helped P &#x0026; W develop the mass production of interchangeable parts.</p>
         <p>In 1901 <corpname>Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Company</corpname> was purchased by the <corpname>Niles-Bement-Pond Company</corpname>.  By that time they concentrated on the  manufacture of machine tools, small tools and gauges.  In 1925 the company began producing  aircraft engines but by 1929 this function moved to another plant in East Hartford and became unaffiliated with the P &#x0026; W Division of <corpname>Niles-Bement-Pond Company</corpname>, yet had paid for the rights to use the Pratt &#x0026; Whitney name.</p>
         <p>In 1945 <corpname>Niles-Bement-Pond Company</corpname> was acquired by <corpname>Chandler Evans</corpname>.  <corpname>Chandler Evans</corpname> merged with <corpname>Penn-Texas Corporation</corpname> in 1955.  <corpname>Penn-Texas Corporation</corpname> was renamed in 1958 as <corpname>Fairbanks Whitney Corporation</corpname> after it merged with <corpname>Fairbanks Morse &#x0026; Company</corpname>.  By 1960 the <corpname>Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Division</corpname>  employed over 2500 workers and produced more than 2000 items.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="520" id="a3">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection consists of a Membership Dues Record Book of Local 251, with entries from 1937 to 1948; a large scrapbook of newspaper clippings and bulletins involving a strike of the union members at the West Hartford plant of the <corpname>Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Division</corpname> of <corpname>Niles-Bement-Pond</corpname> from March to August  1946; the local's charter; an insurance policy on the schedule of positions; per capita  and supply payment reports; and an agreement of the local to affiliate with Amalgamated Local 405 of the <corpname>International Union of United Automobile, Aircraft &#x0026; Agricultural Implement Workers of America</corpname>.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a" id="a4">
         <head>Organization</head>
         <p>The materials are organized chronologically.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="a6">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections has a substantial collection of Connecticut labor records.  For detailed information on these collections please contact the <extref href="http://www.lib.uconn.edu/online/research/speclib/ASC/collections/curatorinfo.cfm?curatorid=4">curator</extref> or ask at the reference desk.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <bibliography id="a10">
         <head>Bibliography</head>
         <p>
            <persname>Lenzi, Dick</persname>.  "Towards Industrial Unionism in Hartford: A History  of the Labor Movement at Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Tool Company, 1900-1937."</p>
      </bibliography>
<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA --><!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS GO HERE: -->
      <controlaccess id="a12">
         <head>Index Terms</head>
         <p>This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
</p>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Organizations:</head>
            <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Company.</corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America--Local 251 (West Hartford, Conn.).</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Places:</head>
            <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="local">West Hartford (Conn.)</geogname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Labor unions--Connecticut.</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Document Types:</head>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Publications.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Administrative Records.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Financial Records.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Minutes.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Press releases.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Fliers. [printed matter]</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Scrap books.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Posters.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Newspapers.</genreform>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess><!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS --><!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->
      <accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506">
         <head>Restrictions on Access</head>
         <p>There are no access restrictions on this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15">
         <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
         <p>Permission to publish from these Records must be obtained in writing from both the University of Connecticut Libraries and the owner(s) of the copyright.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <custodhist encodinganalog="561" id="a16">
         <head>Custodial History</head>
         <p>Materials were in the possession of Mr. <persname>Richard Lenzi</persname> of <geogname>Columbia, Connecticut</geogname>, who received them as a gift from the President  of the local in the 1990s.</p>
      </custodhist>
      <prefercite encodinganalog="510" id="a18">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Item description, #:#],  United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America, Unity Lodge, Local 251 Records.  <corpname>Archives &#x0026; Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center</corpname>, <corpname>University of Connecticut Libraries.</corpname>
         </p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
         <head>Acquisition Information</head>
         <p>The records were donated by Mr. Richard Lenzi in 2003.</p>
      </acqinfo><!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION --><!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
      <dsc type="combined" id="a23">
         <head>Detailed Description</head>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Records, <unitdate>1937-1948</unitdate>
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  <unittitle>Membership Dues Record of <corpname>United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America</corpname>, Unity Lodge, Local 251, <unitdate>1937-1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2:1</container>
                  <unittitle>Union charter, <unitdate>1938</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2:2</container>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook of newspaper clippings and bulletin flyers involving a strike of the union workers against the <corpname>Pratt &#x0026; Whitney Division</corpname> of <corpname>Niles-Bement-Pond</corpname>, in a dispute over a new contract, <unitdate>1946</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2:3</container>
                  <unittitle>Insurance policy of Local 251 covering schedule of positions, <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2:4</container>
                  <unittitle>Per capita and supply payment reports, receipt copies, <unitdate>1947-1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <container type="Box">2:5</container>
                  <unittitle>Assignment of Agreement between <corpname>Niles-Bement-Pond Co.</corpname> and Unity Lodge, Local 251, <corpname>United Electrical, Radio &#x0026; Machine Workers of America</corpname>, affiliating itself with Amalgamated Local 405 of the <corpname>International Union of United Automobile, Aircraft &#x0026; Agricultural Implement Workers of America</corpname>, <unitdate>1948</unitdate>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc><!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
   </archdesc>
</ead>