<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-CtWeharU" url="http://archives.hartford.edu:8081/repositories/2/resources/175">ARCH160</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Julius Smith Augur family papers  <num>ARCH160</num></titleproper><author>Tiffany Crawford </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>University of Hartford Archives &amp; Special Collections</publisher><p><date>2016-01-19</date></p><address><addressline>200 Bloomfield Avenue</addressline><addressline>West Hartford, CT 06117</addressline><addressline>archives@hartford.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.hartford.edu/UniversityLibraries/archspeccoll/default.aspx" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.hartford.edu/UniversityLibraries/archspeccoll/default.aspx" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-06-15 11:47:52 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English </langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>University of Hartford Archives &amp; Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Julius Smith Augur family papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <famname authfilenumber="Julius Smith Augur family" rules="dacs" source="local">Julius Smith Augur Family</famname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARCH160</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1901/1940" type="inclusive">1901-1940, undated </unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_6781d66268550c9dfb97dbefd5b245ee">English</langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_ca3f17621340ff67430091dca140b6ba" label="Mixed Materials (0207303172333)" type="box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_48c10446f0bb0f32f3d80acd6da51bbe" label="Graphic Materials (0207303170048)" type="box">Shared Small Oversized 1</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_270882ee119b967ba93b0e21350e6e3e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>The collection is open to all researchers.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ccde234b46bb7bb9b76dfa1c594d35d0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The materials in this collection may be protected by copyright law (U.S. Code: Title 17). Any use of the material which exceeds fair use requires permission from the copyright holder. Researchers are solely responsible for obtaining the proper permission(s) for their use of the material.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_126f71de3d21dc633eb302053c700b3f">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>AN ACCOUNT OF THE LIFE OF JULIUS SMITH AUGUR:
Julius Smith Augur was born Feb. 2, 1881 in Meriden, CT to Julius Augur and Nettie Eliza (Smith). His father was an alderman in Meridan, owned and managed a Meat Market and Grocery Store in Meriden, Connecticut.</p><p>When he graduated from the 8th grade he was apprenticed to his uncle, Frank Smith, to learn the trade of carpentry and cabinet making. Frank Smith had a furniture store where Julius also learned salesmanship. As a young man Julius loved books and learning. At age 25 he decided to go Mt. Hermon School for boys in Northfield, MA. designed by Dwight L. Moody for young men who wanted further education at the high school level. </p><p>He had a teacher who told him, "You have a college mind. You should increase your Latin studies and apply for Yale." This he did, earning his way by teaching woodworking at Choate and running the recreation program for young people in Meriden in the summers. He also sold fire extinguishers on the side in New Haven. He graduated from Yale, Class of 1913.</p><p>At that time he decided to become a Christian minister and chose to study at Hartford Theological Seminary. In a class behind him at the Seminary he met and fell in love with Gertrude Elmer of West Hartford, a recent graduate of Mount Holyoke. (Only two women per class were allowed in the Seminary in those days.) They became engaged, but the Seminary Dean said they should not marry until after he graduated. She very much wanted to become a missionary and he desired to serve God in any way that he might be called. Therefore they agreed to marry and to apply to The American Board of Commissioners for Missions of the Congregational Churches for an appointment.</p><p>In Sept. 1916 Julius was ordained, two days later they were married and two days later they were
commissioned as missionaries to Davao, Mindanao. They served two terms of five years (with one furlough) from 1916 to 1927. Julius was classified as an "Evangelical Missionary, but he worked in a variety of ways. It included starting schools in villages of the region. For this he needed a horse to take him on jungle trails. Frank Laubach was a fellow missionary who developed a new method of teaching natives to read, "Each one Teach one". Julius started churches training and working with native pastors. There was a mission hospital and he helped in administration and outreach to help immunize people from the scourge of smallpox and other tropical diseases. Both Julius and Gertrude had to learn Spanish and Visayan to work with native people. They enjoyed and were interested in the indigenous peoples, and had many artifacts in our home made by local people, especially the Bagobo tribe, who they worked extensively. Their daughters learned several Bogobo songs.</p><p>It was more difficult working with a local Moro tribe, and Julius' photographs (he was an avid
photographer) showed striking differences in facial expression - the Moro seemed very fierce. I
also remember his telling of having a baseball bat on ready weapon should the fierce Moro tribe
become violent. My impression is they were distrustful of strangers and followers of a extreme
form of Islam. I never heard that the baseball bat was needed.</p><p>Julius and Gertrude were very fond of the Filipino people. They hired local indigenous people to
help at home. In 1918, 1921 and 1926 they were blessed with three daughters: Caroline and
Elisabeth (Betsey) were delivered at home by an American Mission doctor and Fidelia was
delivered by a Filipino doctor at the Mission Hospital. Gertrude did mission work while she home schooled her daughters. She played piano on a portable field organ, She was assisted in childcare by two young native women, Benedicta Lomunda and Susanna Diamonon. Julius and Gertrude treated these two like daughters and part of the family. They, in turn, called Gertrude "Mother Augur" and kept in contact with our family for a number of years after they returned to the United States. It took about a month for letters to go from the US to the Phillipines by ship. Gertrude started the first Girl Scout troop in the Philippine Islands called the Red Rose troop. Julius also started a Boy Scout troop (but not the first).</p><p>Their two school age daughters were home schooled, but when the oldest was nine, they decided to return to the States at the completion of their second term and it became evident that home
schooling was not enough. Benedicta taught little Fidelia (then 1/1/2) to walk so that she would fare better on the long ocean voyage home.</p><p>Once back in Connecticut Julius lived in West Hartford. He sought a parish, but found no openings, therefore he sought other employment. During his days as a student at Mount Hermon school he had worked for the YMCA in Springfield, MA with George C. Hubert. He found that he was General Secretary of the Hartford YMCA and applied for ajob there. Hubert decided he was just the man he was looking for to become Director of Hillyer Evening School (in West Hartford) designed for young men seeking further education. Julius Augur worked in the field of education for the rest of his life. Hillyer offered a variety of practical courses. For example, Julius taught Public Speaking and Salesmanship.</p><p>Julius decided Hillyer needed to become an accredited college. The YMCA agreed. I remember
how hard he worked through all the processes necessary to bring this about. Hillyer finally became an accredited college, affiliated still with the YMCA. He had worked very hard to develop this new college so I believe he would be very proud to know it later became part of the University of Hartford. The YMCA's new General Secretary, now following George Hubert, decided they would need a younger man to be president of the new college. Julius Augur worked with him in selecting the younger person to and was asked to be the Dean of Hillyer College. This was the position he held when he died at the age of 59 in August 1941.</p><p>
Note written by Fidelia Augur Lane, 2008</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ec7f03eb3be860928c45407b866d8ac3">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Originally Processed by Tiffany Crawford and Sean Parke. The 2016 addition processed by Amanda Talbot and Sean Parke.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f60516494d7d68e02fadcf30859e0751">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists primarily of documents pertaining to Julius Smith Augur from the year of 1901 to 1941. Most of the documents are from his time at Hillyer Evening School as Director and later as Dean of Hillyer Junior College including notes, course catalogs, memorandums, provisional policy, and a report. There are also newspaper clippings, personal correspondence, a Hillyer Junior College patch, a Hillyer Junior College Diploma for Gertrude Augur, and photographs of his family as well as his days as a student.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_99630585502870c6d3133929ada8a8b7">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>The Hartford Seminary also has a collection form the family of Julius S. Augur, which consists primarily of documents, photographs, and correspondence, from his missionary years in the Philippines, as well as some materials from his time at Mt. Hermon and Yale.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300046300" source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform authfilenumber="300026877" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Augur, Julius Smith</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2005084798" rules="dacs" source="LCNAF">Hillyer Institute</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
