<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              relatedencoding="marc"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511"
              scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US"
             mainagencycode="US-CtY-BA"
             url="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/ycba.mss.0045">ycba.mss.0045</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Edward Burne-Jones Letters to Cormell Price </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing">Burne-Jones (Edward) Letters to Cormell Price</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Mairead MacRae; edited by Francis Lapka</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Department of Rare Books and Manuscripts</addressline>
               <addressline>1080 Chapel Street</addressline>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208280 </addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8280</addressline>
               <addressline altrender="email">ycba.rarebooks@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <extptr xlink:href="https://britishart.yale.edu/about-us/departments/rare-books-and-manuscripts"
                          xlink:title="https://britishart.yale.edu/about-us/departments/rare-books-and-manuscripts"
                          xlink:show="new"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>December 2017</date>
            <num>MSS 45</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      
      
      
      
      <!--CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)-->
      
      
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Monday April 29, 2019 at 21:00</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones Letters to Cormell Price</unittitle>
         <unitid>MSS 45</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdesc>
            <extent unit="Linear Feet">.42</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="container_summary">1 box</physdesc>
         
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1852/1862">1852-1862</unitdate>
         
         <abstract id="aspace_5ee8ea996fcf1b504d225dd1216f8d42">This collection comprises 16 items, including 15 letters from Sir Edward Coley Burne-Jones and Cormell Price and 1 autograph envelope from Burne-Jones addressed to Price. The correspondence was written over the course of a decade, between 1852 and 1862. The letters are indicative of Burne-Jones and Price's long and close friendship and are very affectionate and personal in nature. The letters are rich in detail, with Burne-Jones sharing news of mutual friends, his Oxford lessons, his social life and his artistic and literary endeavors.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_85e8c3b155ed821a1ae0b664de0dfd67">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Sir Edward Coley Burne-Jones (1833-1898) was a British painter, illustrator and designer. Born in Birmingham in 1833, Ruskin studied at the Birmingham School of Art from 1848 to 1852, before going on to read theology at Exeter College, Oxford, in 1853. At Oxford, Burne-Jones was a key figure of what became known as the Birmingham Set, a group of Oxford students who hailed from Birmingham or who had, as Burne-Jones did, attended King Edward's School, Birmingham. The group were hugely influential in Britain's visual art scene in the mid-nineteenth century and its members Burne-Jones, William Morris and Charles Faulkner were founding members of Morris, Marshall, Faulkner and Co., a company manufacturing furnishings and decorative art, in 1861. Burne-Jones is closely associated with the later phase of the group known as the Pre-Raphaelite Brotherhood. The Pre-Raphaelites sought to reform British art through a return to honest simplicity and the use of luminous colors and literary themes. Burne-Jones deviated from the earlier Pre-Raphaelites in his alignment with the Aestheticism movement which burgeoned throughout the latter half of the nineteenth century and which advocated for an appreciation of art's aesthetic beauty for its own sake rather than for the social-political themes of its subject matter. Alongside other artists associated with the Pre-Raphaelites, including Dante Gabriel Rossetti, Burne-Jones was a contributor to the <title>
               Oxford and Cambridge Magazine.
            </title> Burne-Jones produced many artistic works, in a variety of media including stained glass, watercolors, oils, and tapestries.</p>
         <p>The recipient of the letters, Cormell Price (1835-1910), was one of Burne-Jones's closest friends from their days at King Edward's School, Birmingham. Price attended Oxford two years later than Burne-Jones and, as these letters demonstrate, his decision to apply was very much encouraged by his old school friend. Price studied medicine at the Radcliffe Infirmary under Henry W. Acland (an Oxford physician and close friend of John Ruskin) before going on to tutor the son of a Russian aristocratic, with whose family he travelled around Europe. After returning to Britain, Price went into teaching, becoming the Head of the Modern Side at Haileybury College and Headmaster of the United Services College at Westward Ho! where his nephew, Rudyard Kipling, would eventually become his pupil.</p>
         <p>Burne-Jones and Price met as schoolboys at King Edward's School, Birmingham. The two remained very close friends throughout their lives which is evident from the affectionate correspondence present in this collection.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_85e26ebc8eb19af3eec0a2277bda926f">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_0a8175ab56e8208984ca1ef324216215">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The collection is the physical property of the Yale Center for British Art. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the Curator of Rare Books and Manuscripts.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_53a1e72cfc2884dec1e27a1a5f1bd0e6">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Edward  Burne-Jones Letters to Cormell Price. Yale Center for British Art, Paul Mellon Fund.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_45668e93e36cbd4b712f2dd9dc49bb1e">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Yale Center for British Art, Paul Mellon Fund.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <arrangement id="aspace_bded24c3c08bfbe7c4a00d2ae6286d3a">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The letters are arranged chronologically.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_fbeafcecd5e57f32062f7e2c099350b2">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection comprises 16 items, including 15 letters from Sir Edward Coley Burne-Jones and Cormell Price and 1 autograph envelope from Burne-Jones addressed to Price. The correspondence was written over the course of a decade, between 1852 and 1862. The letters are indicative of Burne-Jones and Price's long and close friendship and are very affectionate and personal in nature. The letters are rich in detail, with Burne-Jones sharing news of mutual friends, his Oxford lessons, his social life and his artistic and literary endeavors.</p>
         <p>The collection gives an account of the early activities of what came to be known as "The Birmingham Set" and Burne-Jones's letters frequently refer to many of the group's members, including William Morris (often affectionately dubbed "Topsy"), William Fulton, Charles Faulkner, Richard Watson Dixon, Edwin Hatch and Harry MacDonald. The close friendship held between Burne-Jones, Price and the wider group is evident in a letter dated May 18th, 1856, in which Burne-Jones sketches for Price a heart surrounded by the names of their friends, including many members of the Birmingham Set.</p>
         <p>The early publishing and exhibition activities of the group are recounted in Burne-Jones's letters. The first letter in the collection, dated January 24, 1852, describes Burne-Jones's agitation to receive articles from Price and Charles Faulkner for a forthcoming publication, perhaps a precursor to <title>
               The Oxford and Cambridge Magazine.
            </title> Discussion of <title>
               The Oxford and Cambridge Magazine
            </title> also features prominently in the correspondence. In one letter (circa 1856 January), Burne-Jones instructs Price to send him a piece of writing for a forthcoming issue while also lamenting the scandal caused by the January issue's article on the work of Charles Kingsley, a university professor, historian, social reformer, novelist and Church of England priest. The letter goes on to state that William Morris has passed editorship of the magazine on to William Fulford, which Burne-Jones remarks is a "great relief" to Morris.</p>
         <p>The post-university activities of the Birmingham Set are also presented in the correspondence. Burne-Jones's letter of June 28, 1861, announces the foundation of Morris, Marshall, Faulkner &amp; Co. by Burne-Jones, William Morris, P.P. Marshall, Ford Madox Brown, Philip Webb and Dante Gabriel Rossetti. The letter describes the company's products as "stained glass, furniture, jewelry, decorations and pictures" and notes that the organization has received many commissions in the short time since its inception.</p>
         <p>Also evident in the collection is Edward Burne-Jones and The Birmingham Set's place within the wider literary and artistic circles of mid-nineteenth century Britain. The letters often demonstrate Burne-Jones's connection and friendship with prominent figures of the era. For instance, in his letter dated January 24, 1852, Burne-Jones expounds, at great length, upon his love of the influential art critic, John Ruskin, and his delight in receiving a letter from Ruskin, an event which Burne-Jones claims has transformed him into "a reformed character." Later letters reveal a closeness with a variety of artists, patrons and writers. Burne-Jones's letter of June 21, 1861, provides a particularly detailed account of the lives of a variety of such figures. In it, Burne-Jones describes the stillborn birth of a child of Elizabeth Siddal and Dante Gabriel Rossetti, the death of the Pre-Raphaelite art collector, Thomas Plint, the death of Elizabeth Barrett Browning, and the marriage of Valentine Cameron "Val" Prinsep.</p>
         <p>The letters abound with contemporary cultural references and accounts of major events in Victorian society. Burne-Jones expresses, at length, his deep love of the poetry of Alfred, Lord Tennyson, who he describes as "save Shakespeare only […] the only guide worth following far to dream-land." In the same letter, Burne-Jones warns Price that he should avoid seeing Chevalier Count George Jones's "mangling" of Shakespeare and, in another, recommends the work of Edgar Allan Poe (see May 1 and October 29, 1853). The letters also give details about major public events, including the Tooley Street Fire in London and the Victorian superstitions surrounding the Great Comet of 1861 (see June 28, 1861).</p>
         <p>The collection chronicles some of the political and academic history of Oxford University in the early to mid-1850s. In a letter dated March 5, 1853, Burne-Jones describes the employment and promotions of various Oxford professors and chaplains and how they relate to the philosophical and ecclesiastical debates of the Oxford Movement. Later, in his encouragement of Price's application to study at the university, Burne-Jones gives long descriptions about Oxford fellowships and scholarships and how to write "Oxford Latin" (see February 28, 1854).</p>
         <p>The long and close friendship between Burne-Jones and Price is reflected in the personal and quotidian events about which Burne-Jones writes to his friend. He sends Price a lengthy description of his infant son's features and personality and the health and happiness of his family(see February 23, 1862). The letters are full of details and references to Burne-Jones's father, aunt, friends, social life and the romantic exploits of his and Price's mutual acquaintances. In one letter, he gives Price an hour-by-hour account of his holiday in the River Wye area. (see January 24, 1852).</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <dsc>
         <c id="aspace_3c2aa3fb031c68a745a6644fc0445c04" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1852 January 24</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_5bc1c29cb78ba6894a06f63e0db13c2d">2 folded sheets (8 pages) : autograph letter signed ; each sheet 19 x 23 cm, folded to 19 x 12 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_cab602d276505a3f6802469df77fcdb0"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_23c5f152cf5791f0a858a5d90eae26f9"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_cab602d276505a3f6802469df77fcdb0">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e46cdfbd9cf7e024d2088f3887b286dd">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones jokingly chastises Price for his last "skinny" letter and promises that "now [he]'ll be revenged" in his response. Burne-Jones describes at length how he spends his time in the River Wye area, which he says is like "Elysium." He describes his daily routine of walking in the countryside, reading and going to the cathedral. He says in his time in the area he has "endured two" parties and complains about the questioning he receives from guests, commenting "girls are such -- hm -- hang 'em they do quiz so, and I [Burne-Jones] make such a capital subject." Burne-Jones asks Price how he is finding reading "Fasti" but admits that he himself has begun the book. He states that, on the "urgent orders of [sic] eminent physician," he is returning home in the next week. He asks his friend if he might see him upon his arrival at Worcester. Burne-Jones ends his letter: "I would have sent you a long illustrated letter, if you had behaved like a gentleman to me, but as it is: good bye." In a postscript, he notes "Oh I have fallen in with such cant, but thank heavens I am still alive, aren't [?] you glad - eating sweetmeats till you burst."</p>
               <p>In an additional sheet, Burne-Jones asks Price to visit Faulkner and draws for Price "an illustration to his article." The drawing is titled "Faulkner's Improved Sewerage" and depicts a set of many bottles and instruments connected to an underground pipe. Burne-Jones admits that he was "in a fearful state" about his writing. He tells Price that he has received a letter response from "the greatest man alive" [John Ruskin] and says that since receiving the missive he is "a reformed character, [he is] not Ted anymore" but "E.C.B Jones," the "man who wrote to Ruskin and got an answer by return.". He declares that he can "better draw [his] feelings" and sketches Ruskin as a saint at whose feet a figure -- perhaps Burne-Jones himself -- is prostrate. He also draws a pig, captioned "THE MAN etc. as before". He ends by sending his good wishes to Price's family and enquiring after the "pretty hand" which addressed the envelope of Price's last letter.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_b0c02c4ee1cc4fc26d86e3446fd116f0">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "Land of Caradoc, Banks of the Wye."</p>
            </odd>
            <odd id="aspace_09ebf64301980c7fdf0f0385c51454c7">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>References: Harrison &amp; Waters, page 7; Georgiana Burne-Jones, v. 1, pages 63-64.</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <geogname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh96001599"
                         source="lcsh">
                  Wye, River, Valley (Wales and England)
               </geogname>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300404676" source="aat">
                  Pen and ink drawings
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Faulkner, Charles Joseph, 1833-1892
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79006950"
                         source="naf">
                  Ruskin, John, 1819-1900
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_0b10b16c0f8d00989f0ab44fe0b781e1" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1853 March 5</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_588c3443bdc201af4e9f4c0f72647c30">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter signed ; 23 x37 cm, folded to 23 x 19 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_8da9c537f75b095dffeb2c1b74bced77"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_d35b51964155657a07be78a809b076d6"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_8da9c537f75b095dffeb2c1b74bced77">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_256a296646aa971be70c875679a92c33">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones opens by observing that, "like Mahomet of old", Price "finding the mountain won't come to [him]" has "gone to the mountain" and written to Burne-Jones. He offers Price a "free pardon" for not having done so earlier. Burne-Jones accepts Price's congratulations on the "issue of my 'little go'" but notes his tardiness.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones writes that "your condolence ... on Sewell's leaving is pathetic" noting that it is likely that Sewell will be promoted to rector upon the incumbent's death. This is perhaps a reference to William Sewell, a tutor at Exeter College, Oxford.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones affirms to Price that he has no plans to move and asks him to relay this information to "the Birmingham people through the medium of the press or in any other more convenient way."</p>
               <p>He asks Price to tell "him" (an unidentified man) that his "reproachful language" insulted Burne-Jones deeply and that Burne-Jones "yearns" for him and will write to him soon. He notes that he pities "Miller" and writes that "Latimer [perhaps the minister at St Paul's, Birmingham] has my good word ... it will help him to make a stand against the uncircumcised." Burne-Jones asks Price if he knows why Hook [i.e., Walter Farquhar Hook?] has been elected to Lincoln instead of Jackson and remarks that he could tell Price "a few truths about Hook that would make [him] sing another tune." Burne-Jones disagrees with Price that Sewell and Gresley will be bishops, claiming that having seen "a little more of the world" than Price has been enough to "disenchant a good deal of [his] grander notions." Burne-Jones notes that he and William Fulford, Charles Faulkner and Richard Watson Dixon talk of little besides these ecclesiastical politics.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones ends by confirming that he will see Price in two weeks times and sends his kind remembrances to Price's sister and their old school friends.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_9767ab17ef10bbd1624479d6de1de7ea">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from Oxford. Addressed to Price (on outer leaf) at King Edward's School, Birmingham. With one penny stamp and wax seal.</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Dixon, Richard Watson, 1833-1900
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Faulkner, Charles Joseph, 1833-1892
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Fulford, William, -1897
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Hook, Walter Farquhar, 1798-1875
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Sewell, William, 1804-1874
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_3e6afc00744a2a10572ac1ca9b8dea1f" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1853 May 1</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_e6e5f5a5286c1e4c54fefb58e5e3dbfe">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter signed ; 23 x37 cm, folded to 23 x 19 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_3fe3249b340c02991a8a1e8b4cb9f221"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_9e76576f38741ae8064b31efa7f83382"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_3fe3249b340c02991a8a1e8b4cb9f221">3</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_11cd2b379301a72d81db4183e81a8ce7">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones congratulates Price on his "dutiful and exemplary" conduct, developed "for many years under [Burne-Jones's] auspices." He adds: "it gives me encouragement that the philosophical notions I have inculcated, and wh. have brought such fruits in you, will be equally productive in others." However, so that Price is not "unduly puffed-up," Burne-Jones goes on to jovially criticize Price's "volatile, hurry-scurry, hyper-condensed" writing style.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones comments that he is glad that he and Price share a similar taste in poetry, noting that "if Tennyson affords you as many hours of unmitigated happiness -- I speak without affection here -- as he has to me, you will look with gratitude to any who helped you to appreciate him -- when I take up the works of any other poet, save Shakespeare only, I seem to have fallen from the only guide worth following far to dream-land." He goes on at length to describe the ways in which poets capture unexpressable emotion, referencing Friedrich von Schlegel's term "sighing after the Infinite."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones notes that he has devoted hours to contemplating Tennyson's "Tears, Idle Tears." He answers Price's question about Tennyson's "Locksley Hall," stating that the term "gleams" refers to the curlews in the poem. Burne-Jones recommends the work of the poet Alexander Smith, stating that "his writing is almost incomparable, although his aim is evidently more subjective and metaphysical."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones describes a visit from his uncle. He goes on to give Price an account of their mutual friends. Burne-Jones remarks that he has been amusing himself by pouring basins of water on the crowd below the window. He warns Price that if the Chevalier Count George Jones ever tours Birmingham, he should not go to see him perform on account of his "mangling" of Shakespeare. Burne-Jones tells Price that he is relying on him to join him in founding a "Brotherhood" of which Sir Galahad is to be patron and that he has already enlisted somebody for the order.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_6766de01c2fb93389d933436627dbe3d">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from Oxford. Addressed to Price (on outer leaf) "to be left at Mr. Jones'," 11 Bennetts' Hill, Birmingham. With one penny stamp and wax seal. With cross writing, pages 1-2. Signed: "Yours, old buffer, for ever, Ted, General of the order of Sir Galahad"</p>
            </odd>
            <odd id="aspace_10e25accc2ae5f9cc1d60fe10aa07551">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>References: Harrison &amp; Waters, p. 10; Georgiana Burnes Jones, v.1, p. p. 76-79</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85043932"
                        source="lcsh">
                  English poetry
               </subject>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85052751"
                        source="lcsh">
                  Galahad (Legendary character)
               </subject>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79142936"
                         rules="aacr"
                         source="naf">
                  Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Smith, Alexander, 1830?-1867
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no92006541"
                         rules="aacr"
                         source="naf">
                  Jones, George, 1810-1879
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78095332"
                         source="naf">
                  Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_710bde1be0d9d3208aaca2fbb7e6bf97" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1853 August 5</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_ac39ef24a1c3f1d2fa0c40eb072dca46">1 envelope : autograph envelope ; 7 x 12 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_ba5f64ca5890a4234ed0c0f879e94c02"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_76c3354e8dabc16257bb1fec45ee4ed1"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_ba5f64ca5890a4234ed0c0f879e94c02">4</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c0321d571f60aab808f6efb7224364bf">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Autograph envelope from Edward Burne-Jones, addressed to Cormell Price. *** come back to this *** add letter content ***</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_30ed9d959e43f22e4d6db5be1de09173">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Date from postmark. Addressed, on separate envelope, to "Cormel Price Esqre., R. Price Esqre., Broadway, Worcestershire."</p>
               <p>Without accompanying letter.</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_cc122472cdf6248157dac0c04631502c" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1853 October 29</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_a531b519bdb3b6b1d405e8ce5ccfd7b3">2 folded sheets (8 pages) : autograph letter signed ; each sheet 23 x 37 cm, folded to 23 x 19 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_2d2252b7cd28575d741feefe6da1afb4"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_3ea243bd7f3cbf334d146c9d654cdbcc"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_2d2252b7cd28575d741feefe6da1afb4">5</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ad6b9a85a39e980c74a89d66f61d8e64">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones expresses his delight upon receiving Price's last letter. He regrets that he cannot respond to Price's latest request on account of being very busy. He also remarks that the subject proposed by Price is "really beyond me." It seems that Price's request is related to a specific poet (perhaps Tennyson, who is discussed at length in the previous letter), for Burne-Jones writes that: "I have not found a day without reading or hearing his work - it is unfair I know to other poets, for he is not a compendium of all that is beautiful, but I take a pleasure in forgetting others, and concentrating myself, for a while, on him alone."</p>
               <p>He congratulates Price upon his ideas, saying that they are "very laudable and worthy of all success." Burne-Jones says he has been reading Edgar Allan Poe's "book of horrors," remarking that although the appeal of his work is shortlived, for the moment, Poe is "lord of the ascendant." He reccommends a number of Poe's stories to Price.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones asks if Price has read Archdeacon Robert Wilberforce's "Holy Eucharist", describing the book as "the most controversial &amp; truly theological work that has come out for ages."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones theorizes on public opinion, claiming that "the multitude is moved by passion &amp; feeling and not reason, therefore you must impel them by Rhetoric before you can convince them by logic" and advises Price that "it can't do [Price] any harm to take every possible occasion to perfect [himself] in the noble art of Dialectic." Burne-Jones states that all men argue logically by nature and that the study of Logic is simply "the science of the processes of thought." He tells Price that in the present moment they must "think highly of [their] species, to dream of development, and the Divinity of mind" and states that man "born in free will" is "more independent than angels, for they cannot see by reason, knowing all things by intuition."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_fe00f6d7c22407dddd5db055d245d64a">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "Greater Coll." Addressed to Price (on outer leaf) at Classical Department, King Edward's School, Birmingham. With one penny stamp and wax seal.</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85113628"
                        source="lcsh">
                  Rhetoric
               </subject>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79142936"
                         rules="aacr"
                         source="naf">
                  Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79029745"
                         source="naf">
                  Poe, Edgar Allan, 1809-1849
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Wilberforce, Robert Isaac, 1802-1857
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_c11590d700f1c38bee60e3444736982f" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1853 November 8</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_31bf6af81dc157fb8d11b2c212d1b29c">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter signed ; 23 x37 cm, folded to 23 x 19 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_371eaa2fdbd8475db3526d579f838f28"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_34bbe2c32bf03d3f0142e68854bf8e3d"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_371eaa2fdbd8475db3526d579f838f28">6</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_dcbb70e2dbb6c6c91139b2ea3e3f7c2e">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones tells Price that he must write a letter to "Harry" (Henry Macdonald), but, not knowing Harry's address, must send it via Price.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones commiserates with Price regarding "the suppression of the Press" which Burne-Jones declares an "act of high-treason against the Great Republic of Literature," "Inquisatorial in a land that acknowledges no Inquisition" and "tyranny." He quotes Tennyson, assuring Price that "the tyrant's cruel glee forces on the freer hour."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones goes on to describe ecclesiastical rows regarding a position at Exeter College or Oxford University, which possibly revolves around the Oxford Movement. (Burne-Jones writes that: "Hook by the by is to be Bishop of Oxford" which could be a reference to Walter Hook. Hook was educated at Oxford but never became bishop of the city.)</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones concludes by describing a "profound &amp; exhaustive" sermon by Edward Bouverie Pusey.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_ed1cb72bc5e65fef1e7d0a1f498c846b">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "Exeter Coll." Addressed to Price (on outer leaf) at "8. Sun St. West, Birmingham." With one penny stamp and wax seal.</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85051711"
                        source="lcsh">
                  Freedom of the press
               </subject>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Macdonald, Henry James, 1835-1891
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Hook, Walter Farquhar, 1798-1875
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_5a67efd2d07bdfb86ad5c718eb99eab3" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1854 February 28</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_e99d3cb919855ad2456fd7a8e16431fb">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter signed ; 23 x 37 cm, folded to 23 x 19 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_07f5c9b91ddb357a87db8ef1aa6d5446"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_57bbcd09a8508c8a61e723c77a18766b"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_07f5c9b91ddb357a87db8ef1aa6d5446">7</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_fc7eb824fa13e3af9ddddaf8386696ab">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones responds to Price's questions about scholarships, noting that the competition for Oxford scholarships "depend entirely upon the men who present themselves for candidacy" and that the University's reputation for "stiffness" deters individuals from applying and so "competition has been less." He tells Price that the scholarships for Queen's College are generous but that the college has changed from "old times." He notes Magdalen College's demyship scholarship form and states that he believes recipients often become full Fellows.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones gives his friend advice on studying "Oxford Latin," remarking that the "accuracy of translator ... to render the meaning of a passage as plainly" as possible is paramount. He states that "Tacitus [?] is better than Cicero" and that participles are "supposed to be connecting links between sentences etc -- not meaningless nonsense for  filling up, to be translated at random by 'forsooth', 'but', 'indeed' etc."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_56bb2c7832a7c53562763b2c8786a8cc">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "Exeter Coll." Addressed to Price (on outer leaf) at "Classical Department, King Edward's School, Birmingham." With one penny stamp and wax seal.</p>
            </odd>
            <odd id="aspace_c58f7268d96d90f6ba91e133df696af3">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>References: Georgiana Burne-Jones, v. 1, p. 98</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85074956"
                        source="lcsh">
                  Latin language -- Study and teaching
               </subject>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79095521"
                         source="naf">
                  University of Oxford
               </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_2491e3f95a182709e09be936843958b3" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1854 March 9</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_de2612d1a1659f8185f5242189e4f1b9">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter signed ; 23 x 37 cm, folded to 23 x 19 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_903df715f24392d0427abdcc7f8d2bd7"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_e4c42355704998b20c9ff4c229c8d9a8"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_903df715f24392d0427abdcc7f8d2bd7">8</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_3d5fcbf1c4e5a4596099bc5dbc76f0c1">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones apologizes for being "forgetful" of Price and admits that he "cannot plead hard work altogether for my cause, so many nameless trifles occur all day long to break the best resolutions." He tells Price that he has heard that he is studying hard and wishes him success in his endeavors. He encourages Price to apply for an Oxford scholarship, noting that even in failure "the practice is very good and often encouraging." He says that this term has been his happiest yet and he has been filling his time with many good things. He admits that he has "fallen back upon my drawings and intend[s] cultivating it to some extent."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones states that William Morris has taken up a lot of his time, describing him as "one of the cleverest fellows" he knows and "far more congenial in all his thoughts and likings, than anyone it has been [his] good fortune to meet with." He believes that Morris's art criticism is better than William Fulford's, who was Burne-Jones's "old ideal in such subjects." He proclaims that Morris is "full of enthusiasm for things holy and beautiful and true" and possesses "the most exquisite perception and judgement" which has "tinged [Burne-Jones's] whole inner being with the beauty of [Morris's] own." He remarks that "if it were not for his boisterous mad outbursts and freaks which break the romance [Morris] sheds [?] around him -- at least to me -- he would be a perfect hero."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones asks Price to spend time with him at Easter. He says of Price's writing piece (presumably sent in correspondence from Price) that, unless it is for a joke, it is unlikely to be profitable. He asks him why he has written blank verse, remarking that the style "is a strange fashion of young poetlings of this generation; on the principle I suppose of the age generally 'as much as you can at the cheapest rate'." He also questions Price's "horticultural facts" and critiques his long preamble to the piece. He recommends that Price translates metrically from Greek lyrics, beginning with either Theocritus or the "chorus of the Dramatists."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_7fcac424e9d6197c7190044f374697a6">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Date from postmark. The letter is dated by Burne-Jones: "March (?) 1854." Addressed from "Exeter Coll." Addressed to Price (on outer leaf) at "Classical Department, King Edward's School, Birmingham." With one penny stamp and wax seal. With cross writing on pages 2 -3.</p>
            </odd>
            <odd id="aspace_985663bacd2a724c5e7aca05b7d4b34c">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>References: Georgiana Burne-Jones, v. 1, p. 95</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85103704"
                        source="lcsh">
                  Poetry
               </subject>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79095521"
                         source="naf">
                  University of Oxford
               </corpname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78095326"
                         source="naf">
                  Morris, William, 1834-1896
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Fulford, William, -1897
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_6e0e9237e63053a9edf2dad2aad16bec" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1854 October 16</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_8d2b1c95291c4358300258d99b769d9b">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter signed ; 25 x 40 cm, folded to 25 x 20 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_a72f1ffc7d1425e62fb9518b721320d0"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_bc4707729bbf0aea0bf28f1073d735a3"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_a72f1ffc7d1425e62fb9518b721320d0">9</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ed8d16688ba24132c1492f8371de15dc">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones says he would have written to Price earlier had he not had "too much friendship to pour my sorrows into your ear." He states that Price's last letter came at a time when he was "suffering greater mental troubles than [he] ever remember[s]."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones complains about the postponement of the start of the university term, remarking that he "longed to be back with [William] Morris and his glorious little company of martyrs." Burne-Jones describes a recent evening party he attended and remarks upon the host's impropriety of offering a rose to "Fanny," noting "there is a language of flowers I hear, and you had better make it out, and see what he means."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones tells Price about the time he has spent with his father and an upcoming visit from friends to their family home. Burne-Jones asks Price to let him know the details of his journey so that he can get settled into his room before Price's arrival.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_60eb973cae5a96fede96346be6ba0560">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "Bristol Road." Addressed to Price (on outer leaf) at "R. Price [illegible], Broadway, Gloucestershire." With one penny stamp and wax seal.</p>
            </odd>
            <odd id="aspace_f886d1abb98190baa18e8be57428dd7e">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Georgiana Burne-Jones, v. 1, p.p. 102-103</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85049319"
                        source="lcsh">
                  Flower language
               </subject>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78095326"
                         source="naf">
                  Morris, William, 1834-1896
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_a95fac7e04c7187b6b69a5f0c384ca41" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1856 January 9</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_e5914f6d05c6d3cd63a359d1bb8366f7">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter ; 19 x 23 cm, folded to 19 x 12 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_68a9a132d31868399cf70e8939e8e4b2"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_7f52238d2c07169274e09515ed120500"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_68a9a132d31868399cf70e8939e8e4b2">10</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_1d80337081bfc70bed8fa801d533f0a4">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones asks why Price has not yet sent the "MS," presumably a piece for The Oxford and Cambridge Magazine. He tells him that Burne-Jones's aunt has been Price's "champion all along," transcribing a humorous conversation he had with her at breakfast the previous day, in which Burne-Jones describes Price as a "reprobate" and "a dissolute little creature" while "Auntie" defends him as a "dear little fellow." Burne-Jones says he does not want to hurry Price over the magazine but that they should "make a work of it, and not a mere pastime." Burne-Jones instructs Price to send his piece to him.</p>
               <p>He laments a previous issue's article on Charles Kingsley, saying that although the group plans to amend the piece in future copies of the article, it has "already done us a great deal of harm, especially in the Universities." He notes that Harry MacDonald has sent a "very severe letter" to Wilfred Heeley about the matter.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones states that William Morris (referred to here as "Topsy") has passed on editorship powers to William Fulford, remarking that the move "will be a good thing for all of us, and a great relief to Topsy." He describes a dinner he had with Morris and MacDonald at Brompton which he says was "like old times." Burne-Jones gleefully comments that he will "get an awful showing up in the Guardian ... for that wretched affair on Kingsley." He ends by telling Price about an upcoming boxing match (?), which he says will be followed by a "general challenge to Universal Pigdom, for the championship -- odds, Ten to one, on the side of Truth and, O.C.M."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_f3b31ad1cc5496f697b88f118f6edeb7">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "Camberwell."</p>
            </odd>
            <odd id="aspace_eb505be8b6871234304ea38d04dba6bb">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>References: Georgiana Burnes-Jones, v. 1, p. 127</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <title source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Oxford and Cambridge magazine
               </title>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Fulford, William, -1897
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Heeley, Wilfred, 1833-1876
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79062749"
                         source="naf">
                  Kingsley, Charles, 1819-1875
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Macdonald, Henry James, 1835-1891
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78095326"
                         source="naf">
                  Morris, William, 1834-1896
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_56d55eaca9eaa495972207f46d1526d1" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1856 May 18</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_ca5187beacbe3c7f29ba8a729dfd81a5">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter, signed ; 21 x 27 cm, folded to 21 x 14 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_4f5009684f68d52f5d1c9ceae1c03a65"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_629acb884a08b4105b1269fb713c0a0e"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_4f5009684f68d52f5d1c9ceae1c03a65">11</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6e82d637040efac7554f3b26aa2f9c3d">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones begins the letter with the following declaration: "Mr Jones begs respectfully to inform the public that he executes pictures of the most chaste and unique description upon the most reasonable terms." He then lists prices for a variety of types of drawings, including "love scenes, executed in bold style, indian ink" (5 shillings) and "full length caricature" (2 shillings and sixpence). He goes on to announce that he is "desirous of forming classes for the reading of Ruskin." Burne-Jones says that if Price were in London, he would see the streets "placarded" with such announcements before he gives up the joke, commenting "no you wouldn't, what lies I tell."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones says he is "desolate" because William Fulford has "gone to Hill's" for a few days. He says that he has taken a 12-mile walk in the rain and plans to "write letters and be miserable" for the rest of the day or "go and join the mob in Hyde Park." He asks Price to write to him often and to encourage Charlie Faulkner and "Dickides" (Richard Watson Dixon?) to do the same.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones says he has received a note from "Topsy" (William Morris) recommending that he see Arthur Hughes's <title>
                     April Love.
                  </title> Burne-Jones says he plans to visit the Royal Academy the following morning to see it. He asks Price to give Morris his love. Burne-Jones offers his love to "all the set" and sketches a heart surrounded by their names (Willie, Harry, Dickides, Hatch, Charlie, Puckle, Oakley and Guest) so that Price "forget[s]none." Sketch measures 5 x7 cm.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_6d5041bf6c86d77738df4901d0f25228">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "13 Sloane Terrace, Sloane St, Chelsea." In the top left hand corner of the letter, Burne-Jones has sketched a hand with its index finger pointing right, towards his Sloane Terrace address. Sketch measures 2 x 5 cm.</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Dixon, Richard Watson, 1833-1900
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Faulkner, Charles Joseph, 1833-1892
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Fulford, William, -1897
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50033179"
                         source="naf">
                  Hughes, Arthur, 1832-1915
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78095326"
                         source="naf">
                  Morris, William, 1834-1896
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79006950"
                         source="naf">
                  Ruskin, John, 1819-1900
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_4c8d92969ae4d0a78e131c1b582e8b6a" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1856 May 30</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_740ba31f2a0929e56e6d5b8392380aef">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter, signed ; 25 x 40 cm, folded to 25 x 20 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_3116431ab8ae786cddd486078fa3068f"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_2792cefdad9d6ccc92c7bc851fda566d"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_3116431ab8ae786cddd486078fa3068f">12</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_3b0272b62367b5222f80fb4c3023384c">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones says that he owes Price more apologies than he has time to write at present. He tells Price he has taken rooms at Old House, Ship Street in Oxford and asks that Price tells him which train he will take to Oxford so that Burne-Jones can meet him.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones goes on to give Price details about gaining entry to New College, remarking that on Sunday morning it is hosting a private party and admission will not be possible. He recommends that Price asks the sub-warden -- rather than the chaplain or one of the Fellows -- for tickets if his party is more than two.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones asks his friend not to think him too unkind for responding to two letters from Price with such a short reply. He asks Price what he means by "Cupids less [?] -- a secret, eh? -- we must get it out of you." He ends by asking Price to remember him kindly to his sisters and assuring Price that he thinks he stands "a very good chance."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_e89891e0ee28943dda492ca7ffdd8112">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "Exeter Coll." Addressed to Price (on outer leaf) at "8 Sun St. West, Birmingham." With one penny stamp and wax seal.</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79095521"
                         source="naf">
                  University of Oxford
               </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_100619b1e38f46b19670da407fd53e83" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1856 June 15</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_e208aa8a6870beeadc0ddb2b8f11dfc4">1 folded sheet (3 pages) : autograph letter, signed ; 23 x 37 cm, folded to 23 x 19 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_e7f34fc2fce716fd82f8de70e89afe66"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_08e20a0b816c6dffe7dfe84c397ec37d"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_e7f34fc2fce716fd82f8de70e89afe66">13</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a8548455eb067e836d43ce28b82501a8">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones sends his best wishes for Price's recovery from a bout of illness, remarking that he "daren't tell Auntie about it, or she'd be hurrying off to nurse [Price]." He asks if Price could stay in Birmingham for the first three days of the following week as Burne-Jones will be visiting his father and would like to see Price, commenting that "it seems generations past since [they] had one of those dear evenings."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones says that he is happier than he has ever been which he follows with the observation that "Art does seem so precious to one, so inexpressibly lovely." He says he is much less lonely now that William Fulford has returned, saying that few people ever visit his rooms, noting that "Fred" only comes in for breakfast from time to time and that "Harry" Macdonald "prefers the company of ladies, so [Burne-Jones] seldom see[s] him." Burne-Jones says he does not enjoy dinner, as he has to walk to a "chop-house, which smells of never-ending ever-wasting joints" and where other customers "monopolise the papers."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_751d95ce05565928faf0d850a1a49334">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "13 Sloane Terrace."</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Fulford, William, -1897
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Macdonald, Henry James, 1835-1891
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_f5ea08a85b60f2effa8e5da12a5d19c9" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1861 June 28</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_45dbe4509d9e1531c8e63f6a0d363c23">2 folded sheets (8 pages) : autograph letter, signed ; both sheets 21 x 27 cm, folded to 21 x 14 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_d3cdd70d8e902b2aca232c378ebaf90a"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_2bfbdb8ef1aae9f7e3f1d1fd02c0f70b"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_d3cdd70d8e902b2aca232c378ebaf90a">14</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c0b007d9a366c5ce10feb0666286f020">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones says he has been a "villain" in his lack of correspondence with Price and says that the rest of the day will be given over to writing him letters, remarking that although the letter will only take half an hour to write, "the exertion will completely do for [him]." He asks if Price is "lonely out there" and says he has encouraged William Morris to write to him and will try to get "everyone" to do the same. He says they will all be so glad when Price comes back.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones has been doing "heaps of work" but admits that when the summer days get hot, he will not work as much. He tells Price that Charles Faulkner will be moving from Oxford to London this month. He says that "there has been such a fire here in London" [referring to the Tooley Street Fire], stating that one could see it from thirty miles away.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones asks Price if he has heard of the "Co." (Morris, Marshall, Faulkner &amp; Co.), stating it has been founded by himself, "Topsy" (William Morris), Marshall, Brown, Webb and Rossetti. He tells Price that they produce "stained glass, furniture, jewelry, decorations and pictures," noting that they have many commissions already.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones describes the ordeal of a friend (probably Elizabeth Siddal) whose baby was stillborn, commenting that the mother is physically better but mourns for her child. Burne-Jones gives an account of his and Price's mutual friends, remarking that Ford Madox Brown is "fat and cheery" and that he sees Richard Watson Dixon about once a year. Burne-Jones does not approve of Dixon's marriage to Maria Sturgeon, the widow of William Thomson of Haddingtonshire, describing Sturgeon as "an old dry coquettish hag."</p>
               <p>On page four, Burne-Jones admits that the first three pages of the letter were written three months ago. He asks Price to forgive him his silence and says he had a dream where Price would not speak to him because he had not written in so long. He says that not much has happened in the intervening period but that he has run in to trouble in the wake of Thomas Edward Plint's death, as Burne-Jones owed him £550. He comments that Elizabeth Barrett Browning has died, describing her as "the cleverest woman alive." Burne-Jones says that there have more murders and fires in London, putting the spate down to "that bloody comet," a reference to the Great Comet of 1861. Burne-Jones tells Price that he and his wife (Georgiana MacDonald) are expecting a baby but pleads with Price not to tell anyone "for fear it should be a monster." He gives further account of there mutual friends, telling Price that Charlie Faulkner has moved to London to work as a civil engineer, that Rossetti has "done a most wonderful picture," that Alice Prinsep is to "marry a rich cove" and that Val Prinsep has returned from Italy, "leaving many broken hearts."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones gives Price his new address in Great Russell Street, commenting that his studio there is much better than his last. Burne-Jones apologizes profusely for not writing and sends love to Price from both himself and Georgiana. He talks of his plans to take her to Italy, if the baby is well enough to be left. He says he will not be able to get home to Birmingham until Christmas. Burne-Jones talks of his desire to move his father closer to London as he is growing old. He reflects upon fatherhood, writing "it's very dull to be a dad, and having a son cuttting about &amp; enjoying himself ... I shall hate it when I'm a dad."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_5ae47dc20eb641b532b19e369c960530">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>References: Georgiana Burne-Jones, v. 1, p. 227, 229</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Faulkner, Charles Joseph, 1833-1892
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81050328"
                         source="naf">
                  Brown, Ford Madox, 1821-1893
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n86091920"
                         rules="aacr"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Georgiana, Lady, 1840-1920
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Dixon, Richard Watson, 1833-1900
               </persname>
               <corpname source="local">
                  Morris, Marshall, Faulkner &amp; Company
               </corpname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78095326"
                         source="naf">
                  Morris, William, 1834-1896
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79117985"
                         rules="aacr"
                         source="naf">
                  Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81121170"
                         source="naf">
                  Siddall, Elizabeth
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_ed73207a256147ccd8323554a37377f4" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1862 February 23</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_9564f9f67f0d140e52751e80a5ec6798">1 folded sheet (4 pages) : autograph letter, signed ; 21 x 27 cm, folded to 21 x 14 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_ccc8c6be66780ffcb9f9d763c66816ba"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_9cb9ab35714cf77c3462816103ad03b3"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_ccc8c6be66780ffcb9f9d763c66816ba">15</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6c2d8201bb5b7843b02097b1fd61c75f">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Burne-Jones thanks Price for his last letter, commenting that it has been passed around and shared with "all who want [Price] back." He pleads with Price to move back to Britain, offering Price a room in his home until he can find something permanent. He tells Price his family are spending three months in Venice from May and that Price could have their home in London to himself.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones tells Price that Elizabeth Siddall has died and that Rossetti is "smashed for the time." He says it is his aunt's birthday and that she is grateful for Price's letter. Burne-Jones reports that his wife and son are well, describing his son as "the fattest boy ... known to Art or nature." He proceeds with a lengthy describe of his son, of whom his parents are "very proud." He tells Price that Jane Burden Morris, wife of William Morris, is expecting twins.</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones says that George Price Boyce is in Cairo and that Hughes (Arthur?) had become father to twins, when last Burne-Jones heard from him. He also describes their friends "Dickides" (Richard Watson Dixon?), Val Prinsep, Ford Madox Brown, William Fulford and Charles Faulkner. Burne-Jones pleads again with Price to come back to live near them all, and describes the excellent location of their house in London to encourage Price to reside there. He describes the seduction techniques employed by their friend William Fulford, who "develop[s] [women] into adoration of him and leaves them to pine."</p>
               <p>Burne-Jones ends by encouraging Price to come back and giving Price Burne- Jones's infant son's "fat little dumpy slobbery love."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_cbd4d465500e8fe12516a9f8811ad407">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>Addressed from "62 Great Russell St."</p>
            </odd>
            <odd id="aspace_91fc4dd2d40fff26e400d73074ef1ceb">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>References: Georgiana Burne-Jones, v. 1, p. 259</p>
            </odd>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81050328"
                         source="naf">
                  Brown, Ford Madox, 1821-1893
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Dixon, Richard Watson, 1833-1900
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Faulkner, Charles Joseph, 1833-1892
               </persname>
               <persname rules="rda" source="local_ycba_rbm">
                  Fulford, William, -1897
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79117985"
                         rules="aacr"
                         source="naf">
                  Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882
               </persname>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81121170"
                         source="naf">
                  Siddall, Elizabeth
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
         <c id="aspace_48563eabad48da7809d2e090f0d2c270" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Edward Burne-Jones letter to Cormell Price</unittitle>
               <origination label="creator">
                  <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                            source="naf">
                     Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898
                  </persname>
               </origination>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1862 June 3</unitdate>
               <physdesc id="aspace_3877ea1654596ee289f86514ecc0b598">1 sheet (1 page) : autograph letter, signed ; 21 x 13 cm</physdesc>
               <container id="aspace_41aa20916efefcb64336bf779b023f7c"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
               <container id="aspace_096ba686a8ccfc279fba647761e621fd"
                          type="folder"
                          parent="aspace_41aa20916efefcb64336bf779b023f7c">16</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_f760815184f8002afb1f200f22bda446">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>"Dearest Crom, I won't write at length; you may never get this -- we shall be in Venice I hope in a week to stop there for nearly a month, direct poste restante. I do do hope we shall meet this year. Love from Georgie. Most affectionately yours, Ned."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <arrangement id="aspace_fdd95f511638768fd963254f246b4da9">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>Addressed from "Milan."</p>
            </arrangement>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
                  Correspondence 
               </genreform>
               <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79120945"
                         source="naf">
                  Burne-Jones, Edward Coley, 1833-1898 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
               <persname source="local">
                  Price, Cormell, approximately 1836-1910 -- Correspondence 
               </persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
