<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="ccsu_schema.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-ctnbt" url="https://library.ccsu.edu/cpaaead/cpaa0805.xml">cpaa0805</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Andrew J. Beck papers
                    <num>CPAA.08.05</num>
                </titleproper>
                <subtitle>Finding Aid</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Finding aid prepared by Renata Vickrey</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Connecticut Polish American Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1615 Stanley Street </addressline>
                    <addressline>New Britain, CT, 06050</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2008</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-12-09T13:07-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546" scriptcode="latn">English</language></langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>2011</date>
                <item>Material added to collection after Andrzej Beck's death.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Andrew J. Beck Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>CPAA.08.05</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Connecticut Polish American Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1926-2011</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">Andrew J. Beck, an engineering executive, worked in several American engineering companies where he was responsible for the Eastern European trade during the Cold War years. Andrzej Beck was born in Poland and was 13 years old when WWII began. He left the country with his mother, Maria Slominska, at the end of September 1939 escaping the Germans and Russians. He is the only son of Jozef Beck, the Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs before the World War II. The collection consists of memoirs written by Andrzej Beck for his family, and a DVD of a TVN Polish television production about Jozef Beck. A CD includes interviews with Andrzej Beck and people who were close to his father, Mr. Jozef Beck, during WWII. Andrzej Beck passed away on July 20, 2011 in Fairfield, CT.</abstract>
            <physdesc id="ref1" label="General Physical Description note">
                <extent encodinganalog="300$a">(0.25 linear ft.)</extent></physdesc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Beck, Andrew Jozef, 1926-2011</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Andrew J. Beck, son of Maria (Slominska) and Jozef Beck, the Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs from 1932 till the outbreak of WWII. Andrew Beck was born on September 11, 1926 in Warsaw, Poland. He left Poland in the Fall of 1939 when the WWII broke out and through Romania, Italy, France and Portugal for the United States in 1940. He received his engineering degree from Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ. He worked in several engineering companies in the US till 1983 when he established his own company Eastport Trading Co. in Cheshire, CT. Mr. Beck served with the Polish Armed Forces in the West from 1944 till 1946. He married Ewa Jedrzejewicz, daughter of Mr. Waclaw Jedrzejewicz, who was the Minister of Education before WWII in Poland. Mr. Jedrzejewicz later established the Pilsudski Institute in New York City. Mr. Andrew Beck was active in several Polish American organizations: Polish American Congress, the Pilsudski Institute in New York, and the Studium - North American Study Center for Political Affairs. Mr. Beck retired from his professional position in 2004. He moved to Fairfiled, CT and still stayed active in Polish American organizations untill his death on July 20, 2011.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
            <p>The collection consists of memoirs written by Andrew Beck for his family and friends. It covers years in pre war Poland till 2008. Collection also consists of a CD with the Polish television program about Jozef Beck, the Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs before the WW II. The television program includes archival footage and interviews with various people who knew Minister Jozef Beck personally. The collection also includes biographical information about Waclaw Jedrzejewicz, a father-in-law of Andrew Beck.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Cite as</emph>: Andrew J. Beck Papers (CPAA 08-05). Connecticut Polish American Archives, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Mr. Andrew J. Beck in May 2008. Andrew Beck passed away on July 25, 2011 and his library and additional visual materials were donated to CPAA by his daughter in September 2011.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Processed by Renata Vickrey.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest">Beck, Jozef, 1894-1944</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Businesspeople - Connecticut - Biography .</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Diplomats - Poland - Biography</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Engineers - United States - Biography.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Interview.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Memoirs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Poland - Foreign relations - 1918-1945</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Polish Americans - Connecticut - Biography.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Story of an interesting life. Memoirs. (Consists of 85 pages, including illustartions).</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid126002" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid126002" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>2007</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Beck, Andrew Jozef, 1926-2011</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Beck, Ewa, 1932-2002</persname>
                </controlaccess>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>"O moim ojcu" (About my father),the Polish Television program about Jozef Beck (DVD)</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="pol"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <container id="cid126004" type="Box" label="Moving Images">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid126004" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>2008</unitdate>
                    <materialspec id="ref11" label="Material Specific Details note">The TV program is recorded on CD and is copyrighted by the Polish Television Programing.</materialspec>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Waclaw Jedrzejewicz - 3 VHS tapes with material related to his life and activities, copied from various TV programs.</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="pol"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <container id="cid129001" type="Box" label="Moving Images">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid129001" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1993</unitdate>
                </did>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jedrzejewicz, Waclaw, 1893-1993</persname>
                </controlaccess>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
