<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="ccsu_schema.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso0907" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-ctnbt" url="https://library.ccsu.edu/cpaaead/cpaa0907.xml ">cpaa0907</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Alvin E. O'Konski papers related to The Katyn Forest Massacre
                    <num>CPAA 09.07</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Special Collections staff.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Connecticut Polish American Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1615 Stanley Street </addressline>
                    <addressline>New Britain, CT, 06050</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-08-21T11:03-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Alvin E. O'Konski papers related to The Katyn Forest Massacre</unittitle>
            <unitid>CPAA 09.07</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Connecticut Polish American Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>4.0 folders</extent>
                <extent>Folders are located in the file cabinet.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1946, 1952</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref12" label="Abstract">Alvin O'Konski was a Polish American Congressman from Wisconsin, whose political career spanned several decades. O'Konski, a Republican, was known for his anti-communist activities, and was a member of the US Congressional Committee and participated in the Katyn Massacre hearing in Frankfurt, Germany. This collections contains material related to the Katyn massacre hearings and reports.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">O'Konski, Alvin E.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <custodhist id="ref2">
            <head>Custodial History note</head>
            <p>The material was donated to CPAA together with the National Polish Center (formerly American Center for Polish Culture) archives in 2009. Materials related to Alvin O'Konski and his activities within the US Congressional Commission investigating the Katyn Forest massacre, were separated and this collection was created.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Alvin E. O'Konski, Republican congressman from Wisconsin, was born May 26, 1904, was educated in public schools in Wisconsin. He worked as a teacher for several years and in 1942 his political career has began. He was elected representative of Wisconsin's Tenth District and served in Congress until defeated in November 1972. Congressman O'Konski's political views were generally conservative. He is best known for his anti-communist activities. He was president of the World Bill of Rights Association, 1945; director of the World League to Stop Communism, 1947; and president of the Anti-Communist Association, 1950. He was voted the “most distinguished American for 1945” in balloting conducted by the Polish language newspaper Everybody's Daily for his work on behalf of small nations against communism and the Yalta agreement. Particularly interested in Poland and Polish issues, he received the “Polonia Restitvta” medal as the outstanding member of a committee investigating the Katyn Forest Massacre of 15,000 Allied officers in early World War II. Mr. O'Konski served on several congressional committees including Labor, Pensions, Veterans Affairs, and Armed Services. His papers are housed in the Wisconsin Historical Society.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>Cite as: Alvin E. O'Konski papers related to The Katyn Forest Massacre (CPAA 09-07). Connecticut Polish American Archives, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>For more information on Alvin E. O'Konski political activities go to Wisconsin Historical Society http://nglvc.org/wisconsin-historical-society-history-center-and-archives</p>
            <p></p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref11">
            <head>Separated Materials note</head>
            <p>Material separated: "Press clippings and news pictures of hearings in Frankfurt conducted by the Select Committee to Investigate the Katyn Massacres", Publisher Frankfurt am Main : Information Branch, Public Affairs Section, American Consulate General Frankfurt Am Main, [1952] Burritt Library, Special Collections, Call # 940.54056 P64</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref13">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection contains reports, press clippings and photographs related to the US Congressional Committee holding hearings on the Katyn Forest Massacre in Frankfurt, Germany in 1952.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh"> Katyn Massacre, Katyn, Russia, 1940</subject>
            <subject source="local">Madden Committee</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>The mass murder of Polish prisoners of war in Katyn, a short report with maps and copies of photographs.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid218001" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate>March 1946</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref6" level="item">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Press conference of select committee to conduct an investigation of the facts, evidence, and circumstances of the Katyn Forest Massacre, Frankfurt/Main, Germany</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid218002" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <unitdate>April 26, 1952</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref7" level="item">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Press releases, clippings, articles related to Katyn Forest Massacre.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid218003" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1952</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref8" level="item">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photographs: Madden commission, formal portrait, social events.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid218004" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <unitdate>ca.1952</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref9" level="item">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photo album of White Eagle Polish Club, London, England. Visit of the Congressional Katyn Commission.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid218005" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <unitdate>1952</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
