<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="ccsu_schema.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-ctnbt" url="https://library.ccsu.edu/cpaaead/cpaa8606.xml">cpaa8606</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Maciora and Mik Family Collection
                    <num>CPAA 86.06</num>
                </titleproper>
                <subtitle>1904-1987</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jordan Sorensen</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Connecticut Polish American Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1615 Stanley Street </addressline>
                    <addressline>New Britain, CT, 06050</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-15T10:37-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Maciora and Mik Family Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>CPAA 86.06</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Connecticut Polish American Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>6 Folders in Filing Cabinet.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1904/1987" type="inclusive">1904-1987</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The collection of Joseph G. V. Maciora, alumni of CCSU, consists of genealogical work done by Mr. Maciora about both sides of his family (Mik and Maciora). Most of the documents are written by Mr. Maciora either from memory or oral histories of his parents, Mary Agnes (Mik) Maciora and Joseph George Maciora. There are some correspondence, prayer cards, and church programs. It also includes some general information on Poland and Polish Americans in Meriden and New Britain, CT.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref4" label="Language of Materials note">English and some Polish.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="local" source="local">Maciora, Joseph</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Joseph G.V. Maciora was born on June 18, 1959 in New London, CT. He was raised in Chesire, CT and Smithtown, Long Island, NY to then settle in Pittsfield, MA. He received a Bachelors of Arts degree in History and American Studies from Central Connecticut State University in 1982. In the 1970’s and 80’s, he recorded genealogies of both sides of his family and left the collection to CCSU in 1986. His parents were Maria (Mary) Agnes (Mik) Maciora (1921-) and Joseph George Maciora (August 18, 1921- July 18, 1998). They were married in 1946 at St. Stanislaus Church in Meridan, Connecticut. Joseph George Maciora was in the U.S. Air Force during WWII, but only served from United States’ locations. Mary Maciora was a graduate of Laurel Business College in Meridan, CT as of 1940 and worked as a secretary at the Personal Finance Corporation. George graduated from Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, NY in 1948. He worked in several states and ended up at General Electric Co. in Pittsfield, MA in 1974. He retired in 1985. Mary, as of 1987, worked for the State of Massachusetts Department of Social Services. Joseph George and Mary had two children, Mary Gerarda and, the donor, Joseph Gerard Vincent. The parents of Maria A. Mik were Helen E. (Bykowski) Mik (1887-1957) and Ignatius Mik (1887-1956). Helen’s parents were Anna Cierpial(1865-1893) and Jozef Bykowski(1849-1916). Ignatuis’ parents were Theresa Medrygał (1863-1936) and Jan Mik (1854-1922). Helen left the village of Różanka, district of Strżyzów, and present day province of Rzeszów, Poland (under Austrian rule) to come to the United States in 1905 while Ignatius, from Wiśniowa, Ropczyce, Rzeszów, Poland, arrived in 1906. They married in 1907 at St. Stanislaus Church in Meridan, CT and had ten children. They resided in Meridan until their deaths. The parents of Joseph George Maciora were Victoria (Zysk) Maciora (1885-1940) and Felix Maciora (1878-1952). Vistoria’s parents were Jozef and Maria (Biegaj) Zysk. Felix’s parents were Zuzanna (Lenkiewiz)(d.1904) and Josef (1836-1915) Maciora. Victoria was from Bandysie, Myszyniec, Ostrołeka, Poland, under Russian rule, and came to the U.S. in 1902 to reside in New Britain, CT. Felix was from Charubin, Turośl, Łomża, Poland also under Russian rule, and came to the U.S. in 1899 to flee the Russian army. He also resided in New Britain and was a farmer and locker maker. They married at Sacred Heart of Jesus R. C. Church in 1904 and had five children. After Victoria died in 1940, Felix remarried in 1942 to Rose Kobus Murzyn Borkowski, a widow. Felix was also the uncle of Lucien J. Maciora who served in the Connecticut House of Representatives from 1932 to 1937. The collection records the aunts, uncles, cousins and their spouses, of family members listed here also.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Collection contains correspondence in Polish with brief English summary, photographs, and written genealogies. It includes material on the Mik family as well. It covers the years from 1904 to 1987 when the material was donated. The material was donated by Joseph G. V. Maciora from Boston, MA.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>Maciora and Mik Family Collection (CPAA 86-06). Connecticut Polish American Archives, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <genreform source="lcsh">Oral History</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Poland -- Emigration and immigration  </subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Polish Americans -- Connecticut -- Genealogy</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Polish Americans -- Connecticut -- Meriden</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Polish Americans -- Connecticut -- New Britain</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Sacred Heart of Jesus Church (New Britain, Conn.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">St. Stanislaus B. &amp; M. Parish (Meriden, Conn.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence, 1904, 1917, undated. Empty envelope from Immigration and Naturalization Service.</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="pol"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <container id="cid89001" type="Drawer" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid89001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1904/1917" type="inclusive">1904-1917</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Oral histories from the 1980’s done by Joseph G.V. Maciora interviewing his family members. Topics are Polonia in Meriden, CT, religious practices, monthly celebrations, biographies of his grandparents, Letter to the Editor, Families residing in Meriden, CT. Also included are a few notes to the library/archivist.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid89002" type="Drawer" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid89002" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1984/1987" type="inclusive">1984-1987</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Maciora and Mik family genealogy information published in “The Berkshire Genealogist” p. 25 (1983), related correspondence. List of marriages of Mik and Maciora families.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid89003" type="Drawer" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid89003" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1983/1986" type="inclusive">1983-1986</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>“An American Life With a Polish Flair” by Joseph G.V. Maciora, 1987 (History of his parents)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid89004" type="Drawer" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid89004" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1987/1987">1987</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>“The Maciora &amp; Mik Families Genealogy” by Joseph G.V. Maciora 1982. Information on whole family, cousins, aunts, uncles, etc.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid89005" type="Drawer" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid89005" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Miscellaneous: 2 programs from The Parish Community of the Holy Cross in East Cambridge, MA from 1987. Prayer cards, program from the Polish Museum of America. Program from Church of St. Hedwig in Union City, CT. Packet of the “Exhumation of the Remains of the Servant of God Mother Mary Theresa.” (1972).</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid89006" type="Drawer" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid89006" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1972/1987" type="inclusive">1972-1987</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
