<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="ccsu_schema.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-ctnbt" url="https://library.ccsu.edu/cpaaead/cpaa8607.xml">cpaa8607</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
		
	                <titleproper>Elzbieta and Jan Merta papers 
                    <lb/>
                    <date>1946-1973</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>CPAA 86.07</num>
                </titleproper>
                <subtitle>Finding Aid</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Finding aid prepared by Renata Vickrey</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Connecticut Polish American Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1615 Stanley Street </addressline>
                    <addressline>New Britain, CT, 06050</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-08-15T12:13-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546" scriptcode="latn">English</language></langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>2014</date>
                <item></item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jan and Elzbieta Merta Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>CPAA 86.07</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Connecticut Polish American Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>6.0 folders</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1946-1973</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">Collection consists of legal documents of Jan and Elzbieta Merta, who immigrated to the US in 1950 from DPs camp in Germany under the Displaced Persons Act.</abstract>
            <physdesc id="ref1" label="General Physical Description note">
                <extent encodinganalog="300$a">(0.25 linear ft.)</extent></physdesc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Jan Merta, Elzbieta Merta</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Mr. and Mrs. Merta life path is typical for many displaced persons (DP's) after WW II. In 1948, the United States Congress established the Displaced Person Act, which permitted Europeans displaced by the war to enter the United States outside of immigration quotas.</p>
            <p>After World War II, millions of people were uprooted from their homes and countries. The majority were the inmates of Nazi concentration camps, forced labor camps and prisoners of war camps. Some displaced persons returned to their home countries however the majority in fear of the Soviet domination and occupation of their countries, mostly Eastern Europeans, decided to stay in the West. Such large numbers of people were a considerable challenge to military and civilian authorities. Therefore to resolve the problem in a timely and effective manner refugees were divided into several categories. Refugees who could return and were willing to do so were sent back to their home countries. Refugees who could not return and stayed had to be given shelter. Initially, military missions of the various Allied nations were established and assisted in the sorting and classifying the DPs. For example, during 1945 and 1946 there were several dozen Polish liaison officers attached to individual occupation army units. Accommodations for displaced persons were made primarily in former military barracks, summer camps, hotels, castles, hospitals and private homes. Situation in camps were often harsh and people were anxious to find out about their families and other countrymen. Therefore millions of names were collected by tracing services. Waiting for resettlement, camp residents quickly established churches, schools, courses and even universities. When it became clear that over a million people needed resettlement, adequate plans had to be made with countries that could accept them. Existing immigrant quotas were inadequate. United States were rather late to accept displaced persons and as a result of political actions to change the situation president Truman signed the first Displaced Person Act on June 25, 1948, which allowed 200,000 people to immigrate to the US. By 1953 a total of 600,000 people resettled in the US.</p>
            <p>Mrs. Elzbieta Merta nee Brown met her husband Jan Merta in a camp in Braunschweig, Germany and they were married there on March 16, 1946. Mrs. Merta was an elementary school teacher with the Polish Association in Germany Central Committee of Education; Mr. Jan Merta was an auto mechanic. They came to the United States in 1950 and settled in Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
            <p>The collection consists of legal documents of Jan and Elzbieta Merta, who came to the US in 1950 from a refugee camp in Braunschweig, Germany under the Displaced Persons Act. Documents include birth certificates, work permits for foreigners during World War II, certificates from DPs camp, green cards and insurance cards, and photographs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Cite as</emph>: Jan and Elzbieta Merta Papers (CPAA 86-07). Connecticut Polish American Archives, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Matthew Bronisz from Manchester, Connecticut in 1986.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Processed by Renata Vickrey.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Poland - Emigration and immigration.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Polish people - Connecticut - Hartford.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Refugees, Polish.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jan Merta - documents include work permit for foreigners in Germany during WW II, pass for public transportation, certification about stay in DPs camp, birth and baptismal certificate (in German), marriage certificate.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid217006" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate>1940-1949</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jan Merta - green card</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid217005" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                    <unitdate>1950</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Elzbieta Merta - identity card and work permit from Polish Association in Germany Central Committee of Education (in Polish and English), birth certificate (in Polish).</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid217004" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1947, 1950</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Elzbieta Merta - green card and permanent residency document.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid217003" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                    <unitdate>1950-1951</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Elzbieta Merta - Polish National Alliance membership card, two photographs of Mrs. Elzbieta Merta.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid217002" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1950, 1983</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Stanislawa Idzikowski - green card and insurance card.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid217001" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1966</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
