<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="ccsu_schema.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-ctnbt" url="https://library.ccsu.edu/cpaaead/glbtq/glbtq2013.04.xml ">glbtq2013.04</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>
                    <num>GLBTQ.2013.04</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Connecticut Polish American Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1615 Stanley Street </addressline>
                    <addressline>New Britain, CT, 06050</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2013</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-03-17T12:33-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>March 2016</date>
                <item></item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>GLBTQ Buttons</unittitle>
            <unitid>GLBTQ.2013.04</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Connecticut Polish American Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>583 pin-back buttons in 26 archival boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1972/2013" type="inclusive">1972-2013</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">This collection reflects the nature and expanse of the GLBTQ Archives at the Elihu Burritt Library. Coming from a variety of donors, these buttons give an overview of the interests within the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender communities of the Greater Hartford area, especially during the late twentieth century.</abstract>
            <physdesc id="ref5" label="General Physical Description note">583 pin-back buttons in 24 archival boxes. Each box contains list of contents and disk containing tiff files of each photograph taken of the buttons. 429 buttons with their metadata are searchable through the Elihu Burritt Library Digital Collection's GLBTQ Archives.</physdesc>
            <langmaterial id="ref10" label="Language of Materials note">The material is chiefly in English with a few buttons in Spanish.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="local" source="local">Irene, Scheibner</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="local" source="local">Stimpson, Donna</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref4">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>Buttons included in this collection are related to: Richard Cardarelli Collection; Hartford Gay and Lesbian Health Center Collection; Connecticut Lesbian and Gay PRIDE Festival Collection; Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights, 1984-2003; Donna C. Stimpson Collection; Richard Nelson Collection of Connecticut Stonewall Foundation Records; Carolyn Gabel-Brett Feminist and LGBT Collections; Hartford Women's Center Papers; Connecticut AIDS Action Council records;</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Pin-back buttons, like bumper stickers, T-shirts and other memorabilia, are used to proclaim a message to the viewer. The buttons in this collection project messages from a wide assortment of subjects within the Gay liberation movement, especially of the 1970's, 80's and 90's.</p>
            <p>Buttons have been used in the place of badges in political campaigns since George Washington’s day. Easy and cheap to produce, they began to be used to promote products during the middle of the 20th century. But it was during the fight for racial equality during the civil rights era that progressive movements began using pin-back buttons to promote their causes in unprecedented numbers. By the time the gay liberation movement began to produce buttons that helped to spread their message in the late 1960’s and 1970’s, pin-back buttons were a normal visual aspect of culture.</p>
            <p>The pin-back button use as proclaiming progressive slogans within LGBT issues can be traced directly to Frank Kameny’s slogan proclaiming “Gay is Good” in 1968. From carrying placards to wearing buttons was an easy transition. There are several remakes of the "Gay is Good" button in the collection.</p>
            <p>Several slogans became a ubiquitous piece of gay rights history, and were remade over and over depending on the fashion of the day. Other buttons or badges include iconic symbols such as the pink triangle or the rainbow in various incarnations. Reacting against the Stonewall riots of 1969, the first gay rights day was held in New York City in 1970. Buttons began to be designed to honor these ephemeral events. People started collecting buttons from events that they attended. Many of the buttons in the GLBTQ Archives collection are derived from personal collections.</p>
            <p>The collection within the GLBTQ Archives in the Elihu Burritt Library includes buttons from a variety of parades, fundraisers, political campaigns, and festivals, as well as pithy catchphrases and clever slogans. Visual iconography and symbolism abounds as well. The peace sign within the circle of a Venus symbol was a visual statement of the feminist peace movement. A pink triangle appears within the iconography of several of the buttons.</p>
            <p>As time went on, renowned artists’ creations were also used on buttons. The collection features buttons with Keith Haring drawings, and Tom of Finland buttons. There is one button designed for the production of “Angels in America” by graphic artist Milton Glaser. The causes of AIDS, first documented in 1981, took many years to understand. Buttons became a way of educating people about HIV/AIDS, especially with regard to safe sex practices. About one-fifth of the collection has a connection to the AIDS crisis in one way or another. One button decrying, “How many more?” refers to the numbers of people who died from AIDS in the early days. There are several buttons which refer to the Names memorial quilt. The collection has several red ribbons.</p>
            <p>To access the digital collection go to: http://content.library.ccsu.edu/cdm/landingpage/collection/GLBTQ</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref7">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>583 pin-back buttons in 24 archival boxes. Each box contains list of contents and disk containing tiff files of each photograph taken of the buttons. 429 buttons with their metadata are searchable through the Elihu Burritt Library Digital Collection's GLBTQ Archives. Buttons not included in the digital collection were either duplicates, or related to topics outside the GLBTQ sphere.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Ranging in dates from 1972 to 2013, with the bulk being from the late 1980's into the 1990's, most of these 583 pin-back buttons project messages having to do with the Gay liberation movement and the AIDS health crisis at that time.</p>
            <p>Many buttons were donated by the Hartford Gay &amp; Lesbian Health Collective. These relate to several issues within the AIDS health crisis, especially safe sex. From the Richard Cardarelli collection came several buttons having to do with Dignity/USA, Dignity Hartford, and other gay catholic groups. Our collections from the founders of the Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Civil Rights yielded many buttons from the marches, parades, and other demonstrations at which they participated.</p>
            <p>The buttons themselves have much information located on the sides and backs. Donnelly/Colt Buttons, a small company that continues to operate as Donnelly/Colt Progressive Resources in eastern Connecticut, manufactured many of the buttons in the collection. Other manufacturers represented include Ferne Sales &amp; Manufacturing of New Jersey, and DKG Graphics of Washington, D.C. Well-known artists designed a few of the buttons, while most were created by anonymous designers. There are several that were made using button-making machinery.</p>
            <p></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>The collection is open for research and is accessible at: http://content.library.ccsu.edu/cdm/landingpage/collection/GLBTQ</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>Cite as: GLBTQ Buttons, (GLBTQ Archives 2013.04), Elihu Burrit Library, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest">Cardarelli, Richard</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="ingest">Estabrook, Linda</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Hartford Gay and Lesbian Health Collective.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh"> Homophobia</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">AIDS (Disease) -- Prevention.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">AIDS activists</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Bisexuality</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Buttons (Information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Catholic gays</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Christian gays </subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Demonstrations</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dignity/Hartford</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dignity/USA</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Feminism -- United States -- History</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay and lesbian studies</subject>
            <occupation source="lcsh">Gay artists -- History</occupation>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay clergy</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay community -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay liberation movement -- Connecticut -- Hartford</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay pride parades</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay rights -- United States -- History</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay wit and humor</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality -- United States</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality and education -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality--Religious aspects--Catholic Church</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lesbians -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lesbians -- United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Safe sex in AIDS prevention</subject>
            <subject source="lcnaf">Women -- Connecticut -- Hartford</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women's music festivals.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women's music.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
