<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="ccsu_schema.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-ctnbt" url="https://library.ccsu.edu/cpaaead/glbtq/glbtq2012.03.xml ">glbtq2012.03</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Carolyn Gabel-Brett Feminist and LGBT Collections.
                    <num>GLBTQ.2012.03</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>GLBTQ Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1615 Stanley Street </addressline>
                    <addressline>New Britain, CT, 06050</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-02-25T14:26-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Carolyn Gabel-Brett Feminist and LGBT Collections</unittitle>
            <unitid>GLBTQ.2012.03</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>GLBTQ Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>9.0 Linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1986/2009" type="inclusive">1986-2009</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials note">English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref7" label="Abstract">Carolyn Gabel-Brett was an avid activist for women’s rights, gender equality and homosexual rights, participating in several Connecticut groups since 1972. This collection includes materials from her endeavors from 1986 through 2009 including documents, periodicals, and photographs regarding local and national events, community projects, and legislation pertaining to gender and homosexual rights.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="local" source="local" role="Creator (cre)">Gabel-Brett, Carolyn</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Carolyn Gabel-Brett was a feminist activist in Connecticut since she moved here in 1972. She worked in women’s reproductive rights for over ten years including establishing the Connecticut chapter of the National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL). She was on the faculty of the University Of Connecticut School Of Social Work where she coordinated a project on violence against women. She was one of the founders and long-time co-manager of the Reader's Feast, Hartford's feminist, progressive bookstore café for 12 years. She joined with Miles Rapoport in founding Democracy Works in 1999. She retired as Executive Director of Democracy Works in 2003. Carolyn has been an out lesbian activist serving in leadership positions in the CT Stonewall Foundation and the Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Civil Rights. She was an active Board member of Latinos/as Contra SIDA for six years. She continues to work with Love Makes a Family fighting for full marriage equality in Connecticut. Carolyn and her partner, Leslie, have been together for 25 years and have three adult children. The Connecticut Women’s Education And Legal Fund (CWEALF) was incorporated in 1973, being one of the oldest women’s organizations in the country. The group is dedicated to empowering women, girls and their families in the Greater Hartford area. They provide a toll free helpline to refer attorneys or obtain a free legal information booklet, training, technical assistance and resources to employers, schools, and community organizations concerning gender equality and legal rights of individuals. They seek to improve laws and policies affecting women, girls and their families, child support programs, and hate crimes prevention programs. Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) was formed during the summer of 1983 by a group of gay men and women discouraged by the continued defeat of the Gay Civil Rights Bill. They decided to form a statewide organization dedicated to the passage of civil rights legislation regarding discrimination based on sexual orientation. The coalition worked with progressive political organizations, other minority groups, religious affiliates, educators, and legal, social, and healthcare professionals to develop a lesbian and gay community. In 1985 the group established four regions throughout the state. In 1986, the group added “Connecticut” to the beginning of their name, becoming the CT CLGCR, in order to be able to back political candidates according to state law. The Political Action Committee was thus formed in 1988. The PAC interviewed candidates and reported the information back to the coalition, focusing mainly on areas of importance for homosexuals. The establishment of the PAC also led to inclusion in the statewide Legislative Electoral Action Program (LEAP), strengthening the CT CLGCR’s voice in the state government. In 1989, the group organized the HIV Task Force which was created to deal with legislative issues involving HIV and AIDS by writing position papers and making suggestions to the rest of the coalition. Another project was called The Anti-Violence Project, following the murder of a Connecticut gay man in 1988. Immediately following this incident, the AVP was created to monitor the murder case but also created Speak Out! in 1989. This program supplied organizations, school, and other interested parties with a participating speaker on homosexual issues. They also focused on the Hate Crimes Bill in 1990 pushing for its passage in conjunction with several other groups. The Religious Task Force was created in 1991 to organize the state’s religious community in support of the Gay Rights Bill. Later, the group changed its name to include transgender individuals, becoming CCLGBTCR. By 1999, the group was organized in six congressional districts and supported issues in the legislature such as anti-discrimination laws for students K-12, private right of action, health issues support such as HIV/AIDS and breast cancer, domestic partner benefits for state employees, and opposition to any state law prohibiting same gender marriage. In 2000, CCLGBTCR embarked on the Diversity Project to expand the membership base by meeting with diverse communities in the state, raise the level of awareness for the coalition, and assist communities in overcoming barriers that hinder their participation in the work of the coalition. The Stonewall Congress was formed to protect and advocate the health, safety, and civil rights of the lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender communities. This group formed in 1995 as a network of diverse organizations and individuals. It was managed by a Steering Committee and included special task forces working on specific issues. Often the Stonewall Congress worked in conjunction with other groups on special projects.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection contains materials related to several gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender civil rights and pride groups in Connecticut from 1986 to 2009. This includes Connecticut P.r.i.d.e., Connecticut Women’s Education and Legal Fund, Family Pride, Gay &amp; Lesbian Parents Coalition International, The Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights, and The Connecticut Stonewall Coalition. Issues discussed include hate crimes legislation, gay marriage, gay civil rights, and domestic partner rights. The range of materials include correspondence, newspaper articles, magazine articles, meeting minutes, agendas, budgets, flyers, and photographs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>Cite as: Carolyn Gabel-Brett Feminist and LGBT Collections (glbtq.2012.003). GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref9">
            <head>Oral history interview</head>
            <p>An oral history interview of Carolyn Gabel-Brett is available within the Digital Collections of the GLBTQ Archives. http://content.library.ccsu.edu/cdm/landingpage/collection/GLBTQ</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">AIDS (Disease) -- Law and legislation -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">AIDS activists</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Brett, Leslie</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Connecticut Stonewall Foundation</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund</subject>
            <subject source="local">Connecticut Women's Political Caucus</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Democracy Works</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Family violence -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Feminism.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay and lesbian studies</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay couples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay liberation movement -- Connecticut -- Hartford</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gay rights -- United States -- History</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hate crimes -- Connecticut -- Legislative history</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Periodicals</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality -- Connecticut -- Periodicals</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality -- Families</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Periodicals</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lamont, Ned, 1954-</subject>
            <subject source="local">Latinos/as Contra SIDA (Latinos/as Against AIDS)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lesbians -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Love Makes a Family</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Marriage law -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="local">Rapoport, Miles S.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Reproductive health -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Same-sex marriage -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Social work education</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">United Way of Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">University of Connecticut, School of Social Work</subject>
            <geogname source="local">West Hartford (Conn.)</geogname>
            <subject source="local">Wollenberg, William L.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Violence against -- Connecticut</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights -- Connecticut</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref10" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Personal and Women's Issues</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Carolyn Gabel-Brett - resume and job applications</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1978-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Carolyn Gabel-Brett - correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1976, 1985, 1999, 2002-2003, 2005-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence - Carolyn Gabel-Brett and Frank Gagliardi</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230004" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Carolyn Gabel-Brett - Resume, "Profile in Metroline, 2000, newspaper articles about Leslie Gabel-Brett 2006</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230003" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>2000, 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Carolyn Gabel-Brett - CT Judicial Training</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230005" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref72" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Carolyn Gabel-Brett - Testimony before the Judiciary Committee in support of Acts concerning Marriage Equality and Recognition</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid231002" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Civil Marriage Collaborative - notes from meetings, minutes, funds</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230016" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>2006-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Family Protection Act - fact sheet, petition</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230009" type="Folder">8</container>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Child Welfare - newsletters, conference brochure</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230010" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1980, 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Family Pride, Gay and Lesbian Parents Coalition International - correspondence, articles, conference announcements, newsletter, "In the Family: The Magazine of Lesbians, Gays, Bisexuals and their Relations"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230025" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Family Diversity Project - "Love Makes a Family" Photo/Text Exhibit</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230026" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Family Pride Coalition - "The Family Tree" newsletter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230027" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Voices for Children - brochure on poverty, "Special Report on Growing up Healthy"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230014" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Casey Family Programs - Family Diversity Projects Photo/Text Exhibit, correspondence regarding gay/lesbian foster parents, Sexual Orientation Diversity Training, "Present Tense...Future Perfect"-Rubber Duck Production</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230033" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230033" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref59" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Youth Advocacy Coalition - advocacy workshop, n.d.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230048" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230048" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>The Connecticut Women's Agenda - legislative priorities</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230008" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Council of Women's Organizations - CT Brigade in Tampa, FL canvassing project</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230013" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref73" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Equality Federation - conference, case studies</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid231003" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref56" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>New England Women's Musical Retreat (NEWMR VII) - program and directory of craftswomen</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230045" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230045" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>September 4-7, 1987</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref74" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Issues in Lilith, The Jewish Women's Magazine, no. 7</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid231004" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Religious Liberty Protection Act (RLPA) - newspaper article, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230012" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rainbow Interfaith Covenant and Outreach - correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230023" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref65" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Interfaith Coalition (WHIC) Planning Group - agendas, minutes, correspondence, notes, fact sheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230054" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230054" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref66" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Interfaith Coalition (WHIC), Community Housing Development Organization, Women, Infants, Children - MLS listings, outline, notes, phone list</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230055" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230055" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref63" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Gay Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Teens - newspaper articles, support groups, handwritten notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230052" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230052" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Community Television - Women's Perspective: the Personal is Political</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230035" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230035" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref51" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Joe Steffan, West Hartford Town Council Candidate - newspaper articles, campaign materials, other candidates</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230040" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230040" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Association for Human Services (CAHS) - newsletter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230011" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Governor's Task Force on Racial Harmony: A Status Report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230006" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>March 9, 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>YWCA nominating committee - minutes, notes, contact information, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230015" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate>1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref55" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>March on Washington - official program, map, article, Washington Blade Special Edition for the 1993 National March on Washington [issue relocated to periodical collection]</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230044" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230044" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref47" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Human Rights Campaign Fund - job discrimination, political information, brochure, newsletter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230036" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230036" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-1995</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Community Foundation Project - partners, workshops for nonprofits, handwritten notes, grant information, "Funders of Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Programs"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230037" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230037" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate>1995-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref62" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Safe and Affirming Network for Education (SANE) - organization information, fact sheet, meeting notes, newspaper article</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230051" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230051" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref49" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>List of proposals for grants</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230038" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230038" type="Folder">35</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref71" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Immigrant and Refugee Coalition "Immigrants in Connecticut: An Unrecognized Asset" - agenda, conference materials, notes, fact sheets about immigration policy, State Capitol Building, January 30, 2004; articles from the Urban Institute about children of immigrants</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid231001" type="Folder">36</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref64" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Responsible Individuals Striving Everyday - Rise-Zine</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230053" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230053" type="Folder">37</container>
                        <unitdate>2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Power Group - correspondence about previous meeting</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230024" type="Folder">38</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref54" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Lesbian Conference, Atlanta, GA - mailings, Connecticut Coalition News</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230043" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230043" type="Folder">39</container>
                        <unitdate>April 24-28, 1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut P.R.I.D.E - brochure, event advertising, Pride Day programs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230031" type="Folder">40</container>
                        <unitdate>1993, 2000-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref43" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut P.R.I.D.E - Gay and Lesbian Art Exhibition program, Pridefest Art Exhibition Committee correspondence, newspaper article about Pride Parade in Hartford</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230032" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230032" type="Folder">41</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref60" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>OutWrite: National Lesbian and Gay Writers Conference - programs, brochures</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230049" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230049" type="Folder">42</container>
                        <unitdate>1995, 1996, 1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref57" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>News articles/media regarding GLBTQ and religion, family, the arts, politics</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230046" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230046" type="Folder">43</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Resource Guide for Gay Connecticut - compiled by the Gay Men's Chorus</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230021" type="Folder">44</container>
                        <unitdate>September 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Lesbian Action Foundation-ASTRAEA - correspondence, advertisements, Lesbian Writers Fund Gala program</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230017" type="Folder">45</container>
                        <unitdate>1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clinton/Gore 1996 - "A Record of Respecting Gay and Lesbian Americans"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230019" type="Folder">46</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref52" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Metroline magazine, 1996-1997; pages from Metroline, 1998 all regarding GLBTQ issues</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230041" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230041" type="Folder">47</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders - news releases, correspondence, newsletters, year-end briefs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230028" type="Folder">48</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Gay and Lesbian Health Collective, Hartford, Women's Advisory Committee - correspondence, events, "The Collective" newsletter, survey, newspaper articles, request for proposal, handwritten notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230030" type="Folder">49</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Gay Lesbian Straight Education Network (GLSEN) Connecticut - correspondence, advertisements for events</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230029" type="Folder">50</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-1999, 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>International Gay and Lesbian Human Rights Commission - annual reports, 1998-2001; newsletter, 2000</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230039" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230039" type="Folder">51</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Queer Alliance, Wesleyan University - correspondence, contacts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230020" type="Folder">52</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref61" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Queer and Active - electronic mailings; Connecticut Stonewall Foundation - conference, advertisement</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230050" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230050" type="Folder">53</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Gay and Lesbian Film Festival - pamphlets, schedule, program</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230022" type="Folder">54</container>
                        <unitdate>June 4-12, 1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref58" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Gay and Lesbian Task Force "Creating Change" conference</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230047" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230047" type="Folder">55</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref53" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Names Project, AIDS Memorial Quilt, Washington, DC, 1992; The National Museum of Women in the Arts exhibit, 1992/1993</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230042" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230042" type="Folder">56</container>
                        <unitdate>1992-1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut HIV/AIDS Action Council - conference program, action alerts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230034" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230034" type="Folder">57</container>
                        <unitdate>1993, 1995-1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut AIDS Action Council - newsletters, articles, AIDS Awareness Day agenda, correspondence, fact sheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid230018" type="Folder">58</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref75" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Material separated</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid231005" type="Folder">59</container>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref69" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Women's Health and Women's Rights</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref129" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domestic abuse, battered women - articles, publications, mailings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231056" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231056" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref80" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domestic Abuse research - papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231011" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref81" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Task Force on Abused Women - meeting minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231012" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref84" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Sexual abuse within families - fact sheets, brochures, checklist, papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231015" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref99" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Women's Health Network - newsletters, alerts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231029" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref82" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hartford Interval House for Battered Women - brochures, pamphlets, training materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231013" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref83" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Violence against women - articles, newsletters, correspondence, National Coalition Against Domestic Violence material</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231014" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref85" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Task Force on Abused Women - fact sheet, funding report, racism awareness, Domestic Violence in CT paper</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231016" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref105" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Health Services - newsletters, mailings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231036" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231036" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref86" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Task Force on Abused Women - brochures, flyers, correspondence, questionnaires, membership application</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231017" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref87" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Alliance of Sexual Assault Services - correspondence, agendas, minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231018" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref88" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Coalition Against Domestic Violence "End Violence in the Lives of Women" - conference materials, information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231019" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>August 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref89" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>University of Connecticut: President's Committee on Violence Against Women - final report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231020" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>December 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref90" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Task Force on Abused Women legislative committee - agendas, forms, minutes, flyers, notes, legislation, job description</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231021" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1982-1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref91" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Advisory Committee on Violence Against Women - status report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231022" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref70" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Health aFair Conference, domestic violence information - fact sheets, support group information, definitions, notes, newsletters, articles, reports, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231006" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>April 1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref76" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Health aFair Conference, Domestic Violence Workshop - fact sheets, correspondence, notes, forms, articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231007" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>April 1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref77" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hartford Interval House Shelter - forms, flyers, handouts, phone lists, newsletter, fact sheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231008" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref78" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Victim Advocate Volunteer Training Workshop - training test, agenda, forms, notes, organizational chart, fact sheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231009" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>January 1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref79" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition Against Domestic Violence (CCADV) Training Coordinator - correspondence, job description, presentation skills information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231010" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>September 1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref123" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Permanent Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) - mailings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231050" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231050" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref101" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Permanent Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) - meeting minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231031" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref113" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Permanent Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) "Making Women Visible Day" - flyer, program, fact sheets, sticker, business card</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231044" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231044" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>February 1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref131" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Commission on the Status of Women - Legislative Report, 1997 and 1998; Annual Report, 1998; newsletters, 1998; handwritten notes; "Diversity and the Vote: Lessons for Exploring the Multicultural Dimensions of the Suffrage Movement," 1995</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231058" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231058" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>1995, 1997, 1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref103" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Reproductive rights and abortion - correspondence, fact sheets, brochures, articles, mailings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231034" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231034" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>1977, 1980, 1981, 1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref124" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abortion Rights - "Once and for All" conference, Yale Law School</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231051" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231051" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>January 22, 1978</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref67" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut NARAL (National Abortion Rights Action League) - newsletters, mailings, meeting minutes, vote counts, 1980</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230056" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid230056" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref68" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>NARAL (National Abortion Rights Action League) - bumper stickers, election material, fact sheets, events, Roe v. Wade anniversary activities, "A State by State Review of Abortion and Reproductive Rights" Voters' Guide, articles related to abortion legislation, "She had a Name. She Had a Family. She was Leona's Sister Gerri." by Roberta Brandes Gratz in Ms. Magazine 1995-2000, 2002</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230057" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid230057" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>1995-2000, 2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref116" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Organization for Women (NOW) - miscellaneous publications, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231047" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231047" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref114" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Organization for Women (NOW) - publications, pamphlets, letters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231045" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231045" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref130" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Organization for Women (CT NOW) Feminist Awards Dinner - articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231057" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231057" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>1997, 1999, 2000, 2001, 2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref115" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Organization for Women (NOW) 10th Annual Feminist Awards Dinner program - C. Gabel-Brett is recipient of Eleanor Roosevelt Award</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231046" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231046" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>March 1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref95" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund (CWEALF) - "Who's Who in the Right Wing" booklet, "Women and their Families" booklet</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231033" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231033" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate>[1980]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref96" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund (CWEALF) - "Rape and the Law" booklet</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231026" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund (CWEALF) - Awards Dinner programs, 2000; Connecticut Pridelink, 1998; 25th Anniversary Program, 1998; Newspaper articles, 1997; Legal Rights of Lesbians, Gay Men and Bisexuals in Connecticut, and Legal Rights of Older Women</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid230007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid230007" type="Folder">35</container>
                        <unitdate>1997, 1998, 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref127" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Family Planning Funding: the Political Process" by Carolyn Gabel Allen</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231054" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231054" type="Folder">36</container>
                        <unitdate>April 25, 1975</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref110" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Marnie W. Mueller - research papers "Economic Determinants of Volunteer Work by Women," "Occupational Segregation and Volunteer Work"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231041" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231041" type="Folder">37</container>
                        <unitdate>1975</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref100" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Rights - various publications</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231030" type="Folder">38</container>
                        <unitdate>1977-1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref122" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coordinating Committee for the National Commission on the Observance of International Women's Year - correspondence, minutes, manual</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231049" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231049" type="Folder">39</container>
                        <unitdate>1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref92" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Displaced Homemakers in Connecticut - surveys, evaluation of services</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231023" type="Folder">40</container>
                        <unitdate>1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref93" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Feminist Press - brochures, announcements, mailings, book lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231024" type="Folder">41</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref94" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Equal Rights Amendment - clippings, petition, "The Right Connection: A Seminar for Business and Professional Women" report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231025" type="Folder">42</container>
                        <unitdate>1979, 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref104" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Title IX - summary, "Equals" newsletter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231035" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231035" type="Folder">43</container>
                        <unitdate>1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref97" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Human services - mailings, newsletters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231027" type="Folder">44</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref98" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous organizations</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231028" type="Folder">45</container>
                        <unitdate>1980, 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref106" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Studies - newspaper clippings, newsletters, mailings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231037" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231037" type="Folder">46</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref117" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ms. Magazine Calendar in support of the many programs of Project Woman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231048" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231048" type="Folder">47</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref126" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"The Dinner Party" Project with Judy Chicago Lecture Series - correspondence, press releases, participants</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231053" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231053" type="Folder">48</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref102" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public Affairs [YWCA] - meeting minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231032" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231032" type="Folder">49</container>
                        <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref112" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Integrating Seminar "Executive Management for Women: A Trainer's Guide," National Board of the YWCA</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231043" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231043" type="Folder">50</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref108" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women for Racial and Economic Equality (WREE) - article, agenda, mailing</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231039" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231039" type="Folder">51</container>
                        <unitdate>1981, 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref109" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Congress - correspondence, minutes, agenda program</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231040" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231040" type="Folder">52</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref128" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>W.I.N. (Women's Issue Network) Political Action Committee (PAC) - endorsement procedure</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231055" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231055" type="Folder">53</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref111" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Leslie Brett - research paper "Adding Age to Gender: Some Thoughts on Identity and Social Status in New Guinea"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231042" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231042" type="Folder">54</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref107" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Women in Prison - correspondence, statement of accounts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231038" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231038" type="Folder">55</container>
                        <unitdate>1984-1985</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref125" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Feminist issues - related articles, clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231052" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid231052" type="Folder">56</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref118" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: University of Connecticut (UCONN) School of Social Work</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref119" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN - Grant application "Delivery of Family Planning Services" C. Gabel, University Educational Assistant</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231059" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231059" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref132" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work - articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231060" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231060" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1976-1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref133" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work Domestic Abuse Project</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231061" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231061" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref134" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work Domestic Abuse Project Grant - final report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231062" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231062" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref135" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Association of Social Workers (NASW) 1st Annual Conference on Social Work Practice with Women - registration, attendees, flyers, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231063" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231063" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref136" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work - Domestic Abuse Proposal</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231064" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231064" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref137" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN Women's Center Annual Report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231065" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231065" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref138" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work - correspondence, notes, reports</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231066" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231066" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref139" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>New England Regional Child Welfare Training Center, UCONN School of Social Work - work plan for 1981, quarterly report 1980</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231067" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231067" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1980, 1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref140" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work - Training about gay and lesbian culture and lifestyle, Title XX</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231068" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231068" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref141" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Title XX Training Grant - report (rough draft), grant summary, questionnaire, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231069" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231069" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1981-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref142" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work Conference "Sensitivity is Not Enough: Social Service Delivery-Lesbians and Gay Men" - flyer, schedule, forms, handouts, articles, bibliography, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231070" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231070" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>September 1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref143" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Association of Social Workers (NASW) Lesbian Gay Task Force - agendas, minutes, correspondence, mailing lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid231071" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid231071" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1982-1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref144" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Integrating Seminar on Women's Issues" SEM 340 taught by C. Gabel - course materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid232001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid232001" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>[1981]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref145" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN Professor of Social Work - notes, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid232002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid232002" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1981-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref146" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN Field Education and Supervision - evaluations, training summaries, correspondence, notes, memoranda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid232003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid232003" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1981-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref147" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work: Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Student Alliance - "Strategies for Change" notes, notices, reports, mailings, flyers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid232004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid232004" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref148" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work courses SEM 340 'Seminar on Women's Issues' and HB 373 'Violence Against Women: A Cultural Heritage' taught by C. Gabel - bibliograpies, course descriptions</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid232005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid232005" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref149" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Violence Against Women: A Cultural Heritage" HB 371 taught by C. Gabel - course materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid232006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid232006" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref150" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Why Women Stay" workshop presented by C. Gabel at social work conference, Southern Connecticut State College - conference materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid232007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid232007" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>May 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref151" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Variety of Living Styles" course, "Gay/Lesbian Families" workshop taught/presented by C. Gabel and Julio Morales - bibliography, articles, student feedback</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid232008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid232008" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref153" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domenstic Abuse Unit - communications</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233001" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>1981-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref154" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domestic Abuse Unit - questionnaire, responses, analysis</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233002" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>1981-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref155" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domestic Abuse Unit - shelter information, legislative information, notes, outlines, bibliography, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233003" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>1982-1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref156" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Meeting the Conservative Challenge of the 80's: Women as Social Workers and Clients" National Association of Social Workers (NASW) Conference - conference materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233004" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>May 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref157" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work field placements - descriptions, correspondence, notes, forms</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233005" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>1982-1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref158" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Violence Against Women" course HB 373 - bibliography, handouts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233006" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>1982-1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref163" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Violence Against Women" course HB 373 - syllabus, student work, grades, course evaluation, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233010" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref159" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Family Violence Conference, Fairfield County Coalition for Abused Women, C. Gabel Keynote Speaker - correspondence, article, brochure, report notes, program, fact sheet, sample press release, business card, paper</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233007" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>May 1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref162" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Family Violence Conference, Fairfield County Coalition for Abused Women, C. Gabel Keynote Speaker - speech, notes, correspondence, newspaper articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233009" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate>May 1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref160" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Curriculum on Battered Women: An Approach Within the Framework of Violence Against Women" presented by C. Gabel at the Council on Social Work Education Annual Program Meeting, Fort Worth, Texas</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233008" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>March 1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref164" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Sensitivity is Still Not Enough: Sixty Workshops Concerning Lesbian/Gay Issues" 2nd Annual UCONN School of Social Work Conference, National Association of Social Workers (NASW) Lesbian/Gay Task Force - conference materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233011" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref165" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Council on Social Work Education: Annual Meeting - proposal, conference, materials, address list, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233012" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref166" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work: Conference on Mediation - agenda, notes, meeting minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233013" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>May 1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref167" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work: termination of Carolyn Gabel - letters of support</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233014" type="Folder">35</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref168" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work Independent Study: "White Women Combatting Racism" - syllabus, articles, bibiography</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233015" type="Folder">36</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref169" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"An Approach for Addressing Racism, Ethnocentrism, and Sexism in the Curriculum" - C. Gabel co-contributor</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233016" type="Folder">37</container>
                        <unitdate>[1986]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref170" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work: "Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Parent and Children Conference"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233017" type="Folder">38</container>
                        <unitdate>1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref171" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work course: "New Perspectives on Lesbians and Gay Men"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233018" type="Folder">39</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref172" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN Safe Zone Project</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233019" type="Folder">40</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref173" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work Course Evaluations</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233020" type="Folder">41</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref174" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work course work - Political Systems</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233021" type="Folder">42</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref175" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UCONN School of Social Work: Advancement of Political Social Work Practice Campaign - correspondence, agenda, map</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid233022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid233022" type="Folder">43</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref120" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: Love Makes a Family (LMF)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref121" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) - articles, Second Parent Adoption Act, advertisements, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref176" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) - testimony, poll, hearing, correspondence, fact sheets, clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>2001, 2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref177" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) - civil unions, economic fact sheet</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref178" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) - newspaper clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234004" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>April 2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref179" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) Defense of Marriage Act (DOMA) - correspondence, vote counts and comments, 2004 election summary</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234005" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref180" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) - correspondence from supporting organizations: American Civil Liberties Union, People for the American Way Foundation, Latinas/Latinos for Marriage Equality, National Gay and Lesbian Task Force, Queer People of Color, Yale, UCONN, Quinnipiac University</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234006" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref181" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) Lobbying Team - meeting agendas, correspondence, notes, fact sheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234007" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref182" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) Political Action Committee - campaign materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234008" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref183" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Love Makes a Family (LMF) - press releases, notes, fundraising, grant proposal, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234009" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>2006-2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref184" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series V: Domestic Partners</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref185" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domestic Partners: Health Benefits - articles, fact sheets, proposals, position paper</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234010" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1993-1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref190" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>State Pride Domestic Partner Benefits - newspaper articles, legislation in other locations (France, California), correspondence, general information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234014" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref186" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domestic Partners: Connecticut State Pride - general information, lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234011" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref187" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domestic Partner Benefits Information - local boards of education, Human Rights Campaign definition</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234012" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>2003-2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref188" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"National, Connecticut State, and Selected Municipal Domestic Partner Health Benefit Policies" - memoranda, general information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234013" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref191" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lesbian Gay Direct Action - protest at CT state capitol, march in Bushnell Park, non-violent civil disobedience information, newspaper articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234015" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref192" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lesbian Gay Direct Action/Queer Nation - directory of resources, meeting minutes, statements, voting guide, clippings, protest guide, holiday card</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234016" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1989-1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref193" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lesbian Gay Direct Action: interruption of Governor's Budget Address - articles, correspondence, photographs, summons, appellate brief</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234017" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref194" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Children from the Shadows II" - conference program</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234018" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>March 1995</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref195" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Children from the Shadows" - advertisements, newspaper articles, resources for youth</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234019" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref196" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Children from the Shadows VII: Taking LGBT Youth Issues Beyond Risk to Resilience" - conference information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234020" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref197" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>True Colors XII Conference, Central Connecticut State University - resource guide, "Deconstructing Labels," conference program</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234021" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>2005-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref198" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>True Colors XV and XVI - conference programs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234022" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>2008-2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref199" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VI: West Hartford Cornerstone Pool Discrimination Case</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref200" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Committee for Fairness - photographs, sign-in sheets, correspondence, facilities rental contracts, notes, signs, flyers, stickers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234023" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref202" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Town Council - meeting minutes, notes, voter guide</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234025" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>February 1998-May 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref201" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Cornerstone Pool Discrimination Case - correspondence, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234024" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>November 1998-September 1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref203" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Cornerstone Pool Discrimination Case - correspondence, notes, reports, notices</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234026" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>October 1999-December 1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref204" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Cornerstone Pool Discrimination Case - correspondence, court papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234027" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>February 2000-May 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref205" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Cornerstone Pool Discrimination Case - correspondence, court papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234028" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>June 2000-December 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref206" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Cornerstone Pool Discrimination Case - correspondence, court papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid234029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid234029" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref207" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>West Hartford Cornerstone Pool Discrimination Case - newspaper clippings, press releases</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid235001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid235001" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2000, 2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref208" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VII: Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref209" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - New Haven Chapter Minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>August 1986-October 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref210" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - covers, flyers, clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1986-1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref211" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights Bill - amendments, correspondence with religious leaders, copies of the bill, Massachusetts Gay and Lesbian Political Caucus Lobby Day information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1987, 1990, 1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref212" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - Steering Committee minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236004" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>December 1987- April 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref213" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - correspondence with politicians and institutions in CT</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236005" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1988-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref214" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - Steering Committee policies/proposals</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236006" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1988, 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref215" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lesbian and Gay Rights Bill - State Senate summary report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236007" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref216" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - By-laws</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236008" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>January 17, 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref217" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - Steering Committee minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236009" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref218" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - budget</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236010" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref219" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Mercy Center Retreat - description of activity, goals, action plans</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236011" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>[1990]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref220" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - Legislative Report by Elizabeth Gallo and Barry Williams (Gallo and Williams Government Relations, West Hartford), correspondence with Elizabeth Gallo</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236012" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref221" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - "An Act Concerning Discrimination on the Basis of Sexual Orientation" law passed April 17, 1991</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236013" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref222" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Political Action Committee (PAC) - meeting minutes, proposal for steering committee, press releases, budgets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236014" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1988-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref223" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - materials about organizing for legislative issues</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236015" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref224" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Lesbian and Gay Rights Coalition Political Action Committee - Connecticut State Elections Enforcement Commission letters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236016" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref225" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - mailing lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236017" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1998, 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref226" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - Steering Committee correspondence, agendas, event advertising, workshops/conferences, member list</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236018" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref227" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Legislative Breakfast - program, floppy disk with program on it, sign-in sheet, name tags</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236019" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref228" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR)/National Gay and Lesbian Task Force - Equality Begins at Home articles, pin, mailers, events, Rainbow Flag Rally, Metroline</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236020" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref229" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - official history by Denise Frances, 1992; research notes, 2001-2003; "The Legal Rights of Lesbians, Gay Men and Bisexuals in Connecticut," 1997; correspondence and minutes 1993-2001</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236021" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>1992-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref230" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR)/Stonewall - correspondence, event advertisements, meetings with legislators, meeting agendas/minutes, receipts, press releases, handwritten notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236022" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref231" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - newsletter, handouts, mailings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236023" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref232" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Haymarket People's Fund Diversity Project - interviews, grant application, original proposal</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236024" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref233" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) National Gay and Lesbian Task Force - Equality Begins At Home Press Kit (2)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236025" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref234" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Legislative Breakfast - sign-in sheet, notes, program, floppy disk with program on it; October 7, 2000</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236026" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>October 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref235" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - Steering Committee correspondence, agendas, event advertising, workshops/conferences, member list</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236027" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref236" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Diversity Project - meeting agendas, minutes, notes, receipts, correspondence, description of project, interview questions for coordinator, applicant's paperwork</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236028" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref237" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - Diversity Project Focus Group Report, celebration dinner/meeting program and planning, correspondence, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236029" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref238" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - minutes, reports, fact sheets, conference information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236030" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref239" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - meeting agenda/minutes, notes, CRS Report for Congress "Public Aid and Faith-Based Organizations (Charitable Choice)," opposition to nomination of John Ashcroft for Attorney General, list of federal and state officials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236031" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref240" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) - meeting agenda, newspaper article</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236032" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236032" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref241" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR)/Stonewall - mail and email addresses, official mailing lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236034" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236034" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref242" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR)/Stonewall - mail and email addresses, various handwritten notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236033" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid236033" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref243" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VIII: Marriage Equality and LGBT miscellaneous issues</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref259" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>GLBTQ miscellaneous events, n.d.; Center for Disease Control weekly report regarding the prevention of HIV, 1987</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237011" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1987</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref277" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>GLBT people-empolyment discrimination - flyers, fact sheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237027" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1990's</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref270" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) photo of State of the State Address by Governor O'Neill interrupted by Coalition</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237020" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>February 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref271" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Gay Rights Bill signing ceremony - photos and clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237021" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref278" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>AIDS Candellight Vigil - notes, meeting minutes, correspondence, press release, articles, flyers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237028" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>October 1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref279" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>AIDS Action Network - correspondence, notes, flyers, petition</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237029" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1992-1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref280" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lesbian/Gay Task Force on Federal Legislation - correspondence, notes, flyers, action kit, meeting minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237030" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref276" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Minority AIDS Council - conference materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237026" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref253" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Institute for Gay and Lesbian Strategic Studies Training - information, articles on homosexuality</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237005" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref256" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Articles from Metroline, GLA Bulletin, Newsweek, and Hartford Courant</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237008" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref244" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hawaii Same Sex Marriage - correspondence, articles, fact sheets, Marriage Project-Hawaii documents, Office of Health Status Monitoring forms for marriage license</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236035" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid236035" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1995-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref245" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Defense of Marriage Act (DOMA) - opposition information, newspaper articles, amendment strategies, correspondence, issues in other states</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236036" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid236036" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1995-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref249" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Freedom to Marry/National Freedom to Marry Day - correspondence, Vermont legislation articles, The Marriage Project, Lambda Legal Defense Fund</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237001" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref255" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund (CWEALF) Latina Event - newspaper articles, agenda notes, planning meeting minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237007" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref263" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Gay and Lesbian Task Force: Establishment of the Federation of Statewide LGBT Political Organizations - correspondence, mailing list, proposal outlines</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237014" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref264" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Commission on Human Rights and Opportunities (CHRO) Transgender Issues - press releases; "Declaratory Ruling on Behalf of John/Jane Doe;" petition; newspaper articles; publications from Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders, The Human Rights Campaign, It's Time Connecticut, and the Gay Lesbian, and Straight Education Network; The Advocate article "Transgendered"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237015" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref251" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Co-Parent Adoption in Connecticut - articles, correspondence, mailing list, "Baby Z Case," legislator lists, Civil Liberty News</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237003" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref281" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Pride Link: a Resource Guide of Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual/Transgender Organizations-Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237031" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref252" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rainbow Flag at Connecticut State Capitol - photographs of speakers, protestor, "outing" Patrick Flaherty, film negatives</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237004" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>March 21, 1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref257" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Out! Awards - program, Hartford October 2, 1999</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237009" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref258" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Veronica Berrill Case: Berrill v. Houde - correspondence, newspaper articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237010" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref261" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>LGBT articles: Gays in the Military, 1999; Newsweek, March 2000</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237013" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>1999, 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref266" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>LGBT Herstory/History Project Questionnaire; "Herstory and History of St. Francis, St. Clare Parish of the American Apostolic Catholic Church," West Hartford, CT</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237017" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref268" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Alfred Stieglitz, Georgia O'Keeffe, and American Modernism Exhibit at the Wadsworth Atheneum news release; Biography of artist Marsden Hartley; Design, Dance, and Music of the Ballet Russes exhibit; Shorter article version (Richard Nelson), June 9, 1999</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237019" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref254" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Institute for Community Research: Sexual Minority Youth Project - memo, program</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237006" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref273" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Conference for Community and Justice: Sexual Orientation - correspondence, reports, lists, brochure, notes, education materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237023" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>1999, 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref274" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Just the Facts About Sexual Orientation and Youth: A Primer for Principals, Educators, and School Personnel" publication</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237024" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref272" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Institute for Community Research LGBT Project - correspondence, fact sheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237022" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>1999-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref260" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Vermont LGBT Marriage Civil Rights - correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237012" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref265" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Commission on Human Rights and Opportunities (CHRO) - testimony of Leslie Brett re: State Empolyee's Campaign Request for Declaratory Ruling Concerning Inclusion of Boy Scouts in Charitable Giving Campaign; related materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237016" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref267" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"OUT and Into the Voting Booth: Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Voters in 2000," a report by the Gill Foundation</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237018" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref275" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hartford Gay and Lesbian Health Collective Gill Foundation Workshops - correspondence, flyers, fact sheets, brochure, forms</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237025" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref250" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Civil Liberties Union - "Reasons for Connecticut to Oppose a Same-Sex Marriage Ban," domestic partnership facts, "Privacy Rights in Connecticut" booklet, annual message</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237002" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref247" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"GLAD (Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders) Files Suit to End Connecticut's Exclusion of Lesbian and Gay Couples from Marriage Rights" - legal papers, press releases</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236038" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid236038" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref246" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Counting on Couples: Fiscal Savings from Allowing Same-Sex Couples to Marry in Connecticut," The Williams Project</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236037" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid236037" type="Folder">35</container>
                        <unitdate>2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref248" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Same-sex couples' right to marry - clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid236039" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid236039" type="Folder">36</container>
                        <unitdate>2006-2008</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref282" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lesbian and Gay Rights miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid237032" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid237032" type="Folder">37</container>
                        <unitdate>1980-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref285" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Who's Behind the Gay Rights Movement?" publication of the National Gay Task Force</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid238001" type="Folder">38</container>
                        <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref283" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IX: Connecticut Stonewall Congress</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref284" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Time Line Project" Resources/Records - Stonewall Riots, legislation, sources taken from different archives, letters to sponsors, drafts of timeline, revisions</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238002" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1987-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref286" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Congress/Stonewall Coalition - articles, legislative proposals, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238003" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1993-1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref287" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation - reports, to the CT Secretary of State</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238004" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref288" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stonewall Congress - mailing lists, part 1</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238005" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1995</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref289" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stonewall Congress - mailing lists, part 2</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238006" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1995</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref290" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation - membership lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238007" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1995</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref291" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stonewall Foundation - notes, membership list, letters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238008" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref292" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Congress - events and flyers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238009" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref293" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Congress - newsletter, brochure</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238010" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref294" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Congress - "Celebrating Our Stories, Embracing Our Future" Trinity College - program; photos of speakers, booths, exhibits, attendees (two envelopes); October 4, 1997</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238011" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref295" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Congress - Stonewall Annual Report, 1997 and Reorganization by-laws, 1998, 1999</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238012" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1997, 1998, 1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref296" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Congress - meeting agendas, written notes, annual report (disk)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238013" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref297" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Conference/Exhibit - program, correspondence, notes, registration slips, planning materials, speaker biographies: October 23 and 27, 1999</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238014" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref298" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation "Challenging and Changing America: The Struggle for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Civil Rights" - conference materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238015" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref299" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation "Challenging and Changing America: An Exhibition on the Struggle for Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Civil Rights" Hartford Public Library - guest book, October 1999</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238016" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref300" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Timeline Exhibit Project, Thomas J. Dodd Research Center at the University of Connecticut - program, resources contact list, newspaper articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238017" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref310" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation documentary video "ONE Step Towards Justice, The Passage of the Connecticut Gay Rights Bill" - agendas, minutes, notes, correspondence, mailing lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid239003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid239003" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref301" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation Challenging and Changing America Timeline Exhibit - fundraising letters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238018" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref302" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation - email and address lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238019" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref303" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation/Community Works - contributors, vendor card report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238020" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref304" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation "Challenging and Changing America" Exhibit at the Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University - program, material from advertising, June-July 2000</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238021" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref305" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation Board-Potential Candidates - correspondence, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238022" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref306" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation/CWEALF Panel on Hate Crimes - mailing list, receipts, documents on floppy disk, flyers, correspondence, notes, diversity news articles, October 25, 2000</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238023" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref307" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bonnie Glasser, Student Intern-Stonewall Foundation - evaluation form, faxes, correspondence, newspaper articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid238024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid238024" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>2000-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref308" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation/Hartford Gay and Lesbian Health Collective 20th anniversary exhibit at Central CT State University February 2, 2003 - message from creator Richard Nelson</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid239001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid239001" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref309" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Stonewall Foundation Annual Meeting, April 12, 2004 - correspondence, notes, by-laws, summary of activities</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid239002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid239002" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref311" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series X: Hate Crimes</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref312" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hate Crimes - articles, reports</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid239004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid239004" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref313" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund (CWEALF) Hate Crimes Project - 13th Annual Awards Dinner program, business listing, community organization listing, Connecticut Pride Link Advisory Committee agenda, grant submitted for Connecticut Pride Link database for Connecticut residents to network</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240001" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref314" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Hate Crimes Legislation - article, fact sheet, press release</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240002" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref315" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund (CWEALF) - grant submission to Gill Foundation regarding funding for hate crimes prevention program along with continued funding of in-place programs, related articles and correspondence regarding hate crimes and legislation, "Legal Rights of Lesbians, Gay Men, and Bisexuals in Connecticut"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240003" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref316" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stop the Hate: An Inter-faith Forum and Press Conference - press releases (protest by Westboro Baptist Church in Hartford and responses), official statement with clergy and community leaders' signatures, November 22, 1999</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240004" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref318" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Eminem's Hate Lyrics - press conference flyers and photographs, July 21, 2000; news articles, media list, correspondence, 2000</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240005" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref319" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Condemning Hate Speech by Eminem - press kit</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240006" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref320" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Leadership Conference on Civil Rights Hate Crimes Coalition: United Against Hate Campaign - correspondence, alleged "gay bashing" at Ocean Beach, New London, CT</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240007" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref321" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Hate Crimes Legislation: "An Act Concerning Intimidation Based on Bigotry or Bias" - correspondence, action alerts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240008" type="Folder">35</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref322" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Hate Crimes Prevention Act" - correspondence, action alert</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid240009" type="Folder">36</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref323" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series XI: Political and Legislative Issues</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref324" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Political Caucus - newsletters, notes, minutes, membership list, clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid240010" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1975-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref325" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Political Caucus - meeting minutes, annual report, fact sheets, reports, convention agenda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid240011" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1976-1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref326" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Political Caucus candidate polling project - correspondence, questionnaire, results</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid240012" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref327" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Political Caucus candidate polling project - completed questionnaires</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid240013" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref328" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Political Caucus - articles, flyers, legislative proposals, newsletters, correspondence, candidate questionnaire</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid240014" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1978-1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref329" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Women's Political Caucus legislative issues - bills, vote counts, notes, correspondence, articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid240015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid240015" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref330" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>William Wollenberg Transcripts - proceedings, testimony</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid241001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid241001" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref331" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>William Wollenberg Transcripts - proceedings, testimony</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid241002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid241002" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref332" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>William Wollenberg Transcripts - testimony, notes, articles, appellate decisions</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid241003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid241003" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref333" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>William Wollenberg Transcripts - correspondence, transcripts, articles, notes, testimony, flyer</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid241004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid241004" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref334" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miles Rapoport "Women for Rapoport Fundraiser" - emails, tickets, poster</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid241005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid241005" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref335" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miles Rapoport articles for the American Prospect - draft, revisions, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid241006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid241006" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref336" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Democracy Works - correspondence, orders, notes, newsletter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid241007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid241007" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1999-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref337" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Democracy Works fundraising - list, briefing sheet</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid241008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid241008" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref338" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Democracy Works - miscellanea, correspondence, notes, agenda, workshop information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242001" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref339" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Democracy Works: Restoration of Voting Rights Project - symposium agenda, program, brochures, correspondence, articles, attendees list</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242002" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref340" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Democracy Works: University of Connecticut Student Interns - orientation materials, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242003" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref341" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Democracy Works: Election Day Voter Registration Workshop - invitation, fact sheets, agenda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242004" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref364" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Democracy Works: Budget Meeting with Senator Kevin Sullivan - correspondence, phone and address lists, notes, mailings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid243004" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref342" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit Lobby Day - notes, sign-up sheets, flyers, program</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242005" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>March 2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref344" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit - testimony before the Human Services Committee and the Appropriations Committee</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242006" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>January 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref345" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit Media/Communitcations - notes, correspondence, articles, editorial</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242007" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>January 2006-April 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref346" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit - bills and timetable, mayor's press conference notes, Connecticut Economic Security Act, Legal Assistance Resource Center of Connecticut</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242008" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>February 2006-March 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref347" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit - Connecticut Association for Human Services grant application, Legislative Outreach Campaign plan and activities</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242009" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>March 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref348" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit Community Partners - correspondence, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242010" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>March 2006-April 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref349" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit: Family Economic Security Action Alerts - correspondence, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242011" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>March 2006-April 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref350" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit - Connecticut Association for Human Services invoices, pay stubs, consulting contract</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242012" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>April 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref351" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earned Income Tax Credit - Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) press conference</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242013" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>April 2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref353" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ned Lamont for Senate/Connecticut Choice Voice Fundraiser - notes, advertisements, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242014" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref354" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ned Lamont for Senate/Equality CT - notes, articles, correspondence, vote counts, flyers, petitions</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242015" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate>2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref355" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ned Lamont for Senate/Choice 2006 - flyers, bumper sticker, voter registration form, list of registrars, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242016" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref356" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellanea - legislative proposals, Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights brochure, photographs with Toby Moffett</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242017" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref357" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lobbying and Legislative Action - correspondence, fact sheet, newsletter, flyer</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242018" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref358" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>People for Change Campaign - plan, district street listing, notes, flyers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242019" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref359" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Presidential Inauguration of William Jefferson Clinton - invitation, tickets, Gay and Lesbian Inaugural Celebration program and portrait, letter of nomination for Inaugural Reception honoree, clipping</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid242020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid242020" type="Folder">35</container>
                        <unitdate>1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref360" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Political Research Associates correspondence, 1996; "How Democracy Works," 1996; election information, 1998; Village Voice Education Supplement, 1998</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid243001" type="Folder">36</container>
                        <unitdate>1996, 1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref361" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legislative Electoral Assistance Project (LEAP) - planning agenda, memoranda, activities, Social and Economic Justice Coalition Project, Northeast Action News</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid243002" type="Folder">37</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref362" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Debt Retirement - meeting notes, agenda, minutes, correspondence, lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid243003" type="Folder">38</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref365" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellanea - brochures, event agendas, candidate forum schedule, jury duty summons, flight itinerary, symposium notice</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid243005" type="Folder">39</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref366" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Election Day Registration/Campaign Finance Reform - testimony before Government, Administration, and Elections Committee, announcement, articles, bills, fact sheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid243006" type="Folder">40</container>
                        <unitdate>2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref367" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hilltop Brigade campaign volunteers - fact sheet, notes, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid243007" type="Folder">41</container>
                        <unitdate>2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref368" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Beth Bye for State Representative Campaign - notes, minutes, article, vote count, survey results, phone list, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid243008" type="Folder">42</container>
                        <unitdate>2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref369" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series XII: United Way and Latinos/as Contra SIDA</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref370" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>United Way Allocations Committee - agency reviews, correspondence, agendas, budget requests, summaries, flyers, reports</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid243009" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref371" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>United Way Site Visit Committee - reports, correspondence, budget requests, schedule, forms, maps, flyers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid243010" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref372" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>United Way/La Casa de Puerto Rico, Inc. - correspondence, financial statements, tax forms</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid243011" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref373" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>United Way Lesbian and Gay Issues - notes, correspondence, forms</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid243012" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref374" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA - correspondence, board of directors minutes and agenda, action alert, newsletter, budget</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid243013" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1991-1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref375" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA Finance Committee - leadership and training materials, reports, notes, minutes, agendas, correspondence, budget spreadsheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid243014" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1992-1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref376" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA - annual report minutes, membership, budget, donations, clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid243015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid243015" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1992-1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref377" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA Annual Report 1993</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244001" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref378" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA - minutes, agendas, correspondence, policies and procedures, memoranda, budget worksheets, article</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244002" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1993-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref379" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA Finance and Development Committee - minutes, agenda, budget worksheet, resumes, correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244003" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1993-1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref380" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA - finance committee and board minutes, agenda; Project J.U.M.P.P. (Jovenes Unidos Movilizados Para Prevencion) reports, newsletter, notes, memoranda, article</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244004" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-1995</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref381" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA Board, Personnel, and Nomination Committee - event programs, notes, lists, action alert flyers, memoranda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244005" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1995-1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref382" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA Development Committee - memoranda, notes, correspondence, development worksheets, agendas, minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244006" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1995-1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref383" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA Board of Directors - agendas, minutes, reports, budget spreadsheets, articles, flyers, memoranda, notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244007" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref384" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA Finance Committee - income worksheets, budgets, notes, memoranda, correspondence, agenda, minutes, budget spreadsheets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244008" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref385" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Latinos/as Contra SIDA Board of Directors - agendas, minutes, notes, memoranda, correspondence, newsletters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid244009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid244009" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref386" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series XIII: Posters</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref390" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Garlic. Chez Panisse Garlic Festival. Berkeley, David Lance Goines, 1979. Autographed on the reverse side by Tirzah, Jenifer, Lesley, Pura and Stonewall Congress. 50.5 x 70.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref391" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Gertrude and Alice. Diana Souhami. Pandora, Imprint of Harper Collins, n.d. 40 x 55 cm. (3 copies)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref392" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Civil Rights. 1997 Legislative Summary. 45.5 x 60.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref393" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Improving Our Services Creating Safe Support Space. . .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 6.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>[1997]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref394" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Screening for Woman to Woman Battering. . .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>[1997]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref395" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Effects of Homophobia, Bi-Phobia, "Coming Out/Closeted Issues". . .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>[1997]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref396" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Differences between S/M and Battering. . .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>[1997]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref397" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Myths about Woman to Woman Battering. . .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>[1997]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref398" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Domestic Violence in Same-Gender Relationships. . .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid245009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>[1997]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref429" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Imogene Knode" poem by Olga Broumas, 14 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid247007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref430" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Activist Women Tell Their Stories," featuring Carolyn Gabel-Brett; Trinity College, Hartford, CT, n.d. 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid247008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref431" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Daedalus Productions of New York Presents "For Colored Girls who have Considered Suicide when the Rainbow is Enuf" a play by Ntozake Shange, 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid248001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref432" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Wallflower Order Dance Collective, A Benefit for Interval House Shelter for Battered Women, n.d. 29 x 44 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid248002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref433" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Institute for Women of Color, "Building a Colorful Coalition," autographed by Marion C. Martinez, 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid248003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref434" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Holly Near and Cris Williamson, A Benefit Concert for the Mediation and Training Collaborative, Franklin Community Action Corporation, autographed by Holly Near and Cris Williamson, 26.5 x 41 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid248004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref408" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Studies Posters and Flyers for Past CCSU Women's Studies Events</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid246013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    </did>
                    <c03 id="ref409" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women in Performing Arts, 45 x 30 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1985</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref410" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women in Sports, 45 x 30 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1985</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref411" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Some Firsts for Women, 45 x 30 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1985</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref412" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women in Science, 45 x 30 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1985</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref413" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>The Common Woman, 45 x 30 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1985</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref414" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women in Government, 45 x 30 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1985</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref415" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women in Art and Literature, 45 x 30 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1985</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref416" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women in Social Reform, 45 x 30 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1985</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref417" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Secretary of Labor Frances Perkins, Author of Social Security, TABS: Aids for Ending Sexism in School, 28 x 43 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1980</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref418" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Congressional Resolution Designating the Month of March as "Women's History Month," n.d. 28 x 42.5 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref419" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>The Committee on the Concerns of Women presents the Annual Women's History Luncheon "A Celebration of Women in the Arts," 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1994</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref420" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Debate: Nancy Johnson, Charlotte Koskoff, Timothy Knibbs - Student Center Ballroom, CCSU, 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref421" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women's History Month Luncheon: Laughter: RX for Survival, co-sponsored by the Committee on the Concerns of Women, Women's Studies, and the Ruth Boyea Women's Center, n.d. 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid246015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref423" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women's History Month activities: Luncheon, Lecture Series, and Performance, n.d., 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid247002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref422" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Take Back the Night: Rally and March Against Sexual Assault, CCSU, 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid247001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref424" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>The CCSU Committee on the Concerns of Women presents "Laughter and Tears: A Celebration of Women Past and Present," n.d. 28 x42 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid247003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref425" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Women's Studies Picnic to Celebrate the 75th Anniversary of Women's Suffrage, 26.5 x 40.5 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid247004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1995</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref426" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>An Illustrated Timeline of the Woman Suffrage Movement produced by the National Women's History Project, set of 8 posters, 28 x 42 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid247005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1994</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref399" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Feminist and Lesbian Posters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid246012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    </did>
                    <c03 id="ref400" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Henrietta Szold, Women of Valor series produced by The Jewish Women's Archive and Ma'yan: The Jewish Women's Project, n.d. 45 x 60 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid245010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref401" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Glikl bas Judah of Hameln, Women of Valor series produced by The Jewish Women's Archive and Ma'yan: The Jewish Women's Project, n.d. 45 x 60 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid245011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref402" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rose Schneiderman, Women of Valor series produced by The Jewish Women's Archive and Ma'yan: The Jewish Women's Project, n.d. 45 x 60 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid245012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref403" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Katherine Dunham by Christine Engle Eber, n.d. 43 x 55.5 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid245013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref404" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Hopi Corn Grinding Song by Christine Engle Eber, 43 x 56 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid245014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1979</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref405" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>An Unauthorised Interview Between The Suffragists and The Statue of Liberty by Alice Duer Miller from Women are People! (1917), 35 x 45 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid245015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1977</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref406" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Maria Mitchell quote by Christine Engle Eber, 55 x 43 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid245016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1975</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref407" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Elizabeth Cady Stanton triangular felt pennant from The National Women's Hall of Fame, n.d. 63 x 22 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid245017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref435" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series XIV: Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref436" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>VHS tape: Andrew Sullivan "Virtually Normal" 1 hour, n.d.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid248005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref478" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>VHS tape: "A Matter of Culture" 15 minutes, n.d.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid251014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref479" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>VHS tape: "G/L channel 6 story!!" n.d.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid251015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref480" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>VHS tape: "CCADV/CIGNA Carolyn 1998"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid251016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref438" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>DVD "Native Americans in Philanthropy" nativephilanthropy.org, n.d.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid248006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref439" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Video tape (reel-to-reel) "Policy and Licensing-Training Seminar" Gay-Lesbian Alliance, January 29, 1981, 2 reels</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid248007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref440" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Framed picture of Senator Joe Lieberman with quotation "I don't have time for this, sweetheart." in response to Carolyn Gabel-Brett's questioning him about his position on same-sex marriage, n.d., 23 x 28.5 cm.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid248008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref441" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stickers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid249001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                    </did>
                    <c03 id="ref443" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>White rectangle, red, white, and blue lettering "Equality Begins at Home" National Gay and Lesbian Task Force, Federation of LGBT Statewide Political Organizations, March 21-27, 1999, 4 x 2.5 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref444" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>White circle with picture of a clothes hanger outlined in red with a red diagonal line through it, n.d., 4 x 4 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref445" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Yellow circle with "Equality" written in black, n.d., 7 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref446" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Red circle with "Making Women Visible Day" written in white, n.d., 9 x 7.3 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref447" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>White square, "This Home's Privacy is Protected by the ACLU," n.d., 7.6 x 7.6 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref448" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Yellow rectangle with blue lettering, "Keep Your Laws off my Body" National Organization for Women, n.d., 23 x 7.5 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref449" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>White rectangle with red, white, and blue lettering "It's a Man's World Unless Women Vote" CT Permanent Commission on the status of Women, n.d., 29 x 7.5 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref450" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Buttons</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid249010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                    </did>
                    <c03 id="ref451" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>White rectangle, red, white, and blue lettering "Equality Begins at Home" National Gay and Lesbian Task Force, Federation of LGBT Statewide Political Organizations, March 21-27, 1999, 5 x 4 cm., 3 buttons</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref452" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Blue circle with white lettering "Gay and Lesbian Voters for Clinton Gore" Human Rights Campaign Fund, n.d., 6.5 cm.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref453" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Directories, booklets, pamphlets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid249013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                    </did>
                    <c03 id="ref455" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Directory of Connecticut's Federal and State Elected Officials 1999-2000, The League of Women Voters of Connecticut Education Fund, Inc., 10 x 22 cm., 25 pages</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1999-2000</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref456" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Directory of Connecticut's Federal and State Elected Officials 2001-2002, The League of Women Voters of Connecticut Education Fund, Inc., 10 x 22 cm., 25 pages</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref454" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Booklet "People Have the Power Rally" Connecticut Progressive Directory, 13.7 x 21 cm., 16 pages</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref457" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Booklet "Connecticut Pridelink 2000, a resource guide of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Organizations," Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund, 10 x 21.5 cm., 50 pages</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref458" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Booklet "Universal Declaration of Human Rights, National Center for Human Rights Education," 9.5 x 12.7 cm., [20 pages]</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid249018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref459" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Booklet "Confronting Homophobia: Notes on Creating a Lesbian Community" by Bernice Goodman, A Matter of LIfe, National Gay Health Coalition Educational Foundation, 16 x 21 cm., 12 pages</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid250001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref460" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Companions: A dating service formed exclusively for lesbians and gay males"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid250002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref461" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "There are 13 Votes Between Equality and You..." National Women's Political Caucus Equal Rights Amendment Fund</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid250003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref462" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Gender Identity Clinic of New England, Information presented by the Twenty Club"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid250004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref463" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Summit Women's Center West: Quality gynecological and counseling services, West Hartford"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid250005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref464" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Why are Parents, Teenagers, Teachers... Fighting the Family Protection Act?" National Coalition to Stop the FPA (Family Protection Act)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid250006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref465" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Why are Women Joinng the National Gay Task Force?" 2 copies</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref466" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Abortion, Legal Since 1973, yet in Connecticut, the Constitution State..." Conn-NARAL (National Abortion Rights Action League), 1978</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref467" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Abortion, Legal Since 1973, yet in Connecticut, the Constitution State..." Conn-NARAL (National Abortion Rights Action League), 1979</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1979</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref468" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "YWCA Sexual Assault Crisis Service 24 Hour Hot LIne"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref469" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Know Your Rights: What to do if You're Stopped by the Police, the FBI, the INS, or the Customs Service," published by the ACLU, updated December 2001</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref470" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Community Works of Connecticut: Give for Change"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref471" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Connecticut General Assembly of 1981" Conn-NARAL (National Abortion Rights Action League)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref472" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "The Connecticut Task Force on Abused Women"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref473" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Three Extraordinary Women," The University of Tennessee Press</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref475" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "Women in China," Philo Press</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref476" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "A Celebration of Our Healing," YWCA of Greater New Haven</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                    <c03 id="ref477" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pamphlet "The Fourth National Lesbian/Gay Health Conference," University of Houston</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid251013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c03>
                </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
